<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#349#000046#     2#         1134#">Va. Code Ann. § 46.2-1134</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_46.2-1134"/><heading><desig>§ 46.2-1134.</desig><title>Special overweight seizure provisions; penalty</title></heading><bodyText><p>Any officer or size and weight compliance agent authorized to serve process or weigh vehicles under the provisions of this chapter may hold an overweight vehicle without an attachment summons or court order, but only for such time as is reasonably necessary to promptly petition for an attachment summons to attach the vehicle.</p><p>After finding reasonable cause for the issuance of an attachment summons, the judicial officer conducting the hearing shall inform the operator of the vehicle of his option to either pay the liquidated damages, civil penalty, weighing fee, and processing fee, or contest the charge through the attachment proceeding. If the operator chooses to make payment, he shall do so to the judicial officer who shall transmit the citation, liquidated damages, civil penalty, weighing fee, and processing fee to the Department for distribution in accordance with <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 46.2-1131"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 46.2-1131">§ 46.2-1131<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000046#     2#         1131#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p><p>The Commonwealth shall not be required to post bond in order to attach a vehicle pursuant to this section. The officer or size and weight compliance agent authorized to hold the overweight vehicle pending a hearing on the attachment petition shall also be empowered to execute the attachment summons if issued. Any bond for the retention of the vehicle or for release of the attachment shall be given in accordance with <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 8.01-553"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 8.01-553">§ 8.01-553<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000008#    01#          553#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> except that the bond shall be taken by a judicial officer. The judicial officer shall return the bond to the clerk of the appropriate court in place of the officer serving the attachment as otherwise provided in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 8.01-554"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 8.01-554">§ 8.01-554<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000008#    01#          554#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p><p>In the event the civil penalty, liquidated damages, weighing fee, and processing fee are not paid in full, or no bond is given by or for the person charged with the weight violation, the vehicle involved in the weight violation shall be stored in a secure place, as may be designated by the owner or operator of the vehicle. If no place is designated, the officer or size and weight compliance agent executing the attachment summons shall designate the place of storage. The owner or operator shall be afforded the right of unloading and removing the cargo from the vehicle. The risk and cost of the storage shall be borne by the owner or operator of the vehicle.</p><p>Whenever an attachment summons is issued for a weight violation, the court shall forward to the Department both a copy of the order disposing of the case and the weight violation citation prepared by the officer or size and weight compliance agent but not served.</p><p>Upon notification of the judgment or administrative order entered for such weight violation and notification of the failure of such person to satisfy the judgment or order, the Department or the Department of State Police or any law-enforcement officer or size and weight compliance agent shall thereafter deny the offending person the right to operate a motor vehicle or vehicles upon the highways of the Commonwealth until the judgment or order has been satisfied and a reinstatement fee of $ 50 has been paid to the Department. Reinstatement fees collected under the provisions of this section shall be paid by the Commissioner into the state treasury and shall be set aside as a special fund to be used to meet the expenses of the Department.</p><p>When informed that the right to operate the motor vehicle has been denied, the driver shall drive the motor vehicle to a nearby location off the public highways and not move it or permit it to be moved until such judgment or order has been satisfied. Failure by the driver to comply with this provision shall constitute a Class 4 misdemeanor.</p><p>All costs incurred by the Commonwealth and all judgments, if any, against the Commonwealth due to action taken pursuant to this section shall be paid from the fund into which liquidated damages are paid.</p><p>Police officers of the Department of State Police and all other law-enforcement officers are vested with the same powers with respect to the enforcement of this chapter as they have with respect to the enforcement of the criminal laws of the Commonwealth.</p></bodyText><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p>1986, c. 588, § 46.1-341.03; 1987, c. 372; <citation normalizedCite="1989 VA CH 727"><content><span normalizedCite="1989 Va. Ch. 727">1989, c. 727<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1989#000727#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2011 VA CH 62"><content><span normalizedCite="2011 Va. Ch. 62">2011, cc. 62<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2011#000062#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2011 VA CH 73"><content><span normalizedCite="2011 Va. Ch. 73">73<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2011#000073#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PTR0-004G-K2NJ-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 46.2.</desig><title>MOTOR VEHICLES</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="subtitle"><heading><desig>SUBTITLE III.</desig><title>OPERATION</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 10.</desig><title>MOTOR VEHICLE AND EQUIPMENT SAFETY</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="article"><heading><desig>ARTICLE 17.</desig><title>MAXIMUM VEHICLE WEIGHTS</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Governments</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjdEQjE4OUJDMzQxNDNEMEI0RTI1QUFCMzJENjEwRTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Clerks of Court</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6REVFMjkzRDI1MkU2NERDNjk3OEUxODY0REYwMUI1NjE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NURENzJGNTEyQzM0NEREQUI2RkVCRTM4RTc1RTZBREU</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Transportation Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RTYzRTk5RDVBQkQ2NDcwQzk2NTU3ODQ5OEE3NDlBNzk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Size &amp; Weight</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NTRGMEEwNjI0N0IxNDYxRjlGOUEzQjNCNzVFNTVFMUY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NkMyNTdFM0IyMjQ2NDQzOEEwNzc4NUE5RjExN0Y3RTU</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification><classificationGroup classificationScheme="indexing-terms"><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem score="90"><className>Transportation</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RTYzRTk5RDVBQkQ2NDcwQzk2NTU3ODQ5OEE3NDlBNzk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></classificationGroup></metadata></legislativeDoc>