<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#123#000055#      66.4#">Va. Code Ann. § 55-66.4</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_55-66.4"/><heading><desig>§ 55-66.4.</desig><title>Partial satisfaction or release</title></heading><bodyText><p>It shall be lawful for any such lienor to make a marginal release or record a certificate of partial satisfaction of any one or more of the separate pieces or parcels of property covered by such lien. It shall also be lawful for any such lienor to make a marginal release or record a certificate of partial satisfaction of any part of the real estate covered by such lien if a plat of such part or a deed of such part is recorded in the clerk's office and a cross reference is made in the marginal release or certificate of partial satisfaction to the book and page where the plat or deed of such part is recorded. Such marginal partial release or satisfaction or certificate of partial satisfaction may be accomplished in manner and form hereinbefore in this chapter provided for making marginal releases or certificates of satisfaction, except that the creditor, or his duly authorized agent, shall make an affidavit to the clerk or in such certificate that such creditor is at the time of making such release the legal holder of the obligation, note, bond or other evidence of debt, secured by such lien, and when made in conformity therewith and as provided herein such partial satisfaction or release shall be as valid and binding as a proper release deed duly executed for the same purpose.</p><p>Any and all partial marginal releases made prior to July 1, 1966, in any county or city of this Commonwealth, in conformity with the provisions of this chapter, either of one or more separate pieces or parcels of real estate or any part of the real estate covered by such lien, or as to one or more of the obligations secured by any such lien, or as to all of the real estate covered by such lien instrument, are hereby validated and declared to be binding upon all parties in interest; but this provision shall not be construed as intended to disturb or impair any vested right.</p></bodyText><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p>Code 1919, § 6456; 1930, p. 70; 1932, p. 121; 1944, p. 199; 1952, c. 469; 1966, c. 505; 1975, c. 469; 1977, c. 141.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PTC0-004G-K2N0-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 55.</desig><title>PROPERTY AND CONVEYANCES</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 4.</desig><title>FORM AND EFFECT OF DEEDS AND COVENANTS; LIENS</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="article"><heading><desig>ARTICLE 2.</desig><title>FORM AND EFFECT OF DEEDS OF TRUST; SALES THEREUNDER; ASSIGNMENTS; RELEASES</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Real Property Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QUUyRTcxRURBNEY2NEE2MDk3QzBCNzRDOEY0NTZDQzk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OUQ1RjgyODZFQUE0NDRGRDkyNTBGMDY0MDY2NkZDMzY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6M0U1QzVGRDA1Q0ZGNEFDNUE2NDY1MjNFNjg2MDhFMkE</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification><classificationGroup classificationScheme="indexing-terms"><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem score="90"><className>Real Property</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QUUyRTcxRURBNEY2NEE2MDk3QzBCNzRDOEY0NTZDQzk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></classificationGroup></metadata></legislativeDoc>