<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#123#000043#        11#">Va. Code Ann. § 43-11</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_43-11"/><heading><desig>§ 43-11.</desig><title>How owner or general contractor made personally liable to subcontractor, laborer or materialman</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Any subcontractor or person furnishing labor or material to the general contractor or subcontractor, may give a preliminary notice in writing to the owner or his agent or the general contractor, stating the nature and character of his contract and the probable amount of his claim.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Additionally, if such subcontractor, or person furnishing labor or material shall at any time after the work is done or material furnished by him and before the expiration of thirty days from the time such building or structure is completed or the work thereon otherwise terminated furnish the owner thereof or his agent and also the general contractor, or the general contractor alone in case he is the only one notified, with a second notice stating a correct account, verified by affidavit, of his actual claim against the general contractor or subcontractor, for work done or materials furnished and of the amount due, then the owner, or the general contractor, if he alone was notified, shall be personally liable to the claimant for the actual amount due to the subcontractor or persons furnishing labor or material by the general contractor or subcontractor, provided the same does not exceed the sum in which the owner is indebted to the general contractor at the time the second notice is given or may thereafter become indebted by virtue of his contract with the general contractor, or in case the general contractor alone is notified the sum in which he is indebted to the subcontractor at the time the second notice is given or may thereafter become indebted by virtue of his contract with the general contractor. But the amount which a person supplying labor or material to a subcontractor can claim shall not exceed the amount for which such subcontractor could file his claim.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Any bona fide agreement for deductions by the owner because of the failure or refusal of the general contractor to comply with his contract shall be binding upon such subcontractor, laborer or materialman.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_4"/><heading><desig>4.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The provisions of this section are subject to the qualification that before any such personal liability of the owner or general contractor herein provided for shall be binding the two notices herein required, with such returns thereon as is sufficient under <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 8.01-325"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 8.01-325">§ 8.01-325<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000008#    01#          325#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, shall be recorded and indexed as provided in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 43-4.1"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 43 -4.1">§ 43-4.1<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#123#000043#       4.1#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> in the appropriate clerk's office; or the two notices herein required shall be mailed by registered or certified mail to and received by the owner or general contractor upon whom personal liability is sought to be imposed, and a return receipt therefor showing delivery to the addressee shall be prima facie evidence of receipt.</p></bodyText></level><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p>1924, p. 658; Michie Code 1942, § 6429a; 1968, c. 568; <citation normalizedCite="2002 VA CH 772"><content><span normalizedCite="2002 Va. Ch. 772">2002, c. 772<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2002#000772#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PT70-004G-K0HR-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 43.</desig><title>MECHANICS' AND CERTAIN OTHER LIENS</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 1.</desig><title>MECHANICS' AND MATERIALMEN'S LIENS</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Torts</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDAwOEM2NTEzQkVDNEI4NzlGMEZERUEyRjQwODM4Njg7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Independent Contractors</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MTM0MzNFNjRCQzRGNDJEMjk0NTFCNzZGREU1OTRDMkY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MTEzNjUzREVEOURGNDE3MEEwQURENDBCMTBDOUVBNEI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></metadata></legislativeDoc>