<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#349#000042#     1#           77#">Va. Code Ann. § 42.1-77</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_42.1-77"/><heading><desig>§ 42.1-77.</desig><title>Definitions</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><bodyText><p>As used in this chapter:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><bodyText><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Agency"</emphasis> means all boards, commissions, departments, divisions, institutions, authorities, or parts thereof, of the Commonwealth or its political subdivisions and includes the offices of constitutional officers.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Archival quality"</emphasis> means a quality of reproduction consistent with established standards specified by state and national agencies and organizations responsible for establishing such standards, such as the Association for Information and Image Management, the American National Standards Institute, and the National Institute of Standards and Technology.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Archival record"</emphasis> means a public record of continuing and enduring value useful to the citizens of the Commonwealth and necessary to the administrative functions of public agencies in the conduct of services and activities mandated by law that is identified on a Library of Virginia approved records retention and disposition schedule as having sufficient informational value to be permanently maintained by the Commonwealth.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Archives"</emphasis> means the program administered by The Library of Virginia for the preservation of archival records.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Board"</emphasis> means the State Library Board.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Conversion"</emphasis> means the act of moving electronic records to a different format, especially data from an obsolete format to a current format.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Custodian"</emphasis> means the public official in charge of an office having public records.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Disaster plan"</emphasis> means the information maintained by an agency that outlines recovery techniques and methods to be followed in case of an emergency that impacts the agency's records.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Electronic record"</emphasis> means a public record whose creation, storage, and access require the use of an automated system or device. Ownership of the hardware, software, or media used to create, store, or access the electronic record has no bearing on a determination of whether such record is a public record.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Essential public record"</emphasis> means records that are required for recovery and reconstruction of any agency to enable it to resume its core operations and functions and to protect the rights and interests of persons.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Librarian of Virginia"</emphasis> means the State Librarian of Virginia or his designated representative.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Lifecycle"</emphasis> means the creation, use, maintenance, and disposition of a public record.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Metadata"</emphasis> means data describing the context, content, and structure of records and their management through time.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Migration"</emphasis> means the act of moving electronic records from one information system or medium to another to ensure continued access to the records while maintaining the records' authenticity, integrity, reliability, and usability.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Original record"</emphasis> means the first generation of the information and is the preferred version of a record. Archival records should to the maximum extent possible be original records.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Preservation"</emphasis> means the processes and operations involved in ensuring the technical and intellectual survival of authentic records through time.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Private record"</emphasis> means a record that does not relate to or affect the carrying out of the constitutional, statutory, or other official ceremonial duties of a public official, including the correspondence, diaries, journals, or notes that are not prepared for, utilized for, circulated, or communicated in the course of transacting public business.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Public official"</emphasis> means all persons holding any office created by the Constitution of Virginia or by any act of the General Assembly, the Governor and all other officers of the executive branch of the state government, and all other officers, heads, presidents or chairmen of boards, commissions, departments, and agencies of the state government or its political subdivisions.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Public record"</emphasis> or <emphasis typeStyle="it">"record"</emphasis> means recorded information that documents a transaction or activity by or with any public officer, agency or employee of an agency. Regardless of physical form or characteristic, the recorded information is a public record if it is produced, collected, received or retained in pursuance of law or in connection with the transaction of public business. The medium upon which such information is recorded has no bearing on the determination of whether the recording is a public record.</p><p>For purposes of this chapter, "public record" shall not include nonrecord materials, meaning materials made or acquired and preserved solely for reference use or exhibition purposes, extra copies of documents preserved only for convenience or reference, and stocks of publications.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><bodyText><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Records retention and disposition schedule"</emphasis> means a Library of Virginia-approved timetable stating the required retention period and disposition action of a records series. The administrative, fiscal, historical, and legal value of a public record shall be considered in appraising its appropriate retention schedule. The terms "administrative," "fiscal," "historical," and "legal" value shall be defined as:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> "Administrative value": Records shall be deemed of administrative value if they have continuing utility in the operation of an agency.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> "Fiscal value": Records shall be deemed of fiscal value if they are needed to document and verify financial authorizations, obligations, and transactions.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> "Historical value": Records shall be deemed of historical value if they contain unique information, regardless of age, that provides understanding of some aspect of the government and promotes the development of an informed and enlightened citizenry.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_4"/><heading><desig>4.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> "Legal value": Records shall be deemed of legal value if they document actions taken in the protection and proving of legal or civil rights and obligations of individuals and agencies.</p></bodyText></level></level><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p>1976, c. 746; 1977, c. 501; 1981, c. 637; 1987, c. 217; <citation normalizedCite="1990 VA CH 778"><content><span normalizedCite="1990 Va. Ch. 778">1990, c. 778<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1990#000778#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1994 VA CH 390"><content><span normalizedCite="1994 Va. Ch. 390">1994, cc. 390<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1994#000390#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1994 VA CH 955"><content><span normalizedCite="1994 Va. Ch. 955">955<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1994#000955#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1998 VA CH 427"><content><span normalizedCite="1998 Va. Ch. 427">1998, cc. 427<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1998#000427#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1998 VA CH 470"><content><span normalizedCite="1998 Va. Ch. 470">470<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1998#000470#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2005 VA CH 787"><content><span normalizedCite="2005 Va. Ch. 787">2005, c. 787<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2005#000787#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2006 VA CH 60"><content><span normalizedCite="2006 Va. Ch. 60">2006, c. 60<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2006#000060#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PT70-004G-K0GT-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 42.1.</desig><title>LIBRARIES</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 7.</desig><title>VIRGINIA PUBLIC RECORDS ACT</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Education Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDkzNUEzQzFBNEZBNEFBREIxNDM5MTc1MUU5QjI4MTY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDBDMzRDODQwQzY3NDNCRDkxNDE1REEyOEFGMzBBNjE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDU1QkREN0FDNThENDhDMTk1MTk4MTQ3OUMzRjAwQjI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Evidence</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUVGQkU0QjJFMTIzNDNBM0FCNTVEQjAxQTM3RDcwOTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MzYwQUQ2RDlBNDUzNEFBRTkwRDZBNEU1NUQxQTNDMzg7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDA2QUFEQUVBNTYyNDUxNUE2MjMzMDk5NzM1NkQ1Mjc</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Governments</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjdEQjE4OUJDMzQxNDNEMEI0RTI1QUFCMzJENjEwRTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OTI0MkYyMDU1OEFCNDczQTgxNTc1NTczREYzMUQ3MzI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QURCRDNBRjBGRTE0NEFBRUEzNUU1MzFGQjg3MTM4MDI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></metadata></legislativeDoc>