<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#349#000002#     2#         1617#">Va. Code Ann. § 2.2-1617</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_2.2-1617"/><heading><desig>§ 2.2-1617.</desig><title>One-stop small business permitting program</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a"/><heading><desig>A.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> As used in this article, unless the context requires a different meaning:</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Business Permitting Center"</emphasis> or <emphasis typeStyle="it">"Center"</emphasis> means the business registration and permitting center established by this section and located in and under the administrative control of the Department.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Comprehensive application"</emphasis> means a document incorporating pertinent data from existing applications for permits covered under this section.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Comprehensive permit"</emphasis> means the single document designed for public display issued by the Business Permitting Center that certifies state agency permit approval and that incorporates the endorsements for individual permits included in the comprehensive permitting program.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Comprehensive permitting program"</emphasis> or <emphasis typeStyle="it">"Program"</emphasis> means the mechanism by which comprehensive permits are issued and renewed, permit and regulatory information is disseminated, and account data is exchanged by state agencies.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Permit"</emphasis> means the whole or part of any state agency permit, license, certificate, approval, registration, charter, or any form or permission required by law, to engage in activity associated with or involving the establishment of a small business in the Commonwealth.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Permit information packet"</emphasis> means a collection of information about permitting requirements and application procedures custom assembled for each request.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Regulatory"</emphasis> means all permitting and other governmental or statutory requirements establishing a small business or professional activities associated with establishing a small business.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Regulatory agency"</emphasis> means any state agency, board, commission, or division that regulates one or more professions, occupations, industries, businesses, or activities.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Renewal application"</emphasis> means a document used to collect pertinent data for renewal of permits covered under this section.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Small business"</emphasis> means an independently owned and operated business that, together with affiliates, has 250 or fewer employees or average annual gross receipts of $ 10 million or less averaged over the previous three years.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Veteran"</emphasis> means an individual who has served in the active military, naval, or air service and who was discharged or released therefrom under conditions other than dishonorable.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b"/><heading><desig>B.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> There is created within the Department the comprehensive permitting program (the Program). The Program is established to serve as a single access point to aid entrepreneurs in filling out the various permit applications associated with establishing a small business in Virginia. The Program in no way supersedes or supplants any regulatory authority granted to any state agency with permits covered by this section. As part of the Program, the Department shall coordinate with the regulatory agency, and the regulatory agency shall determine, consistent with applicable law, what types of permits are appropriate for inclusion in the Program as well as the rules governing the submission of and payment for those permits. The website of the Department shall provide access to information regarding the Program. The Department shall have the power and duty to:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Create a comprehensive application that will allow an entrepreneur, or an agent thereof, seeking to establish a small business, to create accounts that will allow them to acquire the appropriate permits required in the Commonwealth. The comprehensive application shall:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_1_a"/><heading><desig>a.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Allow the business owner to choose a business type and to provide common information, such as name, address, and telephone number, on the front page, eliminating the need to repeatedly provide common information on each permit application;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_1_b"/><heading><desig>b.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Allow the business owner to preview and answer questions related to the operation of the business;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_1_c"/><heading><desig>c.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Provide business owners with a customized to-do agency checklist, which checklist shall provide the permit applications pertinent to each business type and provide the rules, regulations, and general laws applicable to each business type as well as local licensing information;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_1_d"/><heading><desig>d.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Allow the business owner to submit permit applications by electronic means as authorized by <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 59.1-496"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 59.1-496">§ 59.1-496<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000059#     1#          496#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> and to affix thereto his electronic signature as defined in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 59.1-480"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 59.1-480">§ 59.1-480<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000059#     1#          480#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_1_e"/><heading><desig>e.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Allow the business owner to check on the status of applications online and to receive information from the permitting agencies electronically; and</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_1_f"/><heading><desig>f.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Allow a business owner to submit electronic payment of application or permitting fees for applications that have been accepted by the permitting agency.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Develop and administer a computerized system program capable of storing, retrieving, and exchanging permit information while protecting the confidentiality of information submitted to the Department to the extent allowable by law. Information submitted to the Department shall be subject to the provisions of the Virginia Freedom of Information Act (§ 2.2-3700 et seq.) as the same would apply were the information submitted directly to the Department or to any permitting agency.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Issue and renew comprehensive permits in an efficient manner.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_4"/><heading><desig>4.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Identify the types of permits appropriate for inclusion in the Program. The Department shall coordinate with the regulatory agency, and the regulatory agency shall determine, consistent with applicable law, what types of permits are appropriate for inclusion in the Program.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_5"/><heading><desig>5.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Incorporate permits into the Program.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_6"/><heading><desig>6.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Do all acts necessary or convenient to carry out the purposes of this chapter.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c"/><heading><desig>C.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The Business Permitting Center shall compile information regarding the regulatory programs associated with each of the permits obtainable under the Program. This information shall include, at a minimum, a listing of the statutes and administrative rules requiring the permits and pertaining to the regulatory programs that are directly related to the permit. The Center shall provide information governed by this section to any person requesting it. Materials used by the Center to describe the services provided by the Center shall indicate that this information is available upon request.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d"/><heading><desig>D.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Each state agency shall cooperate and provide reasonable assistance to the Department in the implementation of this section.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_e"/><heading><desig>E.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The State Corporation Commission and the Department of Small Business and Supplier Diversity shall:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_e_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> By December 1, 2014, implement a hyperlink from the State Corporation Commission's eFile system to the Center that will facilitate the collection by the Center of a user's information to populate any forms that will be required to be completed at a future date, to the end that the user will not be required unnecessarily to reenter data or information into the forms when the user is accessing the Center; and</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_e_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> By June 30, 2018, fully integrate processes and forms into the Center and shall process all forms within 48 business hours from the time the applicant submits the form electronically.</p><p>The State Corporation Commission and the Center shall report on progress and any barriers to completion of the provisions of subdivision 1 biannually, on each December 1 and June 1, to the Governor, the Secretary of Commerce and Trade, the Secretary of Technology, and the chairs of the Senate Committees on Finance, General Laws and Technology, and Commerce and Labor and of the House Committees on Appropriations and Commerce and Labor.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_f"/><heading><desig>F.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Any person requiring permits that have been incorporated into the Program may submit a comprehensive application to the Department requesting the issuance of the permits. The comprehensive application form shall contain in consolidated form information necessary for the issuance of the permits.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_g"/><heading><desig>G.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The applicant, if not a veteran, shall include with the application the handling fee established by the Department. An applicant who is a veteran shall be exempt from payment of the handling fee prescribed by this subsection. The amount of the handling fee assessed against the applicant shall be set by the Department at a level necessary to cover the costs of administering the comprehensive permitting program.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_h"/><heading><desig>H.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The authority for approving the issuance and renewal of any requested permit that requires investigation, inspection, testing, or other judgmental review by the regulatory agency otherwise legally authorized to issue the permit shall remain with that agency. The Center may issue those permits for which proper fee payment and a completed application form have been received and for which no approval action is required by the regulatory agency.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_i"/><heading><desig>I.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Upon receipt of the application, and proper fee payment for any permit for which issuance is subject to regulatory agency action under subsection H, the Department shall immediately notify the State Corporation Commission or the regulatory agency with authority to approve the permit issuance or renewal requested by the applicant. The State Corporation Commission or the regulatory agency shall advise the Department within a reasonable time after receiving the notice of one of the following:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_i_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> That the State Corporation Commission or the regulatory agency approves the issuance of the requested permit and will advise the applicant of any specific conditions required for issuing the permit;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_i_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> That the State Corporation Commission or the regulatory agency denies the issuance of the permit and gives the applicant reasons for the denial;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_i_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> That the application is pending; or</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_i_4"/><heading><desig>4.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> That the application is incomplete and further information from or action by the applicant is necessary.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_j"/><heading><desig>J.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The Department shall issue a comprehensive permit endorsed for all the approved permits to the applicant and advise the applicant of the status of other requested permits. The applicant shall be responsible for contesting any decision regarding conditions imposed or permits denied through the normal process established by statute or by the State Corporation Commission or the regulatory agency with the authority for approving the issuance of the permit.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_k"/><heading><desig>K.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Regulatory agencies shall be provided information from the comprehensive application for their permitting and regulatory functions.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_l"/><heading><desig>L.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The Department shall be responsible for directing the applicant to make all payments for applicable fees established by the regulatory agency directly to the proper agency.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_m"/><heading><desig>M.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> There is hereby created in the state treasury a special nonreverting fund to be known as the Comprehensive Permitting Fund, hereafter referred to as "the Fund." The Fund shall be established on the books of the Comptroller. The Fund shall consist of all moneys collected from the handling fee established by the Department pursuant to subsection G and such other funds as may be appropriated by the General Assembly. Interest earned on moneys in the Fund shall remain in the Fund and be credited to it. Any moneys remaining in the Fund, including interest thereon, at the end of each fiscal year shall not revert to the general fund but shall remain in the Fund. Moneys in the Fund shall be used solely to administer the Program. Expenditures and disbursements from the Fund shall be made by the State Treasurer on warrants issued by the Comptroller upon written request signed by the Director of the Department.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_n"/><heading><desig>N.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Unless otherwise directed by the regulatory agency, the Department shall not issue or renew a comprehensive permit to any person under any of the following circumstances:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_n_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The person does not have a valid tax registration, if required;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_n_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The person is a corporation, limited liability company, business trust, limited partnership, or registered limited liability partnership that (i) is delinquent in the payment of fees or penalties collected by the State Corporation Commission pursuant to the business entity statutes it administers, (ii) does not exist, or (iii) is not authorized to transact business in the Commonwealth pursuant to one of the business entity statutes administered by the State Corporation Commission; or</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_n_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The person has not submitted the sum of all fees and deposits required for the requested individual permit endorsements, any outstanding comprehensive permit delinquency fee, or other fees and penalties to be collected through the comprehensive permitting program.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_o"/><heading><desig>O.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The Department may adopt regulations in accordance with <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 2.2-1606"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 2.2-1606">§ 2.2-1606<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000002#     2#         1606#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> as may be necessary to carry out the purposes of this section.</p></bodyText></level><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p><citation normalizedCite="2013 VA CH 155"><content><span normalizedCite="2013 Va. Ch. 155">2013, cc. 155<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2013#000155#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2013 VA CH 206"><content><span normalizedCite="2013 Va. Ch. 206">206<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2013#000206#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2013 VA CH 482"><content><span normalizedCite="2013 Va. Ch. 482">482<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2013#000482#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2014 VA CH 758"><content><span normalizedCite="2014 Va. Ch. 758">2014, c. 758<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2014#000758#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PW80-004G-K197-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 2.2.</desig><title>ADMINISTRATION OF GOVERNMENT</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="subtitle"><heading><desig>SUBTITLE I.</desig><title>ORGANIZATION OF STATE GOVERNMENT</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="part"><heading><desig>PART C.</desig><title>STATE AGENCIES RELATED TO THE GENERAL OPERATION OF GOVERNMENT</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 16.1.</desig><title>DEPARTMENT OF SMALL BUSINESS AND SUPPLIER DIVERSITY</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="article"><heading><desig>ARTICLE 3.</desig><title>SMALL BUSINESS PERMITTING.</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Limited Liability Partnerships</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Qzc3QkNFMUExQzM2NDJGRTg3REE0N0I1QzhCQUE3QjM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjA4OEVGODBENzY4NDcxM0IyQzA1OTEwQzVDODRBOUE</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjA4OEVGODBENzY4NDcxM0IyQzA1OTEwQzVDODRBOUE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjQ1NzI5NzRGQUEwNDg1RThBNDE0NTE2MkYzODc3NUQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RUZBNTgwODk0QkRCNDUwQkExNzBFRkU0NkI4MkE5OTU</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NUUwRjE5Nzk1QUU0NEZGQTgxNjExMzg4QjMxQTYwMzI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NUFDMUUyMjFERDQ1NDg3NTg1NzVCNzQyMTU5QzlBODI</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RDVCRkUzRjg3NUFFNDMwNjhGMDc3MkNENDMxNzhFOEM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDFEQjUyNDAyMzQ0NDQyNUE5RjNGOEZEMzNBRDA1RUY</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Limited Liability Partnerships</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Qzc3QkNFMUExQzM2NDJGRTg3REE0N0I1QzhCQUE3QjM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjA4OEVGODBENzY4NDcxM0IyQzA1OTEwQzVDODRBOUE</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Management</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6ODU5MUE4QUUyMDMzNDU4MDg0MUU5NUM3MUQ4ODcyODY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RUZBNTgwODk0QkRCNDUwQkExNzBFRkU0NkI4MkE5OTU</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Governments</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjdEQjE4OUJDMzQxNDNEMEI0RTI1QUFCMzJENjEwRTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Licenses</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6N0IyQjkyQkVENEM2NDczNzg5MDUwQ0U5RDMzRjlDNUM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QURCRDNBRjBGRTE0NEFBRUEzNUU1MzFGQjg3MTM4MDI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification><classificationGroup classificationScheme="indexing-terms"><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem score="90"><className>Governments</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjdEQjE4OUJDMzQxNDNEMEI0RTI1QUFCMzJENjEwRTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></classificationGroup></metadata></legislativeDoc>