<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#123#000056#       576#">Va. Code Ann. § 56-576</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_56-576"/><heading><desig>§ 56-576.</desig><title>Definitions</title></heading><bodyText><p>As used in this chapter:</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Affiliate"</emphasis> means any person that controls, is controlled by, or is under common control with an electric utility.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Aggregator"</emphasis> means a person that, as an agent or intermediary, (i) offers to purchase, or purchases, electric energy or (ii) offers to arrange for, or arranges for, the purchase of electric energy, for sale to, or on behalf of, two or more retail customers not controlled by or under common control with such person. The following activities shall not, in and of themselves, make a person an aggregator under this chapter: (i) furnishing legal services to two or more retail customers, suppliers or aggregators; (ii) furnishing educational, informational, or analytical services to two or more retail customers, unless direct or indirect compensation for such services is paid by an aggregator or supplier of electric energy; (iii) furnishing educational, informational, or analytical services to two or more suppliers or aggregators; (iv) providing default service under <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 56-585"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 56 -585">§ 56-585<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#123#000056#       585#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; (v) engaging in activities of a retail electric energy supplier, licensed pursuant to <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 56-587"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 56 -587">§ 56-587<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#123#000056#       587#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, which are authorized by such supplier's license; and (vi) engaging in actions of a retail customer, in common with one or more other such retail customers, to issue a request for proposal or to negotiate a purchase of electric energy for consumption by such retail customers.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Combined heat and power"</emphasis> means a method of using waste heat from electrical generation to offset traditional processes, space heating, air conditioning, or refrigeration.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Commission"</emphasis> means the State Corporation Commission.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Cooperative"</emphasis> means a utility formed under or subject to Chapter 9.1 (<citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 56-231.15"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 56 -231.15">§ 56-231.15<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#123#000056#    231.15#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> et seq.).</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Covered entity"</emphasis> means a provider in the Commonwealth of an electric service not subject to competition but shall not include default service providers.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Covered transaction"</emphasis> means an acquisition, merger, or consolidation of, or other transaction involving stock, securities, voting interests or assets by which one or more persons obtains control of a covered entity.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Curtailment"</emphasis> means inducing retail customers to reduce load during times of peak demand so as to ease the burden on the electrical grid.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Customer choice"</emphasis> means the opportunity for a retail customer in the Commonwealth to purchase electric energy from any supplier licensed and seeking to sell electric energy to that customer.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Demand response"</emphasis> means measures aimed at shifting time of use of electricity from peak-use periods to times of lower demand by inducing retail customers to curtail electricity usage during periods of congestion and higher prices in the electrical grid.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Distribute," "distributing,"</emphasis> or <emphasis typeStyle="it">"distribution of"</emphasis> electric energy means the transfer of electric energy through a retail distribution system to a retail customer.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Distributor"</emphasis> means a person owning, controlling, or operating a retail distribution system to provide electric energy directly to retail customers.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Electric utility"</emphasis> means any person that generates, transmits, or distributes electric energy for use by retail customers in the Commonwealth, including any investor-owned electric utility, cooperative electric utility, or electric utility owned or operated by a municipality.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Energy efficiency program"</emphasis> means a program that reduces the total amount of electricity that is required for the same process or activity implemented after the expiration of capped rates. Energy efficiency programs include equipment, physical, or program change designed to produce measured and verified reductions in the amount of electricity required to perform the same function and produce the same or a similar outcome. Energy efficiency programs may include, but are not limited to, (i) programs that result in improvements in lighting design, heating, ventilation, and air conditioning systems, appliances, building envelopes, and industrial and commercial processes; (ii) measures, such as but not limited to the installation of advanced meters, implemented or installed by utilities, that reduce fuel use or losses of electricity and otherwise improve internal operating efficiency in generation, transmission, and distribution systems; and (iii) customer engagement programs that result in measurable and verifiable energy savings that lead to efficient use patterns and practices. Energy efficiency programs include demand response, combined heat and power and waste heat recovery, curtailment, or other programs that are designed to reduce electricity consumption so long as they reduce the total amount of electricity that is required for the same process or activity. Utilities shall be authorized to install and operate such advanced metering technology and equipment on a customer's premises; however, nothing in this chapter establishes a requirement that an energy efficiency program be implemented on a customer's premises and be connected to a customer's wiring on the customer's side of the inter-connection without the customer's expressed consent.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Generate," "generating,"</emphasis> or <emphasis typeStyle="it">"generation of"</emphasis> electric energy means the production of electric energy.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Generator"</emphasis> means a person owning, controlling, or operating a facility that produces electric energy for sale.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Incumbent electric utility"</emphasis> means each electric utility in the Commonwealth that, prior to July 1, 1999, supplied electric energy to retail customers located in an exclusive service territory established by the Commission.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Independent system operator"</emphasis> means a person that may receive or has received, by transfer pursuant to this chapter, any ownership or control of, or any responsibility to operate, all or part of the transmission systems in the Commonwealth.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"In the public interest,"</emphasis> for purposes of assessing energy efficiency programs, describes an energy efficiency program if, among other factors, the net present value of the benefits exceeds the net present value of the costs as determined by the Commission upon consideration of the following four tests: (i) the Total Resource Cost Test; (ii) the Utility Cost Test (also referred to as the Program Administrator Test); (iii) the Participant Test; and (iv) the Ratepayer Impact Measure Test. Such determination shall include an analysis of all four tests, and a program or portfolio of programs shall not be rejected based solely on the results of a single test. In addition, an energy efficiency program may be deemed to be "in the public interest" if the program provides measurable and verifiable energy savings to low-income customers or elderly customers.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Measured and verified"</emphasis> means a process determined pursuant to methods accepted for use by utilities and industries to measure, verify, and validate energy savings and peak demand savings. This may include the protocol established by the United States Department of Energy, Office of Federal Energy Management Programs, Measurement and Verification Guidance for Federal Energy Projects, measurement and verification standards developed by the American Society of Heating, Refrigeration and Air Conditioning Engineers (ASHRAE), or engineering-based estimates of energy and demand savings associated with specific energy efficiency measures, as determined by the Commission.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Municipality"</emphasis> means a city, county, town, authority, or other political subdivision of the Commonwealth.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"New underground facilities"</emphasis> means facilities to provide underground distribution service. "New underground facilities" includes underground cables with voltages of 69 kilovolts or less, pad-mounted devices, connections at customer meters, and transition terminations from existing overhead distribution sources.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Peak-shaving"</emphasis> means measures aimed solely at shifting time of use of electricity from peak-use periods to times of lower demand by inducing retail customers to curtail electricity usage during periods of congestion and higher prices in the electrical grid.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Person"</emphasis> means any individual, corporation, partnership, association, company, business, trust, joint venture, or other private legal entity, and the Commonwealth or any municipality.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Renewable energy"</emphasis> means energy derived from sunlight, wind, falling water, biomass, sustainable or otherwise, (the definitions of which shall be liberally construed), energy from waste, landfill gas, municipal solid waste, wave motion, tides, and geothermal power, and does not include energy derived from coal, oil, natural gas, or nuclear power. Renewable energy shall also include the proportion of the thermal or electric energy from a facility that results from the co-firing of biomass.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Renewable thermal energy"</emphasis> means the thermal energy output from (i) a renewable-fueled combined heat and power generation facility that is (a) constructed, or renovated and improved, after January 1, 2012, (b) located in the Commonwealth, and (c) utilized in industrial processes other than the combined heat and power generation facility or (ii) a solar energy system, certified to the OG-100 standard of the Solar Ratings and Certification Corporation or an equivalent certification body, that (a) is constructed, or renovated and improved, after January 1, 2013, (b) is located in the Commonwealth, and (c) heats water or air for residential, commercial, institutional, or industrial purposes.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Renewable thermal energy equivalent"</emphasis> means the electrical equivalent in megawatt hours of renewable thermal energy calculated by dividing (i) the heat content, measured in British thermal units (BTUs), of the renewable thermal energy at the point of transfer to a residential, commercial, institutional, or industrial process by (ii) the standard conversion factor of 3.413 million BTUs per megawatt hour.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Renovated and improved facility"</emphasis> means a facility the components of which have been upgraded to enhance its operating efficiency.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Retail customer"</emphasis> means any person that purchases retail electric energy for its own consumption at one or more metering points or nonmetered points of delivery located in the Commonwealth.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Retail electric energy"</emphasis> means electric energy sold for ultimate consumption to a retail customer.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Revenue reductions related to energy efficiency programs"</emphasis> means reductions in the collection of total non-fuel revenues, previously authorized by the Commission to be recovered from customers by a utility, that occur due to measured and verified decreased consumption of electricity caused by energy efficiency programs approved by the Commission and implemented by the utility, less the amount by which such non-fuel reductions in total revenues have been mitigated through other program-related factors, including reductions in variable operating expenses.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Solar energy system"</emphasis> means a system of components that produces heat or electricity, or both, from sunlight.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Supplier"</emphasis> means any generator, distributor, aggregator, broker, marketer, or other person who offers to sell or sells electric energy to retail customers and is licensed by the Commission to do so, but it does not mean a generator that produces electric energy exclusively for its own consumption or the consumption of an affiliate.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Supply"</emphasis> or <emphasis typeStyle="it">"supplying"</emphasis> electric energy means the sale of or the offer to sell electric energy to a retail customer.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Transmission of," "transmit,"</emphasis> or <emphasis typeStyle="it">"transmitting"</emphasis> electric energy means the transfer of electric energy through the Commonwealth's interconnected transmission grid from a generator to either a distributor or a retail customer.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Transmission system"</emphasis> means those facilities and equipment that are required to provide for the transmission of electric energy.</p></bodyText><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p><citation normalizedCite="1999 VA CH 411"><content><span normalizedCite="1999 Va. Ch. 411">1999, c. 411<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1999#000411#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2000 VA CH 991"><content><span normalizedCite="2000 Va. Ch. 991">2000, c. 991<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2000#000991#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2001 VA CH 421"><content><span normalizedCite="2001 Va. Ch. 421">2001, c. 421<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2001#000421#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2007 VA CH 888"><content><span normalizedCite="2007 Va. Ch. 888">2007, cc. 888<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2007#000888#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2007 VA CH 933"><content><span normalizedCite="2007 Va. Ch. 933">933<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2007#000933#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2008 VA CH 272"><content><span normalizedCite="2008 Va. Ch. 272">2008, cc. 272<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2008#000272#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2008 VA CH 883"><content><span normalizedCite="2008 Va. Ch. 883">883<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2008#000883#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2009 VA CH 748"><content><span normalizedCite="2009 Va. Ch. 748">2009, cc. 748<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2009#000748#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2009 VA CH 824"><content><span normalizedCite="2009 Va. Ch. 824">824<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2009#000824#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2012 VA CH 46"><content><span normalizedCite="2012 Va. Ch. 46">2012, cc. 46<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2012#000046#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2012 VA CH 200"><content><span normalizedCite="2012 Va. Ch. 200">200<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2012#000200#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2012 VA CH 210"><content><span normalizedCite="2012 Va. Ch. 210">210<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2012#000210#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2012 VA CH 821"><content><span normalizedCite="2012 Va. Ch. 821">821<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2012#000821#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2013 VA CH 494"><content><span normalizedCite="2013 Va. Ch. 494">2013, c. 494<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2013#000494#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2014 VA CH 212"><content><span normalizedCite="2014 Va. Ch. 212">2014, cc. 212<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2014#000212#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2014 VA CH 548"><content><span normalizedCite="2014 Va. Ch. 548">548<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2014#000548#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PV40-004G-K3X1-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 56.</desig><title>PUBLIC SERVICE COMPANIES</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 23.</desig><title>VIRGINIA ELECTRIC UTILITY REGULATION ACT</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Appliance Standards</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OTlEODAxN0MwRTQ5NEYyQ0ExNTE1Q0YzNDQxQzZEOUE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NTY1MkM5NEQwRkY0NDEwNjgwM0JBNUQyNzNFM0QwNkY</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Contracts Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QzY0RTZFMzE0RjkwNDdFQUI5M0U5N0ZFMjYyREMyQzU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QThGMUNGMEQ4NTI2NDg0OTgwMkQ4MzVFMDc3MDNDMzY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OEUwODg4REEzQ0E4NDUzMjlGMjFFRDE4RUJGM0NBREE</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Energy &amp; Utilities Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OUUzODAyRDk1QzVFNEZGMEJDM0RGMDYxOTlEMEEzRDA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Appliance Standards</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OTlEODAxN0MwRTQ5NEYyQ0ExNTE1Q0YzNDQxQzZEOUE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NTY1MkM5NEQwRkY0NDEwNjgwM0JBNUQyNzNFM0QwNkY</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Buying &amp; Selling of Power</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NzFFNTI4RkYwRjMzNDcwMTkyNDE2M0JFQTFCMDQ1NTc7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NkU4REM5MTFCOTEzNDRDQ0IyNEEyRkNGRDQyQjM3REY</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Deregulation &amp; Restructuring</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Q0Y5NzE5OTc0QjdBNDdBOTg1RUExMzc4N0FENjM2MjQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MzMyRjFDNjRCQUVENEJBMkEzMjZEMUVBQzA2MUIwQ0I</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Electricity Transmission</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6M0FEMjU2NjgxQUJCNDYwOEE2RTU4OUUxOEYxNjQ5MDc7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjMwQzNCRThDRjkwNDY0QjlFNDJFQzY5QzVCMEE0MTY</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6ODcxOEQ3MjY5MjY4NDIwQUFFODlGNTYxQTcxQzkyOUY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NTAwOTgyMTVBNkJFNENFMzgyODE3NEYxNzdBQTU4RkM</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MkQ3REIyNjY3MzExNDgyQkE4ODE2MDI0MzA3RTRCNEU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MzMyRjFDNjRCQUVENEJBMkEzMjZEMUVBQzA2MUIwQ0I</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NjE5MzE1NDYzNDE4NEIzQzhERTAzQjRDRURFRDI5RDQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjNBOTc1MjdCNkU5NENCRDg1OTk1QjQyRjNBNDMwOUU</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NEIxQzc2REQwRUFENDU3MEE1QUFDOEM0NkRGQkRDRjg7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Q0E1RURCMEU0OTk5NEREODkwRTVDQ0YxRTEwQTk5NjQ</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Qzk3MzQ5NjhDQjRGNEJBNzhBOEI5MkE3RjBEMTZDOUU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Rjk2NTk2ODk2RkMwNDZGQjgxNUI1RjE0MDk4MTNDQzY</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDY5NTYwQzVGM0I4NEE4QjkwODhFMTBERDc4NkY1REE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RkRGQUUxMjkwNTk3NDc4REJDM0I0M0IwNkVGMzVBNzY</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDYwNDUwQTk3Mzc5NDFFQTkxQTdFMjI3MTE5OTM3MjU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NjBBNzlERUQ4N0I1NDUwMEE1MDYyOEExQTM3NEU1NEU</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Independent System Operators</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6M0QzQkI2QUFGMkVENDQzOEE5MEFDQzRBRDlFQ0Y3QUY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NjA4RkYyRkZCODUxNDM3MkIxNjg0QzQ5RjgyNzRGN0E</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Joint Ventures &amp; Partnerships</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RTgxRDg0NTc1QjI3NDg5OUI1MjdBMjdCRjRDRjZFRjg7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6M0VBNkQ0RUY5NENENDhEQUI4REU1MEFBQ0ExQjUyNTY</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Municipal &amp; State Ownership</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RTIxOTVEQ0RGRjI1NDEzQTk2QTg1QzMwMzJGMEZFNEI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjNBOTc1MjdCNkU5NENCRDg1OTk1QjQyRjNBNDMwOUU</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Ratemaking Procedures</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NURFMjYyMkQzNTQ2NDNBQjlFMzI4NzlCNzVDMkNGNDI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NjY3Q0UyNTVFNkQ2NDI1QkEyQkIxRDRGMzQzRjAxOEE</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Solar Power Industry</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDlCOTMzNzhGREJBNDJENEEyM0ZGMjVFODI5Nzc4NTE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OUUzODAyRDk1QzVFNEZGMEJDM0RGMDYxOTlEMEEzRDA</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Utility Interconnection</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NzI4QUU4RTFGNjYzNEY2NUI0NDU1ODJFQzI1MThFM0U7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NjA4RkYyRkZCODUxNDM3MkIxNjg0QzQ5RjgyNzRGN0E</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Environmental Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NzFDRDYyNkI2QjhBNDg3NTkyRjRDRkZEQjlCRkRBQzM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Municipal Landfills</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUY1NzhDMkQ5OTZENEIwQzlBRkZFQkNGNkU3QTZFMTg7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OTVBMjY4ODg4OEM2NEIyMDg1MDBFQTVDQTgwNTczRTc</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Governments</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjdEQjE4OUJDMzQxNDNEMEI0RTI1QUFCMzJENjEwRTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Duties &amp; Powers</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Njk1NTNGMzM0RTc3NDcyMUI4MENCQUQ1RDhEN0M1RUM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Njg1MkM3RkYyNzIxNEVFRkJFMTI2NUM4NUU1ODdEM0Q</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></metadata></legislativeDoc>