<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#349#000058#     1#          512#">Va. Code Ann. § 58.1-512</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_58.1-512"/><heading><desig>§ 58.1-512.</desig><title>Land preservation tax credits for individuals and corporations</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a"/><heading><desig>A.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> For taxable years beginning on or after January 1, 2000, there shall be allowed as a credit against the tax liability imposed by <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 58.1-320"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 58.1-320">§§ 58.1-320<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000058#     1#          320#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> and <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 58.1-400"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 58.1-400">58.1-400<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000058#     1#          400#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, an amount equal to 50 percent of the fair market value of any land or interest in land located in Virginia which is conveyed for the purpose of agricultural and forestal use, open space, natural resource, and/or biodiversity conservation, or land, agricultural, watershed and/or historic preservation, as an unconditional donation by the landowner/taxpayer to a public or private conservation agency eligible to hold such land and interests therein for conservation or preservation purposes. For such conveyances made on or after January 1, 2007, the tax credit shall be 40 percent of the fair market value of the land or interest in land so conveyed.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b"/><heading><desig>B.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The fair market value of qualified donations made under this section shall be determined in accordance with <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 58.1-512.1"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 58.1-512.1">§ 58.1-512.1<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000058#     1#        512.1#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> and substantiated by a "qualified appraisal" prepared by a "qualified appraiser," as those terms are defined under applicable federal law and regulations governing charitable contributions. The value of the donated interest in land that qualifies for credit under this section, as determined according to appropriate federal law and regulations, shall be subject to the limits established by United States Internal Revenue Code § 170(e). In order to qualify for a tax credit under this section, the qualified appraisal shall be signed by the qualified appraiser, who must be licensed in the Commonwealth of Virginia as provided in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 54.1-2011"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 54.1-2011">§ 54.1-2011<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000054#     1#         2011#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, and a copy of the appraisal shall be submitted to the Department. In the event that any appraiser falsely or fraudulently overstates the value of the contributed property in an appraisal that the appraiser has signed, the Department may disallow further appraisals signed by the appraiser and shall refer the appraiser to the Real Estate Appraiser Board for appropriate disciplinary action pursuant to <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 54.1-2013"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 54.1-2013">§ 54.1-2013<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000054#     1#         2013#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, which may include, but need not be limited to, revocation of the appraiser's license. Any appraisal that, upon audit by the Department, is determined to be false or fraudulent, may be disregarded by the Department in determining the fair market value of the property and the amount of tax credit to be allowed under this section.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c"/><heading><desig>C.</desig></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The amount of the credit that may be claimed by each taxpayer, including credit claimed by applying unused credits as provided under subsection C of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 58.1-513"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 58.1-513">§ 58.1-513<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000058#     1#          513#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, shall not exceed $ 50,000 for 2000 taxable years; $ 75,000 for 2001 taxable years; $ 100,000 for each of 2002 through 2008 taxable years; $ 50,000 for each of 2009, 2010, and 2011 taxable years; $ 100,000 for each of 2012, 2013, and 2014 taxable years; $ 20,000 for each of 2015 and 2016 taxable years; and $ 50,000 for 2017 taxable years and for each taxable year thereafter. However, for any fee simple donation of land conveyed to the Commonwealth on or after January 1, 2015, the amount of the credit claimed shall not exceed $ 100,000 for each taxable year, provided that no part of the charitable contributions deduction under <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="26 USC 170"><content><span normalizedCite="26 U.S.C. 170">§ 170 of the Internal Revenue Code<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#29854#1127#00000000170#1#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> related to such fee simple donation is allowable by reason of a sale or exchange of property. In addition, for each taxpayer, in any one taxable year the credit used may not exceed the amount of individual, fiduciary or corporate income tax otherwise due. Any portion of the credit that is unused in any one taxable year may be carried over for a maximum of 10 consecutive taxable years following the taxable year in which the credit originated until fully expended. A credit shall not be reduced by the amount of unused credit that could have been claimed in a prior year by the taxpayer but was unclaimed. For taxpayers affected by the credit reduction for taxable years 2009, 2010, 2011, and 2015 and thereafter, any portion of the credit that is unused in any one taxable year may be carried over for a maximum of 13 consecutive taxable years following the taxable year in which the credit originated until fully expended.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Qualified donations shall include the conveyance of a fee interest in real property or the conveyance in perpetuity of a less-than-fee interest in real property, such as a conservation restriction, preservation restriction, agricultural preservation restriction, or watershed preservation restriction, provided that such less-than-fee interest qualifies as a charitable deduction under <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="26 USC 170"><content><span normalizedCite="26 U.S.C. 170">§ 170(h) of the United States Internal Revenue Code of 1986<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#29854#1127#00000000170#1#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, as amended.</p><p><pre/>The Department of Conservation and Recreation shall compile an annual report on qualified donations of less-than-fee interests accepted by any public or private conservation agency in the respective calendar year and shall submit the report by December 1 of each year to the Chairmen of the House Committee on Appropriations, House Committee on Finance, and the Senate Committee on Finance. In preparing such report, the Department of Conservation and Recreation shall consult and coordinate with the Department of Taxation and the Departments of Forestry and Agriculture and Consumer Services to provide an estimate of the number of acres of land currently being used for "production agriculture and silviculture" as defined in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 3.2-300"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 3.2-300">§ 3.2-300<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000003#     2#          300#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> that have been protected by qualified donations of less-than-fee interests. This report shall include information, when available, on land qualifying for credits being used for "production agriculture and silviculture" that have onsite operational best management practices, which are designed to reduce the amount of nutrients and sediment entering public waters. In addition, the report shall include information, when available, on riparian buffers, both vegetated/forested buffers and no-plow buffers, required by deed restriction on land qualifying for credits in order to protect water quality. This information shall be reported in summary fashion as appropriate to preserve confidentiality of information. Qualified donations shall not include the conveyance of a fee interest, or a less-than-fee interest, in real property by a charitable organization that (i) meets the definition of "holder" in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 10.1-1009"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 10.1-1009">§ 10.1-1009<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000010#     1#         1009#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> and (ii) holds one or more conservation easements acquired pursuant to the authority conferred on a "holder" by <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 10.1-1010"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 10.1-1010">§ 10.1-1010<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000010#     1#         1010#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Any fee interest, or a less-than-fee interest, in real property that has been dedicated as open space within, or as part of, a residential subdivision or any other type of residential or commercial development; dedicated as open space in, or as part of, any real estate development plan; or dedicated for the purpose of fulfilling density requirements to obtain approvals for zoning, subdivision, site plan, or building permits shall not be a qualified donation under this article.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c_4"/><heading><desig>4.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Qualified donations shall be eligible for the tax credit herein described if such donations are made to the Commonwealth of Virginia, an instrumentality thereof, or a charitable organization described in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="26 USC 501"><content><span normalizedCite="26 U.S.C. 501">§ 501(c)(3) of the United States Internal Revenue Code of 1986<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#29854#1127#00000000501#1#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, as amended, if such charitable organization (i) meets the requirements of § 509(a)(2) or (ii) meets the requirements of § 509(a)(3) and is controlled by an organization described in § 509(a)(2).</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c_5"/><heading><desig>5.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The preservation, agricultural preservation, historic preservation or similar use and purpose of such property shall be assured in perpetuity. In the case of conveyances of a fee interest to a charitable organization that is a "holder" as defined in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 10.1-1009"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 10.1-1009">§ 10.1-1009<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000010#     1#         1009#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, the credit shall not be allowed until the charitable organization agrees that subsequent conveyances of the fee interest in the property will be (i) subject to a previous conveyance in perpetuity of a conservation easement, as that term is defined in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 10.1-1009"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 10.1-1009">§ 10.1-1009<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000010#     1#         1009#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, or subject to the conveyance in perpetuity of an open-space easement, as that term is defined in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 10.1-1700"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 10.1-1700">§ 10.1-1700<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000010#     1#         1700#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, or (ii) conveyed to the Commonwealth of Virginia or to a federal conservation agency. No credit shall be allowed with respect to any subsequent conveyances by the charitable organization.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d"/><heading><desig>D.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The issuance of tax credits under this article for donations made on and after January 1, 2007, shall be in accordance with procedures and deadlines established by the Department and shall be administered under the following conditions:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The taxpayer shall apply for a credit after completing the donation by submitting a form or forms prescribed by the Department in consultation with the Department of Conservation and Recreation. If the application requests a credit of $ 1 million or more or if the donation meets the conditions of subdivision 3 c, then a copy of the application shall also be filed with the Department of Conservation and Recreation by the taxpayer. The application shall include, but not be limited to:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d_1_a"/><heading><desig>a.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A description of the conservation purpose or purposes being served by the donation;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d_1_b"/><heading><desig>b.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The fair market value of land being donated in the absence of any easement or other restriction;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d_1_c"/><heading><desig>c.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The public benefit derived from the donation;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d_1_d"/><heading><desig>d.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The extent to which water quality best management practices will be implemented on the property; and</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d_1_e"/><heading><desig>e.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Whether the property is fully or partially forested and a forest management plan is included in the terms of the donation.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Applications for otherwise qualified donations of a less-than-fee interest shall be accompanied by an affidavit describing how the donated interest in land meets the requirements of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="26 USC 170"><content><span normalizedCite="26 U.S.C. 170">§ 170(h) of the United States Internal Revenue Code of 1986<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#29854#1127#00000000170#1#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, as amended, and the regulations adopted thereunder. The application with accompanying affidavit shall be submitted to the Department of Taxation, with a copy also provided to the Department of Conservation and Recreation.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> a. No credit in the amount of $ 1 million or more shall be issued with respect to a donation unless the conservation value of the donation has been verified by the Director of the Department of Conservation and Recreation, based on the criteria adopted by the Virginia Land Conservation Foundation for this purpose. Such criteria and subsequent amendments shall be exempt from the Administrative Process Act (<citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 2.2-4000"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 2.2-4000">§ 2.2-4000<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000002#     2#         4000#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> et seq.), but the Virginia Land Conservation Foundation shall provide for adequate public participation, including adequate notice and opportunity to provide comments on the proposed criteria. The Director shall act on applications within 90 days of his receipt of a complete application and shall notify the taxpayer and the Department of Taxation of his action.</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d_3_b"/><heading><desig>b.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> For purposes of determining whether a credit requires verification of the conservation value, the credits allowed under this article with respect to donations of any other portion of a recorded parcel of land within the preceding 11 years shall be aggregated with the credit claimed for the current donation. This subdivision shall not apply if (i) all owners of the parcel who have been allowed credit for a qualified donation are not affiliated with the person or entity seeking credit for the current donation of a different portion of the parcel and (ii) in the case of an individual seeking credit, the individual has not previously made a qualified donation for any portion of the parcel and is not an immediate family member of any such owners.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d_3_c"/><heading><desig>c.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> If (i) the real property that is the subject of the donation was partitioned from or part of another parcel of land and any other portion of such parcel, or any land partitioned from such parcel of land, has been allowed a tax credit under this article (or an application for tax credit is pending) within three years of such donation and (ii) the tax credit that would otherwise be allowed to the donor for such donation is at least $ 250,000, then no credit under this article shall be issued with respect to such donation described in clause (i) unless the conservation value of the donation has been verified by the Director of the Department of Conservation and Recreation. The Director shall act on applications within 90 days of his receipt of a complete application and shall notify the taxpayer and the Department of Taxation of his action. Nothing in this subdivision shall be construed or interpreted (a) as allowing additional tax credit for any land or interest in land previously conveyed for which tax credit has already been allowed under this article or (b) affecting the validity of any tax credit allowed under this article for a prior conveyance of any land or interest in land.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d_4"/><heading><desig>4.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> a. Tax credits shall be issued on a calendar year basis, and in no case shall the Department issue more than the maximum allowed for the calendar year. The maximum amount of credits that may be issued in a calendar year shall be $ 100 million plus any credits previously issued under this article but subsequently disallowed or invalidated by the Department. Credits previously issued but subsequently disallowed or invalidated shall be reissued in a subsequent calendar year. All credits shall be issued in the order that each complete application is filed. For filings by mail or a recognized commercial delivery service, the postmark or confirmation of shipment shall determine the date of filing. If within 30 days after an application for credits has been filed the Tax Commissioner provides written notice to the donor that he has determined that the preparation of a second qualified appraisal is warranted, the application shall not be deemed complete until the fair market value of the donation has been finally determined by the Tax Commissioner. The Tax Commissioner shall make a final determination within 180 days of notifying the donor, unless the donor has filed an appeal. The donor shall have the right to appeal any decision of the Department in accordance with the provisions of Chapter 18 (<citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 58.1-1800"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 58.1-1800">§ 58.1-1800<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000058#     1#         1800#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> et seq.). If more than one complete application is filed at the same time, the credits with respect to those applications shall be issued in the order that the conveyances were recorded in the appropriate circuit court of the Commonwealth. In the event that a credit requires verification of the conservation value by the Department of Conservation and Recreation and such verification has not been received at the time the maximum $ 100 million allowed is reached for the calendar year of the donation, such credit shall not be issued for that calendar year but shall be issued in the calendar year that the conservation value of the credit is verified by the Department of Conservation and Recreation.</p><p><pre/>No credit shall be allowed for any land or interest in land conveyed on or after July 1, 2015, unless a complete application for tax credit with regard to the conveyance has been filed with the Department by December 31 of the year following the calendar year of the conveyance. For filings by mail or a recognized commercial delivery service, the postmark or confirmation of shipment shall determine the date of filing. Solely for purposes of this condition, any application for which the Tax Commissioner has given written notice to the donor that the preparation of a second qualified appraisal is warranted shall be deemed timely filed, provided that the application was otherwise complete as of such filing deadline.</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d_4_b"/><heading><desig>b.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Beginning with calendar year 2008, the $ 100 million amount contained in subdivision 4 a shall be increased by an amount equal to $ 100 million multiplied by the percentage by which the consumer price index for all-urban consumers published by the United States Department of Labor (CPI-U) for the 12-month period ending August 31 of the preceding year exceeds the CPI-U for the 12-month period ending August 31, 2006.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d_4_c"/><heading><desig>c.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Beginning with calendar year 2015, the maximum amount of credits that may be issued in a calendar year shall not exceed $ 75 million. In no case shall the Department issue any tax credit for a donation from any allocation or pool of tax credits attributable to a calendar year prior to the year in which the complete tax credit application for the donation was filed.</p><p><pre/>Beginning with the submission due on or before December 20, 2015, and in each year thereafter, the Governor shall include in "The Budget Bill" submitted pursuant to subsection A of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 2.2-1509"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 2.2-1509">§ 2.2-1509<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000002#     2#         1509#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> or in his amendments to the general appropriation act in effect submitted pursuant to subsection E of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 2.2-1509"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 2.2-1509">§ 2.2-1509<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000002#     2#         1509#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> a recommended appropriation from the general fund equal to the difference between the amount calculated pursuant to subdivision b and $ 75 million, but not more than $ 20 million, to be allocated as follows: 80 percent to the Virginia Land Conservation Fund to be used in accordance with <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 10.1-1020"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 10.1-1020">§ 10.1-1020<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000010#     1#         1020#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, with no less than 50 percent of such appropriation to be used for fee simple acquisitions with public access or acquisitions of easements with public access; 10 percent to the Virginia Battlefield Preservation Fund to be used in accordance with <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 10.1-2202.4"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 10.1-2202.4">§ 10.1-2202.4<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000010#     1#       2202.4#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; and 10 percent to the Virginia Farmland Preservation Fund to be used in accordance with <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 3.2-201"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 3.2-201">§ 3.2-201<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000003#     2#          201#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d_5"/><heading><desig>5.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> a. Any taxpayer that has been issued a tax credit by the Department shall be allowed to use such credit for his or its taxable year that begins in the calendar year for which such credit was issued and for succeeding taxable years in accordance with the 10 consecutive taxable year carryforward provisions of this article, except for any taxpayer affected by the credit limitation for taxable years 2009, 2010, 2011, and 2015 and taxable years thereafter. Such a taxpayer shall be allowed to use such credit for his or its taxable year that begins in the calendar year for which such credit was issued and for succeeding taxable years in accordance with the 13 consecutive taxable year carryforward provisions of this article.</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d_5_b"/><heading><desig>b.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Any taxpayer to whom a credit has been transferred may use such credit for the taxable year in which the transfer occurred and unused amounts may be carried forward to succeeding taxable years, but in no event may such transferred credit be used more than 11 years after it was originally issued by the Department or in any taxable year of such taxpayer that ended prior to the date of transfer, except for any taxpayer affected by the credit limitation for taxable years 2009, 2010, 2011, and 2015 and taxable years thereafter. Such a taxpayer may use such credit for the taxable year in which the transfer occurred and unused amounts may be carried forward to succeeding taxable years, but in no event may such transferred credit be used more than 14 years after it was originally issued by the Department or in any taxable year of such taxpayer that ended prior to the date of transfer.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d_6"/><heading><desig>6.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Neither the verification of conservation value by the Department of Conservation and Recreation nor the issuance of a credit by the Department of Taxation shall in any way be construed or interpreted as prohibiting the Department of Taxation or the Tax Commissioner from auditing any credit claimed pursuant to the provisions of this article or from assessing tax relating to the claiming of any credit under this article.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_e"/><heading><desig>E.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> In any review or appeal before the Tax Commissioner or in any court in the Commonwealth the burden of proof shall be on the taxpayer to show that the fair market value and conservation value at the time of the qualified donation is consistent with this section and that all requirements of this article have been satisfied.</p></bodyText></level><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p><citation normalizedCite="1999 VA CH 968"><content><span normalizedCite="1999 Va. Ch. 968">1999, cc. 968<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1999#000968#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1999 VA CH 983"><content><span normalizedCite="1999 Va. Ch. 983">983<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1999#000983#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2005 VA CH 940"><content><span normalizedCite="2005 Va. Ch. 940">2005, c. 940<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2005#000940#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2006 VA CH 4"><content><span normalizedCite="2006 Va. Ch. 4">2006, Sp. Sess. I, cc. 4<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2006#000004#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2006 VA CH 5"><content><span normalizedCite="2006 Va. Ch. 5">5<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2006#000005#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2009 VA CH 12"><content><span normalizedCite="2009 Va. Ch. 12">2009, cc. 12<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2009#000012#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2009 VA CH 510"><content><span normalizedCite="2009 Va. Ch. 510">510<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2009#000510#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2010 VA CH 246"><content><span normalizedCite="2010 Va. Ch. 246">2010, cc. 246<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2010#000246#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2010 VA CH 265"><content><span normalizedCite="2010 Va. Ch. 265">265<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2010#000265#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2010 VA CH 321"><content><span normalizedCite="2010 Va. Ch. 321">321<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2010#000321#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2010 VA CH 384"><content><span normalizedCite="2010 Va. Ch. 384">384<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2010#000384#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2011 VA CH 212"><content><span normalizedCite="2011 Va. Ch. 212">2011, cc. 212<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2011#000212#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2011 VA CH 296"><content><span normalizedCite="2011 Va. Ch. 296">296<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2011#000296#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2011 VA CH 377"><content><span normalizedCite="2011 Va. Ch. 377">377<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2011#000377#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2011 VA CH 672"><content><span normalizedCite="2011 Va. Ch. 672">672<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2011#000672#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2013 VA CH 798"><content><span normalizedCite="2013 Va. Ch. 798">2013, c. 798<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2013#000798#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2015 VA CH 235"><content><span normalizedCite="2015 Va. Ch. 235">2015, cc. 235<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2015#000235#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2015 VA CH 467"><content><span normalizedCite="2015 Va. Ch. 467">467<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2015#000467#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2015 VA CH 680"><content><span normalizedCite="2015 Va. Ch. 680">680<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2015#000680#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PV40-004G-K453-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 58.1.</desig><title>TAXATION</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="subtitle"><heading><desig>SUBTITLE I.</desig><title>TAXES ADMINISTERED BY THE DEPARTMENT OF TAXATION</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 3.</desig><title>INCOME TAX</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="article"><heading><desig>ARTICLE 20.1.</desig><title>VIRGINIA LAND CONSERVATION INCENTIVES ACT OF 1999</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Formation</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDJENDRCOUZDMTg5NEU1N0JGNjFCNjFFMTNDOTEzRDQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Njg2NjY4ODFGMkM4NDBERjg2ODkwNEMyNTM4QTgyQjk</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjA4OEVGODBENzY4NDcxM0IyQzA1OTEwQzVDODRBOUE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Formation</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDJENDRCOUZDMTg5NEU1N0JGNjFCNjFFMTNDOTEzRDQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Njg2NjY4ODFGMkM4NDBERjg2ODkwNEMyNTM4QTgyQjk</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Governments</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjdEQjE4OUJDMzQxNDNEMEI0RTI1QUFCMzJENjEwRTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Forest Lands</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RTkzOTc4NEQ2MTQwNDg0Q0E0NDNFRkRDRDU1QUE0OEU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6ODE4NDg4QUI2RDA3NDQ2RkI1QTRFNjA4OUM3QjA4MzA</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Real Property Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QUUyRTcxRURBNEY2NEE2MDk3QzBCNzRDOEY0NTZDQzk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Conservation Easements</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6N0YzQjVDMTA0QzZDNDc1Mjg4NTIwNzlEMkU4QzhEQTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6REY1N0QwQTgyRjkyNEQ2M0FDMDhDQzJCRTM1QTM4NTk</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Elements</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MTJGNkEyOEUzOUFFNEE4NTkzQjg1RDIyNTU4Njg4RUM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjRCMUU0RUM1REQ2NDYyMDk1Qjc2QzYzNDg1RjgxNDg</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Express Easements</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MTdDQUM2QzhBOEE1NDc0QjhCRTM3QTY5QTREMUY0NTE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6N0VCMzRGMzZFQTdDNDYyMzgwMjdFRUMzNEUwQTk2NEE</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Fee Simple Estates</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QzVDNjEwREVBRTdBNEFBNUFGREI5RDU3NTUyM0NENjg7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjZEODAxMDMxMjkwNEQzQTlGQzJEQjFERDI1OUEzNTM</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Characteristics</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QTUwOEVFREQyNTI2NDJBRjg2NzdGNjA0QzNFMjVFODQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6REY1N0QwQTgyRjkyNEQ2M0FDMDhDQzJCRTM1QTM4NTk</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjEyRTY2MDNGMDFDNDU1OEI4Mjc5ODM3NDk2QjYzQ0E7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QUQ1MDM3OENCNjYyNEFDMDkyNDQ0RTE2Q0Y5M0NDQzU</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6M0M3NUYwQUZFNUQ3NDU2NkFFQ0RGRTBFQkVFN0UyQUI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjRCMUU0RUM1REQ2NDYyMDk1Qjc2QzYzNDg1RjgxNDg</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Partition Actions</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MTY1REU3NTUwRDI4NEIwQThEREM4QjgzOTFBMDJEN0U7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6M0QwNEZGNTU3OTQwNDAzNkE5NEMyOTg4NTEwRkUxQUQ</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Property Valuations</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NkI0ODJENjlDNkNCNEE3MkI1RkNCMjVBODkzNUI3MTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QUUyRTcxRURBNEY2NEE2MDk3QzBCNzRDOEY0NTZDQzk</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Public Easements</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6ODk4NTc4NkI3NkRBNDQ2RTk5NjkzNUZFNTI2MkQ0RTk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6REY1N0QwQTgyRjkyNEQ2M0FDMDhDQzJCRTM1QTM4NTk</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Tax Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OTNEM0E2OEE0RkQyNEY1MDhBQzdGMkQ4ODI4QTJDODE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Allowance of Deduction</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NTVFM0ZDNTRDMDdENDNCNzg1NEJDQ0Q0OTZBMUM3ODM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QkI4MzdCQzJFRDlBNDlENzlFOERGQjdGREVCOTJDNEU</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Audits &amp; Investigations</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RDg3ODgwMDY2NTQwNEY2OEFFQjhDRENCNkE1RTU2MjY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjkxRkVDMkNDMjBGNDdFMkI1RDQ3Nzk4QjgwOTBGQjU</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6M0ExNjNFRENBOEQ3NEE0MEJFNzdDRDk5NkU3RkU5ODM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MkVCMjY1MzA5RkY4NERERTk5ODFBRkU3NTkyNTcwRjk</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OEVBODVEMEFGQUUzNDQwQUFGNkEzRkM1RjNGRUQyNTU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QkI4MzdCQzJFRDlBNDlENzlFOERGQjdGREVCOTJDNEU</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QkEwRUIzN0QxNUUyNDg3RTlGREZENjVFRkQwRUUyMTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MTc2OEQxMDJEQTRENDMyODkyRUYyQ0FENDQ3M0JFNTQ</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Judicial Review</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NTVCMTBCQTEwRkExNDhDMTg2RjY5QjFEMTk3ODAwMEE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjkxRkVDMkNDMjBGNDdFMkI1RDQ3Nzk4QjgwOTBGQjU</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification><classificationGroup classificationScheme="indexing-terms"><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem score="90"><className>Tax</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OTNEM0E2OEE0RkQyNEY1MDhBQzdGMkQ4ODI4QTJDODE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></classificationGroup></metadata></legislativeDoc>