<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#349#000013#     1#          803#">Va. Code Ann. § 13.1-803</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_13.1-803"/><heading><desig>§ 13.1-803.</desig><title>Definitions</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><bodyText><p>As used in this Act:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><bodyText><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Articles of incorporation"</emphasis> means all documents constituting, at any particular time, the charter of a corporation. It includes the original charter issued by the General Assembly, a court or the Commission and all amendments including certificates of merger, consolidation or correction. When the articles of incorporation have been restated pursuant to any articles of restatement, amendment, domestication, or merger, it includes only the restated articles of incorporation without the accompanying articles of restatement, amendment, domestication, or merger.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Board of directors" </emphasis> means the group of persons vested with the management of the business of the corporation irrespective of the name by which such group is designated, and "director" means a member of the board of directors.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Certificate," </emphasis> when relating to articles filed with the Commission, means the order of the Commission that makes the articles effective, together with the articles.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Commission" </emphasis> means the State Corporation Commission of Virginia.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Conspicuous" </emphasis> means so written, displayed, or presented that a reasonable person against whom the writing is to operate should have noticed it. For example, text that is italicized, is in boldface, contrasting colors, or capitals, or is underlined is conspicuous.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Corporation" </emphasis> or <emphasis typeStyle="it">"domestic corporation" </emphasis> means a corporation not authorized by law to issue shares, irrespective of the nature of the business to be transacted, organized under this Act or existing pursuant to the laws of the Commonwealth on January 1, 1986, or that, by virtue of articles of incorporation, amendment, or merger, has become a domestic corporation of the Commonwealth, even though also being a corporation organized under laws other than the laws of the Commonwealth or that has become a domestic corporation of the Commonwealth pursuant to Article 11.1 (§ 13.1-898.2 et seq.) of this Act.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Deliver" </emphasis> or <emphasis typeStyle="it">"delivery" </emphasis> means any method of delivery used in conventional commercial practice, including delivery by hand, mail, commercial delivery, and, if authorized in accordance with <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 13.1-810"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 13.1-810">§ 13.1-810<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000013#     1#          810#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, by electronic transmission.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Disinterested director" </emphasis> means a director who, at the time action is to be taken under <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 13.1-871"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 13.1-871">§ 13.1-871<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000013#     1#          871#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 13.1-878"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 13.1-878">13.1-878<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000013#     1#          878#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, or <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 13.1-880"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 13.1-880">13.1-880<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000013#     1#          880#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, does not have (i) a financial interest in a matter that is the subject of such action or (ii) a familial, financial, professional, employment, or other relationship with a person who has a financial interest in the matter, either of which would reasonably be expected to affect adversely the objectivity of the director when participating in the action, and if the action is to be taken under <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 13.1-878"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 13.1-878">§ 13.1-878<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000013#     1#          878#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> or <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 13.1-880"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 13.1-880">13.1-880<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000013#     1#          880#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, is also not a party to the proceeding. The presence of one or more of the following circumstances shall not by itself prevent a person from being a disinterested director: (a) nomination or election of the director to the current board by any person, acting alone or participating with others, who is so interested in the matter or (b) service as a director of another corporation of which an interested person is also a director.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Document" </emphasis> means (i) any tangible medium on which information is inscribed, and includes any writing or written instrument, or (ii) an electronic record.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Domestic business trust" </emphasis> has the same meaning as specified in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 13.1-1201"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 13.1-1201">§ 13.1-1201<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000013#     1#         1201#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Domestic limited liability company" </emphasis> has the same meaning as specified in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 13.1-1002"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 13.1-1002">§ 13.1-1002<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000013#     1#         1002#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Domestic limited partnership" </emphasis> has the same meaning as specified in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 50-73.1"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 50 -73.1">§ 50-73.1.<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#123#000050#      73.1#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation></p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Domestic partnership" </emphasis> means an association of two or more persons to carry on as co-owners of a business for profit formed under <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 50-73.88"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 50 -73.88">§ 50-73.88<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#123#000050#     73.88#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> or predecessor law of the Commonwealth and includes, for all purposes of the laws of the Commonwealth, a registered limited liability partnership.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Domestic stock corporation" </emphasis> has the same meaning as "domestic corporation" as specified in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 13.1-603"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 13.1-603">§ 13.1-603<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000013#     1#          603#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Effective date of notice"</emphasis> is defined in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 13.1-810"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 13.1-810">§ 13.1-810<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000013#     1#          810#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Electronic" </emphasis> means relating to technology having electrical, digital, magnetic, wireless, optical, electromagnetic, or similar capabilities.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Electronic record" </emphasis> means information that is stored in an electronic or other medium and is retrievable in paper form through an automated process used in conventional commercial practice, unless otherwise authorized in accordance with subsection J of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 13.1-810"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 13.1-810">§ 13.1-810<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000013#     1#          810#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Electronic transmission" </emphasis> or <emphasis typeStyle="it"> "electronically transmitted" </emphasis> means any form or process of communication, not directly involving the physical transfer of paper or other tangible medium, that (i) is suitable for the retention, retrieval, and reproduction of information by the recipient, and (ii) is retrievable in paper form by the recipient through an automated process used in conventional commercial practice, unless otherwise authorized in accordance with subsection J of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 13.1-810"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 13.1-810">§ 13.1-810<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000013#     1#          810#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Eligible entity" </emphasis> means a domestic or foreign unincorporated entity or a domestic or foreign stock corporation.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Eligible interests" </emphasis> means interests or shares.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Employee" </emphasis> includes, unless otherwise provided in the bylaws, an officer but not a director. A director may accept duties that make him also an employee.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Entity" </emphasis> includes any domestic or foreign corporation; any domestic or foreign stock corporation; any domestic or foreign unincorporated entity; any estate or trust; and any state, the United States, and any foreign government.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Foreign business trust" </emphasis> has the same meaning as specified in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 13.1-1201"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 13.1-1201">§ 13.1-1201<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000013#     1#         1201#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Foreign corporation" </emphasis> means a corporation not authorized by law to issue shares, organized under laws other than the laws of the Commonwealth.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Foreign limited liability company" </emphasis> has the same meaning as specified in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 13.1-1002"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 13.1-1002">§ 13.1-1002<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000013#     1#         1002#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Foreign limited partnership" </emphasis> has the same meaning as specified in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 50-73.1"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 50 -73.1">§ 50-73.1.<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#123#000050#      73.1#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation></p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Foreign partnership" </emphasis> means an association of two or more persons to carry on as co-owners of a business for profit formed under the laws of any state or jurisdiction other than the Commonwealth, and includes, for all purposes of the laws of the Commonwealth, a foreign registered limited liability partnership.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Foreign registered limited liability partnership" </emphasis> has the same meaning as specified in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 50-73.79"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 50 -73.79">§ 50-73.79.<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#123#000050#     73.79#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation></p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Foreign stock corporation" </emphasis> has the same meaning as "foreign corporation" as specified in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 13.1-603"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 13.1-603">§ 13.1-603<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000013#     1#          603#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Foreign unincorporated entity" </emphasis> means an unincorporated entity whose internal affairs are governed by an organic law of a jurisdiction other than the Commonwealth.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Government subdivision" </emphasis> includes authority, county, district, and municipality.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Includes" </emphasis> denotes a partial definition.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Individual" </emphasis> means a natural person.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><bodyText><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Interest" </emphasis> means either or both of the following rights under the organic law of a foreign or domestic unincorporated entity:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The right to receive distributions from the entity either in the ordinary course or upon liquidation; or</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The right to receive notice or vote on issues involving its internal affairs, other than as an agent, assignee, proxy, or person responsible for managing its business and affairs.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><bodyText><p><pre/><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Means" </emphasis> denotes an exhaustive definition.</p><p><pre/><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Member" </emphasis> means one having a membership interest in a corporation in accordance with the provisions of its articles of incorporation or bylaws.</p><p><pre/><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Membership interest"</emphasis> means the interest of a member in a domestic or foreign corporation, including voting and all other rights associated with membership.</p><p><pre/><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Organic document" </emphasis> means the document, if any, that is filed of public record to create an unincorporated entity. Where an organic document has been amended or restated, the term means the organic document as last amended or restated.</p><p><pre/><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Organic law"</emphasis> means the statute governing the internal affairs of a domestic or foreign corporation or eligible entity.</p><p><pre/><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Person"</emphasis> includes an individual and an entity.</p><p><pre/><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Principal office"</emphasis> means the office, in or out of the Commonwealth, where the principal executive offices of a domestic or foreign corporation are located, or, if there are no such offices, the office, in or out of the Commonwealth, so designated by the board of directors. The designation of the principal office in the most recent annual report filed pursuant to <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 13.1-936"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 13.1-936">§ 13.1-936<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000013#     1#          936#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> shall be conclusive for purposes of this Act.</p><p><pre/><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Proceeding" </emphasis> includes civil suit and criminal, administrative and investigatory action conducted by a governmental agency.</p><p><pre/><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Record date" </emphasis> means the date established under Article 7 (<citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 13.1-837"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 13.1-837">§ 13.1-837<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000013#     1#          837#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> et seq.) of this Act on which a corporation determines the identity of its members and their membership interests for purposes of this Act. The determination shall be made as of the close of business at the principal office of the corporation on the record date unless another time for doing so is specified when the record date is fixed.</p><p><pre/><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Shares" </emphasis> has the same meaning as specified in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 13.1-603"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 13.1-603">§ 13.1-603<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000013#     1#          603#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p><p><pre/><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Sign" </emphasis> or <emphasis typeStyle="it"> "signature" </emphasis> means, with present intent to authenticate or adopt a document: (i) to execute or adopt a tangible symbol to a document, and includes any manual, facsimile, or conformed signature; or (ii) to attach to or logically associate with an electronic transmission an electronic sound, symbol, or process, and includes an electronic signature in an electronic transmission.</p><p><pre/><emphasis typeStyle="it">"State" </emphasis> when referring to a part of the United States, includes a state, commonwealth, and the District of Columbia, and their agencies and governmental subdivisions; and a territory or insular possession, and their agencies and governmental subdivisions, of the United States.</p><p><pre/><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Transact business" </emphasis> includes the conduct of affairs by any corporation that is not organized for profit.</p><p><pre/><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Unincorporated entity" </emphasis> or <emphasis typeStyle="it">"domestic unincorporated entity" </emphasis> means a domestic partnership, limited liability company, limited partnership, or business trust.</p><p><pre/><emphasis typeStyle="it">"United States" </emphasis> includes any district, authority, bureau, commission, department, or any other agency of the United States.</p><p><pre/><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Voting group" </emphasis> means all members of one or more classes that under the articles of incorporation or this Act are entitled to vote and be counted together collectively on a matter at a meeting of members. All members entitled by the articles of incorporation or this Act to vote generally on the matter are for that purpose a single voting group.</p><p><pre/><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Voting power" </emphasis> means the current power to vote in the election of directors.</p><p><pre/><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Writing" </emphasis> or <emphasis typeStyle="it">"written"</emphasis> means any information in the form of a document.</p></bodyText></level><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p>Code 1950, § 13.1-202; 1956, c. 428; 1985, c. 522; <citation normalizedCite="1997 VA CH 801"><content><span normalizedCite="1997 Va. Ch. 801">1997, c. 801<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1997#000801#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2002 VA CH 285"><content><span normalizedCite="2002 Va. Ch. 285">2002, c. 285<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2002#000285#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2007 VA CH 925"><content><span normalizedCite="2007 Va. Ch. 925">2007, c. 925<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2007#000925#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2010 VA CH 171"><content><span normalizedCite="2010 Va. Ch. 171">2010, c. 171<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2010#000171#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2012 VA CH 706"><content><span normalizedCite="2012 Va. Ch. 706">2012, c. 706<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2012#000706#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PV20-004G-K23B-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 13.1.</desig><title>CORPORATIONS</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 10.</desig><title>VIRGINIA NONSTOCK CORPORATION ACT</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="article"><heading><desig>ARTICLE 1.</desig><title>GENERAL PROVISIONS</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Limited Liability Partnerships</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Qzc3QkNFMUExQzM2NDJGRTg3REE0N0I1QzhCQUE3QjM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjA4OEVGODBENzY4NDcxM0IyQzA1OTEwQzVDODRBOUE</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjA4OEVGODBENzY4NDcxM0IyQzA1OTEwQzVDODRBOUE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Amendments to Articles of Incorporation</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QkY4NEQ1REM5MTNGNDA0NDlFRUEyN0E2QTJDRjA5Mzk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QUQ2RDA4Mzc1QTE5NDk2MjgxOUZEM0RBOENDRTY3N0M</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RkFGNEU2QURBRkI2NEU2MjgzQ0RENUY5RDRDNzg4MkI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDY4MDk1M0I4ODA0NEFDMUEzMjgxOEYxRkIyQ0Y1Q0M</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QzM4NTRCMzg3RTNFNDNFQjkxRUI2ODQzNzQ2MEFBRjU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUJFRTkxOEFCMTI4NDZFNEI5NUZCNEJENzc4REE3RkQ</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NzUyMzhDOTNENkM4NDUyNUIzRkM5QkNFRUUwMTA2NkU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6ODY0NjZDRTIzQzRBNEQ5RDk1Qjk5NzdDNUY1MTVBOTA</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OURBNTNBMkQxMTVENEY5RDkzMDkzRDIzQjBENTNFRjg7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDQ3M0RFODczN0I4NDg2RjlFRDNFMUNBODRDQTU0Q0E</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDk5NzZBNzE5Q0QyNENCNjk4QjcxMjUxQTY4MUUxRDU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QUQ2RDA4Mzc1QTE5NDk2MjgxOUZEM0RBOENDRTY3N0M</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDc1MERFNzE3ODExNDEyMDgwM0RDMTdBRjUxMDQwQUQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NkU1RUZCODkyMDJCNDgzODlDREYzQkNBQkZDNTNBMzc</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RDVCRkUzRjg3NUFFNDMwNjhGMDc3MkNENDMxNzhFOEM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDFEQjUyNDAyMzQ0NDQyNUE5RjNGOEZEMzNBRDA1RUY</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Limited Liability Partnerships</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Qzc3QkNFMUExQzM2NDJGRTg3REE0N0I1QzhCQUE3QjM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjA4OEVGODBENzY4NDcxM0IyQzA1OTEwQzVDODRBOUE</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Management Duties &amp; Liabilities</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NjM4RDFBNzVFNkFENDI1MDlENzhCRjEzMTQ3QTRERjI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NUFDMUUyMjFERDQ1NDg3NTg1NzVCNzQyMTU5QzlBODI</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Member Duties &amp; Liabilities</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDM4QzlDMjYxODY0NDYwNjg2OUFBMjVGNzYyQjFGMzQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NUFDMUUyMjFERDQ1NDg3NTg1NzVCNzQyMTU5QzlBODI</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Qualifications</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QUI1N0JGNTUwRTJGNDcxRTlBQjc0MjEzQTNEMTc4RkM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NkU1RUZCODkyMDJCNDgzODlDREYzQkNBQkZDNTNBMzc</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Evidence</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUVGQkU0QjJFMTIzNDNBM0FCNTVEQjAxQTM3RDcwOTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MzYwQUQ2RDlBNDUzNEFBRTkwRDZBNEU1NUQxQTNDMzg7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDA2QUFEQUVBNTYyNDUxNUE2MjMzMDk5NzM1NkQ1Mjc</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Family Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NEI4M0U5Qzg3RTk0NDdBRUJGNDRGNkZEQkU3RDdFNDU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Registration</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NUMzMTg5NjZBMkI1NDEwRkIyNTI5MjNBMDNDQkY2OTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RDBDQzM0MkIyRjFDNEU2Rjk0QUQzNDY1ODczRUE0REQ</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Mergers &amp; Acquisitions Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjRDRTUzQzBCMEIyNDU5QkE4QjFDMEE2Qjg2MUZDOTk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QzZFQzQyQUJEMzIxNEYyRTkyM0M2NDhGN0FGNzhFOTc7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjRDRTUzQzBCMEIyNDU5QkE4QjFDMEE2Qjg2MUZDOTk</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification><classificationGroup classificationScheme="indexing-terms"><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem score="90"><className>Businesses &amp; Corporations</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjA4OEVGODBENzY4NDcxM0IyQzA1OTEwQzVDODRBOUE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></classificationGroup></metadata></legislativeDoc>