<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#349#000016#     1#        340.1#">Va. Code Ann. § 16.1-340.1</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_16.1-340.1"/><heading><desig>§ 16.1-340.1.</desig><title>Involuntary temporary detention; issuance and execution of order</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a"/><heading><desig>A.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A magistrate shall issue, upon the sworn petition of a minor's treating physician or parent or, if the parent is not available or is unable or unwilling to file a petition, by any responsible adult, including the person having custody over a minor in detention or shelter care pursuant to an order of a juvenile and domestic relations district court, or upon his own motion and only after an evaluation conducted in-person or by means of a two-way electronic video and audio communication system as authorized in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 16.1-345.1"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 16.1-345.1">§ 16.1-345.1<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000016#     1#        345.1#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> by an employee or designee of the local community services board to determine whether the minor meets the criteria for temporary detention, a temporary detention order if it appears from all evidence readily available, including any recommendation from a physician or clinical psychologist treating the person, that (i) because of mental illness, the minor (a) presents a serious danger to himself or others to the extent that severe or irremediable injury is likely to result, as evidenced by recent acts or threats, or (b) is experiencing a serious deterioration of his ability to care for himself in a developmentally age-appropriate manner, as evidenced by delusionary thinking or by a significant impairment of functioning in hydration, nutrition, self-protection, or self-control; and (ii) the minor is in need of compulsory treatment for a mental illness and is reasonably likely to benefit from the proposed treatment. The magistrate shall also consider the recommendations of the minor's parents and of any treating or examining physician licensed in Virginia if available either verbally or in writing prior to rendering a decision. To the extent possible, the petition shall contain the information required by <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 16.1-339.1"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 16.1-339.1">§ 16.1-339.1.<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000016#     1#        339.1#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> Any temporary detention order entered pursuant to this section shall be effective until such time as the juvenile and domestic relations district court serving the jurisdiction in which the minor is located conducts a hearing pursuant to subsection B of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 16.1-341"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 16.1-341">§ 16.1-341<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000016#     1#          341#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>. Any temporary detention order entered pursuant to this section shall provide for the disclosure of medical records pursuant to subsection B of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 16.1-337"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 16.1-337">§ 16.1-337<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000016#     1#          337#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>. This subsection shall not preclude any other disclosures as required or permitted by law.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b"/><heading><desig>B.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> When considering whether there is probable cause to issue a temporary detention order, the magistrate may, in addition to the petition, consider (i) the recommendations of any treating or examining physician or psychologist licensed in Virginia, if available, (ii) any past actions of the minor, (iii) any past mental health treatment of the minor, (iv) any relevant hearsay evidence, (v) any medical records available, (vi) any affidavits submitted, if the witness is unavailable and it so states in the affidavit, and (vii) any other information available that the magistrate considers relevant to the determination of whether probable cause exists to issue a temporary detention order.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c"/><heading><desig>C.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A magistrate may issue a temporary detention order without an emergency custody order proceeding. A magistrate may issue a temporary detention order without a prior evaluation pursuant to subsection A if (i) the minor has been personally examined within the previous 72 hours by an employee or designee of the local community services board or (ii) there is a significant physical, psychological, or medical risk to the minor or to others associated with conducting such evaluation.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d"/><heading><desig>D.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> An employee or designee of the community services board shall determine the facility of temporary detention in accordance with the provisions of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 16.1-340.1:1"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 16.1-340.1:1">§ 16.1-340.1:1<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#958#0000000016#0000000001#     340.1#0000000001#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> for all minors detained pursuant to this section. The facility shall be identified on the preadmission screening report and indicated on the temporary detention order. Subject to the provisions of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 16.1-340.1:1"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 16.1-340.1:1">§ 16.1-340.1:1<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#958#0000000016#0000000001#     340.1#0000000001#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, if a facility of temporary detention cannot be identified by the time of the expiration of the period of emergency custody pursuant to <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 16.1-340"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 16.1-340">§ 16.1-340<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000016#     1#          340#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, the minor shall be detained in a state facility for the treatment of minors with mental illness and such facility shall be indicated on the temporary detention order. Except for minors who are detained for a criminal offense by a juvenile and domestic relations district court and who require hospitalization in accordance with this article, the minor shall not be detained in a jail or other place of confinement for persons charged with criminal offenses and shall remain in the custody of law enforcement until the minor is either detained within a secure facility or custody has been accepted by the appropriate personnel designated by the facility identified in the temporary detention order.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_e"/><heading><desig>E.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Any facility caring for a minor placed with it pursuant to a temporary detention order is authorized to provide emergency medical and psychiatric services within its capabilities when the facility determines that the services are in the best interests of the minor within its care. The costs incurred as a result of the hearings and by the facility in providing services during the period of temporary detention shall be paid and recovered pursuant to <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 37.2-804"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 37.2-804">§ 37.2-804<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000037#     2#          804#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>. The maximum costs reimbursable by the Commonwealth pursuant to this section shall be established by the State Board of Medical Assistance Services based on reasonable criteria. The State Board of Medical Assistance Services shall, by regulation, establish a reasonable rate per day of inpatient care for temporary detention.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_f"/><heading><desig>F.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The employee or designee of the local community services board who is conducting the evaluation pursuant to this section shall determine, prior to the issuance of the temporary detention order, the insurance status of the minor. Where coverage by a third party payor exists, the facility seeking reimbursement under this section shall first seek reimbursement from the third party payor. The Commonwealth shall reimburse the facility only for the balance of costs remaining after the allowances covered by the third party payor have been received.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_g"/><heading><desig>G.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The duration of temporary detention shall be sufficient to allow for completion of the examination required by <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 16.1-342"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 16.1-342">§ 16.1-342<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000016#     1#          342#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, preparation of the preadmission screening report required by <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 16.1-340.4"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 16.1-340.4">§ 16.1-340.4<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000016#     1#        340.4#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, and initiation of mental health treatment to stabilize the minor's psychiatric condition to avoid involuntary commitment where possible, but shall not exceed 96 hours prior to a hearing. If the 96-hour period herein specified terminates on a Saturday, Sunday, or legal holiday, the minor may be detained, as herein provided, until the close of business on the next day that is not a Saturday, Sunday, or legal holiday. The minor may be released, pursuant to <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 16.1-340.3"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 16.1-340.3">§ 16.1-340.3<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000016#     1#        340.3#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, before the 96-hour period herein specified has run.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_h"/><heading><desig>H.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> If a temporary detention order is not executed within 24 hours of its issuance, or within a shorter period as is specified in the order, the order shall be void and shall be returned unexecuted to the office of the clerk of the issuing court or, if the office is not open, to any magistrate serving the jurisdiction of the issuing court. Subsequent orders may be issued upon the original petition within 96 hours after the petition is filed. However, a magistrate must again obtain the advice of an employee or designee of the local community services board prior to issuing a subsequent order upon the original petition. Any petition for which no temporary detention order or other process in connection therewith is served on the subject of the petition within 96 hours after the petition is filed shall be void and shall be returned to the office of the clerk of the issuing court.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_i"/><heading><desig>I.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> For purposes of this section a healthcare provider or an employee or designee of the local community services board shall not be required to encrypt any email containing information or medical records provided to a magistrate unless there is reason to believe that a third party will attempt to intercept the email.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_j"/><heading><desig>J.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The employee or designee of the local community services board who is conducting the evaluation pursuant to this section shall, if he recommends that the minor should not be subject to a temporary detention order, inform the petitioner and an on-site treating physician of his recommendation.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_k"/><heading><desig>K.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Each community services board shall provide to each juvenile and domestic relations district court and magistrate's office within its service area a list of employees and designees who are available to perform the evaluations required herein.</p></bodyText></level><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p><citation normalizedCite="2010 VA CH 778"><content><span normalizedCite="2010 Va. Ch. 778">2010, cc. 778<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2010#000778#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2010 VA CH 825"><content><span normalizedCite="2010 Va. Ch. 825">825<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2010#000825#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2014 VA CH 691"><content><span normalizedCite="2014 Va. Ch. 691">2014, cc. 691<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2014#000691#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2014 VA CH 773"><content><span normalizedCite="2014 Va. Ch. 773">773<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2014#000773#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PVR0-004G-K343-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 16.1.</desig><title>COURTS NOT OF RECORD</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 11.</desig><title>JUVENILE AND DOMESTIC RELATIONS DISTRICT COURTS</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="article"><heading><desig>ARTICLE 16.</desig><title>PSYCHIATRIC TREATMENT OF MINORS ACT</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Criminal Law &amp; Procedure</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NEU0RkE1OUQwNUQwNDgxODhEODZCMjkzOTg3NThBNzk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Detention</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NjhEMjRDMkUwQTJDNDNEQTk1MTZGOTQ1NDRGN0FGNUM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QTc2N0NFQzYyRUE3NDZBMTk3REExRTgyMUQ4OEY4MjU</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Mental Incapacity</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MTM2NTM1NjkwMkFCNDYxNkI0NUMwNkIwNjkwMzRGNTQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUIzQ0NGRDZERUU3NERCODg2MEZFMDI2RTI0RTA3RTc</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Family Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NEI4M0U5Qzg3RTk0NDdBRUJGNDRGNkZEQkU3RDdFNDU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Involuntary Commitment</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NUZEMkEzNzVGNEU2NERGREIzNTU2OTI1RDRGMkNEMDA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6N0UzRjg5QjhFNTdFNDQ3N0FEMUY0NTVEQkEzQ0M2RTA</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Governments</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjdEQjE4OUJDMzQxNDNEMEI0RTI1QUFCMzJENjEwRTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Administrative Boards</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QTYwRUFCMDc5MzQ5NDEyREFEQkU2NkE2MjRGQTlCNzY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Njg1MkM3RkYyNzIxNEVFRkJFMTI2NUM4NUU1ODdEM0Q</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Clerks of Court</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6REVFMjkzRDI1MkU2NERDNjk3OEUxODY0REYwMUI1NjE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NURENzJGNTEyQzM0NEREQUI2RkVCRTM4RTc1RTZBREU</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Healthcare Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NkUxMkVDQjJDOEY5NDVDQ0E5NTFEMTlDMjIwNzVERjc7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6REIzOUJERjYzNEE1NEI2QUFENjZDQTBERkIzNTk0RjY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NjM2NTg4ODQ2MEU0NENDOUE4NzlDN0E2QjM5MjJFQjg</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MTE1QUJDMEU3QTA4NDJGN0I0NkFFQjdEMTg2NEI1RDI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QzA5NjIyOEJGMkZDNEUwMUJFODFENUUxRTQxOUY5NDg</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Labor &amp; Employment Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MTE3QUQwOTA0MUYzNDlCMEFFMjUwRUNDM0RDRkM5QzM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Invasion of Privacy</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDg2RkJDNTA4NjM2NEQwNEE3RDU4MEU0RUZBNDI5NjY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6M0YxREQzODhGODFBNDUyODkzQ0Y1NTk1M0ExMUUxRkQ</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Public Health &amp; Welfare Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDYwRTY1MDg3MTk5NDUyNkFFRDI1RjJBRERGQ0UxNzI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Commitment of Children</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDhEOUU4MDAzRjFCNEQ0NzgyRjFGOUE0MEFERjFCMTg7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QkQzMjQzQzhBQUQ2NDRBQTg4MjYwMzQ0QTI0N0E3RTQ</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RjM3NDdEQTcwRDVENDFENEI4QUJFMzQ5NzVGMTE1RDA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6REY3QUUxQ0YxMDFENEE3MTg3QTU4QTdBNkRGMEVCMDc</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification><classificationGroup classificationScheme="indexing-terms"><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem score="90"><className>Governments</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjdEQjE4OUJDMzQxNDNEMEI0RTI1QUFCMzJENjEwRTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></classificationGroup></metadata></legislativeDoc>