<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#349#000018#     2#       340.33#">Va. Code Ann. § 18.2-340.33</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_18.2-340.33"/><heading><desig>§ 18.2-340.33.</desig><title>Prohibited practices</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><bodyText><p>In addition to those other practices prohibited by this article, the following acts or practices are prohibited:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> No part of the gross receipts derived by a qualified organization may be used for any purpose other than (i) reasonable and proper gaming expenses, (ii) reasonable and proper business expenses, (iii) those lawful religious, charitable, community or educational purposes for which the organization is specifically chartered or organized, and (iv) expenses relating to the acquisition, construction, maintenance, or repair of any interest in the real property involved in the operation of the organization and used for lawful religious, charitable, community or educational purposes. For the purposes of clause (iv), such expenses may include the expenses of a corporation formed for the purpose of serving as the real estate holding entity of a qualified organization, provided (a) such holding entity is qualified as a tax exempt organization under § 501(c) of the Internal Revenue Code and (b) the membership of the qualified organization is identical to such holding entity.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Except as provided in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 18.2-340.34:1"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 18.2-340.34:1">§ 18.2-340.34:1<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#958#0000000018#0000000002#    340.34#0000000001#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, no qualified organization shall enter into a contract with or otherwise employ for compensation any person for the purpose of organizing, managing, or conducting any charitable games. However, organizations composed of or for deaf or blind persons may use a part of their gross receipts for costs associated with providing clerical assistance in the management and operation but not the conduct of charitable gaming.</p><p><pre/>The provisions of this subdivision shall not prohibit the joint operation of bingo games held in accordance with <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 18.2-340.29"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 18.2-340.29">§ 18.2-340.29.<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000018#     2#       340.29#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation></p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> No person shall pay or receive for use of any premises devoted, in whole or in part, to the conduct of any charitable games, any consideration in excess of the current fair market rental value of such property. Fair market rental value consideration shall not be based upon or determined by reference to a percentage of the proceeds derived from the operation of any charitable games or to the number of people in attendance at such charitable games.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_4"/><heading><desig>4.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> No building or other premises shall be utilized in whole or in part for the purpose of conducting charitable gaming more frequently than two calendar days in any one calendar week. However, no building or other premises owned by (i) a qualified organization which is exempt from taxation pursuant to <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="26 USC 501"><content><span normalizedCite="26 U.S.C. 501">§ 501(c) of the Internal Revenue Code<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#29854#1127#00000000501#1#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> or (ii) any county, city or town shall be utilized in whole or in part for the purpose of conducting bingo games more frequently than four calendar days in any one calendar week.</p><p><pre/>The provisions of this subdivision shall not apply to the playing of bingo games pursuant to a special permit issued in accordance with <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 18.2-340.27"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 18.2-340.27">§ 18.2-340.27.<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000018#     2#       340.27#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation></p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_5"/><heading><desig>5.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> No person shall participate in the management or operation of any charitable game unless such person is and, for a period of at least 30 days immediately preceding such participation, has been a bona fide member of the organization. For any organization that is not composed of members, a person who is not a bona fide member may volunteer in the conduct of a charitable game as long as that person is directly supervised by a bona fide official member of the organization.</p><p><pre/>The provisions of this subdivision shall not apply to (i) persons employed as clerical assistants by qualified organizations composed of or for deaf or blind persons; (ii) employees of a corporate sponsor of a qualified organization, provided such employees' participation is limited to the management, operation or conduct of no more than one raffle per year; (iii) the spouse or family member of any such bona fide member of a qualified organization provided at least one bona fide member is present; or (iv) persons employed by a qualified organization authorized to sell pull tabs or seal cards in accordance with <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 18.2-340.16"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 18.2-340.16">§ 18.2-340.16<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000018#     2#       340.16#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, provided (a) such sales are conducted by no more than two on-duty employees, (b) such employees receive no compensation for or based on the sale of the pull tabs or seal cards, and (c) such sales are conducted in the private social quarters of the organization.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_6"/><heading><desig>6.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> No person shall receive any remuneration for participating in the management, operation or conduct of any charitable game, except that:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_6_a"/><heading><desig>a.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Persons employed by organizations composed of or for deaf or blind persons may receive remuneration not to exceed $ 30 per event for providing clerical assistance in the management and operation but not the conduct of charitable games only for such organizations;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_6_b"/><heading><desig>b.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Persons under the age of 19 who sell raffle tickets for a qualified organization to raise funds for youth activities in which they participate may receive nonmonetary incentive awards or prizes from the organization;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_6_c"/><heading><desig>c.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Remuneration may be paid to off-duty law-enforcement officers from the jurisdiction in which such bingo games are played for providing uniformed security for such bingo games even if such officer is a member of the sponsoring organization, provided the remuneration paid to such member is in accordance with off-duty law-enforcement personnel work policies approved by the local law-enforcement official and further provided that such member is not otherwise engaged in the management, operation or conduct of the bingo games of that organization, or to private security services businesses licensed pursuant to § 9.1-139 providing uniformed security for such bingo games, provided that employees of such businesses shall not otherwise be involved in the management, operation, or conduct of the bingo games of that organization;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_6_d"/><heading><desig>d.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A member of a qualified organization lawfully participating in the management, operation or conduct of a bingo game may be provided food and nonalcoholic beverages by such organization for on-premises consumption during the bingo game provided the food and beverages are provided in accordance with Board regulations; and</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_6_e"/><heading><desig>e.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Remuneration may be paid to bingo managers or callers who have a current registration certificate issued by the Department in accordance with <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 18.2-340.34:1"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 18.2-340.34:1">§ 18.2-340.34:1<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#958#0000000018#0000000002#    340.34#0000000001#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, or who are exempt from such registration requirement. Such remuneration shall not exceed $ 100 per session.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_7"/><heading><desig>7.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> No landlord shall, at bingo games conducted on the landlord's premises, (i) participate in the conduct, management, or operation of any bingo games; (ii) sell, lease or otherwise provide for consideration any bingo supplies, including, but not limited to, bingo cards, instant bingo cards, or other game pieces; or (iii) require as a condition of the lease or by contract that a particular manufacturer, distributor or supplier of bingo supplies or equipment be used by the organization.</p><p><pre/>The provisions of this subdivision shall not apply to any qualified organization conducting bingo games on its own behalf at premises owned by it.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_8"/><heading><desig>8.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> No qualified organization shall enter into any contract with or otherwise employ or compensate any member of the organization on account of the sale of bingo supplies or equipment.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_9"/><heading><desig>9.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> No organization shall award any bingo prize money or any merchandise valued in excess of the following amounts:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_9_a"/><heading><desig>a.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> No bingo door prize shall exceed $ 50 for a single door prize or $ 250 in cumulative door prizes in any one session;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_9_b"/><heading><desig>b.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> No regular bingo or special bingo game prize shall exceed $ 100;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_9_c"/><heading><desig>c.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> No instant bingo, pull tab, or seal card prize for a single card shall exceed $ 1,000;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_9_d"/><heading><desig>d.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Except as provided in subdivision 9, no bingo jackpot of any nature whatsoever shall exceed $ 1,000, nor shall the total amount of bingo jackpot prizes awarded in any one session exceed $ 1,000. Proceeds from the sale of bingo cards and the sheets used for bingo jackpot games shall be accounted for separately from the bingo cards or sheets used for any other bingo games; and</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_9_e"/><heading><desig>e.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> No single network bingo prize shall exceed $ 25,000. Proceeds from the sale of network bingo cards shall be accounted for separately from bingo cards and sheets used for any other bingo game.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_10"/><heading><desig>10.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The provisions of subdivision 9 shall not apply to:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><bodyText><p><pre/>Any progressive bingo game, in which (a) a regular or special prize, not to exceed $ 100, is awarded on the basis of predetermined numbers or patterns selected at random and (b) a progressive prize, not to exceed $ 500 for the initial progressive prize and $ 5,000 for the maximum progressive prize, is awarded if the predetermined numbers or patterns are covered when a certain number of numbers is called, provided (i) there are no more than six such games per session per organization, (ii) the amount of increase of the progressive prize per session is no more than $ 100, (iii) the bingo cards or sheets used in such games are sold separately from the bingo cards or sheets used for any other bingo games, (iv) the organization separately accounts for the proceeds from such sale, and (v) such games are otherwise operated in accordance with the Department's rules of play.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_11"/><heading><desig>11.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> No organization shall award any raffle prize valued at more than $ 100,000.</p><p><pre/>The provisions of this subdivision shall not apply to a raffle conducted no more than once per calendar year by a qualified organization qualified as a tax-exempt organization pursuant to <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="26 USC 501"><content><span normalizedCite="26 U.S.C. 501">§ 501(c) of the Internal Revenue Code<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#29854#1127#00000000501#1#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> for a prize consisting of a lot improved by a residential dwelling where 100 percent of the moneys received from such a raffle, less deductions for the fair market value for the cost of acquisition of the land and materials, are donated to lawful religious, charitable, community, or educational organizations specifically chartered or organized under the laws of the Commonwealth and qualified as a § 501(c) tax-exempt organization.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_12"/><heading><desig>12.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> No qualified organization composed of or for deaf or blind persons which employs a person not a member to provide clerical assistance in the management and operation but not the conduct of any charitable games shall conduct such games unless it has in force fidelity insurance, as defined in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 38.2-120"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 38.2-120">§ 38.2-120<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000038#     2#          120#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, written by an insurer licensed to do business in the Commonwealth.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_13"/><heading><desig>13.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> No person shall participate in the management or operation of any charitable game if he has ever been convicted of any felony or if he has been convicted of any misdemeanor involving fraud, theft, or financial crimes within the preceding five years. No person shall participate in the conduct of any charitable game if, within the preceding 10 years, he has been convicted of any felony or if, within the preceding five years he has been convicted of any misdemeanor involving fraud, theft, or financial crimes. In addition, no person shall participate in the management, operation or conduct of any charitable game if that person, within the preceding five years, has participated in the management, operation, or conduct of any charitable game which was found by the Department or a court of competent jurisdiction to have been operated in violation of state law, local ordinance or Board regulation.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_14"/><heading><desig>14.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Qualified organizations jointly conducting bingo games pursuant to <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 18.2-340.29"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 18.2-340.29">§ 18.2-340.29<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000018#     2#       340.29#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> shall not circumvent any restrictions and prohibitions which would otherwise apply if a single organization were conducting such games. These restrictions and prohibitions shall include, but not be limited to, the frequency with which bingo games may be held, the value of merchandise or money awarded as prizes, or any other practice prohibited under this section.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_15"/><heading><desig>15.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A qualified organization shall not purchase any charitable gaming supplies for use in the Commonwealth from any person who is not currently registered with the Department as a supplier pursuant to <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 18.2-340.34"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 18.2-340.34">§ 18.2-340.34.<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000018#     2#       340.34#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation></p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_16"/><heading><desig>16.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Unless otherwise permitted in this article, no part of an organization's charitable gaming gross receipts shall be used for an organization's social or recreational activities.</p></bodyText></level></level><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p><citation normalizedCite="1995 VA CH 837"><content><span normalizedCite="1995 Va. Ch. 837">1995, c. 837<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1995#000837#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1996 VA CH 919"><content><span normalizedCite="1996 Va. Ch. 919">1996, c. 919<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1996#000919#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1997 VA CH 777"><content><span normalizedCite="1997 Va. Ch. 777">1997, cc. 777<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1997#000777#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1997 VA CH 838"><content><span normalizedCite="1997 Va. Ch. 838">838<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1997#000838#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1998 VA CH 57"><content><span normalizedCite="1998 Va. Ch. 57">1998, cc. 57<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1998#000057#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1998 VA CH 398"><content><span normalizedCite="1998 Va. Ch. 398">398<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1998#000398#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1999 VA CH 534"><content><span normalizedCite="1999 Va. Ch. 534">1999, c. 534<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1999#000534#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2000 VA CH 1000"><content><span normalizedCite="2000 Va. Ch. 1000">2000, c. 1000<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2000#001000#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2001 VA CH 754"><content><span normalizedCite="2001 Va. Ch. 754">2001, c. 754<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2001#000754#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2002 VA CH 282"><content><span normalizedCite="2002 Va. Ch. 282">2002, c. 282<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2002#000282#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2003 VA CH 884"><content><span normalizedCite="2003 Va. Ch. 884">2003, c. 884<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2003#000884#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2004 VA CH 275"><content><span normalizedCite="2004 Va. Ch. 275">2004, c. 275<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2004#000275#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2005 VA CH 776"><content><span normalizedCite="2005 Va. Ch. 776">2005, cc. 776<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2005#000776#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2005 VA CH 826"><content><span normalizedCite="2005 Va. Ch. 826">826<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2005#000826#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2006 VA CH 644"><content><span normalizedCite="2006 Va. Ch. 644">2006, c. 644<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2006#000644#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2007 VA CH 226"><content><span normalizedCite="2007 Va. Ch. 226">2007, cc. 226<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2007#000226#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2007 VA CH 790"><content><span normalizedCite="2007 Va. Ch. 790">790<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2007#000790#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2008 VA CH 352"><content><span normalizedCite="2008 Va. Ch. 352">2008, c. 352<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2008#000352#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2010 VA CH 429"><content><span normalizedCite="2010 Va. Ch. 429">2010, c. 429<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2010#000429#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2013 VA CH 36"><content><span normalizedCite="2013 Va. Ch. 36">2013, cc. 36<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2013#000036#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2013 VA CH 350"><content><span normalizedCite="2013 Va. Ch. 350">350<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2013#000350#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PVB0-004G-K29G-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 18.2.</desig><title>CRIMES AND OFFENSES GENERALLY</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 8.</desig><title>CRIMES INVOLVING MORALS AND DECENCY</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="article"><heading><desig>ARTICLE 1.1:1.</desig><title>CHARITABLE GAMING</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Distribution, Processing &amp; Storage of Food &amp; Agricultural Products</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NENGNzZCMDU5RjcyNEM0NEFFOUU4ODFCQkZCOThBRkI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NkVDMzM4QkJENTg3NDQ0RDg3NTA5OEM3RkMyQTlENDI</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Formation</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDJENDRCOUZDMTg5NEU1N0JGNjFCNjFFMTNDOTEzRDQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Njg2NjY4ODFGMkM4NDBERjg2ODkwNEMyNTM4QTgyQjk</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Gaming &amp; Lotteries</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NTRERjNCQTM4Mjk5NDA5RDlERDk3NDI1RENCQTI2OTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NEE4RUEzNEFFNDE3NDE1RTkxMTc0QkE3RTU2QTBEQjc</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Gaming &amp; Lotteries</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NzJGRTBFOEMyOENBNDQ5MTg1NTA2NDdFQjhCNzhERjI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6M0JFMDdFQkREMkFENDRFMEFGRkJEQ0E4OTg1NEM5RTc</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjA4OEVGODBENzY4NDcxM0IyQzA1OTEwQzVDODRBOUE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Dissolution &amp; Winding Up</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RjVENjk4NzUwQkU0NDQyNUExQkZBRkY1MzlCNTdERjU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Njg2NjY4ODFGMkM4NDBERjg2ODkwNEMyNTM4QTgyQjk</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Formation</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDJENDRCOUZDMTg5NEU1N0JGNjFCNjFFMTNDOTEzRDQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Njg2NjY4ODFGMkM4NDBERjg2ODkwNEMyNTM4QTgyQjk</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RjI3QTdDNjdBOUE1NDg2MTk5Q0ZGNEQ1MDUyRjBFN0Q7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Njg2NjY4ODFGMkM4NDBERjg2ODkwNEMyNTM4QTgyQjk</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Contracts Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QzY0RTZFMzE0RjkwNDdFQUI5M0U5N0ZFMjYyREMyQzU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QTdGQUE3QkZDMDlBNDQ1MTkzRjEzMEQ1OEUwNzdDOTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NjZEOEU3MEJBRUQ2NDNFNzhFRjAxRTk1OEU1QjY2QTc</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Criminal Law &amp; Procedure</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NEU0RkE1OUQwNUQwNDgxODhEODZCMjkzOTg3NThBNzk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NzU4OThERDQxNTVCNDkzRUE4QTM5NzEyMTBBNTg4OEI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDgzOEREQUY2MEY2NDZGQjg0REJDQ0I2MTQ5RDlFMTQ</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Governments</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjdEQjE4OUJDMzQxNDNEMEI0RTI1QUFCMzJENjEwRTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Distribution, Processing &amp; Storage</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NENGNzZCMDU5RjcyNEM0NEFFOUU4ODFCQkZCOThBRkI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NkVDMzM4QkJENTg3NDQ0RDg3NTA5OEM3RkMyQTlENDI</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Gaming &amp; Lotteries</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NTRERjNCQTM4Mjk5NDA5RDlERDk3NDI1RENCQTI2OTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Njg1MkM3RkYyNzIxNEVFRkJFMTI2NUM4NUU1ODdEM0Q</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Gaming &amp; Lotteries</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NzJGRTBFOEMyOENBNDQ5MTg1NTA2NDdFQjhCNzhERjI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QURCRDNBRjBGRTE0NEFBRUEzNUU1MzFGQjg3MTM4MDI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Insurance Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDM4MzQ2QUYzMTY0NDQzQTkxRDQwRUUzRUM5RDg0OEM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Qjc0QTcwOTM4RTExNDQ4QjgwRkZGOURERDdDMjk0N0U7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Q0NDMDkzNDlGQkM5NDI3RjlBODhCMzM3Qzg2NUFGRjg</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Labor &amp; Employment Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MTE3QUQwOTA0MUYzNDlCMEFFMjUwRUNDM0RDRkM5QzM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Compensation &amp; Benefits</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjIyOURFQThFQzZGNDFERUFGNkQ2MzdDN0UzRDIxRTQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NkM0MEYwMzFDQzhDNEY3NUIyMzBCRkNBNkI4Q0ZFN0M</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OUY1OTdBM0M0MzM2NDRERjkzNTZDQ0QyQ0RBQUVEQUM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NkM0MEYwMzFDQzhDNEY3NUIyMzBCRkNBNkI4Q0ZFN0M</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Tax Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OTNEM0E2OEE0RkQyNEY1MDhBQzdGMkQ4ODI4QTJDODE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OEVBODVEMEFGQUUzNDQwQUFGNkEzRkM1RjNGRUQyNTU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QkI4MzdCQzJFRDlBNDlENzlFOERGQjdGREVCOTJDNEU</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MkM0RDIzQ0VFNjRFNDU2QzlDNjA2N0E2N0RBODEwQkY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NzQ3RTREM0I0QTMxNDRDNEI2OEFDMEUxRjVDOEQ5RDE</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDM0MzI2OUIyMEFENDNFOUI2RkQ5NzFFRDAwQjg4RjA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RkEwQjZENTRGQzE3NDk4QThFOEQwRjE5NjBBNDk1RjE</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MEMzQzdEM0Q2NEEyNDg5RDhDMEE3NDAwMDNGOUU2MkM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MEI0QjM4RDg1M0IxNDk1RDkwOTVGMEMxRTQxQTg1ODU</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification><classificationGroup classificationScheme="indexing-terms"><classification classificationScheme="legal"/></classificationGroup></metadata></legislativeDoc>