<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#123#000036#       105#">Va. Code Ann. § 36-105</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_36-105"/><heading><desig>§ 36-105.</desig><title>Enforcement of Code; appeals from decisions of local department; inspection of buildings; inspection warrants; inspection of elevators; issuance of permits</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a"/><heading><desig>A.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Enforcement generally. Enforcement of the provisions of the Building Code for construction and rehabilitation shall be the responsibility of the local building department. There shall be established within each local building department a local board of Building Code appeals whose composition, duties and responsibilities shall be prescribed in the Building Code. Any person aggrieved by the local building department's application of the Building Code or refusal to grant a modification to the provisions of the Building Code may appeal to the local board of Building Code appeals. No appeal to the State Building Code Technical Review Board shall lie prior to a final determination by the local board of Building Code appeals. Whenever a county or a municipality does not have such a building department or board of Building Code appeals, the local governing body shall enter into an agreement with the local governing body of another county or municipality or with some other agency, or a state agency approved by the Department for such enforcement and appeals resulting therefrom. For the purposes of this section, towns with a population of less than 3,500 may elect to administer and enforce the Building Code; however, where the town does not elect to administer and enforce the Building Code, the county in which the town is situated shall administer and enforce the Building Code for the town. In the event such town is situated in two or more counties, those counties shall administer and enforce the Building Code for that portion of the town situated within their respective boundaries.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b"/><heading><desig>B.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> New construction. Any building or structure may be inspected at any time before completion, and shall not be deemed in compliance until approved by the inspecting authority. Where the construction cost is less than $ 2,500, however, the inspection may, in the discretion of the inspecting authority, be waived. A building official may issue an annual permit for any construction regulated by the Building Code. The building official shall coordinate all reports of inspections for compliance with the Building Code, with inspections of fire and health officials delegated such authority, prior to issuance of an occupancy permit. Fees may be levied by the local governing body in order to defray the cost of such enforcement and appeals.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c"/><heading><desig>C.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Existing buildings and structures.</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Inspections and enforcement of the Building Code. The local governing body may also inspect and enforce the provisions of the Building Code for existing buildings and structures, whether occupied or not. Such inspection and enforcement shall be carried out by an agency or department designated by the local governing body.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Complaints by tenants. However, upon a finding by the local building department, following a complaint by a tenant of a residential dwelling unit that is the subject of such complaint, that there may be a violation of the unsafe structures provisions of the Building Code, the local building department shall enforce such provisions.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Inspection warrants. If the local building department receives a complaint that a violation of the Building Code exists that is an immediate and imminent threat to the health or safety of the owner, tenant, or occupants of any building or structure, or the owner, occupant, or tenant of any nearby building or structure, and the owner, occupant, or tenant of the building or structure that is the subject of the complaint has refused to allow the local building official or his agent to have access to the subject building or structure, the local building official or his agent may make an affidavit under oath before a magistrate or a court of competent jurisdiction and request that the magistrate or court grant the local building official or his agent an inspection warrant to enable the building official or his agent to enter the subject building or structure for the purpose of determining whether violations of the Building Code exist. After issuing a warrant under this section, the magistrate or judge shall file the affidavit in the manner prescribed by <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 19.2-54"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 19.2-54">§ 19.2-54<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000019#     2#           54#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>. After executing the warrant, the local building official or his agents shall return the warrant to the clerk of the circuit court of the city or county wherein the inspection was made. The local building official or his agent shall make a reasonable effort to obtain consent from the owner, occupant, or tenant of the subject building or structure prior to seeking the issuance of an inspection warrant under this section.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c_4"/><heading><desig>4.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Transfer of ownership. If the local building department has initiated an enforcement action against the owner of a building or structure and such owner subsequently transfers the ownership of the building or structure to an entity in which the owner holds an ownership interest greater than 50 percent, the pending enforcement action shall continue to be enforced against the owner.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c_5"/><heading><desig>5.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Elevator, escalator, or related conveyance inspections. The local governing body shall, however, inspect and enforce the Building Code for elevators, escalators, or related conveyances, except for elevators in single- and two-family homes and townhouses. Such inspection shall be carried out by an agency or department designated by the local governing body.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c_6"/><heading><desig>6.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A locality may require by ordinance that any landmark, building or structure that contributes to a district delineated pursuant to <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 15.2-2306"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 15.2-2306">§ 15.2-2306<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000015#     2#         2306#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> shall not be razed, demolished or moved until the razing, demolition or moving thereof is approved by the review board, or, on appeal, by the governing body after consultation with the review board unless the local maintenance code official consistent with the Uniform Statewide Building Code, Part III Maintenance, determines that it constitutes such a hazard that it shall be razed, demolished or moved.</p><p><pre/>For the purpose of this subdivision, a contributing landmark, building or structure is one that adds to or is consistent with the historic or architectural qualities, historic associations, or values for which the district was established pursuant to <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 15.2-2306"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 15.2-2306">§ 15.2-2306<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000015#     2#         2306#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, because it (i) was present during the period of significance, (ii) relates to the documented significance of the district, and (iii) possesses historic integrity or is capable of yielding important information about the period.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c_7"/><heading><desig>7.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Fees may be levied by the local governing body in order to defray the cost of such enforcement and appeals. For purposes of this section, "defray the cost" may include the fair and reasonable costs incurred for such enforcement during normal business hours, but shall not include overtime costs unless conducted outside of the normal working hours established by the locality. A schedule of such costs shall be adopted by the local governing body in a local ordinance. A locality shall not charge an overtime rate for inspections conducted during the normal business hours established by the locality. Nothing herein shall be construed to prohibit a private entity from conducting such inspections, provided the private entity has been approved to perform such inspections in accordance with the written policy of the maintenance code official for the locality.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d"/><heading><desig>D.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Fees may be levied by the local governing body to be paid by the applicant for the issuance of a building permit as otherwise provided under this chapter, however, notwithstanding any provision of law, general or special, if the applicant for a building permit is a tenant or the owner of an easement on the owner's property, such applicant shall not be denied a permit under the Building Code solely upon the basis that the property owner has financial obligations to the locality that constitute a lien on such property in favor of the locality. If such applicant is the property owner, in addition to payment of the fees for issuance of a building permit, the locality may require full payment of any and all financial obligations of the property owner to the locality to satisfy such lien prior to issuance of such permit. For purposes of this subsection, "property owner" means the owner of such property as reflected in the land records of the circuit court clerk where the property is located, the owner's agent, or any entity in which the owner holds an ownership interest greater than 50 percent.</p></bodyText></level><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p>1972, c. 829; 1974, c. 433; 1977, cc. 423, 613; 1978, c. 578; 1981, c. 498; 1982, c. 267; <citation normalizedCite="1992 VA CH 73"><content><span normalizedCite="1992 Va. Ch. 73">1992, c. 73<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1992#000073#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1993 VA CH 328"><content><span normalizedCite="1993 Va. Ch. 328">1993, c. 328<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1993#000328#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1994 VA CH 214"><content><span normalizedCite="1994 Va. Ch. 214">1994, cc. 214<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1994#000214#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1994 VA CH 256"><content><span normalizedCite="1994 Va. Ch. 256">256<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1994#000256#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1994 VA CH 574"><content><span normalizedCite="1994 Va. Ch. 574">574<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1994#000574#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1995 VA CH 95"><content><span normalizedCite="1995 Va. Ch. 95">1995, cc. 95<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1995#000095#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1995 VA CH 523"><content><span normalizedCite="1995 Va. Ch. 523">523<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1995#000523#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1995 VA CH 702"><content><span normalizedCite="1995 Va. Ch. 702">702<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1995#000702#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1995 VA CH 827"><content><span normalizedCite="1995 Va. Ch. 827">827<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1995#000827#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1999 VA CH 333"><content><span normalizedCite="1999 Va. Ch. 333">1999, cc. 333<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1999#000333#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1999 VA CH 341"><content><span normalizedCite="1999 Va. Ch. 341">341<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1999#000341#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2001 VA CH 119"><content><span normalizedCite="2001 Va. Ch. 119">2001, c. 119<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2001#000119#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2002 VA CH 720"><content><span normalizedCite="2002 Va. Ch. 720">2002, c. 720<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2002#000720#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2003 VA CH 650"><content><span normalizedCite="2003 Va. Ch. 650">2003, c. 650<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2003#000650#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2004 VA CH 851"><content><span normalizedCite="2004 Va. Ch. 851">2004, c. 851<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2004#000851#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2006 VA CH 424"><content><span normalizedCite="2006 Va. Ch. 424">2006, c. 424<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2006#000424#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2007 VA CH 291"><content><span normalizedCite="2007 Va. Ch. 291">2007, c. 291<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2007#000291#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2009 VA CH 181"><content><span normalizedCite="2009 Va. Ch. 181">2009, cc. 181<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2009#000181#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2009 VA CH 184"><content><span normalizedCite="2009 Va. Ch. 184">184<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2009#000184#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2009 VA CH 551"><content><span normalizedCite="2009 Va. Ch. 551">551<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2009#000551#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2009 VA CH 586"><content><span normalizedCite="2009 Va. Ch. 586">586<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2009#000586#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2010 VA CH 63"><content><span normalizedCite="2010 Va. Ch. 63">2010, c. 63<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2010#000063#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2012 VA CH 494"><content><span normalizedCite="2012 Va. Ch. 494">2012, cc. 494<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2012#000494#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2012 VA CH 607"><content><span normalizedCite="2012 Va. Ch. 607">607<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2012#000607#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2014 VA CH 354"><content><span normalizedCite="2014 Va. Ch. 354">2014, c. 354<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2014#000354#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PT30-004G-K3YM-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 36.</desig><title>HOUSING</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 6.</desig><title>UNIFORM STATEWIDE BUILDING CODE</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="article"><heading><desig>ARTICLE 1.</desig><title>GENERAL PROVISIONS</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Administrative Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NjMxMjc0MUIzQjkzNEM4MEI4NkZGQjVCREJCRDk4OUM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Standing</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NUU1RTE2NDk5MjE3NDVCNzlBN0M0OTE2NDJBNzk1OUQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RDQ2OTA3NjY4NjgyNEYyQjhBN0E1M0VFQkM3QzQ1MDQ</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Governments</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjdEQjE4OUJDMzQxNDNEMEI0RTI1QUFCMzJENjEwRTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Administrative Boards</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QTYwRUFCMDc5MzQ5NDEyREFEQkU2NkE2MjRGQTlCNzY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Njg1MkM3RkYyNzIxNEVFRkJFMTI2NUM4NUU1ODdEM0Q</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Clerks of Court</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6REVFMjkzRDI1MkU2NERDNjk3OEUxODY0REYwMUI1NjE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NURENzJGNTEyQzM0NEREQUI2RkVCRTM4RTc1RTZBREU</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Employees &amp; Officials</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDNCMDQzRTY3RDY3NDNEOEE4RDg2OUFEOTRBNDREQzg7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Njg1MkM3RkYyNzIxNEVFRkJFMTI2NUM4NUU1ODdEM0Q</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Licenses</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QUQzRDFDRDE0OTA0NDU2OEIwMUZCNDZEQTBBODdCODA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Njg1MkM3RkYyNzIxNEVFRkJFMTI2NUM4NUU1ODdEM0Q</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Real Property Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QUUyRTcxRURBNEY2NEE2MDk3QzBCNzRDOEY0NTZDQzk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Building &amp; Housing Codes</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDZGNTdFRUIyNEQ2NDQ1QjlBMzEwRDQyOUZFRUFCRjM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NjcyQTdEMEUxODYyNDY0OThFQTg1NUNGMjFBMTkxQ0M</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Construction Loans</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RDNGMDlENjQ4NUYyNEM0MEIxRTAwMjAyRTdFRUNBRkY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MTY1MzRERDhBMDZCNDFBMDk0QUEwRjcyN0ZFNEY3REM</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RjBBQTVENjZENjJFNEEzNjlBRDE1QjZDRjQyM0FBNkM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NjcyQTdEMEUxODYyNDY0OThFQTg1NUNGMjFBMTkxQ0M</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Historic Preservation</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjQ4MjBCNkQ0QjUzNDZBQzlCRERBMzg1RUJENUVBQTc7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NjcyQTdEMEUxODYyNDY0OThFQTg1NUNGMjFBMTkxQ0M</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Lien Priorities</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MTIxMTU0NDU3QTVBNEZERUI3QkNFMTA5Q0ExNDg1Njk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDVEQUQ4RkIyOUFGNDA2OTlEODNGQ0Y0RTk1NjE0N0E</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></metadata></legislativeDoc>