<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#349#000015#     2#         6308#">Va. Code Ann. § 15.2-6308</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_15.2-6308"/><heading><desig>§ 15.2-6308.</desig><title>Powers of authorities generally</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><bodyText><p>An authority shall have the following powers:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> To sue and be sued; to adopt and use a common seal and to alter the same as may be deemed expedient; to have perpetual succession; to make and execute contracts and other instruments necessary or convenient to the exercise of the powers of the authority; and to make and from time to time amend and repeal bylaws, rules and regulations, not inconsistent with law, to carry into effect the powers and purposes of the authority.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> To foster and stimulate the industrial, social and other economic development of its area of operation, including without limitation development for industrial, employment, housing, commercial, recreational, educational and other public purposes; to prepare and carry out plans and projects to accomplish such objectives; to provide for the construction, reconstruction, improvement, alteration, maintenance, removal, equipping or repair of any buildings, structures or land of any kind; to sell, lease or rent to others or to develop, operate or manage with others in a joint venture or other partnering arrangement, on such terms as it deems proper and which are consistent with the provisions of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 15.2-6317"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 15.2-6317">§ 15.2-6317<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000015#     2#         6317#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, any lands, dwellings, houses, accommodations, structures, buildings, facilities, or appurtenances embraced within its area of operations; to establish, collect and revise the rents charged and terms and conditions of occupancy thereof; to terminate any such lease or rental obligation upon the failure of the lessee or renter to comply with any of the obligations thereof; to arrange or contract for the furnishing by any person or agency, public or private, of works, services, privileges or facilities in connection with any activity in which the authority may engage; to acquire, own, hold, and improve real or personal property; to purchase, lease, obtain options upon, acquire by gift, grant, bequest, devise, easement, dedication or otherwise any real or personal property or any interest therein, which purchase, lease, or acquisition may be made for less than fair market value; to sell, lease, exchange, transfer, assign, or pledge any real or personal property or any interest therein, which sale, lease, or other transfer or assignment may be made for less than fair market value; to dedicate, make a gift of, or lease for a nominal amount, any real or personal property or any interest therein to the Commonwealth, or the localities or agencies, public or private, within the area of operation or adjacent to such authority, jointly or severally, for public use or benefit, such as, but not limited to, game preserves, playgrounds, park and recreational areas and facilities, hospitals, clinics, schools and airports; to acquire, lease, maintain, alter, operate, improve, expand, sell or otherwise dispose of on-site utility and infrastructure systems or sell any excess service capacity for off-site use; to acquire, lease, construct, maintain and operate and dispose of tracks, spurs, crossings, terminals, warehouses and terminal facilities of every kind and description necessary or useful in the transportation and storage of goods, wares and merchandise; and to insure or provide for the insurance of any real or personal property or operation of the authority against any risks or hazards.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> To invest any funds held in reserves or sinking funds, or any funds not required for immediate disbursements, in property or security in which fiduciaries may legally invest funds subject to their control; to purchase its bonds at a price not more than the principal amount thereof and accrued interest, all bonds so purchased to be cancelled.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_4"/><heading><desig>4.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> To undertake and carry out examinations, investigations, studies and analyses of the business, industrial, agricultural, utility, transportation and other economic development needs, requirements and potentialities of its area of operation, or off-site needs, requirements and potentialities which directly affect the successful industrial and economic development of its area of operation, and the manner in which such needs and requirements and potentialities are being met, or should be met, in order to accomplish the purposes for which it is created; to make use of the facts determined in such research and analyses in its own operation; and to make the results of such studies and analyses available to public bodies and to private individuals, groups and businesses, except as such information may be exempted pursuant to the Virginia Freedom of Information Act (<citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 2.2-3700"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 2.2-3700">§ 2.2-3700<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000002#     2#         3700#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> et seq.).</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_5"/><heading><desig>5.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> In the discharge of its enumerated powers, to cooperate with the federal government, the Commonwealth and the localities within its area of operation or adjacent to such authority.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_6"/><heading><desig>6.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> To appoint an authority advisory committee to advise it, consisting of such number of persons as it may deem proper. Such persons so appointed shall be residents of the locality in which the authority is located. They shall not receive any compensation for their services but may be reimbursed for their necessary traveling and other expenses incurred while on business of the authority.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_7"/><heading><desig>7.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> To exercise all or any part or combination of powers herein granted.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_8"/><heading><desig>8.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> To do any and all other acts and things that may be reasonably necessary and convenient to carry out its purposes and powers.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><bodyText><p>No provision of law with respect to the acquisition, operation or disposition of property by other political subdivisions or public bodies shall be applicable to an authority unless specifically stated therein. In any locality where planning, zoning or development regulations may apply, the authority shall comply with and is subject to those regulations to the same extent as a private commercial or industrial enterprise.</p></bodyText></level><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p>Code 1950, § 15-946; 1954, c. 645; 1962, c. 623, § 15.1-1329; <citation normalizedCite="1996 VA CH 740"><content><span normalizedCite="1996 Va. Ch. 740">1996, c. 740<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1996#000740#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1997 VA CH 587"><content><span normalizedCite="1997 Va. Ch. 587">1997, c. 587<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1997#000587#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2005 VA CH 869"><content><span normalizedCite="2005 Va. Ch. 869">2005, cc. 869<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2005#000869#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2005 VA CH 887"><content><span normalizedCite="2005 Va. Ch. 887">887<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2005#000887#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PSM0-004G-K3X6-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 15.2.</desig><title>COUNTIES, CITIES AND TOWNS</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="subtitle"><heading><desig>SUBTITLE IV.</desig><title>OTHER GOVERNMENTAL ENTITIES</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 63.</desig><title>AUTHORITIES FOR DEVELOPMENT OF FORMER FEDERAL AREAS</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Contracts Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QzY0RTZFMzE0RjkwNDdFQUI5M0U5N0ZFMjYyREMyQzU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QTdGQUE3QkZDMDlBNDQ1MTkzRjEzMEQ1OEUwNzdDOTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NjZEOEU3MEJBRUQ2NDNFNzhFRjAxRTk1OEU1QjY2QTc</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Environmental Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NzFDRDYyNkI2QjhBNDg3NTkyRjRDRkZEQjlCRkRBQzM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Public Participation</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MzkwQTAyQTM0QjIzNDAzN0I2RjBBNDczNzA0N0I2NzE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjI3QUU4NUZEQzZFNEYzRThENkZBRTA1MkUyQTAwQTA</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Public Health &amp; Welfare Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDYwRTY1MDg3MTk5NDUyNkFFRDI1RjJBRERGQ0UxNzI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Community &amp; Economic Development</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MEUxOUMwOTFCRDdFNEVFOUJFMjE2RDE0NERDOTM0QjY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDZDNTZENUNCRjVBNEY4OEIyQzVBNjRDRTcyOEQ4NDQ</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Real Property Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QUUyRTcxRURBNEY2NEE2MDk3QzBCNzRDOEY0NTZDQzk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Assignments</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6ODVCN0FCRTQ3MEE4NEJCRkE3OTRGOUQzODE4RDZENjc7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDU3NDIyNUI2MzczNEUwMzk0M0Y4MkZDQjk2OUUyRTQ</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6M0M3NUYwQUZFNUQ3NDU2NkFFQ0RGRTBFQkVFN0UyQUI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjRCMUU0RUM1REQ2NDYyMDk1Qjc2QzYzNDg1RjgxNDg</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OUMxMzhDNkRFNkYxNEVCQzkxMzEzQTgyRjA3QzBEODA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6N0ZFMkU1NEFCMjY5NDY0MjhBNTE5Njk1QjZCNTkzMzI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Transportation Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RTYzRTk5RDVBQkQ2NDcwQzk2NTU3ODQ5OEE3NDlBNzk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Establishment, Maintenance &amp; Operation</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RjY3MjFDOUZBQjJFNDlFNThEQTdEMTgwQzI0MDlBNzU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QzdDOUIxNEQzQzA5NEM0Q0E5RjlERDVFNzIzNEQyQzA</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification><classificationGroup classificationScheme="indexing-terms"><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem score="90"><className>Governments</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjdEQjE4OUJDMzQxNDNEMEI0RTI1QUFCMzJENjEwRTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></classificationGroup></metadata></legislativeDoc>