<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#349#000059#     1#          323#">Va. Code Ann. § 59.1-323</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_59.1-323"/><heading><desig>§ 59.1-323.</desig><title>Denial, suspension, or revocation of registration; hearing; summary action</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a"/><heading><desig>A.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The Commissioner may deny an application for registration of a membership camping operator or may suspend, or revoke such registration if the Commissioner finds that such action is necessary for the protection of purchasers or prospective purchasers or that any one of the following is true:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The membership camping operator has failed to comply with any provision of this chapter that materially affects the rights of purchasers, prospective purchasers or owners of membership camping contracts.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The membership camping operator's offering or execution of membership camping contracts is fraudulent.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The membership camping operator's application for registration or any amendment thereto is incomplete in any respect.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_4"/><heading><desig>4.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The membership camping operator has failed to file timely amendments to the application for registration or meet any other requirement of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 59.1-318"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 59.1-318">§ 59.1-318<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000059#     1#          318#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> of this chapter.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_5"/><heading><desig>5.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The membership camping operator has represented or is representing to purchasers in connection with the offer to sell membership camping contracts that a particular facility or facilities are planned without reasonable expectation that such facility will be completed within a reasonable time, or without the apparent means to ensure its completion.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_6"/><heading><desig>6.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The membership camping operator has permanently withdrawn from use all or any substantial portion of any campground and that (i) no adequate provision has been made to provide a substitute campground of comparable quality and attraction in the same general area within a reasonable time after such withdrawal, and (ii) the rights of all purchasers at the affected location have not expired, and (iii) the Commissioner has found that the withdrawal is consistent with the protection of purchasers. Notwithstanding the foregoing, a membership camping operator may reserve the right to withdraw permanently from use all or any portion of a campground devoted to membership camping if, after the membership camping operator first represents to purchasers that the campground is or will be available for camping, the specific date upon which the withdrawal becomes effective is disclosed in writing to all purchasers at or prior to the time the membership camping contract is executed.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_7"/><heading><desig>7.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The membership camping operator has made any representation in any document or information filed with the Commissioner which is false or misleading.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_8"/><heading><desig>8.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The membership camping operator has engaged or is engaging in any unlawful act or practice.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_9"/><heading><desig>9.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The membership camping operator has disseminated or caused to be disseminated, any false or misleading promotional materials in connection with a campground.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_10"/><heading><desig>10.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The membership camping operator does not have a reasonable ability to discharge the obligations imposed upon him by any membership camping contract.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b"/><heading><desig>B.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Except as provided in subsection C of this section, before denying, suspending or revoking a registration, as provided in subsection A of this section, the Commissioner shall issue to the membership camping operator a notice of opportunity for a hearing to consider the denial, suspension, or revocation.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c"/><heading><desig>C.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> If the Commissioner finds that the public health, safety or welfare requires emergency action and incorporates this finding in his order, the Commissioner may summarily deny, suspend or revoke a registration.  The membership camping operator shall be given an opportunity within ten days after entry of such an order to appear before the Commissioner and show cause why the summary order should not remain in effect. If good cause is shown, the Commissioner shall vacate the summary order. If good cause is not shown, the summary order shall remain in effect. The membership camping operator shall have fifteen days thereafter within which to request a hearing, or the Commissioner may within thirty days thereafter set the matter for a hearing.</p></bodyText></level><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p>1985, c. 409; <citation normalizedCite="1992 VA CH 545"><content><span normalizedCite="1992 Va. Ch. 545">1992, c. 545<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1992#000545#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PTM0-004G-K0GN-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 59.1.</desig><title>TRADE AND COMMERCE</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 25.</desig><title>VIRGINIA MEMBERSHIP CAMPING ACT</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="article"><heading><desig>ARTICLE 2.</desig><title>REGISTRATION</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Civil Procedure</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MzUxNjJDMEQ5N0YwNDMzM0JDMjEzM0UzOTYzMzI3OTU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RDkxMkU3MzM5RjU4NDcyNjkyN0E2RTJFQzQ1NTY5RjU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RUFDMkE0QkZBRDY0NDU4MEJBN0IzQTFGMjcyOTFFQkI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Insurance Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDM4MzQ2QUYzMTY0NDQzQTkxRDQwRUUzRUM5RDg0OEM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6ODdENDhFNDcwQ0Y4NEFDMTk1RTAwRjk2NkZERUYwRTY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NjVGQjM2Rjk5M0I2NDJFQThCMzU5QTQ4NzA4NTI1MEE</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification><classificationGroup classificationScheme="indexing-terms"><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem score="90"><className>Antitrust</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6REEyRTNDM0JGQzYyNEMyOEFGNTAwNUJEOUU1MDg4NjU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></classificationGroup></metadata></legislativeDoc>