<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#123#000055#       374#">Va. Code Ann. § 55-374</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_55-374"/><heading><desig>§ 55-374.</desig><title>Public offering statement</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a"/><heading><desig>A.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The developer shall prepare and distribute to each prospective purchaser prior to the execution of a contract for the purchase of a time-share, a copy of the current public offering statement about which the time-share relates. The public offering statement shall fully and accurately disclose the material characteristics of the time-share project registered under this chapter and such time-share offered, and shall make known to each prospective purchaser all material circumstances affecting such time-share project. A developer need not make joint disclosures concerning two or more time-share projects owned by the developer or any related entity unless such projects are included in the same time-share program and marketed jointly at any of the time-share projects. The proposed public offering statement shall be filed with the Board, and shall be in a form prescribed by its regulations. The public offering statement may limit the information provided for the specific time-share project to which the developer's registration relates. The public offering statement shall include the following only to the extent a given disclosure is applicable; otherwise no reference shall be required of the developer or contained in the public offering statement:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The name and principal address of the developer and the time-share project registered with the Board about which the public offering statement relates, including:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_1_a"/><heading><desig>a.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The name, principal occupation and address of every director, partner, limited liability company manager, or trustee of the developer;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_1_b"/><heading><desig>b.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The name and address of each person owning or controlling an interest of 20 percent or more in each time-share project registered with the Board;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_1_c"/><heading><desig>c.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The particulars of any indictment, conviction, judgment, decree or order of any court or administrative agency against the developer or managing entity for violation of a federal, state, local or foreign country law or regulation in connection with activities relating to time-share sales, land sales, land investments, security sales, construction or sale of homes or improvements or any similar or related activity;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_1_d"/><heading><desig>d.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The nature of each unsatisfied judgment, if any, against the developer or the managing entity, the status of each pending suit involving the sale or management of real estate to which the developer, the managing entity, or any general partner, executive officer, director, limited liability company manager, or majority stockholder thereof, is a defending party, and the status of each pending suit, if any, of significance to any time-share project registered with the Board; and</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_1_e"/><heading><desig>e.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The name and address of the developer's agent for service of any notice permitted by this chapter.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A general description of the time-share project registered with the Board and the units and common elements promised available to purchasers, including without limitation, the developer's estimated schedule of commencement and completion of all promised and incomplete units and common elements.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> As to all time-shares offered by the developer:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_3_a"/><heading><desig>a.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The form of time-share ownership offered in the project registered with the Board;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_3_b"/><heading><desig>b.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The types, duration, and number of units and time-shares in the project registered with the Board;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_3_c"/><heading><desig>c.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Identification of units that are subject to the time-share program;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_3_d"/><heading><desig>d.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The estimated number of units that may become subject to the time-share program;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_3_e"/><heading><desig>e.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Provisions, if any, that have been made for public utilities in the time-share project including water, electricity, telephone, and sewerage facilities;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_3_f"/><heading><desig>f.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A statement to the effect of whether or not the developer has reserved the right to add to or delete from the time-share program a time-share project or any incidental benefit or alternative purchase; and</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_3_g"/><heading><desig>g.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> If the developer utilizes the possibility of reverter, a statement to that effect referring the purchaser to the reverter deed for an explanation thereof.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_4"/><heading><desig>4.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> In a time-share estate program, a copy of the annual report or budget required by <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 55-370.1"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 55 -370.1">§ 55-370.1<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#123#000055#     370.1#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, which copy may take the form of an exhibit to the public offering statement. In the case where multiple time-share projects are registered with the Board, the copy or exhibit may be in summary form.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_5"/><heading><desig>5.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> In a time-share use program where the developer's net worth is less than $ 250,000, a current audited balance sheet and where the developer's net worth exceeds such amount, a statement by such developer that its equity in the time-share program exceeds that amount.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_6"/><heading><desig>6.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Any initial or special fee due from the purchaser at settlement together with a description of the purpose and method of calculating the fee.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_7"/><heading><desig>7.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A description of any liens, defects, or encumbrances affecting the time-share project and in particular the time-share offered to the purchaser.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_8"/><heading><desig>8.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A general description of any financing offered by or available through the developer.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_9"/><heading><desig>9.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A statement that the purchaser has a nonwaivable right of cancellation, referring such purchaser to that portion of the contract in which such right may be found.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_10"/><heading><desig>10.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> If the time-share interest in a condominium unit may be conveyed before that unit is certified as substantially complete in accordance with <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 55-79.58"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 55 -79.58">§ 55-79.58<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#123#000055#     79.58#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, a statement of the developer's obligation to complete the unit. Such statement shall include the approximate date by which the condominium unit shall be completed, together with the form and amount of the bond filed in accordance with subsection B of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 55-79.58:1"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 55 -79.58:1">§ 55-79.58:1.<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#142#        55#     79.58#         1#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation></p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_11"/><heading><desig>11.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Any restraints on alienation of any number or portion of any time-shares.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_12"/><heading><desig>12.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A description of the insurance coverage provided for the benefit of time-share owners.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_13"/><heading><desig>13.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The extent to which financial arrangements, if any, have been provided for completion of any incomplete but promised time-share unit or common element being then offered for sale, including a statement of the developer's obligation to complete the promised units and common elements comprising the time-share project that have not begun, or begun but not yet completed.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_14"/><heading><desig>14.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The extent to which a time-share unit may become subject to a tax or other lien arising out of claims against other owners of the same unit.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_15"/><heading><desig>15.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The name and address of the managing entity for the project.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_16"/><heading><desig>16.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Copies of the project instrument and the association's articles of incorporation and bylaws, each of which may be a supplement to the public offering statement.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_17"/><heading><desig>17.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Any services that the developer provides or expense it pays and that it expects may become at any subsequent time a time-share expense of the owners, and the projected time-share expense liability attributable to each of those services or expenses for each time-share.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_18"/><heading><desig>18.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A description of the terms of the deposit escrow requirements, including a statement that deposits may be removed from escrow at the termination of the cancellation period.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_19"/><heading><desig>19.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A description of the facilities, if any, provided by the developer to the association in a time-share estate project for the management of the project.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_20"/><heading><desig>20.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Any other information required by the Board to assure full and fair meaningful disclosure to prospective purchasers.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b"/><heading><desig>B.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> If any prospective purchaser is offered the opportunity to subscribe to or participate in any exchange program, the public offering statement shall include as an exhibit or supplement, the disclosure document prepared by the exchange company in accordance with <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 55-374.2"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 55 -374.2">§ 55-374.2<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#123#000055#     374.2#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> and a brief narrative description of the exchange program which shall include the following:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A statement of whether membership or participation in the program is voluntary or mandatory;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The name and address of the exchange company together with the names of its top three officers and directors;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A statement of whether the exchange company or any of its top three officers, directors, or holders of a 10 percent or greater interest in the exchange company has any interest in the developer, managing entity or the time-share project;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_4"/><heading><desig>4.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A statement that the purchaser's contract with the exchange company is a contract separate and distinct from the purchaser's contract with the developer; and</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_5"/><heading><desig>5.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A brief narrative description of the procedure whereby exchanges are conducted.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c"/><heading><desig>C.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The public offering statement of a conversion time-share project shall also include the following, which may take the form of an exhibit to the public offering statement:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A specific statement of the amount of any initial or special fee, if any, due from the purchaser of a time-share on or before settlement of the purchase contract and the basis of such fee occasioned by the fact that the project is a conversion time-share project;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Information on the actual expenditures, if available, made on all repairs, maintenance, operation, or upkeep of the building or buildings within the last three years. This information shall be set forth in a tabular manner within the proposed budget of the project. If such building or buildings have not been occupied for a period of three years then the information shall be set forth for the period during which such building or buildings were occupied;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A description of any provisions made in the budget for reserves for capital expenditures and an explanation of the basis for such reserves occasioned by the fact that the project is a conversion time-share project, or, if no provision is made for such reserves, a statement to that effect; and</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c_4"/><heading><desig>4.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A statement of the present condition of all structural components and major utility installations in the building, which statement shall include the approximate dates of construction, installations, and major repairs as well as the expected useful life of each such item, together with the estimated cost, in current dollars, of replacing each such component.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d"/><heading><desig>D.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> In the case of a conversion project, the developer shall give at least 90 days' notice to each of the tenants of the building or buildings which the developer intends to submit to the provisions of this chapter. During the first 60 days of such 90-day period, each of these tenants shall have the exclusive right to contract for the purchase of a time-share from the unit he occupies, but only if such unit is to be retained in the conversion project without substantial alteration in its physical layout. Such notice shall be hand delivered or sent by first-class mail, return receipt requested, and shall inform the tenants of the developer's intent to create a conversion project. Such notice may also constitute the notice to terminate the tenancy as provided for in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 55-222"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 55 -222">§ 55-222<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#123#000055#       222#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, except that, despite the provisions of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 55-222"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 55 -222">§ 55-222<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#123#000055#       222#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, a tenancy from month to month may only be terminated upon 120 days' notice as set forth herein when such termination is in regard to the creation of a conversion project. If, however, a tenant so notified remains in possession of the unit he occupies after the expiration of the 120-day period with the permission of the developer, in order to then terminate the tenancy, such developer shall give the tenant a further notice as provided in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 55-222"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 55 -222">§ 55-222<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#123#000055#       222#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p><p>The developer of a conversion project, shall, in addition to the requirements of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 55-391.1"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 55 -391.1">§ 55-391.1<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#123#000055#     391.1#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, include with the application for registration a copy of the notice required by this subsection and a certified statement that such notice which fully complies with the provisions of this subsection shall be, at the time of the registration of the conversion project, mailed or delivered to each of the tenants in the building or buildings for which registration is sought.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_e"/><heading><desig>E.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The developer shall amend the public offering statement to reflect any material change in the time-share program or time-share project. If the developer has reserved in the time-share instrument the right to add to or delete incidental benefits or alternative purchases, the addition or deletion thereof shall not constitute a material change. Prior to distribution, the developer shall file with the Board the public offering statement amended to reflect any material change.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_f"/><heading><desig>F.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The Board may at any time require a developer to alter or supplement the form or substance of the public offering statement to assure full and fair disclosure to prospective purchasers. A developer may, in its discretion, prepare and distribute a public offering statement for each product offered or one public offering statement for all products offered.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_g"/><heading><desig>G.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> In the case of a time-share project located outside the Commonwealth, (i) the developer may amend the public offering statement to reflect any additions or deletions of a time-share project to the existing time-share program registered in the Commonwealth, and (ii) similar disclosure statements required by other situs laws governing time-sharing may be acceptable alternative disclosure statements.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_h"/><heading><desig>H.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The developer shall prepare and distribute to each prospective purchaser prior to the execution of a purchase contract for a registered alternative purchase, a copy of the public offering statement about which such alternative purchase relates. The public offering statement shall fully and accurately disclose the material characteristics of such alternative purchase. The public offering statement for an alternative purchase shall be filed with the Board and shall be in a form prescribed by its regulations, if any.</p><p>The public offering statement for an alternative purchase need not contain any information about the time-share project, time-share program or the time-shares offered by the developer which was initially offered to such purchaser by the developer. If the developer so elects, the public offering statement for an alternative purchase is not required to have any exhibits.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_i"/><heading><desig>I.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The public offering statement may be in any format, including a compact disc, provided the prospective buyer has available for review, along with ample time for any questions and answers, a copy of the public offering statement prior to his execution of a contract.</p></bodyText></level><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p>1981, c. 462; 1983, c. 59; 1984, c. 455; 1985, c. 517; 1986, c. 359; <citation normalizedCite="1989 VA CH 637"><content><span normalizedCite="1989 Va. Ch. 637">1989, c. 637<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1989#000637#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1994 VA CH 580"><content><span normalizedCite="1994 Va. Ch. 580">1994, c. 580<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1994#000580#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1998 VA CH 460"><content><span normalizedCite="1998 Va. Ch. 460">1998, c. 460<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1998#000460#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1999 VA CH 560"><content><span normalizedCite="1999 Va. Ch. 560">1999, c. 560<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1999#000560#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2001 VA CH 543"><content><span normalizedCite="2001 Va. Ch. 543">2001, c. 543<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2001#000543#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2004 VA CH 143"><content><span normalizedCite="2004 Va. Ch. 143">2004, c. 143<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2004#000143#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2006 VA CH 653"><content><span normalizedCite="2006 Va. Ch. 653">2006, c. 653<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2006#000653#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2007 VA CH 267"><content><span normalizedCite="2007 Va. Ch. 267">2007, c. 267<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2007#000267#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2014 VA CH 39"><content><span normalizedCite="2014 Va. Ch. 39">2014, cc. 39<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2014#000039#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2014 VA CH 716"><content><span normalizedCite="2014 Va. Ch. 716">716<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2014#000716#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PTD0-004G-K3BK-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 55.</desig><title>PROPERTY AND CONVEYANCES</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 21.</desig><title>THE VIRGINIA REAL ESTATE TIME-SHARE ACT</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="article"><heading><desig>ARTICLE 3.</desig><title>PROTECTION OF PURCHASERS</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjA4OEVGODBENzY4NDcxM0IyQzA1OTEwQzVDODRBOUE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Classes of Stock</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjAxRUY2QTUwODFFNEUwNzhBRjE1RTc0OTc1QzNBQzM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QUMwNTJCQTlCODkzNEVENDkwNEExOTcwMjBDNTIwNUY</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NzQwNjJBMUVBRDAwNEVFNUIwNjE0M0JFQ0IwNjk5MDU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NTBBOERFMzlGNEE5NDI2OUEwMUFDNkNFOURENTQ5MDQ</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MzZCNTdCQ0Q2OTRDNDYxOTg2MTY2NTREQUVGNjBBQzE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RTYwRjBDQTc2RUU5NDVGQkEwNjMwMTExRkI4QjQwNEQ</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NUUwRjE5Nzk1QUU0NEZGQTgxNjExMzg4QjMxQTYwMzI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NUFDMUUyMjFERDQ1NDg3NTg1NzVCNzQyMTU5QzlBODI</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Management Duties &amp; Liabilities</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NjM4RDFBNzVFNkFENDI1MDlENzhCRjEzMTQ3QTRERjI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NUFDMUUyMjFERDQ1NDg3NTg1NzVCNzQyMTU5QzlBODI</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Member Duties &amp; Liabilities</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDM4QzlDMjYxODY0NDYwNjg2OUFBMjVGNzYyQjFGMzQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NUFDMUUyMjFERDQ1NDg3NTg1NzVCNzQyMTU5QzlBODI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Energy &amp; Utilities Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OUUzODAyRDk1QzVFNEZGMEJDM0RGMDYxOTlEMEEzRDA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Qzk3MzQ5NjhDQjRGNEJBNzhBOEI5MkE3RjBEMTZDOUU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Rjk2NTk2ODk2RkMwNDZGQjgxNUI1RjE0MDk4MTNDQzY</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NEFGODVDQ0YxOEU1NEU5OThGMDAzNzk5RDlENjc0MTY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RjFGM0IxMEExQzRGNEM3OEI0Mjg2QzVGMDlENDk3QUQ</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Governments</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjdEQjE4OUJDMzQxNDNEMEI0RTI1QUFCMzJENjEwRTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Administrative Boards</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QTYwRUFCMDc5MzQ5NDEyREFEQkU2NkE2MjRGQTlCNzY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Njg1MkM3RkYyNzIxNEVFRkJFMTI2NUM4NUU1ODdEM0Q</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Real Property Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QUUyRTcxRURBNEY2NEE2MDk3QzBCNzRDOEY0NTZDQzk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjJCOTVGQkMzRkQzNEQ2RjkzOEFGNzY4QUVBNEUzRTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjQxMkNBNkE1ODE5NDg0NUJDMTkzNzA1NTMwQzRFQ0M</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OUMxMzhDNkRFNkYxNEVCQzkxMzEzQTgyRjA3QzBEODA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6N0ZFMkU1NEFCMjY5NDY0MjhBNTE5Njk1QjZCNTkzMzI</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Liability of Developers &amp; Vendors</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6N0QxNkYzMTc4RjYzNDNFMzk3RkI1NTNGMzVFNTJCQzc7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjJFMEE0QjUxMkVGNEMzMkI1MDZBQ0REREYyRkQ4RTU</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Management</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDQwRTc5MEY0MjE3NDRDRUFCRjFFODhBMUY5NDU2MDA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUMzQTI2Qzg3NkJDNDI5MEI1MTU1QkM0RDlGN0JENUU</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Periodic Tenancies</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NTNERUNGNzRCOTg0NDNGQkIyNjRENkZERjg5MjNBREQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RjBEQURGNzk3ODY4NEQ3RUI3Q0E1OTE1RDY5NkEwMkI</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Purchase &amp; Sale</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDNDNTc1MDExODM4NDA0NUEyRjMzNURBMDk0MTQxNTM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUMzQTI2Qzg3NkJDNDI5MEI1MTU1QkM0RDlGN0JENUU</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Reversions &amp; Reverter</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUJENjRGMTg1QUVFNEQwMzlBQUI5NzdFMjA4RTJFOTY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RDYwODMxODEzOTIxNDY1QTg1MDY2RUI5M0Y4NjhEQ0U</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Timeshares</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OTQ2MTA5RjlGODA0NDhFMEIzMEE2NDI4ODRBM0Y3MDU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjQxMkNBNkE1ODE5NDg0NUJDMTkzNzA1NTMwQzRFQ0M</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Tax Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OTNEM0E2OEE0RkQyNEY1MDhBQzdGMkQ4ODI4QTJDODE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Tax Liens</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NzlBODVCRkY5RUYwNDRBMkI1QjIxMjYzMTYwMDgwRkY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjkxRkVDMkNDMjBGNDdFMkI1RDQ3Nzk4QjgwOTBGQjU</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification><classificationGroup classificationScheme="indexing-terms"><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem score="90"><className>Real Property</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QUUyRTcxRURBNEY2NEE2MDk3QzBCNzRDOEY0NTZDQzk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></classificationGroup></metadata></legislativeDoc>