<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#349#000023#     1#         1012#">Va. Code Ann. § 23.1-1012</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_23.1-1012"/><heading><desig>§ 23.1-1012.</desig><title>(Effective October 1, 2016) Covered institutions; operational authority; financial operations generally</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a"/><heading><desig>A.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Each covered institution may (i) independently manage its operations and finances, including holding and investing its tuition, fees, research funds, and auxiliary enterprise funds and all other public funds; (ii) create any policy deemed necessary to conduct its financial operations; (iii) adopt the budget for the institution; and (iv) control the expenditures of all moneys generated or received by the institution, including tuition, fees, and other nongeneral fund revenue sources.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b"/><heading><desig>B.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Subject to the express terms of the management agreement, the governing board of each covered institution has the sole authority to establish tuition, mandatory fees, room and board, and other necessary charges consistent with sum sufficient appropriation authority for all nongeneral funds as provided by the Governor and the General Assembly in the general appropriation act. In the event that the institution retains any nongeneral funds, it shall invest such funds consistent with an investment policy established by the governing board and retain all income earned on such investments. In the event that the Commonwealth holds any nongeneral funds on behalf of the institution, the institution shall receive a share of the income earned by the Commonwealth on the investment of such funds as provided in subsection C of § 23.1-1002.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c"/><heading><desig>C.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The governing board of each covered institution shall include in its six-year plan pursuant to § 23.1-306 its commitment to providing need-based grant aid for middle-income and lower-income Virginia students in a manner that encourages student enrollment and progression without respect to potential increases in tuition and fees.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d"/><heading><desig>D.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Each covered institution's management agreement shall include the quantification of cost savings realized as a result of the restructured operational authority pursuant to this article.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_e"/><heading><desig>E.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Each covered institution may enter into any contract that it determines to be necessary or appropriate to place any bond or investment of the institution, in whole or in part, on the interest rate, cash flow, or other basis desired by the institution, including contracts commonly known as interest rate swap agreements, futures, and contracts providing for payments based on levels of, or changes in, interest rates. Each covered institution may enter into such contracts in connection with, incidental to, or for the purpose of entering into or maintaining any (i) agreement that secures bonds, notes, or other obligations or (ii) investment or contract providing for investment, otherwise authorized by law, including § 23.1-1013. Such contracts may contain such payment, security, default, remedy, and other terms and conditions as determined by the institution after giving due consideration to the creditworthiness of the counterpart or other obligated party, including any rating by any nationally recognized rating agency, and any other criteria that may be appropriate. Any money set aside and pledged to secure payments of bonds, notes, or other obligations or any contract entered into pursuant to this section may be pledged to and used to service any such contract.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_f"/><heading><desig>F.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The governing board of each covered institution shall adopt a system of independent financial management that includes bookkeeping and accounting procedures that have been prescribed for governmental organizations by the Government Accounting Standards Board.</p></bodyText></level><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p><citation normalizedCite="2005 VA CH 933"><content><span normalizedCite="2005 Va. Ch. 933">2005, cc. 933<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2005#000933#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2005 VA CH 945"><content><span normalizedCite="2005 Va. Ch. 945">945<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2005#000945#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 23-38.104"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 23 -38.104">§§ 23-38.104<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#123#000023#    38.104#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 23-38.106"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 23 -38.106">23-38.106<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#123#000023#    38.106#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2016 VA CH 588"><content><span normalizedCite="2016 Va. Ch. 588">2016, c. 588<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2016#000588#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PWD0-004G-K3R0-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 23.1.</desig><title>INSTITUTIONS OF HIGHER EDUCATION; OTHER EDUCATIONAL AND CULTURAL INSTITUTIONS</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="subtitle"><heading><desig>SUBTITLE III.</desig><title>MANAGEMENT AND FINANCING</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 10.</desig><title>RESTRUCTURED HIGHER EDUCATION FINANCIAL AND ADMINISTRATIVE OPERATIONS ACT</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="article"><heading><desig>ARTICLE 4.</desig><title>RESTRUCTURED FINANCIAL AND ADMINISTRATIVE AUTHORITY; COVERED INSTITUTIONS; MANAGEMENT AGREEMENTS.</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Contracts Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QzY0RTZFMzE0RjkwNDdFQUI5M0U5N0ZFMjYyREMyQzU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Futures</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RUUzNDUzQTZERTFBNDI5RDhFOEM2QzA1RDIxMjQ2RkQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Qjg1NzgyRDNGQzg1NEM5Nzg3RjA3MEUwRTA1QUI0NkU</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Investment Contracts</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RTY1ODlBODVBOEFENDQ5QTk0RjhBNjJBM0FFRjQ4MDE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Qjg1NzgyRDNGQzg1NEM5Nzg3RjA3MEUwRTA1QUI0NkU</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification><classificationGroup classificationScheme="indexing-terms"><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem score="90"><className>Education</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDkzNUEzQzFBNEZBNEFBREIxNDM5MTc1MUU5QjI4MTY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></classificationGroup></metadata></legislativeDoc>