<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#349#000009#     1#          101#">Va. Code Ann. § 9.1-101</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><note><bodyText><p>This section has more than one version with varying effective dates.  To view a complete list of the versions of this section see Table of Contents.</p></bodyText></note><anchor id="_9.1-101"/><heading><desig>§ 9.1-101.</desig><title>(Effective July 1, 2018) Definitions</title></heading><bodyText><p>As used in this chapter or in Chapter 23 (<citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 19.2-387"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 19.2-387">§ 19.2-387<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000019#     2#          387#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> et seq.) of Title 19.2, unless the context requires a different meaning:</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Administration of criminal justice"</emphasis> means performance of any activity directly involving the detection, apprehension, detention, pretrial release, post-trial release, prosecution, adjudication, correctional supervision, or rehabilitation of accused persons or criminal offenders or the collection, storage, and dissemination of criminal history record information.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Board"</emphasis> means the Criminal Justice Services Board.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Conviction data"</emphasis> means information in the custody of any criminal justice agency relating to a judgment of conviction, and the consequences arising therefrom, in any court.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Correctional status information"</emphasis> means records and data concerning each condition of a convicted person's custodial status, including probation, confinement, work release, study release, escape, or termination of custody through expiration of sentence, parole, pardon, or court decision.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Criminal history record information"</emphasis> means records and data collected by criminal justice agencies on adult individuals consisting of identifiable descriptions and notations of arrests, detentions, indictments, informations, or other formal charges, and any disposition arising therefrom. The term shall not include juvenile record information which is controlled by Chapter 11 (<citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 16.1-226"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 16.1-226">§ 16.1-226<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000016#     1#          226#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> et seq.) of Title 16.1, criminal justice intelligence information, criminal justice investigative information, or correctional status information.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Criminal justice agency"</emphasis> means (i) a court or any other governmental agency or subunit thereof which as its principal function performs the administration of criminal justice and any other agency or subunit thereof which performs criminal justice activities, but only to the extent that it does so; (ii) for the purposes of Chapter 23 (<citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 19.2-387"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 19.2-387">§ 19.2-387<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000019#     2#          387#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> et seq.) of Title 19.2, any private corporation or agency which, within the context of its criminal justice activities, employs special conservators of the peace appointed under Chapter 2 (<citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 19.2-12"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 19.2-12">§ 19.2-12<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000019#     2#           12#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> et seq.) of Title 19.2, provided that (a) such private corporation or agency requires its officers or special conservators to meet compulsory training standards established by the Criminal Justice Services Board and submits reports of compliance with the training standards and (b) the private corporation or agency complies with the provisions of Article 3 (<citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 9.1-126"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 9.1-126">§ 9.1-126<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000009#     1#          126#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> et seq.), but only to the extent that the private corporation or agency so designated as a criminal justice agency performs criminal justice activities; and (iii) the Office of the Attorney General, for all criminal justice activities otherwise permitted under clause (i) and for the purpose of performing duties required by the Civil Commitment of Sexually Violent Predators Act (<citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 37.2-900"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 37.2-900">§ 37.2-900<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000037#     2#          900#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> et seq.).</p><p>"Criminal justice agency" includes any program certified by the Commission on VASAP pursuant to <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 18.2-271.2"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 18.2-271.2">§ 18.2-271.2.<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000018#     2#        271.2#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation></p><p>"Criminal justice agency" includes the Department of Criminal Justice Services.</p><p>"Criminal justice agency" includes the Virginia State Crime Commission.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Criminal justice information system"</emphasis> means a system including the equipment, facilities, procedures, agreements, and organizations thereof, for the collection, processing, preservation, or dissemination of criminal history record information. The operations of the system may be performed manually or by using electronic computers or other automated data processing equipment.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Department"</emphasis> means the Department of Criminal Justice Services.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Dissemination"</emphasis> means any transfer of information, whether orally, in writing, or by electronic means. The term shall not include access to the information by officers or employees of a criminal justice agency maintaining the information who have both a need and right to know the information.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Law-enforcement officer"</emphasis> means any full-time or part-time employee of a police department or sheriff's office which is a part of or administered by the Commonwealth or any political subdivision thereof, or any full-time or part-time employee of a private police department, and who is responsible for the prevention and detection of crime and the enforcement of the penal, traffic or highway laws of the Commonwealth, and shall include any (i) special agent of the Department of Alcoholic Beverage Control; (ii) police agent appointed under the provisions of § 56-353; (iii) officer of the Virginia Marine Police; (iv) conservation police officer who is a full-time sworn member of the enforcement division of the Department of Game and Inland Fisheries; (v) investigator who is a full-time sworn member of the security division of the Virginia Lottery; (vi) conservation officer of the Department of Conservation and Recreation commissioned pursuant to <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 10.1-115"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 10.1-115">§ 10.1-115<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000010#     1#          115#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; (vii) full-time sworn member of the enforcement division of the Department of Motor Vehicles appointed pursuant to <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 46.2-217"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 46.2-217">§ 46.2-217<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000046#     2#          217#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; (viii) animal protection police officer employed under <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 15.2-632"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 15.2-632">§ 15.2-632<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000015#     2#          632#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> or 15.2-836.1; (ix) campus police officer appointed under Article 3 (§ 23.1-809 et seq.) of Chapter 8 of Title 23.1; or (x) private police officer employed by a private police department. Part-time employees are those compensated officers who are not full-time employees as defined by the employing police department, sheriff's office, or private police department.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Private police department"</emphasis> means any police department, other than a department that employs police agents under the provisions of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 56-353"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 56 -353">§ 56-353<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#123#000056#       353#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, that employs private police officers operated by an entity authorized by statute or an act of assembly to establish a private police department or such entity's successor in interest, provided it complies with the requirements set forth herein. No entity is authorized to operate a private police department or represent that it is a private police department unless such entity has been authorized by statute or an act of assembly or such entity is the successor in interest of an entity that has been authorized pursuant to this section, provided it complies with the requirements set forth herein. The authority of a private police department shall be limited to real property owned, leased, or controlled by the entity and, if approved by the local chief of police or sheriff, any contiguous property; such authority shall not supersede the authority, duties, or jurisdiction vested by law with the local police department or sheriff's office including as provided in §§ 15.2-1609 and 15.2-1704. The chief of police or sheriff who is the chief local law-enforcement officer shall enter into a memorandum of understanding with the private police department that addresses the duties and responsibilities of the private police department and the chief law-enforcement officer in the conduct of criminal investigations. Private police departments and private police officers shall be subject to and comply with the Constitution of the United States; the Constitution of Virginia; the laws governing municipal police departments, including the provisions of §§ 9.1-600, 15.2-1705 through 15.2-1708, 15.2-1719, 15.2-1721, and 15.2-1722; and any regulations adopted by the Board that the Department designates as applicable to private police departments. Any person employed as a private police officer pursuant to this section shall meet all requirements, including the minimum compulsory training requirements, for law-enforcement officers pursuant to this chapter. A private police officer is not entitled to benefits under the Line of Duty Act (§ 9.1-400 et seq.) or under the Virginia Retirement System, is not a "qualified law enforcement officer" or "qualified retired law enforcement officer" within the meaning of the federal Law Enforcement Officers Safety Act, <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="18 USC 926B"><content><span normalizedCite="18 U.S.C. 926B">18 U.S.C. § 926B<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1828#123#000018#       926b#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> et seq., and shall not be deemed an employee of the Commonwealth or any locality. An authorized private police department may use the word "police" to describe its sworn officers and may join a regional criminal justice academy created pursuant to Article 5 (<citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 15.2-1747"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 15.2-1747">§ 15.2-1747<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000015#     2#         1747#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> et seq.) of Chapter 17 of Title 15.2. Any private police department in existence on January 1, 2013, that was not otherwise established by statute or an act of assembly and whose status as a private police department was recognized by the Department at that time is hereby validated and may continue to operate as a private police department as may such entity's successor in interest, provided it complies with the requirements set forth herein.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"School resource officer"</emphasis> means a certified law-enforcement officer hired by the local law-enforcement agency to provide law-enforcement and security services to Virginia public elementary and secondary schools.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"School security officer"</emphasis> means an individual who is employed by the local school board for the singular purpose of maintaining order and discipline, preventing crime, investigating violations of school board policies, and detaining students violating the law or school board policies on school property or at school-sponsored events and who is responsible solely for ensuring the safety, security, and welfare of all students, faculty, staff, and visitors in the assigned school.</p></bodyText><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p>1981, c. 632, § 9-169; 1982, c. 419; 1983, c. 357; 1984, c. 543; <citation normalizedCite="1989 VA CH 233"><content><span normalizedCite="1989 Va. Ch. 233">1989, c. 233<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1989#000233#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1991 VA CH 338"><content><span normalizedCite="1991 Va. Ch. 338">1991, c. 338<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1991#000338#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1992 VA CH 422"><content><span normalizedCite="1992 Va. Ch. 422">1992, cc. 422<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1992#000422#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1992 VA CH 569"><content><span normalizedCite="1992 Va. Ch. 569">569<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1992#000569#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1993 VA CH 533"><content><span normalizedCite="1993 Va. Ch. 533">1993, cc. 533<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1993#000533#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1993 VA CH 622"><content><span normalizedCite="1993 Va. Ch. 622">622<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1993#000622#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1993 VA CH 866"><content><span normalizedCite="1993 Va. Ch. 866">866<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1993#000866#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2000 VA CH 426"><content><span normalizedCite="2000 Va. Ch. 426">2000, c. 426<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2000#000426#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2001 VA CH 844"><content><span normalizedCite="2001 Va. Ch. 844">2001, c. 844<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2001#000844#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2002 VA CH 789"><content><span normalizedCite="2002 Va. Ch. 789">2002, cc. 789<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2002#000789#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2002 VA CH 836"><content><span normalizedCite="2002 Va. Ch. 836">836<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2002#000836#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2002 VA CH 868"><content><span normalizedCite="2002 Va. Ch. 868">868<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2002#000868#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2003 VA CH 744"><content><span normalizedCite="2003 Va. Ch. 744">2003, cc. 744<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2003#000744#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2003 VA CH 934"><content><span normalizedCite="2003 Va. Ch. 934">934<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2003#000934#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2003 VA CH 937"><content><span normalizedCite="2003 Va. Ch. 937">937<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2003#000937#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2004 VA CH 30"><content><span normalizedCite="2004 Va. Ch. 30">2004, c. 30<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2004#000030#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2005 VA CH 914"><content><span normalizedCite="2005 Va. Ch. 914">2005, c. 914<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2005#000914#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2007 VA CH 87"><content><span normalizedCite="2007 Va. Ch. 87">2007, c. 87<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2007#000087#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2008 VA CH 460"><content><span normalizedCite="2008 Va. Ch. 460">2008, c. 460<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2008#000460#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2010 VA CH 621"><content><span normalizedCite="2010 Va. Ch. 621">2010, c. 621<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2010#000621#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2012 VA CH 776"><content><span normalizedCite="2012 Va. Ch. 776">2012, c. 776<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2012#000776#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2014 VA CH 225"><content><span normalizedCite="2014 Va. Ch. 225">2014, cc. 225<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2014#000225#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2014 VA CH 342"><content><span normalizedCite="2014 Va. Ch. 342">342<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2014#000342#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2014 VA CH 543"><content><span normalizedCite="2014 Va. Ch. 543">543<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2014#000543#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2015 VA CH 38"><content><span normalizedCite="2015 Va. Ch. 38">2015, cc. 38<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2015#000038#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2015 VA CH 195"><content><span normalizedCite="2015 Va. Ch. 195">195<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2015#000195#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2015 VA CH 224"><content><span normalizedCite="2015 Va. Ch. 224">224<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2015#000224#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2015 VA CH 730"><content><span normalizedCite="2015 Va. Ch. 730">730<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2015#000730#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2016 VA CH 498"><content><span normalizedCite="2016 Va. Ch. 498">2016, cc. 498<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2016#000498#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2016 VA CH 618"><content><span normalizedCite="2016 Va. Ch. 618">618<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2016#000618#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PWC0-004G-K30B-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 9.1.</desig><title>COMMONWEALTH PUBLIC SAFETY</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 1.</desig><title>DEPARTMENT OF CRIMINAL JUSTICE SERVICES</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="article"><heading><desig>ARTICLE 1.</desig><title>GENERAL PROVISIONS</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjA4OEVGODBENzY4NDcxM0IyQzA1OTEwQzVDODRBOUE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Q0I0MEM0NzQwMjFGNEU3MzgxMUVEN0IyNzI0RjNGNEE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MkE1OTExQkYxN0UyNDU0NkIxRjRCOTVFM0UwQ0MxMTk</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MzFGQzZBOEY1NkZDNDBFQkE5NkJENDU4QzZCMkQ5ODA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RjM5OTQwMzlEOUNGNDY4OThCRDRFQTkyQkZFMDhBQjk</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Criminal Law &amp; Procedure</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NEU0RkE1OUQwNUQwNDgxODhEODZCMjkzOTg3NThBNzk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Community Confinement</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QzI4Mzk3OTJERjBFNEVEMkJBQjQwRTQzQzU1MEFBODI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QUM4NjRENzc2NUY4NEQwMUEyQTdBNkM4MDhEQURCQjU</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Conditions</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NzY3NkM1QTQ5NTlGNDFGMjlCQzdBNjBBMjQ2NjUyNDI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OUM3MzRDMkUwM0Y3NENCNDk1OEM1OEM2NTE2NjQxODY</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NTdDNkUxRDBFRUY4NDBFNjkyOEEyNTIwQTQ3MUE0NjM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NEE5MkQ0M0FBNzYyNEI4MzgwMjg5MTk5NzNDMzI3ODE</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Education Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDkzNUEzQzFBNEZBNEFBREIxNDM5MTc1MUU5QjI4MTY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RDZGQjQzQzZBMzkwNEZDNzgzRTRBNTBBQTBGNzU5QUE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QUY0N0ZBMDUxNDIxNEVGNTlCQUNBNUY5NDRCNzA2ODI</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Security Personnel</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6M0I0QjcwMDAyNTkxNEM2NTg1RjlCNEU4Q0YwNTVBNzg7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QUY0N0ZBMDUxNDIxNEVGNTlCQUNBNUY5NDRCNzA2ODI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Governments</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjdEQjE4OUJDMzQxNDNEMEI0RTI1QUFCMzJENjEwRTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Employees &amp; Officials</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NzhCNTkxRUNENDI5NDQxMDk3NkNGOTI5REE1RjI0QjM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MkM1MTYwRDE0NkJBNEVFMEIxQjM3RUE2NDRFQUFEODY</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Employees &amp; Officials</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDNCMDQzRTY3RDY3NDNEOEE4RDg2OUFEOTRBNDREQzg7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Njg1MkM3RkYyNzIxNEVFRkJFMTI2NUM4NUU1ODdEM0Q</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Judges</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OTg1QUIzNkIwNzk5NDQ4NzhGMDdDQjVGNEYyRjY5OTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NURENzJGNTEyQzM0NEREQUI2RkVCRTM4RTc1RTZBREU</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Police Power</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MzMzRDQ0NDc5NDEzNEZEMUI2MUFENjIzM0MwMTU5RjA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Njg1MkM3RkYyNzIxNEVFRkJFMTI2NUM4NUU1ODdEM0Q</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Labor &amp; Employment Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MTE3QUQwOTA0MUYzNDlCMEFFMjUwRUNDM0RDRkM5QzM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Definition of Employees</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QUIyNDcxQkExREQ4NDBEMkE1MkRERTE3QkI2RTkzNEY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6M0Y4OTVEMTE3QTc3NDI5QTkwMjMwMkRBNjRBMUM2NkM</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Pensions &amp; Benefits Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QzNEOEE3NjhDNTJBNDhCOTgxRkQzNzc1Q0JCMkU4Q0I7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Police Pensions</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QTU4MjNDOEFCNzc1NDZDQkI1MDE2QjBBM0FGRDMzQjk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NzUzMDgwRDk4QjFDNDBFQUExMUVGQzBCMkNGQzYyNzk</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Torts</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDAwOEM2NTEzQkVDNEI4NzlGMEZERUEyRjQwODM4Njg7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MkQwMTc0MUU5MzkxNEMwQzhEQkU0QjA2REQzQzNGMTc7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RjMzQjNFQ0U1MDdFNEQzMjg0MTA0MTY4MUZCQTZBM0U</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></metadata></legislativeDoc>