<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#349#000054#     1#          118#">Va. Code Ann. § 54.1-118</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_54.1-118"/><heading><desig>§ 54.1-118.</desig><title>Qualifications for licensure, etc.; substantially equivalent military training and education</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a"/><heading><desig>A.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Except as provided in this section, the regulatory boards within the Department of Professional and Occupational Regulation, the Department of Health Professions, or any board named in this title shall accept the military training, education, or experience of a service member honorably discharged from active military service in the armed forces of the United States, to the extent that such training, education, or experience is substantially equivalent to the requirements established by law and regulations of the respective board for the issuance of any license, permit, certificate, or other document, however styled or denominated, required for the practice of any business, profession, or occupation in the Commonwealth. To the extent that the service member's military training, education, or experience, or portion thereof, is not deemed substantially equivalent, the respective board shall credit whatever portion of the military training, education, or experience that is substantially equivalent toward meeting the requirements for the issuance of the license, permit, certificate, or other document.</p><p>The provisions of this subsection shall not apply to the Board of Medicine in the regulation of the practice of medicine or osteopathic medicine. Nor shall this subsection apply to the Board of Dentistry in the regulation of dentists or oral and maxillofacial surgeons.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b"/><heading><desig>B.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The Board of Medicine may accept a service member's military training, education, or experience as an intern or resident in an approved facility to satisfy the requirement of one year of satisfactory postgraduate training as an intern or resident in a hospital or health care facility, provided the applicant for licensure (i) has been honorably discharged from active military service in the armed forces of the United States, (ii) is a graduate of a Board-approved institution, (iii) has successfully completed all required examinations for licensure, and (iv) applies for licensure within six months of discharge from active military service.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c"/><heading><desig>C.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The Board of Dentistry may accept the military training, education, or experience of a service member provided the applicant for licensure (i) has been honorably discharged from active military service in the armed forces of the United States, (ii) has been in continuous clinical practice for four of the six years immediately preceding the application for licensure, (iii) holds a diploma or certificate of a dental program accredited by the Commission on Dental Accreditation of the American Dental Association, and (iv) has successfully completed all required examinations for licensure. Active patient care in the Dental Corps of the United States armed forces, voluntary practice in a public health clinic, or practice in an intern or residency program may be accepted by the Board to satisfy requirements for licensure.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d"/><heading><desig>D.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Any regulatory board may require the service member to provide such documentation of his training, education, or experience as deemed necessary by the board to determine substantial equivalency.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_e"/><heading><desig>E.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> As used in this section, "active military service" means federally funded military duty as (i) a member of the armed forces of the United States on active duty pursuant to Title 10 of the United States Code or (ii) a member of the Virginia National Guard on active duty pursuant to either Title 10 or Title 32 of the United States Code.</p></bodyText></level><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p><citation normalizedCite="2012 VA CH 524"><content><span normalizedCite="2012 Va. Ch. 524">2012, c. 524<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2012#000524#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PVX0-004G-K03X-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 54.1.</desig><title>PROFESSIONS AND OCCUPATIONS</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="subtitle"><heading><desig>SUBTITLE I.</desig><title>GENERAL PROVISIONS RELATING TO REGULATORY BOARDS</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 1.</desig><title>GENERAL PROVISIONS</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Healthcare Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NkUxMkVDQjJDOEY5NDVDQ0E5NTFEMTlDMjIwNzVERjc7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NTVDMzIyNkJCMTRBNDI0NUJBOTlBOTYyMjQ0MDkyODU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QTJGRDdFQzgwODczNDI0NDgwMzEyM0JBOEQ2MUVDNjg</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Personnel Licensing</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6M0VCMTAwM0MwNDA1NEI4OThDNUVEMEIwRTJDQjU2QTM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QTJGRDdFQzgwODczNDI0NDgwMzEyM0JBOEQ2MUVDNjg</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Military &amp; Veterans Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NzM1OUEyRDNERTdENEU2MTk3RTlCNEJCRUY0NjRGRjQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RTkwRDAwRDBEM0NCNDQ2Qzk3QkQzM0VFOTRDQkJGRUU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RDE3QjNGOTc4Mzc2NDNDMjg0RDE5ODIzMkMwM0Y1Qzk</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>US National Guard</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NTkwM0VGNDEwNEJENEExOEJGMzY1NUQxM0MwNzVGQjQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MEZGOTk3QzJDQUY1NDk5MDlDOTI5MDI4NDYxRDU5NjE</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification><classificationGroup classificationScheme="indexing-terms"><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem score="90"><className>Businesses &amp; Corporations</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjA4OEVGODBENzY4NDcxM0IyQzA1OTEwQzVDODRBOUE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></classificationGroup></metadata></legislativeDoc>