<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#349#000038#     2#       3113.3#">Va. Code Ann. § 38.2-3113.3</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_38.2-3113.3"/><heading><desig>§ 38.2-3113.3.</desig><title>Educational loan provisions in life insurance policies</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><bodyText><p>Educational loan provisions may be included as additional benefits, as part of the policy, or as a rider or as a separate agreement, subject to the following requirements:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Any and all necessary eligibility qualifications for an educational loan shall be specified in the life insurance policy, rider or separate agreement. The policy, rider or separate agreement shall also state clearly that the loan will be granted provided the covered individual applying for such loan has satisfied the stated qualifications. Loan eligibility qualifications shall not be more restrictive than the following:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_1_a"/><heading><desig>a.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The loan applicant is a covered individual under the life insurance policy;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_1_b"/><heading><desig>b.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The purpose of the loan is to provide funds for a covered individual under the policy, rider or separate agreement, or the dependent of a covered individual under the policy, rider or separate agreement to attend an institution of higher learning, a trade school or a technical school. As used in this section, an "institution of higher learning" shall not be defined more restrictively than an accredited college or university that is also approved by the United States Department of Education. Age eligibility of the individual for whom the educational loan will be used may be limited to an age range no less restrictive than age fifteen to age twenty-five, subject to continued life insurance coverage of the covered individual during this duration; and</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_1_c"/><heading><desig>c.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The individual for whose education the loan will be used must attend a qualifying institution at least halftime, determined in a manner consistent with the institution's standards for establishing full-time and half-time attendance, and must maintain an academic record sufficient to demonstrate reasonable progression or advancement.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The amount of funds available for an educational loan shall be specified in the policy, rider or separate agreement, and shall be further limited to an amount not to exceed the actual cost of the school or institution during any given year of attendance less other aid received. If the amount available for the educational loan varies by the year of attendance in the school or institution, this shall be so stated and a schedule of annual loan availability by dollar amount shall be included in the policy, rider or separate agreement.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The terms of the loan shall be clearly stated in the policy or rider, or the policy or rider shall refer to the availability of a separate document specifying all loan terms upon request of any insured individual. If the terms of the loan are included in a separate document, such document must be filed with the Commission for review. For purposes of this section, "terms of the loan" include, but are not limited to, (i) any and all fees, charges, and interest rates applied to borrowed funds, including a clear statement concerning possible fluctuation of such fees and charges depending upon the applicant's credit worthiness and/or depending upon any sources or indices used to determine such fees, charges or interest rates, (ii) minimum monthly payments, (iii) maximum amount of years for loan repayment, and (iv) policy assignment, if applicable.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_4"/><heading><desig>4.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Any life insurance policy, rider or separate agreement providing for educational loans shall include a prominent disclosure advising the reader of the prudence of obtaining information about educational loans from a variety of sources before making any decision about borrowing funds for financing higher education.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_5"/><heading><desig>5.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> No policy, rider or separate agreement providing for educational loans shall be delivered or issued for delivery in this Commonwealth unless a copy of the form has been filed with and approved by the Commission in accordance with <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 38.2-316"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 38.2-316">§ 38.2-316<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000038#     2#          316#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>. No advertising material shall be used in the solicitation or promotion of the educational loan feature of a life insurance policy, rider or separate agreement until such material has been filed with and approved by the Commission in the same manner as is required for forms pursuant to <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 38.2-316"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 38.2-316">§ 38.2-316<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000038#     2#          316#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></level></level><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p><citation normalizedCite="2000 VA CH 173"><content><span normalizedCite="2000 Va. Ch. 173">2000, c. 173<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2000#000173#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PV50-004G-K4G3-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 38.2.</desig><title>INSURANCE</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 31.</desig><title>LIFE INSURANCE</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="article"><heading><desig>ARTICLE 1.</desig><title>GENERAL PROVISIONS</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Approval Process</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QzA1NkU5MUJGQzkxNEUyOThEQUY4NkFDMTI1QTMxMTQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NjFGQ0Q3QUZFNUFENEFBMjhGNkE1MUREQzZERUY5RkI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Insurance Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDM4MzQ2QUYzMTY0NDQzQTkxRDQwRUUzRUM5RDg0OEM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Approval Process</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QzA1NkU5MUJGQzkxNEUyOThEQUY4NkFDMTI1QTMxMTQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NjFGQ0Q3QUZFNUFENEFBMjhGNkE1MUREQzZERUY5RkI</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Assignments &amp; Transfers</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NzA3QjYwRTY4QzI2NDgxMkI2MDhFRTFEQkZCNDMzMkU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MzFEOTQ4RjM2RDk4NDJDNEJERDY1NjREOEVGMTRCOTA</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6N0JBNThGMzAzM0Q2NEMyOUJCMTY0N0E2M0NBMzE0MUY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MzFEOTQ4RjM2RDk4NDJDNEJERDY1NjREOEVGMTRCOTA</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RTJENUZEMkQzMzZGNDQ5MDkyNzZGQjk3QUFCNTZDRTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjVCQjlDMTYwQjlFNERDN0FFRTE0RjgxQkI4N0U3RjM</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification><classificationGroup classificationScheme="indexing-terms"><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem score="90"><className>Insurance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDM4MzQ2QUYzMTY0NDQzQTkxRDQwRUUzRUM5RDg0OEM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></classificationGroup></metadata></legislativeDoc>