<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#349#000032#     1#        111.3#">Va. Code Ann. § 32.1-111.3</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_32.1-111.3"/><heading><desig>§ 32.1-111.3.</desig><title>Statewide Emergency Medical Services Plan; Trauma Triage Plan; Stroke Triage Plan</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a"/><heading><desig>A.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The Board of Health shall develop a Statewide Emergency Medical Services Plan that shall provide for a comprehensive, coordinated, emergency medical services system in the Commonwealth and shall review, update, and publish the Plan triennially, making such revisions as may be necessary to improve the effectiveness and efficiency of the Commonwealth's emergency medical services system. The Plan shall incorporate the regional emergency medical services plans prepared by the regional emergency medical services councils pursuant to <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 32.1-111.4:2"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 32.1-111.4:2">§ 32.1-111.4:2.<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#958#0000000032#0000000001#     111.4#0000000002#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> Publishing through electronic means and posting on the Department website shall satisfy the publication requirement. The objectives of such Plan and the emergency medical services system shall include, but not be limited to, the following:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Establishing a comprehensive statewide emergency medical services system, incorporating facilities, transportation, manpower, communications, and other components as integral parts of a unified system that will serve to improve the delivery of emergency medical services and thereby decrease morbidity, hospitalization, disability, and mortality;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Reducing the time period between the identification of an acutely ill or injured patient and the definitive treatment;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Increasing the accessibility of high quality emergency medical services to all citizens of Virginia;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_4"/><heading><desig>4.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Promoting continuing improvement in system components including ground, water, and air transportation; communications; hospital emergency departments and other emergency medical care facilities; health care provider training and health care service delivery; and consumer health information and education;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_5"/><heading><desig>5.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Ensuring performance improvement of the emergency medical services system and emergency medical services and care delivered on scene, in transit, in hospital emergency departments, and within the hospital environment;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_6"/><heading><desig>6.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Working with professional medical organizations, hospitals, and other public and private agencies in developing approaches whereby the many persons who are presently using the existing emergency department for routine, nonurgent, primary medical care will be served more appropriately and economically;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_7"/><heading><desig>7.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Conducting, promoting, and encouraging programs of education and training designed to upgrade the knowledge and skills of emergency medical services personnel, including expanding the availability of paramedic and advanced life support training throughout the Commonwealth with particular emphasis on regions underserved by emergency medical services personnel having such skills and training;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_8"/><heading><desig>8.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Consulting with and reviewing, with agencies and organizations, the development of applications to governmental or other sources for grants or other funding to support emergency medical services programs;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_9"/><heading><desig>9.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Establishing a statewide air medical evacuation system which shall be developed by the Department of Health in coordination with the Department of State Police and other appropriate state agencies;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_10"/><heading><desig>10.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Establishing and maintaining a process for designation of appropriate hospitals as trauma centers and specialty care centers based on an applicable national evaluation system;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_11"/><heading><desig>11.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Maintaining a comprehensive emergency medical services patient care data collection and performance improvement system pursuant to Article 3.1 (<citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 32.1-116.1"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 32.1-116.1">§ 32.1-116.1<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000032#     1#        116.1#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> et seq.);</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_12"/><heading><desig>12.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Collecting data and information and preparing reports for the sole purpose of the designation and verification of trauma centers and other specialty care centers pursuant to this section. All data and information collected shall remain confidential and shall be exempt from the provisions of the Virginia Freedom of Information Act (<citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 2.2-3700"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 2.2-3700">§ 2.2-3700<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000002#     2#         3700#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> et seq.);</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_13"/><heading><desig>13.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Establishing and maintaining a process for crisis intervention and peer support services for emergency medical services personnel and public safety personnel, including statewide availability and accreditation of critical incident stress management teams;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_14"/><heading><desig>14.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Establishing a statewide program of emergency medical services for children to provide coordination and support for emergency pediatric care, availability of pediatric emergency medical care equipment, and pediatric training of health care providers;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_15"/><heading><desig>15.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Establishing and supporting a statewide system of health and medical emergency response teams, including emergency medical services disaster task forces, coordination teams, disaster medical assistance teams, and other support teams that shall assist local emergency medical services agencies at their request during mass casualty, disaster, or whenever local resources are overwhelmed;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_16"/><heading><desig>16.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Establishing and maintaining a program to improve dispatching of emergency medical services personnel and vehicles, including establishment of and support for emergency medical services dispatch training, accreditation of 911 dispatch centers, and public safety answering points;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_17"/><heading><desig>17.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Identifying and establishing best practices for managing and operating emergency medical services agencies, improving and managing emergency medical services response times, and disseminating such information to the appropriate persons and entities;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_18"/><heading><desig>18.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Ensuring that the Department of Criminal Justice Services and the Virginia Criminal Injuries Compensation Fund shall be contacted immediately to deploy assistance in the event there are victims as defined in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 19.2-11.01"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 19.2-11.01">§ 19.2-11.01<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000019#     2#        11.01#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, and that the Department of Criminal Justice Services and the Virginia Criminal Injuries Compensation Fund become the lead coordinating agencies for those individuals determined to be victims; and</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_19"/><heading><desig>19.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Maintaining current contact information for both the Department of Criminal Justice Services and the Virginia Criminal Injuries Compensation Fund.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b"/><heading><desig>B.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The Board of Health shall also develop and maintain as a component of the Emergency Medical Services Plan a statewide prehospital and interhospital Trauma Triage Plan designed to promote rapid access for pediatric and adult trauma patients to appropriate, organized trauma care through the publication and regular updating of information on resources for trauma care and generally accepted criteria for trauma triage and appropriate transfer. The Trauma Triage Plan shall include:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A strategy for maintaining the statewide Trauma Triage Plan through development of regional trauma triage plans that take into account the region's geographic variations and trauma care capabilities and resources, including hospitals designated as trauma centers pursuant to subsection A and inclusion of such regional plans in the statewide Trauma Triage Plan. The regional trauma triage plans shall be reviewed triennially. Plans should ensure that the Department of Criminal Justice Services and the Virginia Criminal Injuries Compensation Fund shall be contacted immediately to deploy assistance in the event there are victims as defined in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 19.2-11.01"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 19.2-11.01">§ 19.2-11.01<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000019#     2#        11.01#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, and that the Department of Criminal Justice Services and the Virginia Criminal Injuries Compensation Fund become the lead coordinating agencies for those individuals determined to be victims; and maintain current contact information for both the Department of Criminal Justice Services and the Virginia Criminal Injuries Compensation Fund.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A uniform set of proposed criteria for prehospital and interhospital triage and transport of trauma patients developed by the Advisory Board, in consultation with the Virginia Chapter of the American College of Surgeons, the Virginia College of Emergency Physicians, the Virginia Hospital and Healthcare Association, and prehospital care providers. The Advisory Board may revise such criteria from time to time to incorporate accepted changes in medical practice or to respond to needs indicated by analyses of data on patient outcomes. Such criteria shall be used as a guide and resource for health care providers and are not intended to establish, in and of themselves, standards of care or to abrogate the requirements of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 8.01-581.20"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 8.01-581.20">§ 8.01-581.20.<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000008#    01#       581.20#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> A decision by a health care provider to deviate from the criteria shall not constitute negligence per se.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A performance improvement program for monitoring the quality of emergency medical services and trauma services, consistent with other components of the Emergency Medical Services Plan. The program shall provide for collection and analysis of data on emergency medical and trauma services from existing validated sources, including the emergency medical services patient care information system, pursuant to Article 3.1 (<citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 32.1-116.1"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 32.1-116.1">§ 32.1-116.1<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000032#     1#        116.1#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> et seq.), the Patient Level Data System, and mortality data. The Advisory Board shall review and analyze such data on a quarterly basis and report its findings to the Commissioner. The Advisory Board may execute these duties through a committee composed of persons having expertise in critical care issues and representatives of emergency medical services providers. The program for monitoring and reporting the results of emergency medical services and trauma services data analysis shall be the sole means of encouraging and promoting compliance with the trauma triage criteria.</p><p><pre/>The Commissioner shall report aggregate findings of the analysis annually to each regional emergency medical services council. The report shall be available to the public and shall identify, minimally, as defined in the statewide plan, the frequency of (i) incorrect triage in comparison to the total number of trauma patients delivered to a hospital prior to pronouncement of death and (ii) incorrect interfacility transfer for each region.</p><p><pre/>The Advisory Board or its designee shall ensure that each hospital director or emergency medical services agency chief is informed of any incorrect interfacility transfer or triage, as defined in the statewide Trauma Triage Plan, specific to the hospital or agency and shall give the hospital or agency an opportunity to correct any facts on which such determination is based, if the hospital or agency asserts that such facts are inaccurate. The findings of the report shall be used to improve the Trauma Triage Plan, including triage, and transport and trauma center designation criteria.</p><p><pre/>The Commissioner shall ensure the confidentiality of patient information, in accordance with <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 32.1-116.2"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 32.1-116.2">§ 32.1-116.2.<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000032#     1#        116.2#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> Such data or information in the possession of or transmitted to the Commissioner, the Advisory Board, any committee acting on behalf of the Advisory Board, any hospital or prehospital care provider, any regional emergency medical services council, emergency medical services agency that holds a valid license issued by the Commissioner, or group or committee established to monitor the quality of emergency medical services or trauma services pursuant to this subdivision, or any other person shall be privileged and shall not be disclosed or obtained by legal discovery proceedings, unless a circuit court, after a hearing and for good cause shown arising from extraordinary circumstances, orders disclosure of such data.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c"/><heading><desig>C.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The Board shall also develop and maintain as a component of the Statewide Emergency Medical Services Plan a statewide prehospital and interhospital Stroke Triage Plan designed to promote rapid access for stroke patients to appropriate, organized stroke care through the publication and regular updating of information on resources for stroke care and generally accepted criteria for stroke triage and appropriate transfer. The Stroke Triage Plan shall include:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A strategy for maintaining the statewide Stroke Triage Plan through development of regional stroke triage plans that take into account the region's geographic variations and stroke care capabilities and resources, including hospitals designated as "primary stroke centers" through certification by the Joint Commission, DNV Healthcare, or a comparable process consistent with the recommendations of the Brain Attack Coalition, and inclusion of such regional plans in the statewide Stroke Triage Plan. The regional stroke triage plans shall be reviewed triennially.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A uniform set of proposed criteria for prehospital and interhospital triage and transport of stroke patients developed by the Advisory Board, in consultation with the American Stroke Association, the Virginia College of Emergency Physicians, the Virginia Hospital and Healthcare Association, and prehospital care providers. The Board may revise such criteria from time to time to incorporate accepted changes in medical practice or to respond to needs indicated by analyses of data on patient outcomes. Such criteria shall be used as a guide and resource for health care providers and are not intended to establish, in and of themselves, standards of care or to abrogate the requirements of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 8.01-581.20"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 8.01-581.20">§ 8.01-581.20.<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000008#    01#       581.20#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> A decision by a health care provider to deviate from the criteria shall not constitute negligence per se.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d"/><heading><desig>D.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Whenever any state-owned aircraft, vehicle, or other form of conveyance is utilized under the provisions of this section, an appropriate amount not to exceed the actual costs of operation may be charged by the agency having administrative control of such aircraft, vehicle, or other form of conveyance.</p></bodyText></level><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p><citation normalizedCite="1996 VA CH 899"><content><span normalizedCite="1996 Va. Ch. 899">1996, c. 899<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1996#000899#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1997 VA CH 321"><content><span normalizedCite="1997 Va. Ch. 321">1997, c. 321<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1997#000321#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1998 VA CH 317"><content><span normalizedCite="1998 Va. Ch. 317">1998, c. 317<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1998#000317#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1999 VA CH 1000"><content><span normalizedCite="1999 Va. Ch. 1000">1999, c. 1000<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1999#001000#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2005 VA CH 632"><content><span normalizedCite="2005 Va. Ch. 632">2005, cc. 632<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2005#000632#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2005 VA CH 686"><content><span normalizedCite="2005 Va. Ch. 686">686<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2005#000686#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2006 VA CH 412"><content><span normalizedCite="2006 Va. Ch. 412">2006, c. 412<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2006#000412#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2007 VA CH 15"><content><span normalizedCite="2007 Va. Ch. 15">2007, c. 15<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2007#000015#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2008 VA CH 66"><content><span normalizedCite="2008 Va. Ch. 66">2008, cc. 66<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2008#000066#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2008 VA CH 567"><content><span normalizedCite="2008 Va. Ch. 567">567<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2008#000567#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2009 VA CH 222"><content><span normalizedCite="2009 Va. Ch. 222">2009, cc. 222<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2009#000222#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2009 VA CH 269"><content><span normalizedCite="2009 Va. Ch. 269">269<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2009#000269#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2012 VA CH 418"><content><span normalizedCite="2012 Va. Ch. 418">2012, c. 418<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2012#000418#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2014 VA CH 320"><content><span normalizedCite="2014 Va. Ch. 320">2014, c. 320<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2014#000320#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2015 VA CH 502"><content><span normalizedCite="2015 Va. Ch. 502">2015, cc. 502<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2015#000502#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2015 VA CH 503"><content><span normalizedCite="2015 Va. Ch. 503">503<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2015#000503#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PV10-004G-K1GC-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 32.1.</desig><title>HEALTH</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 4.</desig><title>HEALTH CARE PLANNING</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="article"><heading><desig>ARTICLE 2.1.</desig><title>STATEWIDE EMERGENCY MEDICAL SERVICES SYSTEM AND SERVICES</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Accreditation</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MzkwMTVGOURFMEQ2NEY2NkIyNjA2MzhGM0Q3QUQ5QzA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MkIwM0E1RTM4NkY5NEU4QjhBM0RCNzc5QjE4RkIzOEI</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Electronic Publishing</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6N0ZBQkI2RThFQ0Y2NDFFNzk0MzQ1MkI0REVDNTVBNzU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6M0E5MjdDNDRFRUIzNEJFNDkyMDk5MThGNTE5M0RFNEU</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Civil Procedure</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MzUxNjJDMEQ5N0YwNDMzM0JDMjEzM0UzOTYzMzI3OTU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RURENTNCNzNFMkUyNDk4MkIxNDg3QzMxMDY3QUQyQTE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6REQ5NjdFN0M2ODlFNDVCMUEwRTRCMjQyNkNEREMyNDI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Communications Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MEQxMkU0NzE2OEE2NDIxNEE3QzU0NjU2MDRERUNGNDE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Electronic Publishing</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6N0ZBQkI2RThFQ0Y2NDFFNzk0MzQ1MkI0REVDNTVBNzU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6M0E5MjdDNDRFRUIzNEJFNDkyMDk5MThGNTE5M0RFNEU</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Criminal Law &amp; Procedure</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NEU0RkE1OUQwNUQwNDgxODhEODZCMjkzOTg3NThBNzk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Information From Others</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MEZFQTg4NUE3OUYyNDE2N0E2OURFODY0NzgyN0FFNjY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RDQ4NjQ0QTc1OTczNDkyMTlEQjgxNDg0NENCMEE1N0U</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Family Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NEI4M0U5Qzg3RTk0NDdBRUJGNDRGNkZEQkU3RDdFNDU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Medical Support</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NjAwMkI1RjgzNjE3NENGMkI5OTBGQzg0RTMzQjM5RjQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NjYxMTA0Qjg0NkVENEU2M0I4RTk2MTMzMDg4RTM4OEY</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Healthcare Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NkUxMkVDQjJDOEY5NDVDQ0E5NTFEMTlDMjIwNzVERjc7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Accreditation</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MzkwMTVGOURFMEQ2NEY2NkIyNjA2MzhGM0Q3QUQ5QzA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MkIwM0E1RTM4NkY5NEU4QjhBM0RCNzc5QjE4RkIzOEI</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MkM0RjM1NjlERDhBNDk2Q0I2RTZCOEIxM0Y0MjI0RDE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NTg4RTkyNjk5MUY0NEU4Q0FBMDg2MzI1ODBCRUQ3OEY</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Public Health &amp; Welfare Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDYwRTY1MDg3MTk5NDUyNkFFRDI1RjJBRERGQ0UxNzI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NEE2Q0JCMzAwMTExNEU4QjlDNTJFODAwNzYyOThFRTc7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NjhBRDBBMTY1RjVDNEI5Q0E5QjNDOTcyNDY2NjU3MUM</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RjM3NDdEQTcwRDVENDFENEI4QUJFMzQ5NzVGMTE1RDA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6REY3QUUxQ0YxMDFENEE3MTg3QTU4QTdBNkRGMEVCMDc</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Torts</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDAwOEM2NTEzQkVDNEI4NzlGMEZERUEyRjQwODM4Njg7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QkQyODcyODZCNzg5NDIyNkEwRDRCQTMzOTY0MkRFQzU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NzIyMDg2OUYzNTJCNEFCNUI0QjEwRDc5RDc4QUVFMDI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification><classificationGroup classificationScheme="indexing-terms"><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem score="90"><className>Healthcare</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NkUxMkVDQjJDOEY5NDVDQ0E5NTFEMTlDMjIwNzVERjc7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></classificationGroup></metadata></legislativeDoc>