<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#349#000015#     2#         2242#">Va. Code Ann. § 15.2-2242</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_15.2-2242"/><heading><desig>§ 15.2-2242.</desig><title>Optional provisions of a subdivision ordinance</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><bodyText><p>A subdivision ordinance may include:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Provisions for variations in or exceptions to the general regulations of the subdivision ordinance in cases of unusual situations or when strict adherence to the general regulations would result in substantial injustice or hardship.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A requirement (i) for the furnishing of a preliminary opinion from the applicable health official regarding the suitability of a subdivision for installation of subsurface sewage disposal systems where such method of sewage disposal is to be utilized in the development of a subdivision and (ii) that all buildings constructed on lots resulting from subdivision of a larger tract that abuts or adjoins a public water or sewer system or main shall be connected to that public water or sewer system or main subject to the provisions of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 15.2-2121"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 15.2-2121">§ 15.2-2121<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000015#     2#         2121#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A requirement that, in the event streets in a subdivision will not be constructed to meet the standards necessary for inclusion in the secondary system of state highways or for state street maintenance moneys paid to municipalities, the subdivision plat and all approved deeds of subdivision, or similar instruments, must contain a statement advising that the streets in the subdivision do not meet state standards and will not be maintained by the Department of Transportation or the localities enacting the ordinances. Grantors of any subdivision lots to which such statement applies must include the statement on each deed of conveyance thereof. However, localities in their ordinances may establish minimum standards for construction of streets that will not be built to state standards.</p><p><pre/>For streets constructed or to be constructed, as provided for in this subsection, a subdivision ordinance may require that the same procedure be followed as that set forth in provision 5 of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 15.2-2241"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 15.2-2241">§ 15.2-2241<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000015#     2#         2241#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>. Further, the subdivision ordinance may provide that the developer's financial commitment shall continue until such time as the local government releases such financial commitment in accordance with provision 11 of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 15.2-2241"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 15.2-2241">§ 15.2-2241<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000015#     2#         2241#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_4"/><heading><desig>4.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Reasonable provision for the voluntary funding of off-site road improvements and reimbursements of advances by the governing body. If a subdivider or developer makes an advance of payments for or construction of reasonable and necessary road improvements located outside the property limits of the land owned or controlled by him, the need for which is substantially generated and reasonably required by the construction or improvement of his subdivision or development, and such advance is accepted, the governing body may agree to reimburse the subdivider or developer from such funds as the governing body may make available for such purpose from time to time for the cost of such advance together with interest, which shall be excludable from gross income for federal income tax purposes, at a rate equal to the rate of interest on bonds most recently issued by the governing body on the following terms and conditions:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_4_a"/><heading><desig>a.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The governing body shall determine or confirm that the road improvements were substantially generated and reasonably required by the construction or improvement of the subdivision or development and shall determine or confirm the cost thereof, on the basis of a study or studies conducted by qualified traffic engineers and approved and accepted by the subdivider or developer.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_4_b"/><heading><desig>b.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The governing body shall prepare, or cause to be prepared, a report accepted and approved by the subdivider or developer, indicating the governmental services required to be furnished to the subdivision or development and an estimate of the annual cost thereof for the period during which the reimbursement is to be made to the subdivider or developer.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_4_c"/><heading><desig>c.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The governing body may make annual reimbursements to the subdivider or developer from funds made available for such purpose from time to time, including but not limited to real estate taxes assessed and collected against the land and improvements on the property included in the subdivision or development in amounts equal to the amount by which such real estate taxes exceed the annual cost of providing reasonable and necessary governmental services to such subdivision or development.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_5"/><heading><desig>5.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> In Arlington County, Fairfax County, Loudoun County, and Prince William County, in any town located within such counties, in Bedford County, Pittsylvania County, Spotsylvania County, and Stafford County, or in the Cities of Alexandria, Fairfax, Falls Church, Hampton, Manassas, and Manassas Park, provisions for payment by a subdivider or developer of land of a pro rata share of the cost of reasonable and necessary road improvements, located outside the property limits of the land owned or controlled by him but serving an area having related traffic needs to which his subdivision or development will contribute, to reimburse an initial subdivider or developer who has advanced such costs or constructed such road improvements. Such ordinance may apply to road improvements constructed after July 1, 1988, in Fairfax County; in Arlington County, Loudoun County, and Prince William County, in any town located within such counties, in Bedford County, Pittsylvania County, Spotsylvania County, and Stafford County, or in the Cities of Alexandria, Fairfax, Falls Church, Hampton, Manassas, and Manassas Park, such ordinance may only apply to road improvements constructed after the effective date of such ordinance.</p><p><pre/>Such provisions shall provide for the adoption of a pro rata reimbursement plan which shall include reasonable standards to identify the area having related traffic needs, to determine the total estimated or actual cost of road improvements required to adequately serve the area when fully developed in accordance with the comprehensive plan or as required by proffered conditions, and to determine the proportionate share of such costs to be reimbursed by each subsequent subdivider or developer within the area, with interest (i) at the legal rate or (ii) at an inflation rate prescribed by a generally accepted index of road construction costs, whichever is less.</p><p><pre/>For any subdivision ordinance adopted pursuant to provision 5 of this section after February 1, 1993, no such payment shall be assessed or imposed upon a subsequent developer or subdivider if (i) prior to the adoption of a pro rata reimbursement plan the subsequent subdivider or developer has proffered conditions pursuant to <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 15.2-2303"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 15.2-2303">§ 15.2-2303<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000015#     2#         2303#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> for offsite road improvements and such proffered conditions have been accepted by the locality, (ii) the locality has assessed or imposed an impact fee on the subsequent development or subdivision pursuant to Article 8 (<citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 15.2-2317"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 15.2-2317">§ 15.2-2317<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000015#     2#         2317#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> et seq.) of Chapter 22, or (iii) the subsequent subdivider or developer has received final site plan, subdivision plan, or plan of development approval from the locality prior to the adoption of a pro rata reimbursement plan for the area having related traffic needs.</p><p><pre/>The amount of the costs to be reimbursed by a subsequent developer or subdivider shall be determined before or at the time the site plan or subdivision is approved. The ordinance shall specify that such costs are to be collected at the time of the issuance of a temporary or final certificate of occupancy or functional use and occupancy within the development, whichever shall come first. The ordinance also may provide that the required reimbursement may be paid (i) in lump sum, (ii) by agreement of the parties on installment at a reasonable rate of interest or rate of inflation, whichever is less, for a fixed number of years, or (iii) on such terms as otherwise agreed to by the initial and subsequent subdividers and developers.</p><p><pre/>Such ordinance provisions may provide that no certificate of occupancy shall be issued to a subsequent developer or subdivider until (i) the initial developer certifies to the locality that the subsequent developer has made the required reimbursement directly to him as provided above or (ii) the subsequent developer has deposited the reimbursement amount with the locality for transfer forthwith to the initial developer.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_6"/><heading><desig>6.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Provisions for establishing and maintaining access to solar energy to encourage the use of solar heating and cooling devices in new subdivisions. The provisions shall be applicable to a new subdivision only when so requested by the subdivider.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_7"/><heading><desig>7.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Provisions, in any town with a population between 14,500 and 15,000, granting authority to the governing body, in its discretion, to use funds escrowed pursuant to provision 5 of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 15.2-2241"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 15.2-2241">§ 15.2-2241<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000015#     2#         2241#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> for improvements similar to but other than those for which the funds were escrowed, if the governing body (i) obtains the written consent of the owner or developer who submitted the escrowed funds; (ii) finds that the facilities for which funds are escrowed are not immediately required; (iii) releases the owner or developer from liability for the construction or for the future cost of constructing those improvements for which the funds were escrowed; and (iv) accepts liability for future construction of these improvements. If such town fails to locate such owner or developer after making a reasonable attempt to do so, the town may proceed as if such consent had been granted. In addition, the escrowed funds to be used for such other improvement may only come from an escrow that does not exceed a principal amount of $ 30,000 plus any accrued interest and shall have been escrowed for at least five years.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_8"/><heading><desig>8.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Provisions for clustering of single-family dwellings and preservation of open space developments, which provisions shall comply with the requirements and procedures set forth in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 15.2-2286.1"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 15.2-2286.1">§ 15.2-2286.1.<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000015#     2#       2286.1#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation></p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_9"/><heading><desig>9.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Provisions requiring that where a lot being subdivided or developed fronts on an existing street, and adjacent property on either side has an existing sidewalk, a locality may require the dedication of land for, and construction of, a sidewalk on the property being subdivided or developed, to connect to the existing sidewalk. Nothing in this paragraph shall alter in any way any authority of localities or the Department of Transportation to require sidewalks on any newly constructed street or highway.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_10"/><heading><desig>10.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Provisions for requiring and considering Phase I environmental site assessments based on the anticipated use of the property proposed for the subdivision or development that meet generally accepted national standards for such assessments, such as those developed by the American Society for Testing and Materials, and Phase II environmental site assessments, that also meet accepted national standards, such as, but not limited to, those developed by the American Society for Testing and Materials, if the locality deems such to be reasonably necessary, based on findings in the Phase I assessment, and in accordance with regulations of the United States Environmental Protection Agency and the American Society for Testing and Materials. A reasonable fee may be charged for the review of such environmental assessments. Such fees shall not exceed an amount commensurate with the services rendered, taking into consideration the time, skill, and administrative expense involved in such review.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_11"/><heading><desig>11.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Provisions for requiring disclosure and remediation of contamination and other adverse environmental conditions of the property prior to approval of subdivision and development plans.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_12"/><heading><desig>12.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Provisions, in any town located in the Northern Virginia Transportation District, granting authority to the governing body to require the dedication of land for sidewalk, curb, and gutter improvements on the property being subdivided or developed if the property is designated for such improvements on the locality's adopted pedestrian plan.</p></bodyText></level></level><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p>Code 1950, §§ 15-781, 15-967.1; 1950, p. 183; 1962, c. 407, § 15.1-466; 1970, c. 436; 1973, cc. 169, 480; 1975, c. 641; 1976, c. 270; 1978, cc. 429, 439, 440; 1979, cc. 183, 188, 395; 1980, cc. 379, 381; 1981, c. 348; 1983, cc. 167, 609; 1984, c. 111; 1985, cc. 422, 455; 1986, c. 54; 1987, c. 717; 1988, cc. 279, 735; <citation normalizedCite="1989 VA CH 332"><content><span normalizedCite="1989 Va. Ch. 332">1989, cc. 332<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1989#000332#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1989 VA CH 393"><content><span normalizedCite="1989 Va. Ch. 393">393<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1989#000393#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1989 VA CH 403"><content><span normalizedCite="1989 Va. Ch. 403">403<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1989#000403#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1989 VA CH 495"><content><span normalizedCite="1989 Va. Ch. 495">495<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1989#000495#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1990 VA CH 170"><content><span normalizedCite="1990 Va. Ch. 170">1990, cc. 170<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1990#000170#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1990 VA CH 176"><content><span normalizedCite="1990 Va. Ch. 176">176<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1990#000176#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1990 VA CH 287"><content><span normalizedCite="1990 Va. Ch. 287">287<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1990#000287#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1990 VA CH 708"><content><span normalizedCite="1990 Va. Ch. 708">708<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1990#000708#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1990 VA CH 973"><content><span normalizedCite="1990 Va. Ch. 973">973<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1990#000973#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1991 VA CH 30"><content><span normalizedCite="1991 Va. Ch. 30">1991, cc. 30<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1991#000030#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1991 VA CH 47"><content><span normalizedCite="1991 Va. Ch. 47">47<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1991#000047#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1991 VA CH 288"><content><span normalizedCite="1991 Va. Ch. 288">288<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1991#000288#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1991 VA CH 538"><content><span normalizedCite="1991 Va. Ch. 538">538<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1991#000538#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1992 VA CH 380"><content><span normalizedCite="1992 Va. Ch. 380">1992, c. 380<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1992#000380#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1993 VA CH 836"><content><span normalizedCite="1993 Va. Ch. 836">1993, cc. 836<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1993#000836#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1993 VA CH 846"><content><span normalizedCite="1993 Va. Ch. 846">846<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1993#000846#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1993 VA CH 864"><content><span normalizedCite="1993 Va. Ch. 864">864<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1993#000864#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1994 VA CH 421"><content><span normalizedCite="1994 Va. Ch. 421">1994, c. 421<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1994#000421#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1995 VA CH 386"><content><span normalizedCite="1995 Va. Ch. 386">1995, cc. 386<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1995#000386#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1995 VA CH 388"><content><span normalizedCite="1995 Va. Ch. 388">388<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1995#000388#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1995 VA CH 389"><content><span normalizedCite="1995 Va. Ch. 389">389<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1995#000389#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1995 VA CH 452"><content><span normalizedCite="1995 Va. Ch. 452">452<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1995#000452#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1995 VA CH 457"><content><span normalizedCite="1995 Va. Ch. 457">457<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1995#000457#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1995 VA CH 474"><content><span normalizedCite="1995 Va. Ch. 474">474<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1995#000474#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1996 VA CH 77"><content><span normalizedCite="1996 Va. Ch. 77">1996, cc. 77<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1996#000077#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1996 VA CH 325"><content><span normalizedCite="1996 Va. Ch. 325">325<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1996#000325#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1996 VA CH 452"><content><span normalizedCite="1996 Va. Ch. 452">452<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1996#000452#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1996 VA CH 456"><content><span normalizedCite="1996 Va. Ch. 456">456<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1996#000456#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1997 VA CH 587"><content><span normalizedCite="1997 Va. Ch. 587">1997, c. 587<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1997#000587#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2000 VA CH 652"><content><span normalizedCite="2000 Va. Ch. 652">2000, cc. 652<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2000#000652#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2000 VA CH 711"><content><span normalizedCite="2000 Va. Ch. 711">711<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2000#000711#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2002 VA CH 703"><content><span normalizedCite="2002 Va. Ch. 703">2002, c. 703<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2002#000703#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2005 VA CH 567"><content><span normalizedCite="2005 Va. Ch. 567">2005, c. 567<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2005#000567#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2006 VA CH 421"><content><span normalizedCite="2006 Va. Ch. 421">2006, cc. 421<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2006#000421#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2006 VA CH 514"><content><span normalizedCite="2006 Va. Ch. 514">514<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2006#000514#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2006 VA CH 533"><content><span normalizedCite="2006 Va. Ch. 533">533<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2006#000533#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2006 VA CH 903"><content><span normalizedCite="2006 Va. Ch. 903">903<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2006#000903#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2007 VA CH 813"><content><span normalizedCite="2007 Va. Ch. 813">2007, c. 813<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2007#000813#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2014 VA CH 619"><content><span normalizedCite="2014 Va. Ch. 619">2014, c. 619<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2014#000619#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PV20-004G-K2G5-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 15.2.</desig><title>COUNTIES, CITIES AND TOWNS</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="subtitle"><heading><desig>SUBTITLE II.</desig><title>POWERS OF LOCAL GOVERNMENT</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 22.</desig><title>PLANNING, SUBDIVISION OF LAND AND ZONING</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="article"><heading><desig>ARTICLE 6.</desig><title>LAND SUBDIVISION AND DEVELOPMENT</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Comprehensive &amp; General Plans</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RDQ4MjdBMDYzNTJCNENGRjlEQjI1MzI3NEM3ODdFMDQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6REM3NjlCMTNCRkNCNDc1Mzk5MzlGNjBBN0I2N0NENDU</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Energy &amp; Utilities Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OUUzODAyRDk1QzVFNEZGMEJDM0RGMDYxOTlEMEEzRDA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Solar Power Industry</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDlCOTMzNzhGREJBNDJENEEyM0ZGMjVFODI5Nzc4NTE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OUUzODAyRDk1QzVFNEZGMEJDM0RGMDYxOTlEMEEzRDA</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Environmental Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NzFDRDYyNkI2QjhBNDg3NTkyRjRDRkZEQjlCRkRBQzM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Comprehensive &amp; General Plans</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RDQ4MjdBMDYzNTJCNENGRjlEQjI1MzI3NEM3ODdFMDQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6REM3NjlCMTNCRkNCNDc1Mzk5MzlGNjBBN0I2N0NENDU</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MkJDMzEzRDkxMDVBNDA3N0FDRjNDODI2NUIzMzZDMDQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjI3QUU4NUZEQzZFNEYzRThENkZBRTA1MkUyQTAwQTA</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Governments</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjdEQjE4OUJDMzQxNDNEMEI0RTI1QUFCMzJENjEwRTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Bridges &amp; Roads</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RTBBOTc0NTk5Nzg4NEM4MEI5REUxMTc4OEY4RDIwQzA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MEY3NUIxODI2RjU2NEY0NzgwMDQyNjFDMEQ1QUExRjM</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Finance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjMzOTBBRTg2MUVDNDdDNUE1M0QxNDk1RERCNjNCN0I7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Njg1MkM3RkYyNzIxNEVFRkJFMTI2NUM4NUU1ODdEM0Q</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Financing</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Q0QyN0IxRDI1MTE0NDQ3NkEzMzZCMTBCMkE2QkM3RTM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MEY3NUIxODI2RjU2NEY0NzgwMDQyNjFDMEQ1QUExRjM</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Sanitation &amp; Water</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NUJBQUJCRjYwQjU5NDg3RkI5RjBBMjZENTZDMkM2QzA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MEY3NUIxODI2RjU2NEY0NzgwMDQyNjFDMEQ1QUExRjM</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Real Property Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QUUyRTcxRURBNEY2NEE2MDk3QzBCNzRDOEY0NTZDQzk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Construction Loans</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RDNGMDlENjQ4NUYyNEM0MEIxRTAwMjAyRTdFRUNBRkY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MTY1MzRERDhBMDZCNDFBMDk0QUEwRjcyN0ZFNEY3REM</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Elements</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MTJGNkEyOEUzOUFFNEE4NTkzQjg1RDIyNTU4Njg4RUM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjRCMUU0RUM1REQ2NDYyMDk1Qjc2QzYzNDg1RjgxNDg</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Escrow</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6N0NCMUM2OTRDMUZENDlDMTk2OUM0NEMyRjVCNjUwQjI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NzNFRkY2MkZBNjVCNDE1NEE4NEE5NUU4NTlCNTFCQjM</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NzIxOUEwNTk5MTZCNEM3ODgxNjAzMkQ3MzIxMzQ1OUE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Nzg5NTlBMjdCREU3NDE1OTg1QjFCODExQkZENkM1Nzk</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Impact Fees</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6M0RCOTBBQjUwOTg4NEE0OThDODM4MTU3OUUyNDFEREM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NjcyQTdEMEUxODYyNDY0OThFQTg1NUNGMjFBMTkxQ0M</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Local Regulations</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NUE4NDYxMTk4MEI0NDlDODgyODIxNzBDMjAyOTZENkM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Nzg5NTlBMjdCREU3NDE1OTg1QjFCODExQkZENkM1Nzk</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Procedure</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RkYxQjZBMjExMjlDNDQ4M0EwMTgwODNGQjE0RUJERUY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjRCMUU0RUM1REQ2NDYyMDk1Qjc2QzYzNDg1RjgxNDg</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Tax Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OTNEM0E2OEE0RkQyNEY1MDhBQzdGMkQ4ODI4QTJDODE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6ODYxQ0YyQUI2ODA2NEMxQUI5RjMxRUVERjlFRDUzMTg7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QTYyMTM4M0E1MTQ1NDY3MUIxN0RBNjQwMjc2NTY3Qzc</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MEMzQzdEM0Q2NEEyNDg5RDhDMEE3NDAwMDNGOUU2MkM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MEI0QjM4RDg1M0IxNDk1RDkwOTVGMEMxRTQxQTg1ODU</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RTc0QzJDRUM0OTI1NDkyQTgyQzExM0RFMDAwRTAzOEI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RUE2N0VFNDM5OUY4NENCQjlDQjQ1NjdGMkU4NkFFREQ</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Transportation Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RTYzRTk5RDVBQkQ2NDcwQzk2NTU3ODQ5OEE3NDlBNzk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Funding</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QTFFNkIxMEVFQTA2NERDMDhDRUUwNUY2NEQ4MTYyOUM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjVCODE3RDNEMENDNDkxRjg5MzBBNTJFQkNCRDlFOEU</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NTkyRUE5REJENDMwNDE4OTg3OTg5NTg0OEVEOUE3M0E7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjVCODE3RDNEMENDNDkxRjg5MzBBNTJFQkNCRDlFOEU</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification><classificationGroup classificationScheme="indexing-terms"><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem score="90"><className>Governments</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjdEQjE4OUJDMzQxNDNEMEI0RTI1QUFCMzJENjEwRTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></classificationGroup></metadata></legislativeDoc>