<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#349#000015#     2#         2644#">Va. Code Ann. § 15.2-2644</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_15.2-2644"/><heading><desig>§ 15.2-2644.</desig><title>Issuance or exchange for indebtedness to be retired; sale and disposition of proceeds; rights of owners</title></heading><bodyText><p>Any refunding bonds may be issued or exchanged for the indebtedness to be retired by them, including indebtedness not matured, redeemable or surrendered for retirement. Unless so exchanged, any locality may sell refunding bonds authorized under the provisions of this article in such manner, either at public or private sale, and for such price as the governing body of the locality may determine. The proceeds of any refunding bonds may be applied to (i) the payment of matured or redeemable indebtedness, including any redemption premium, (ii) the payment of unmatured indebtedness the evidences of which are on deposit with a bank or trust company designated by the locality for surrender to the locality upon receipt of payment in an amount not exceeding the amount of the indebtedness, or (iii) the establishment of an escrow or sinking fund consisting of cash and noncallable obligations of, or unconditionally guaranteed by, the United States of America or noncallable obligations of, or unconditionally guaranteed by, the Commonwealth in an amount which together with interest to be earned on such obligations shall be sufficient to pay all indebtedness to be refunded either at maturity or upon redemption as provided for upon the creation of the escrow or sinking fund. Any escrow or sinking fund established, in whole or in part, from the proceeds of the sale of refunding bonds shall be irrevocably pledged to the payment of the indebtedness to be refunded and shall be used solely to pay the indebtedness at maturity or upon redemption or for the purchase of not less than all of the indebtedness to be refunded. It is the intent that any escrow or sinking fund established pursuant to this section shall constitute a special fund for the payment of the refunded indebtedness and that the refunded indebtedness shall not be included for the purpose of determining any limitation upon the amount of indebtedness of the locality which is imposed by law.</p><p>The owners of any outstanding indebtedness to be refunded shall be divested of all rights and security relating to the indebtedness, except the right to payment when due of principal, premium, if any, and interest, which shall be paid solely from the escrow or sinking fund; provided that, in the case of debt issued before March 27, 1977, the governing body of the locality may provide that if the escrow or sinking fund is in any respect insufficient to make payment of principal, premium, if any, and interest, the original rights and security relating to the indebtedness shall be restored to the extent necessary to provide full payment.</p></bodyText><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p>Code 1950, § 15-666.34; 1958, c. 640; 1962, c. 623, § 15.1-193; 1977, c. 442; 1985, c. 196; <citation normalizedCite="1991 VA CH 668"><content><span normalizedCite="1991 Va. Ch. 668">1991, c. 668<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1991#000668#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, § 15.1-227.45; <citation normalizedCite="1994 VA CH 714"><content><span normalizedCite="1994 Va. Ch. 714">1994, c. 714<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1994#000714#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1997 VA CH 587"><content><span normalizedCite="1997 Va. Ch. 587">1997, c. 587<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1997#000587#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PSK0-004G-K2Y4-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 15.2.</desig><title>COUNTIES, CITIES AND TOWNS</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="subtitle"><heading><desig>SUBTITLE II.</desig><title>POWERS OF LOCAL GOVERNMENT</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 26.</desig><title>PUBLIC FINANCE ACT</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="article"><heading><desig>ARTICLE 5.</desig><title>REFUNDING BONDS</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Governments</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjdEQjE4OUJDMzQxNDNEMEI0RTI1QUFCMzJENjEwRTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Finance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjMzOTBBRTg2MUVDNDdDNUE1M0QxNDk1RERCNjNCN0I7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Njg1MkM3RkYyNzIxNEVFRkJFMTI2NUM4NUU1ODdEM0Q</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification><classificationGroup classificationScheme="indexing-terms"><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem score="90"><className>Governments</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjdEQjE4OUJDMzQxNDNEMEI0RTI1QUFCMzJENjEwRTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></classificationGroup></metadata></legislativeDoc>