<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#123#000044#    146.18#">Va. Code Ann. § 44-146.18</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_44-146.18"/><heading><desig>§ 44-146.18.</desig><title>Department of Emergency Services continued as Department of Emergency Management; administration and operational control; coordinator and other personnel; powers and duties</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a"/><heading><desig>A.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The State Office of Emergency Services is continued and shall hereafter be known as the Department of Emergency Management. Wherever the words "State Department of Emergency Services" are used in any law of the Commonwealth, they shall mean the Department of Emergency Management. During a declared emergency this Department shall revert to the operational control of the Governor. The Department shall have a coordinator who shall be appointed by and serve at the pleasure of the Governor and also serve as State Emergency Planning Director. The Department shall employ the professional, technical, secretarial, and clerical employees necessary for the performance of its functions.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b"/><heading><desig>B.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The Department of Emergency Management shall in the administration of emergency services and disaster preparedness programs:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> In coordination with political subdivisions and state agencies, ensure that the Commonwealth has up-to-date assessments and preparedness plans to prevent, respond to and recover from all disasters including acts of terrorism;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Conduct a statewide emergency management assessment in cooperation with political subdivisions, private industry and other public and private entities deemed vital to preparedness, public safety and security. The assessment shall include a review of emergency response plans, which include the variety of hazards, natural and man-made. The assessment shall be updated annually;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Submit to the Governor and to the General Assembly, no later than the first day of each regular session of the General Assembly, an annual executive summary and report on the status of emergency management response plans throughout the Commonwealth and other measures taken or recommended to prevent, respond to and recover from disasters, including acts of terrorism. This report shall be made available to the Division of Legislative Automated Systems for the processing of legislative documents and reports. Information submitted in accordance with the procedures set forth in subdivision 4 of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 2.2-3705.2"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 2.2-3705.2">§ 2.2-3705.2<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000002#     2#       3705.2#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> shall not be disclosed unless:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_3_a"/><heading><desig>a.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> It is requested by law-enforcement authorities in furtherance of an official investigation or the prosecution of a criminal act;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_3_b"/><heading><desig>b.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The agency holding the record is served with a proper judicial order; or</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_3_c"/><heading><desig>c.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The agency holding the record has obtained written consent to release the information from the Department of Emergency Management;</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_4"/><heading><desig>4.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Promulgate plans and programs that are conducive to adequate disaster mitigation preparedness, response and recovery programs;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_5"/><heading><desig>5.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Prepare and maintain a State Emergency Operations Plan for disaster response and recovery operations that assigns primary and support responsibilities for basic emergency services functions to state agencies, organizations and personnel as appropriate;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_6"/><heading><desig>6.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Coordinate and administer disaster mitigation, preparedness, response and recovery plans and programs with the proponent federal, state and local government agencies and related groups;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_7"/><heading><desig>7.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Provide guidance and assistance to state agencies and units of local government in developing and maintaining emergency management and continuity of operations (COOP) programs, plans and systems;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_8"/><heading><desig>8.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Make necessary recommendations to agencies of the federal, state, or local governments on preventive and preparedness measures designed to eliminate or reduce disasters and their impact;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_9"/><heading><desig>9.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Determine requirements of the Commonwealth and its political subdivisions for those necessities needed in the event of a declared emergency which are not otherwise readily available;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_10"/><heading><desig>10.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Assist state agencies and political subdivisions in establishing and operating training programs and programs of public information and education regarding emergency services and disaster preparedness activities;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_11"/><heading><desig>11.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Consult with the Board of Education regarding the development and revision of a model school crisis and emergency management plan for the purpose of assisting public schools in establishing, operating, and maintaining emergency services and disaster preparedness activities;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_12"/><heading><desig>12.</desig><title><emphasis typeStyle="it"> (Effective until October 1, 2016)</emphasis></title></heading><bodyText><p> Consult with the State Council of Higher Education in the development and revision of a model institutional crisis and emergency management plan for the purpose of assisting public and private two-year and four-year institutions of higher education in establishing, operating, and maintaining emergency services and disaster preparedness activities and, as needed, in developing an institutional crisis and emergency management plan pursuant to <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 23-9.2:9"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 23 -9.2:9">§ 23-9.2:9<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#142#        23#       9.2#         9#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_12_seq_2"/><heading><desig>12.</desig><title><emphasis typeStyle="it"> (Effective October 1, 2016)</emphasis></title></heading><bodyText><p> Consult with the State Council of Higher Education in the development and revision of a model institutional crisis and emergency management plan for the purpose of assisting public and private two-year and four-year institutions of higher education in establishing, operating, and maintaining emergency services and disaster preparedness activities and, as needed, in developing an institutional crisis and emergency management plan pursuant to § 23.1-804;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_13"/><heading><desig>13.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Develop standards, provide guidance and encourage the maintenance of local and state agency emergency operations plans, which shall include the requirement for a provision that the Department of Criminal Justice Services and the Virginia Criminal Injuries Compensation Fund be contacted immediately to deploy assistance in the event of an emergency as defined in the emergency response plan when there are victims as defined in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 19.2-11.01"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 19.2-11.01">§ 19.2-11.01.<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000019#     2#        11.01#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> The Department of Criminal Justice Services and the Virginia Criminal Injuries Compensation Fund shall be the lead coordinating agencies for those individuals determined to be victims, and the plan shall also contain current contact information for both agencies;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_14"/><heading><desig>14.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Prepare, maintain, coordinate or implement emergency resource management plans and programs with federal, state and local government agencies and related groups, and make such surveys of industries, resources, and facilities within the Commonwealth, both public and private, as are necessary to carry out the purposes of this chapter;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_15"/><heading><desig>15.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Coordinate with the federal government and any public or private agency or entity in achieving any purpose of this chapter and in implementing programs for disaster prevention, mitigation, preparation, response, and recovery;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_16"/><heading><desig>16.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Establish guidelines pursuant to <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 44-146.28"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 44 -146.28">§ 44-146.28<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#123#000044#    146.28#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, and administer payments to eligible applicants as authorized by the Governor;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_17"/><heading><desig>17.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Coordinate and be responsible for the receipt, evaluation, and dissemination of emergency services intelligence pertaining to all probable hazards affecting the Commonwealth;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_18"/><heading><desig>18.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Coordinate intelligence activities relating to terrorism with the Department of State Police; and</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_19"/><heading><desig>19.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Develop an emergency response plan to address the needs of individuals with household pets and service animals in the event of a disaster and assist and coordinate with local agencies in developing an emergency response plan for household pets and service animals.</p><p><pre/>The Department of Emergency Management shall ensure that all such plans, assessments, and programs required by this subsection include specific preparedness for, and response to, disasters resulting from electromagnetic pulses and geomagnetic disturbances.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c"/><heading><desig>C.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The Department of Emergency Management shall during a period of impending emergency or declared emergency be responsible for:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The receipt, evaluation, and dissemination of intelligence pertaining to an impending or actual disaster;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Providing facilities from which state agencies and supporting organizations may conduct emergency operations;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Providing an adequate communications and warning system capable of notifying all political subdivisions in the Commonwealth of an impending disaster within a reasonable time;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c_4"/><heading><desig>4.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Establishing and maintaining liaison with affected political subdivisions;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c_5"/><heading><desig>5.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Determining requirements for disaster relief and recovery assistance;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c_6"/><heading><desig>6.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Coordinating disaster response actions of federal, state and volunteer relief agencies;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c_7"/><heading><desig>7.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Coordinating and providing guidance and assistance to affected political subdivisions to ensure orderly and timely response to and recovery from disaster effects.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d"/><heading><desig>D.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The Department of Emergency Management shall be provided the necessary facilities and equipment needed to perform its normal day-to-day activities and coordinate disaster-related activities of the various federal, state, and other agencies during a state of emergency declaration by the Governor or following a major disaster declaration by the President.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_e"/><heading><desig>E.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The Department of Emergency Management is authorized to enter into all contracts and agreements necessary or incidental to performance of any of its duties stated in this section or otherwise assigned to it by law, including contracts with the United States, other states, agencies and government subdivisions of the Commonwealth, and other appropriate public and private entities.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_f"/><heading><desig>F.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The Department of Emergency Management shall encourage private industries whose goods and services are deemed vital to the public good to provide annually updated preparedness assessments to the local coordinator of emergency management on or before April 1 of each year, to facilitate overall Commonwealth preparedness. For the purposes of this section, "private industry" means companies, private hospitals, and other businesses or organizations deemed by the State Coordinator of Emergency Management to be essential to the public safety and well-being of the citizens of the Commonwealth.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_g"/><heading><desig>G.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The Department of Emergency Management shall establish a Coordinator of Search and Rescue. Powers and duties of the Coordinator shall include:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_g_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Coordinating the search and rescue function of the Department of Emergency Management;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_g_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Coordinating with local, state, and federal agencies involved in search and rescue;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_g_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Coordinating the activities of search and rescue organizations involved in search and rescue;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_g_4"/><heading><desig>4.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Maintaining a register of search and rescue certifications, training, and responses;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_g_5"/><heading><desig>5.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Establishing a memorandum of understanding with the Virginia Search and Rescue Council and its respective member agencies regarding search and rescue efforts;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_g_6"/><heading><desig>6.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Providing on-scene search and rescue coordination when requested by an authorized person;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_g_7"/><heading><desig>7.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Providing specialized search and rescue training to police, fire-rescue, EMS, emergency managers, volunteer search and rescue responders, and others who might have a duty to respond to a search and rescue emergency;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_g_8"/><heading><desig>8.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Gathering and maintaining statistics on search and rescue in the Commonwealth;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_g_9"/><heading><desig>9.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Compiling, maintaining, and making available an inventory of search and rescue resources available in the Commonwealth;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_g_10"/><heading><desig>10.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Periodically reviewing search and rescue cases and developing best professional practices; and</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_g_11"/><heading><desig>11.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Providing an annual report to the Secretary of Public Safety and Homeland Security on the current readiness of Virginia's search and rescue efforts.</p><p><pre/>Nothing in this chapter shall be construed as authorizing the Department of Emergency Management to take direct operational responsibilities from local, state, or federal law enforcement in the course of search and rescue or missing person cases.</p></bodyText></level></level><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p>1973, c. 260; 1974, c. 4; 1975, c. 11; 1979, c. 193; 1984, c. 720; 1985, cc. 443, 447; <citation normalizedCite="1997 VA CH 893"><content><span normalizedCite="1997 Va. Ch. 893">1997, c. 893<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1997#000893#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2000 VA CH 309"><content><span normalizedCite="2000 Va. Ch. 309">2000, c. 309<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2000#000309#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2001 VA CH 841"><content><span normalizedCite="2001 Va. Ch. 841">2001, c. 841<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2001#000841#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2003 VA CH 622"><content><span normalizedCite="2003 Va. Ch. 622">2003, c. 622<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2003#000622#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2004 VA CH 690"><content><span normalizedCite="2004 Va. Ch. 690">2004, c. 690<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2004#000690#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2005 VA CH 165"><content><span normalizedCite="2005 Va. Ch. 165">2005, cc. 165<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2005#000165#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2005 VA CH 490"><content><span normalizedCite="2005 Va. Ch. 490">490<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2005#000490#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2007 VA CH 902"><content><span normalizedCite="2007 Va. Ch. 902">2007, c. 902<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2007#000902#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2008 VA CH 450"><content><span normalizedCite="2008 Va. Ch. 450">2008, cc. 450<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2008#000450#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2008 VA CH 526"><content><span normalizedCite="2008 Va. Ch. 526">526<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2008#000526#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2009 VA CH 222"><content><span normalizedCite="2009 Va. Ch. 222">2009, cc. 222<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2009#000222#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2009 VA CH 269"><content><span normalizedCite="2009 Va. Ch. 269">269<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2009#000269#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2012 VA CH 418"><content><span normalizedCite="2012 Va. Ch. 418">2012, c. 418<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2012#000418#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2015 VA CH 97"><content><span normalizedCite="2015 Va. Ch. 97">2015, cc. 97<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2015#000097#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2015 VA CH 205"><content><span normalizedCite="2015 Va. Ch. 205">205<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2015#000205#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2015 VA CH 223"><content><span normalizedCite="2015 Va. Ch. 223">223<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2015#000223#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PT70-004G-K0SG-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 44.</desig><title>MILITARY AND EMERGENCY LAWS</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 3.2.</desig><title>EMERGENCY SERVICES AND DISASTER LAW</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Criminal Law &amp; Procedure</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NEU0RkE1OUQwNUQwNDgxODhEODZCMjkzOTg3NThBNzk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDVFMkQ0NjEwMDU2NEM1N0I3MDU0ODc4MDFEM0UxNTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6ODg4MDhDQ0I2QkY5NDU2Rjg1RDNEREFBODk1Nzg1QTY</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NUNBNkM5RDJCM0M2NDQzQTgyODI4QTIzMjc1RTVBMDg7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDlBOEIwQjg0OTdFNEFDQUJCRkZBMEZCNTJDMTlEQTY</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Governments</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjdEQjE4OUJDMzQxNDNEMEI0RTI1QUFCMzJENjEwRTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Domestic Security</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RTIxMzgzQUZDMDA1NDIyRTk1NENFN0U0RTEzMEY1Qjk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MkM1MTYwRDE0NkJBNEVFMEIxQjM3RUE2NDRFQUFEODY</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Employees &amp; Officials</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDNCMDQzRTY3RDY3NDNEOEE4RDg2OUFEOTRBNDREQzg7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Njg1MkM3RkYyNzIxNEVFRkJFMTI2NUM4NUU1ODdEM0Q</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Finance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjMzOTBBRTg2MUVDNDdDNUE1M0QxNDk1RERCNjNCN0I7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Njg1MkM3RkYyNzIxNEVFRkJFMTI2NUM4NUU1ODdEM0Q</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Pets &amp; Service Animals</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDJCMUQ4NTBCM0RCNDIwMDk3M0RDODBDN0QwQjY2RDI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NkVDMzM4QkJENTg3NDQ0RDg3NTA5OEM3RkMyQTlENDI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Military &amp; Veterans Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NzM1OUEyRDNERTdENEU2MTk3RTlCNEJCRUY0NjRGRjQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Inspections &amp; Inventories</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NzM0RDhDMTg0MTUwNDE5Rjg0QTEwOTFBMzQzMTgyNkU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6M0I5NDA0N0Q5ODg1NEE1NTg1OUYyNTNGNDgzOEQxQzk</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Public Health &amp; Welfare Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDYwRTY1MDg3MTk5NDUyNkFFRDI1RjJBRERGQ0UxNzI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Emergency Services</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Q0E1M0VGRUVDNkJENDMyMkJGQjE5OThCMTVGNUMyREU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDZDNTZENUNCRjVBNEY4OEIyQzVBNjRDRTcyOEQ4NDQ</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Torts</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDAwOEM2NTEzQkVDNEI4NzlGMEZERUEyRjQwODM4Njg7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MkQwMTc0MUU5MzkxNEMwQzhEQkU0QjA2REQzQzNGMTc7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RjMzQjNFQ0U1MDdFNEQzMjg0MTA0MTY4MUZCQTZBM0U</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification><classificationGroup classificationScheme="indexing-terms"><classification classificationScheme="legal"/></classificationGroup></metadata></legislativeDoc>