<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#349#000009#     1#        150.2#">Va. Code Ann. § 9.1-150.2</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_9.1-150.2"/><heading><desig>§ 9.1-150.2.</desig><title>Powers of Criminal Justice Services Board relating to special conservators of the peace appointed pursuant to § 19.2-13</title></heading><bodyText><p>The Board shall adopt regulations establishing compulsory minimum, entry-level, in-service, and advanced training standards for special conservators of the peace. The regulations may include provisions delegating to the Board's staff the right to inspect the facilities and programs of persons conducting training to ensure compliance with the law and its regulations. In establishing compulsory training standards for special conservators of the peace, the Board shall require training to be obtained at a criminal justice training academy established pursuant to § 15.2-1747, or at a private security training school certified by the Department, and shall ensure the public safety and welfare against incompetent or unqualified persons engaging in the activities regulated by this section. The regulations may provide for exemption from training of persons having previous employment as law-enforcement officers for a state or the federal government. However, no such exemption shall be granted to persons having less than five continuous years of such employment, nor shall an exemption be provided for any person whose employment as a law-enforcement officer was terminated because of his misconduct or incompetence or who has been decertified as a law-enforcement officer. The regulations may include provisions for exemption from such training for persons having previous training that meets or exceeds the minimum training standards and has been approved by the Department. The Board may also adopt regulations that (i) establish the qualifications of applicants for registration; (ii) cause to be examined the qualifications of each applicant for registration; (iii) provide for collection of fees for registration and renewal that are sufficient to cover all expenses for administration and operation of a program of registration; (iv) ensure continued competency and prevent deceptive or misleading practices by practitioners; (v) effectively administer the regulatory system promulgated by the Board; (vi) provide for receipt of complaints concerning the conduct of any person whose activities are regulated by the Board; (vii) provide for investigations, and appropriate disciplinary action if warranted; and (viii) allow the Board to revoke, suspend or refuse to renew a registration, certification, or license for just cause as enumerated in regulations of the Board. The Board shall adopt compulsory, entry-level training standards that shall not exceed, but shall be a minimum of 98 hours for unarmed special conservators of the peace and that shall not exceed, but shall be a minimum of 130 hours for armed special conservators of the peace. In adopting its regulations, the Board shall seek the advice of the Private Security Services Advisory Board established pursuant to § 9.1-143.</p></bodyText><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p><citation normalizedCite="2003 VA CH 922"><content><span normalizedCite="2003 Va. Ch. 922">2003, c. 922<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2003#000922#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2015 VA CH 766"><content><span normalizedCite="2015 Va. Ch. 766">2015, cc. 766<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2015#000766#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2015 VA CH 772"><content><span normalizedCite="2015 Va. Ch. 772">772<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2015#000772#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PVC0-004G-K352-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 9.1.</desig><title>COMMONWEALTH PUBLIC SAFETY</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 1.</desig><title>DEPARTMENT OF CRIMINAL JUSTICE SERVICES</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="article"><heading><desig>ARTICLE 4.1.</desig><title>SPECIAL CONSERVATORS OF THE PEACE</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Administrative Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NjMxMjc0MUIzQjkzNEM4MEI4NkZGQjVCREJCRDk4OUM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Inspections</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QzU1MDA1QTM2MEFENDAzQjhBMkJBMTgxRkZGN0MyOUU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjFEMzdFMzJFMjk4NEYyNjk0M0IyNTE3Qzc4Qzg1MDA</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></metadata></legislativeDoc>