<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#349#000038#     2#         1710#">Va. Code Ann. § 38.2-1710</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_38.2-1710"/><heading><desig>§ 38.2-1710.</desig><title>Miscellaneous provisions</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a"/><heading><desig>A.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Nothing in this chapter shall be construed to reduce the liability for unpaid assessments of the insureds on an impaired or insolvent insurer operating under a plan with assessment liability.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b"/><heading><desig>B.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Records shall be kept of all meetings of the board of directors to discuss the activities of the Association in carrying out its powers and duties under <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 38.2-1704"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 38.2-1704">§ 38.2-1704<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000038#     2#         1704#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>. The records of the Association with respect to an impaired or insolvent insurer shall not be disclosed prior to the termination of a liquidation, rehabilitation, or conservation proceeding involving the impaired or insolvent insurer, except (i) upon the termination of the impairment or insolvency of the insurer or (ii) upon the order of a court of competent jurisdiction. Nothing in this subsection shall limit the duty of the Association to render a report of its activities under <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 38.2-1711"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 38.2-1711">§ 38.2-1711<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000038#     2#         1711#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c"/><heading><desig>C.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> For the purpose of carrying out its obligations under this chapter, the Association shall be deemed to be a creditor of the impaired or insolvent insurer to the extent of assets attributable to covered policies and contracts reduced by any amounts to which the Association is entitled as subrogee pursuant to subsection K of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 38.2-1704"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 38.2-1704">§ 38.2-1704<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000038#     2#         1704#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>. Assets of the impaired or insolvent insurer attributable to covered policies and contracts shall be used to continue all covered policies and contracts and pay all contractual obligations of the impaired or insolvent insurer as required by this chapter. "Assets attributable to covered policies and contracts" means that proportion of the assets which the reserves that should have been established for these policies and contracts bear to the reserves that should have been established for all insurance policies and contracts written by the impaired or insolvent insurer.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d"/><heading><desig>D.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> As a creditor of the impaired or insolvent insurer as established in subsection C and consistent with subsection B of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 38.2-1509"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 38.2-1509">§ 38.2-1509<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000038#     2#         1509#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, the Association and other similar associations shall be entitled to receive a disbursement of assets out of the marshaled assets, from time to time as the assets become available to reimburse it, as a credit against contractual obligations under this chapter. If the liquidator has not, within 120 days of a final determination of insolvency of an insurer by the receivership court, made an application to the court for the approval of a proposal to disburse assets out of marshaled assets to guaranty associations having obligations because of the insolvency, then the Association shall be entitled to make application to the receivership court for approval of its own proposal to disburse these assets.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_e"/><heading><desig>E.</desig></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_e_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Prior to the termination of any liquidation, rehabilitation, or conservation proceeding, the court, in making an equitable distribution of the ownership rights of the insolvent insurer, may take into consideration the contributions of the respective parties, including the Association, the shareholders, and policy and contract owners of the insolvent insurer, and any other party with a legitimate interest. In this determination, consideration shall be given to the welfare of the policy and contract owners of the continuing or successor insurer.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_e_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> No distribution to any stockholders, if any, of an impaired or insolvent insurer shall be made until and unless the total amount of valid claims of the Association with interest thereon for funds expended in carrying out its powers and duties under <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 38.2-1704"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 38.2-1704">§ 38.2-1704<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000038#     2#         1704#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> with respect to the insurer have been fully recovered by the Association.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_f"/><heading><desig>F.</desig></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_f_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> If an order for liquidation or rehabilitation of an insurer domiciled in this Commonwealth has been entered, the receiver appointed under that order shall have a right to recover on behalf of the insurer, from any affiliate that controlled it, the amount of distributions, other than stock dividends paid by the insurer on its capital stock, made at any time during the five years preceding the petition for liquidation or rehabilitation, subject to the limitations of subdivisions 2 through 4.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_f_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> No such distribution shall be recoverable if the insurer shows that when paid the distribution was lawful and reasonable, and that the insurer did not know and could not reasonably have known that the distribution might adversely affect the ability of the insurer to fulfill its contractual obligations.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_f_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Any person who was an affiliate that controlled the insurer at the time the distributions were paid shall be liable up to the amount of distributions received. Any person who was an affiliate that controlled the insurer at the time the distributions were declared shall be liable up to the amount of distributions that would have been received if they had been paid immediately. If two or more persons are liable with respect to the same distributions, they shall be jointly and severally liable.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_f_4"/><heading><desig>4.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The maximum amount recoverable under this subsection shall be the amount in excess of all other available assets of the insolvent insurer needed to pay (i) the contractual obligations of the insolvent insurer and (ii) the reasonable expenses of the Association incurred in connection with the performance of its duties for the insolvent insurer.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_f_5"/><heading><desig>5.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> If any person liable under subdivision 3 is insolvent, all its affiliates that controlled it at the time the distribution was paid shall be jointly and severally liable for any resulting deficiency in the amount recovered from the insolvent affiliate.</p></bodyText></level></level><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p>1976, c. 330, § 38.1-482.28; 1986, c. 562; <citation normalizedCite="2010 VA CH 510"><content><span normalizedCite="2010 Va. Ch. 510">2010, c. 510<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2010#000510#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PT40-004G-K4H5-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 38.2.</desig><title>INSURANCE</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 17.</desig><title>VIRGINIA LIFE, ACCIDENT AND SICKNESS INSURANCE GUARANTY ASSOCIATION</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="article"><heading><desig>ARTICLE 1.</desig><title>ESTABLISHMENT AND OPERATION OF THE ASSOCIATION</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Contracts Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QzY0RTZFMzE0RjkwNDdFQUI5M0U5N0ZFMjYyREMyQzU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Creditors &amp; Debtors</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6ODZDNjdDMUIxNjdGNERDRkFDNzAwRTI4NDhCNTBGNTk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OTdCODg3NEVGQTY5NENDQ0EzRkEwMzNGOTVBQTE0NEY</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Insurance Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDM4MzQ2QUYzMTY0NDQzQTkxRDQwRUUzRUM5RDg0OEM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NTUxNTQ1ODNFODA3NDQxOTkwRTkwNUE3M0Y2MThGNjE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDQ0MzAyMTAyNjY5NDRENEFDMzkyRjFDRUE4ODVGQjg</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NTk0MDE5RjU3RjdBNEMzRDlEMzhDMTE4Q0YxNjgwQ0E7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6M0VBODI0MEUyNjM0NDFFMkJDN0YwOEE0NEI4NjFCNTc</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Liquidations &amp; Rehabilitations</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NEFFNzJCNDAzRDIwNDc5QkFFMDlCRDUyOTJFQTM2MTg7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6M0VBODI0MEUyNjM0NDFFMkJDN0YwOEE0NEI4NjFCNTc</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification><classificationGroup classificationScheme="indexing-terms"><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem score="90"><className>Insurance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDM4MzQ2QUYzMTY0NDQzQTkxRDQwRUUzRUM5RDg0OEM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></classificationGroup></metadata></legislativeDoc>