<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#349#000046#     2#          483#">Va. Code Ann. § 46.2-483</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_46.2-483"/><heading><desig>§ 46.2-483.</desig><title>Compact enacted into law; terms</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><bodyText><p>The Driver License Compact is hereby enacted into law and entered into with all other jurisdictions legally joining therein in the form substantially as follows:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><bodyText><p>THE DRIVER LICENSE COMPACT </p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="article"><anchor id="_i"/><heading><desig>Article I</desig></heading><bodyText><p>Findings and Declaration of Policy </p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_i_a"/><heading><desig>(a)</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The party states find that:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_i_a_1"/><heading><desig>(1)</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The safety of their streets and highways is materially affected by the degree of compliance with state and local ordinances relating to the operation of motor vehicles.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_i_a_2"/><heading><desig>(2)</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Violation of such a law or ordinance is evidence that the violator engages in conduct which is likely to endanger the safety of persons and property.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_i_a_3"/><heading><desig>(3)</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The continuance in force of a license to drive is predicated upon compliance with laws and ordinances relating to the operation of motor vehicles, in whichever jurisdiction the vehicle is operated.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_i_b"/><heading><desig>(b)</desig></heading><bodyText><p> It is the policy of each of the party states to:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_i_b_1"/><heading><desig>(1)</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Promote compliance with the laws, ordinances, and administrative rules and regulations relating to the operation of motor vehicles by their operators in each of the jurisdictions where such operators drive motor vehicles.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_i_b_2"/><heading><desig>(2)</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Make the reciprocal recognition of licenses to drive and eligibility therefor more just and equitable by considering the overall compliance with motor vehicle laws, ordinances and administrative rules and regulations as a condition precedent to the continuance or issuance of any license by reason of which the licensee is authorized or permitted to operate a motor vehicle in any of the party states.</p></bodyText></level></level></level><level levelType="article"><anchor id="_ii"/><heading><desig>Article II</desig></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><bodyText><p>Definitions </p><p>As used in this compact:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_ii_a"/><heading><desig>(a)</desig><title><emphasis typeStyle="it">"State"</emphasis></title></heading><bodyText><p> means a state, territory or possession of the United States, the District of Columbia, or the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_ii_b"/><heading><desig>(b)</desig><title><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Home state"</emphasis></title></heading><bodyText><p> means the state which has issued and has the power to suspend or revoke the use of the license or permit to operate a motor vehicle.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_ii_c"/><heading><desig>(c)</desig><title><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Conviction"</emphasis></title></heading><bodyText><p> means a conviction of any offense related to the use or operation of a motor vehicle which is prohibited by state law, municipal ordinance or administrative rule or regulation, or a forfeiture of bail, bond, or other security deposited to secure appearance by a person charged with having committed any such offense, and which conviction or forfeiture is required to be reported to the licensing authority.</p></bodyText></level></level></level><level levelType="article"><anchor id="_iii"/><heading><desig>Article III</desig></heading><bodyText><p>Reports of Conviction </p><p>The licensing authority of a party state shall report each conviction of a person from another party state occurring within its jurisdiction to the licensing authority of the home state of the licensee.  Such report shall clearly identify the person convicted; describe the violation specifying the section of the statute, code or ordinance violated; identify the court in which action was taken; indicate whether a plea of guilty or not guilty was entered, or the conviction was a result of the forfeiture of bail, bond or other security; and shall include any special findings made in connection therewith.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="article"><anchor id="_iv"/><heading><desig>Article IV</desig></heading><bodyText><p>Effect of Conviction </p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_iv_a"/><heading><desig>(a)</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The licensing authority in the home state, for the purposes of suspension, revocation or limitation of the license to operate a motor vehicle, shall give the same effect to the conduct reported, pursuant to Article III of this compact, as it would if such conduct had occurred in the home state, in the case of convictions for:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_iv_a_1"/><heading><desig>(1)</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Manslaughter or negligent homicide resulting from the operation of a motor vehicle;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_iv_a_2"/><heading><desig>(2)</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Driving a motor vehicle while under the influence of intoxicating liquor or a narcotic drug, or under the influence of any other drug to a degree which renders the driver incapable of safely driving a motor vehicle;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_iv_a_3"/><heading><desig>(3)</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Any felony in the commission of which a motor vehicle is used;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_iv_a_4"/><heading><desig>(4)</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Failure to stop and render aid in the event of a motor vehicle accident resulting in the death or personal injury of another.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_iv_b"/><heading><desig>(b)</desig></heading><bodyText><p> As to other convictions, reported pursuant to Article III, the licensing authority in the home state shall give such effect to the conduct as is provided by the laws of the home state.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_iv_c"/><heading><desig>(c)</desig></heading><bodyText><p> If the laws of a party state do not provide for offenses or violations denominated or described in precisely the words employed in subdivision (a) of this article, such party state shall construe the denominations and descriptions appearing in subdivision (a) hereof as being applicable to and identifying those offenses or violations of a substantially similar nature and the laws of such party state shall contain such provisions as may be necessary to ensure that full force and effect is given to this article.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="article"><anchor id="_v"/><heading><desig>Article V</desig></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><bodyText><p>Applications for New Licenses </p><p>Upon application for a license to drive, the licensing authority in a party state shall ascertain whether the applicant has ever held, or is the holder of a license to drive issued by any other party state.  The licensing authority in the state where application is made shall not issue a license to drive to the applicant if:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_v_1"/><heading><desig>(1)</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The applicant has held such a license, but the same has been suspended by reason, in whole or in part, of a violation and if such suspension period has not terminated.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_v_2"/><heading><desig>(2)</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The applicant has held such a license, but the same has been revoked by reason, in whole or in part, of a violation and if such revocation has not terminated, except that after the expiration of one year from the date the license was revoked, such person may make application for a new license if permitted by law.  The licensing authority may refuse to issue a license to any such applicant if, after investigation, the licensing authority determines that it will not be safe to grant to such person the privilege of driving a motor vehicle on the public highways.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_v_3"/><heading><desig>(3)</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The applicant is the holder of a license to drive issued by another party state and currently in force unless the applicant surrenders such license.</p></bodyText></level></level></level><level levelType="article"><anchor id="_vi"/><heading><desig>Article VI</desig></heading><bodyText><p>Applicability of Other Laws </p><p>Except as expressly required by provisions of this compact, nothing contained herein shall be construed to affect the right of any party state to apply any of its other laws relating to licenses to drive to any person or circumstance, nor to invalidate or prevent any driver license agreement or other cooperative arrangement between a party state and a nonparty state.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="article"><anchor id="_vii"/><heading><desig>Article VII</desig></heading><bodyText><p>Compact Administrator and Interchange of Information </p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_vii_a"/><heading><desig>(a)</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The head of the licensing authority of each party state shall be the administrator of this compact for his state.  The administrators, acting jointly, shall have the power to formulate all necessary and proper procedures for the exchange of information under this compact.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_vii_b"/><heading><desig>(b)</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The administrator of each party state shall furnish to the administrator of each other party state any information or documents reasonably necessary to facilitate the administration of this compact.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="article"><anchor id="_viii"/><heading><desig>Article VIII</desig></heading><bodyText><p>Entry Into Force and Withdrawal </p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_viii_a"/><heading><desig>(a)</desig></heading><bodyText><p> This compact shall enter into force and become effective as to any state when it has enacted the same into law.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_viii_b"/><heading><desig>(b)</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Any party state may withdraw from this compact by enacting a statute repealing the same, but no such withdrawal shall take effect until six months after the executive head of the withdrawing state has given notice of the withdrawal to the executive heads of all other party states.  No withdrawal shall affect the validity or applicability by the licensing authorities of states remaining party to the compact of any report of conviction occurring prior to the withdrawal.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="article"><anchor id="_ix"/><heading><desig>Article IX</desig></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><bodyText><p>Construction and Severability </p><p>This compact shall be liberally construed so as to effectuate the purposes thereof.  The provisions of this compact shall be severable and if any phrase, clause, sentence or provision of this compact is declared to be contrary to the constitution of any party state or of the United States or the applicability thereof to any government, agency, person or circumstance is held invalid, the validity of the remainder of this compact and the applicability thereof to any government, agency, person or circumstance shall not be affected thereby.  If this compact shall be held contrary to the constitution of any state party thereto, the compact shall remain in full force and effect as to the remaining states and in full force and effect as to the state affected as to all severable matters.</p></bodyText></level></level><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p>1968, c. 166, § 46.1-167.8; <citation normalizedCite="1989 VA CH 727"><content><span normalizedCite="1989 Va. Ch. 727">1989, c. 727<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1989#000727#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PTP0-004G-K23X-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 46.2.</desig><title>MOTOR VEHICLES</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="subtitle"><heading><desig>SUBTITLE II.</desig><title>TITLING, REGISTRATION AND LICENSURE</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 3.</desig><title>LICENSURE OF DRIVERS</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="article"><heading><desig>ARTICLE 18.</desig><title>DRIVER LICENSE COMPACT</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Criminal Law &amp; Procedure</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NEU0RkE1OUQwNUQwNDgxODhEODZCMjkzOTg3NThBNzk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Nzk3NTlBMDhDNEZGNEZFQzk1QzI4QzVBRjIyRjU1Q0M7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RUUwRTU3NTU1NkRGNDlBQTkzQkRCM0RFQTZENTlBMUY</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NzlBNzRCQTM1NDIwNENBRjlFN0UzQzE2M0MwNDVFNEM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NUZCRUUyMDVEODIzNEY3Qjk0MTRBN0RDNzE3NEE1MjM</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Not Guilty</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6M0IzOTc3MjFGRDI4NDQzNkFFMUI2Mzc1QkRFQjc5QTY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Q0ZBQUEzNzY1ODUwNDJCN0I0RkZFNjBEQjk0QUY5MkU</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Governments</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjdEQjE4OUJDMzQxNDNEMEI0RTI1QUFCMzJENjEwRTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Licenses</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QUQzRDFDRDE0OTA0NDU2OEIwMUZCNDZEQTBBODdCODA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Njg1MkM3RkYyNzIxNEVFRkJFMTI2NUM4NUU1ODdEM0Q</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Licenses</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6N0IyQjkyQkVENEM2NDczNzg5MDUwQ0U5RDMzRjlDNUM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QURCRDNBRjBGRTE0NEFBRUEzNUU1MzFGQjg3MTM4MDI</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Ordinances &amp; Regulations</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NjQ1MzRDRUY1OTZBNDRDNTlDODQzRDRCMUFCNDc2RTU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Njg1MkM3RkYyNzIxNEVFRkJFMTI2NUM4NUU1ODdEM0Q</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Severability</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OTVDNDdDODk2RjgyNDRBQjhBMkY4MEI3NkNEOUE3MTQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Q0M3QUYzNjlBN0UzNEVBMDk4OEIyMzdBMDlGQzA2RjI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Transportation Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RTYzRTk5RDVBQkQ2NDcwQzk2NTU3ODQ5OEE3NDlBNzk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6M0RGOEU0NUFFOTU3NDUxNjhEOEIxMDE2NUU1NzRDQUQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6ODY1RjFBNDEzNUFBNEYzMjhCMjhDRkU1NDlCQ0U3RkU</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Revocation &amp; Suspension</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QUNDMUM0MDYwNEE1NDZGQkIyNzQyNzQ0RTIzNkFBMzk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6ODY1RjFBNDEzNUFBNEYzMjhCMjhDRkU1NDlCQ0U3RkU</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification><classificationGroup classificationScheme="indexing-terms"><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem score="90"><className>Transportation</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RTYzRTk5RDVBQkQ2NDcwQzk2NTU3ODQ5OEE3NDlBNzk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></classificationGroup></metadata></legislativeDoc>