<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#349#000051#     1#          165#">Va. Code Ann. § 51.1-165</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_51.1-165"/><heading><desig>§ 51.1-165.</desig><title>Optional benefits</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a"/><heading><desig>A.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Any member not taking 50/10 retirement as provided in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 51.1-153"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 51.1-153">§ 51.1-153<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000051#     1#          153#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> or <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 51.1-216"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 51.1-216">51.1-216<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000051#     1#          216#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, in accordance with the retirement plan covering such member, may elect to have his retirement allowance payable under one of the options set forth in this subsection and receive the actuarial equivalent of the retirement allowance otherwise payable to him. The election of an optional benefit shall be subject to the approval of the Board.</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig><title> Straight life option. --</title></heading><bodyText><p> A member may elect to receive an increased retirement allowance in lieu of any death benefits.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig><title> Joint and last-survivor option. --</title></heading><bodyText><p> A member may elect to receive a decreased retirement allowance during his lifetime in order that a fraction of such retirement allowance be continued to a contingent annuitant at the death of the member. The amount to be received by the contingent annuitant, in accordance with such election by the member, shall not exceed 100 percent of the amount to be received by the member during his lifetime nor shall it be less than 10 percent of such amount. In case of such an election, death benefits that might otherwise be provided shall not be payable upon the death of the member unless death of the member occurs prior to the effective date of retirement as set forth in subsection C of this section. This option may be elected if the contingent annuitant is the spouse of the member. If the contingent annuitant is not the spouse of the member, this option may be elected only if the actuarial present value of the payments expected to be made to the member is greater than one-half of the actuarial present value of the total payments expected to be made to the member and contingent annuitant.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig><title> Level income option. --</title></heading><bodyText><p> If a member retires from service prior to his retirement age, as such term is defined under the Social Security Act <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="42 USC 416"><content><span normalizedCite="42 U.S.C. 416">(42 U.S.C. § 416<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1828#123#000042#        416#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> et seq., as now or hereafter amended), he may elect to receive an increased retirement allowance beginning on the member's effective date of retirement and continuing until the member reaches age 62 or any whole age up to his normal retirement age, as such term is defined under the Social Security Act <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="42 USC 416"><content><span normalizedCite="42 U.S.C. 416">(42 U.S.C. § 416<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1828#123#000042#        416#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> et seq., as now or hereafter amended) and a decreased retirement allowance thereafter, thereby providing a more nearly level retirement allowance when such decreased retirement allowance is added to his anticipated primary benefits under the federal Social Security Act. In determining the amount of such retirement allowance under this option before the electing retiree reaches his retirement age, as such term is defined under the Social Security Act <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="42 USC 416"><content><span normalizedCite="42 U.S.C. 416">(42 U.S.C. § 416<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1828#123#000042#        416#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> et seq., as now or hereafter amended), the Board may use an estimate of the member's anticipated social security benefit for computing the amount of such retirement allowance. Any member electing to receive such an allowance shall not be entitled to a joint and last survivor benefit. The amount of the increased retirement allowance shall be determined actuarially, but the election of this option shall not result in more than a 50 percent reduction in the member's benefit as provided in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 51.1-155"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 51.1-155">§ 51.1-155<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000051#     1#          155#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 51.1-206"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 51.1-206">51.1-206<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000051#     1#          206#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 51.1-217"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 51.1-217">51.1-217<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000051#     1#          217#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, or <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 51.1-306"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 51.1-306">51.1-306<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000051#     1#          306#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b"/><heading><desig>B.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Any member taking 50/10 retirement as provided in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 51.1-153"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 51.1-153">§ 51.1-153<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000051#     1#          153#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> or <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 51.1-216"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 51.1-216">51.1-216<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000051#     1#          216#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, in accordance with the retirement plan covering such member, may elect to have his retirement allowance payable under the option set forth in this subsection and receive the actuarial equivalent of the retirement allowance otherwise payable to him. The election of this optional benefit shall be subject to the approval of the Board.</p><p>50/10 retirement joint and last-survivor option. -- A member may elect to receive a decreased retirement allowance during his lifetime and have the retirement allowance continued after his death to a contingent annuitant during the lifetime of such person. The retirement allowance pursuant to this option shall be determined as provided in subdivision A 5 of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 51.1-155"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 51.1-155">§ 51.1-155<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000051#     1#          155#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> or subsection A of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 51.1-217"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 51.1-217">§ 51.1-217<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000051#     1#          217#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, in accordance with the retirement plan covering such member, except (i) the present value of future retirement benefits shall be calculated based on the life expectancies of both the member and the contingent annuitant and (ii) the actuarially computed present value of the payments expected to be made under this option shall be actuarially equivalent to the actuarially computed present value of the payments expected to be made to the member as determined pursuant to subdivision A 5 of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 51.1-155"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 51.1-155">§ 51.1-155<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000051#     1#          155#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> or subsection A of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 51.1-217"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 51.1-217">§ 51.1-217<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000051#     1#          217#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, in accordance with the retirement plan covering such member.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c"/><heading><desig>C.</desig></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The election of any one of the options stated in this section shall be null and void if the member dies prior to the Board receiving written notification of the member's effective date of retirement. The election of a joint and last-survivor option shall be null and void if the contingent annuitant dies before the member's retirement. Except as provided in subdivision 2 of this subsection, in all cases where the death of the member occurs prior to the effective date of retirement but after the Board has received written notification of the member's effective date of retirement, benefits shall be paid in accordance with the provisions of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 51.1-163"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 51.1-163">§ 51.1-163<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000051#     1#          163#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> and the requirement that the member be in service shall not apply. For purposes of this subdivision, retirement shall be deemed to commence on the effective date of a member's service retirement or disability.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> If (i) the death of the member occurs prior to the effective date of retirement but after the Board has received written notification of the member's effective date of retirement; (ii) the member died while in service; (iii) at the time of the member's death the election for payment of the member's retirement allowance was a joint and last-survivor optional retirement benefit; and (iv) the member named his spouse, minor child, or parent as the contingent annuitant under the joint and last-survivor optional benefit, then benefits shall be paid in accordance with the provisions of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 51.1-163"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 51.1-163">§ 51.1-163<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000051#     1#          163#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>. However, if such contingent annuitant or annuitants are the same person or persons who would receive a monthly benefit under subsection B of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 51.1-162"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 51.1-162">§ 51.1-162<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000051#     1#          162#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> and the monthly benefit under such subsection would be greater than the benefit provided in accordance with the provisions of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 51.1-163"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 51.1-163">§ 51.1-163<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000051#     1#          163#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, then retirement benefits shall be paid in accordance with the provisions of subsection B of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 51.1-162"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 51.1-162">§ 51.1-162<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000051#     1#          162#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p><p><pre/>For purposes of this subdivision, retirement shall be deemed to commence on the effective date of a member's service retirement or disability.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d"/><heading><desig>D.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A member who has elected any of the options stated in this section may revoke such an election by written notification to the Board any time prior to the later of the effective date of retirement or the date of written notification to the Board of retirement of the member.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_e"/><heading><desig>E.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A retired member who has elected a joint and last-survivor option may, in a manner prescribed by the Board, revoke such election and elect to receive from time of notification either the retirement allowance to which he would have been entitled had no option been elected initially or an allowance actuarially equivalent thereto under a joint and last-survivor option with a different contingent annuitant, if (i) the original contingent annuitant has died, (ii) a final decree of divorce of the retired member from the original contingent annuitant has been entered, or (iii) the written consent of the original contingent annuitant, together with evidence satisfactory to the Board of the good health of the original contingent annuitant, is submitted with the notification. If the provisions of this subsection are invoked by a retired member on the basis of the member's having been divorced from his contingent annuitant and the marriage had been of a duration of 20 years or more, the provisions of this subsection shall not be applicable until the death or remarriage of the former spouse unless such spouse consents in writing to the revocation of the option prior to death or remarriage.</p><p>If such an election is made as a result of the death or divorce of the contingent annuitant, the benefit payable to the retired member may be adjusted retroactively for a period of not more than 60 days from the date the Board first receives notification of the desire of the retired member to make such a change.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_f"/><heading><desig>F.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Subject to the provisions of subsection E of this section, any member who retires on or after July 1, 1986, and returns to covered employment shall not be entitled to select a different optional benefit upon making application for retirement a second or subsequent time.</p></bodyText></level><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p>1952, c. 157, § 51-111.60; 1956, c. 560; 1966, c. 174; 1970, c. 476; 1974, c. 353; 1975, c. 597; 1976, cc. 511, 542; 1978, c. 841; 1980, cc. 85, 642, 646; 1982, c. 581; 1986, c. 474; <citation normalizedCite="1990 VA CH 832"><content><span normalizedCite="1990 Va. Ch. 832">1990, c. 832<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1990#000832#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1992 VA CH 518"><content><span normalizedCite="1992 Va. Ch. 518">1992, cc. 518<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1992#000518#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1992 VA CH 548"><content><span normalizedCite="1992 Va. Ch. 548">548<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1992#000548#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1992 VA CH 811"><content><span normalizedCite="1992 Va. Ch. 811">811<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1992#000811#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1993 VA CH 548"><content><span normalizedCite="1993 Va. Ch. 548">1993, c. 548<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1993#000548#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1995 VA CH 152"><content><span normalizedCite="1995 Va. Ch. 152">1995, cc. 152<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1995#000152#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1995 VA CH 307"><content><span normalizedCite="1995 Va. Ch. 307">307<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1995#000307#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1995 VA CH 692"><content><span normalizedCite="1995 Va. Ch. 692">692<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1995#000692#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1995 VA CH 811"><content><span normalizedCite="1995 Va. Ch. 811">811<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1995#000811#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1998 VA CH 676"><content><span normalizedCite="1998 Va. Ch. 676">1998, c. 676<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1998#000676#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1999 VA CH 111"><content><span normalizedCite="1999 Va. Ch. 111">1999, c. 111<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1999#000111#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2001 VA CH 679"><content><span normalizedCite="2001 Va. Ch. 679">2001, cc. 679<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2001#000679#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2001 VA CH 699"><content><span normalizedCite="2001 Va. Ch. 699">699<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2001#000699#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2003 VA CH 263"><content><span normalizedCite="2003 Va. Ch. 263">2003, c. 263<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2003#000263#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2005 VA CH 146"><content><span normalizedCite="2005 Va. Ch. 146">2005, cc. 146<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2005#000146#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2005 VA CH 162"><content><span normalizedCite="2005 Va. Ch. 162">162<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2005#000162#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PTW0-004G-K52Y-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 51.1.</desig><title>PENSIONS, BENEFITS, AND RETIREMENT</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 1.</desig><title>VIRGINIA RETIREMENT SYSTEM</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="article"><heading><desig>ARTICLE 9.</desig><title>BENEFITS</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Public Health &amp; Welfare Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDYwRTY1MDg3MTk5NDUyNkFFRDI1RjJBRERGQ0UxNzI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjIwNDlBNjZGM0IxNDc4MkE5MkI2QTVCNkNEQ0M0QzM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MTNCNURBMjAwMTdCNDU0NjhDREEwOUE4MUI1M0FFREI</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QTVCOUQyMkU2RjU1NEMxMTlDMTQ2NTA5MEYyMDIxQ0I7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OUFCMjkwRjk1OEIxNEI2NTk5NzgyMDA4NDAwMDkxNjE</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification><classificationGroup classificationScheme="indexing-terms"><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem score="90"><className>Pensions &amp; Benefits</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QzNEOEE3NjhDNTJBNDhCOTgxRkQzNzc1Q0JCMkU4Q0I7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></classificationGroup></metadata></legislativeDoc>