<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#349#000002#     2#         3704#">Va. Code Ann. § 2.2-3704</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_2.2-3704"/><heading><desig>§ 2.2-3704.</desig><title>Public records to be open to inspection; procedure for requesting records and responding to request; charges; transfer of records for storage, etc</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a"/><heading><desig>A.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Except as otherwise specifically provided by law, all public records shall be open to inspection and copying by any citizens of the Commonwealth during the regular office hours of the custodian of such records. Access to such records shall not be denied to citizens of the Commonwealth, representatives of newspapers and magazines with circulation in the Commonwealth, and representatives of radio and television stations broadcasting in or into the Commonwealth. The custodian may require the requester to provide his name and legal address. The custodian of such records shall take all necessary precautions for their preservation and safekeeping.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b"/><heading><desig>B.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A request for public records shall identify the requested records with reasonable specificity. The request need not make reference to this chapter in order to invoke the provisions of this chapter or to impose the time limits for response by a public body. Any public body that is subject to this chapter and that is the custodian of the requested records shall promptly, but in all cases within five working days of receiving a request, provide the requested records to the requester or make one of the following responses in writing:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The requested records are being entirely withheld. Such response shall identify with reasonable particularity the volume and subject matter of withheld records, and cite, as to each category of withheld records, the specific Code section that authorizes the withholding of the records.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The requested records are being provided in part and are being withheld in part. Such response shall identify with reasonable particularity the subject matter of withheld portions, and cite, as to each category of withheld records, the specific Code section that authorizes the withholding of the records.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The requested records could not be found or do not exist. However, if the public body that received the request knows that another public body has the requested records, the response shall include contact information for the other public body.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_4"/><heading><desig>4.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> It is not practically possible to provide the requested records or to determine whether they are available within the five-work-day period. Such response shall specify the conditions that make a response impossible. If the response is made within five working days, the public body shall have an additional seven work days in which to provide one of the four preceding responses.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c"/><heading><desig>C.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Any public body may petition the appropriate court for additional time to respond to a request for records when the request is for an extraordinary volume of records or requires an extraordinarily lengthy search, and a response by the public body within the time required by this chapter will prevent the public body from meeting its operational responsibilities. Before proceeding with the petition, however, the public body shall make reasonable efforts to reach an agreement with the requester concerning the production of the records requested.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d"/><heading><desig>D.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Subject to the provisions of subsection G, no public body shall be required to create a new record if the record does not already exist. However, a public body may abstract or summarize information under such terms and conditions as agreed between the requester and the public body.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_e"/><heading><desig>E.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Failure to respond to a request for records shall be deemed a denial of the request and shall constitute a violation of this chapter.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_f"/><heading><desig>F.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A public body may make reasonable charges not to exceed its actual cost incurred in accessing, duplicating, supplying, or searching for the requested records. No public body shall impose any extraneous, intermediary, or surplus fees or expenses to recoup the general costs associated with creating or maintaining records or transacting the general business of the public body. Any duplicating fee charged by a public body shall not exceed the actual cost of duplication. The public body may also make a reasonable charge for the cost incurred in supplying records produced from a geographic information system at the request of anyone other than the owner of the land that is the subject of the request. However, such charges shall not exceed the actual cost to the public body in supplying such records, except that the public body may charge, on a pro rata per acre basis, for the cost of creating topographical maps developed by the public body, for such maps or portions thereof, which encompass a contiguous area greater than 50 acres. All charges for the supplying of requested records shall be estimated in advance at the request of the citizen.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_g"/><heading><desig>G.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Public records maintained by a public body in an electronic data processing system, computer database, or any other structured collection of data shall be made available to a requester at a reasonable cost, not to exceed the actual cost in accordance with subsection F. When electronic or other databases are combined or contain exempt and nonexempt records, the public body may provide access to the exempt records if not otherwise prohibited by law, but shall provide access to the nonexempt records as provided by this chapter.</p><p>Public bodies shall produce nonexempt records maintained in an electronic database in any tangible medium identified by the requester, including, where the public body has the capability, the option of posting the records on a website or delivering the records through an electronic mail address provided by the requester, if that medium is used by the public body in the regular course of business. No public body shall be required to produce records from an electronic database in a format not regularly used by the public body. However, the public body shall make reasonable efforts to provide records in any format under such terms and conditions as agreed between the requester and public body, including the payment of reasonable costs. The excision of exempt fields of information from a database or the conversion of data from one available format to another shall not be deemed the creation, preparation, or compilation of a new public record.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_h"/><heading><desig>H.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> In any case where a public body determines in advance that charges for producing the requested records are likely to exceed $ 200, the public body may, before continuing to process the request, require the requester to agree to payment of a deposit not to exceed the amount of the advance determination. The deposit shall be credited toward the final cost of supplying the requested records. The period within which the public body shall respond under this section shall be tolled for the amount of time that elapses between notice of the advance determination and the response of the requester.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_i"/><heading><desig>I.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Before processing a request for records, a public body may require the requester to pay any amounts owed to the public body for previous requests for records that remain unpaid 30 days or more after billing.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_j"/><heading><desig>J.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> In the event a public body has transferred possession of public records to any entity, including but not limited to any other public body, for storage, maintenance, or archiving, the public body initiating the transfer of such records shall remain the custodian of such records for purposes of responding to requests for public records made pursuant to this chapter and shall be responsible for retrieving and supplying such public records to the requester. In the event a public body has transferred public records for storage, maintenance, or archiving and such transferring public body is no longer in existence, any public body that is a successor to the transferring public body shall be deemed the custodian of such records. In the event no successor entity exists, the entity in possession of the public records shall be deemed the custodian of the records for purposes of compliance with this chapter, and shall retrieve and supply such records to the requester. Nothing in this subsection shall be construed to apply to records transferred to the Library of Virginia for permanent archiving pursuant to the duties imposed by the Virginia Public Records Act (<citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 42.1-76"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 42.1-76">§ 42.1-76<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000042#     1#           76#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> et seq.). In accordance with <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 42.1-79"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 42.1-79">§ 42.1-79<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000042#     1#           79#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, the Library of Virginia shall be the custodian of such permanently archived records and shall be responsible for responding to requests for such records made pursuant to this chapter.</p></bodyText></level><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p>1968, c. 479, § 2.1-342; 1973, c. 461; 1974, c. 332; 1975, cc. 307, 312; 1976, cc. 640, 709; 1977, c. 677; 1978, c. 810; 1979, cc. 682, 684, 686, 689; 1980, cc. 678, 754; 1981, cc. 456, 464, 466, 589; 1982, cc. 225, 449, 452, 560, 635; 1983, cc. 372, 462, 607; 1984, cc. 85, 395, 433, 513, 532; 1985, cc. 81, 155, 502, 618; 1986, cc. 273, 291, 383, 469, 592; 1987, cc. 401, 491, 581; 1988, cc. 39, 151, 395, 411, 891, 902; <citation normalizedCite="1989 VA CH 56"><content><span normalizedCite="1989 Va. Ch. 56">1989, cc. 56<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1989#000056#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1989 VA CH 358"><content><span normalizedCite="1989 Va. Ch. 358">358<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1989#000358#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1989 VA CH 478"><content><span normalizedCite="1989 Va. Ch. 478">478<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1989#000478#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1990 VA CH 217"><content><span normalizedCite="1990 Va. Ch. 217">1990, cc. 217<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1990#000217#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1990 VA CH 538"><content><span normalizedCite="1990 Va. Ch. 538">538<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1990#000538#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1990 VA CH 721"><content><span normalizedCite="1990 Va. Ch. 721">721<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1990#000721#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1990 VA CH 819"><content><span normalizedCite="1990 Va. Ch. 819">819<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1990#000819#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1990 VA CH 968"><content><span normalizedCite="1990 Va. Ch. 968">968<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1990#000968#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1991 VA CH 213"><content><span normalizedCite="1991 Va. Ch. 213">1991, cc. 213<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1991#000213#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1991 VA CH 561"><content><span normalizedCite="1991 Va. Ch. 561">561<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1991#000561#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1992 VA CH 40"><content><span normalizedCite="1992 Va. Ch. 40">1992, cc. 40<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1992#000040#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1992 VA CH 150"><content><span normalizedCite="1992 Va. Ch. 150">150<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1992#000150#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1992 VA CH 167"><content><span normalizedCite="1992 Va. Ch. 167">167<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1992#000167#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1992 VA CH 200"><content><span normalizedCite="1992 Va. Ch. 200">200<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1992#000200#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1992 VA CH 203"><content><span normalizedCite="1992 Va. Ch. 203">203<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1992#000203#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1992 VA CH 207"><content><span normalizedCite="1992 Va. Ch. 207">207<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1992#000207#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1992 VA CH 593"><content><span normalizedCite="1992 Va. Ch. 593">593<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1992#000593#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1992 VA CH 612"><content><span normalizedCite="1992 Va. Ch. 612">612<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1992#000612#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1993 VA CH 205"><content><span normalizedCite="1993 Va. Ch. 205">1993, cc. 205<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1993#000205#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1993 VA CH 270"><content><span normalizedCite="1993 Va. Ch. 270">270<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1993#000270#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1993 VA CH 296"><content><span normalizedCite="1993 Va. Ch. 296">296<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1993#000296#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1993 VA CH 537"><content><span normalizedCite="1993 Va. Ch. 537">537<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1993#000537#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1993 VA CH 552"><content><span normalizedCite="1993 Va. Ch. 552">552<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1993#000552#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1993 VA CH 638"><content><span normalizedCite="1993 Va. Ch. 638">638<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1993#000638#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1993 VA CH 750"><content><span normalizedCite="1993 Va. Ch. 750">750<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1993#000750#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1993 VA CH 883"><content><span normalizedCite="1993 Va. Ch. 883">883<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1993#000883#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1994 VA CH 485"><content><span normalizedCite="1994 Va. Ch. 485">1994, cc. 485<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1994#000485#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1994 VA CH 532"><content><span normalizedCite="1994 Va. Ch. 532">532<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1994#000532#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1994 VA CH 606"><content><span normalizedCite="1994 Va. Ch. 606">606<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1994#000606#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1994 VA CH 839"><content><span normalizedCite="1994 Va. Ch. 839">839<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1994#000839#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1994 VA CH 853"><content><span normalizedCite="1994 Va. Ch. 853">853<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1994#000853#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1994 VA CH 918"><content><span normalizedCite="1994 Va. Ch. 918">918<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1994#000918#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1995 VA CH 299"><content><span normalizedCite="1995 Va. Ch. 299">1995, cc. 299<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1995#000299#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1995 VA CH 362"><content><span normalizedCite="1995 Va. Ch. 362">362<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1995#000362#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1995 VA CH 499"><content><span normalizedCite="1995 Va. Ch. 499">499<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1995#000499#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1995 VA CH 562"><content><span normalizedCite="1995 Va. Ch. 562">562<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1995#000562#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1995 VA CH 638"><content><span normalizedCite="1995 Va. Ch. 638">638<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1995#000638#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1995 VA CH 722"><content><span normalizedCite="1995 Va. Ch. 722">722<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1995#000722#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1995 VA CH 812"><content><span normalizedCite="1995 Va. Ch. 812">812<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1995#000812#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1995 VA CH 837"><content><span normalizedCite="1995 Va. Ch. 837">837<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1995#000837#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1996 VA CH 168"><content><span normalizedCite="1996 Va. Ch. 168">1996, cc. 168<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1996#000168#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1996 VA CH 469"><content><span normalizedCite="1996 Va. Ch. 469">469<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1996#000469#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1996 VA CH 589"><content><span normalizedCite="1996 Va. Ch. 589">589<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1996#000589#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1996 VA CH 599"><content><span normalizedCite="1996 Va. Ch. 599">599<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1996#000599#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1996 VA CH 783"><content><span normalizedCite="1996 Va. Ch. 783">783<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1996#000783#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1996 VA CH 786"><content><span normalizedCite="1996 Va. Ch. 786">786<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1996#000786#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1996 VA CH 794"><content><span normalizedCite="1996 Va. Ch. 794">794<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1996#000794#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1996 VA CH 855"><content><span normalizedCite="1996 Va. Ch. 855">855<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1996#000855#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1996 VA CH 862"><content><span normalizedCite="1996 Va. Ch. 862">862<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1996#000862#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1996 VA CH 902"><content><span normalizedCite="1996 Va. Ch. 902">902<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1996#000902#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1996 VA CH 905"><content><span normalizedCite="1996 Va. Ch. 905">905<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1996#000905#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1996 VA CH 1001"><content><span normalizedCite="1996 Va. Ch. 1001">1001<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1996#001001#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1996 VA CH 1046"><content><span normalizedCite="1996 Va. Ch. 1046">1046<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1996#001046#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1997 VA CH 198"><content><span normalizedCite="1997 Va. Ch. 198">1997, cc. 198<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1997#000198#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1997 VA CH 295"><content><span normalizedCite="1997 Va. Ch. 295">295<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1997#000295#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1997 VA CH 439"><content><span normalizedCite="1997 Va. Ch. 439">439<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1997#000439#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1997 VA CH 567"><content><span normalizedCite="1997 Va. Ch. 567">567<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1997#000567#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1997 VA CH 636"><content><span normalizedCite="1997 Va. Ch. 636">636<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1997#000636#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1997 VA CH 641"><content><span normalizedCite="1997 Va. Ch. 641">641<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1997#000641#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1997 VA CH 777"><content><span normalizedCite="1997 Va. Ch. 777">777<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1997#000777#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1997 VA CH 782"><content><span normalizedCite="1997 Va. Ch. 782">782<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1997#000782#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1997 VA CH 785"><content><span normalizedCite="1997 Va. Ch. 785">785<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1997#000785#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1997 VA CH 838"><content><span normalizedCite="1997 Va. Ch. 838">838<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1997#000838#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1997 VA CH 861"><content><span normalizedCite="1997 Va. Ch. 861">861<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1997#000861#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1998 VA CH 427"><content><span normalizedCite="1998 Va. Ch. 427">1998, cc. 427<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1998#000427#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1998 VA CH 891"><content><span normalizedCite="1998 Va. Ch. 891">891<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1998#000891#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1999 VA CH 438"><content><span normalizedCite="1999 Va. Ch. 438">1999, cc. 438<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1999#000438#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1999 VA CH 703"><content><span normalizedCite="1999 Va. Ch. 703">703<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1999#000703#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1999 VA CH 726"><content><span normalizedCite="1999 Va. Ch. 726">726<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1999#000726#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2001 VA CH 844"><content><span normalizedCite="2001 Va. Ch. 844">2001, c. 844<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2001#000844#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2002 VA CH 715"><content><span normalizedCite="2002 Va. Ch. 715">2002, cc. 715<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2002#000715#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2002 VA CH 830"><content><span normalizedCite="2002 Va. Ch. 830">830<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2002#000830#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2003 VA CH 275"><content><span normalizedCite="2003 Va. Ch. 275">2003, cc. 275<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2003#000275#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2003 VA CH 981"><content><span normalizedCite="2003 Va. Ch. 981">981<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2003#000981#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2003 VA CH 1021"><content><span normalizedCite="2003 Va. Ch. 1021">1021<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2003#001021#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2007 VA CH 439"><content><span normalizedCite="2007 Va. Ch. 439">2007, c. 439<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2007#000439#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2009 VA CH 626"><content><span normalizedCite="2009 Va. Ch. 626">2009, c. 626<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2009#000626#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2010 VA CH 627"><content><span normalizedCite="2010 Va. Ch. 627">2010, c. 627<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2010#000627#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2011 VA CH 604"><content><span normalizedCite="2011 Va. Ch. 604">2011, c. 604<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2011#000604#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2016 VA CH 620"><content><span normalizedCite="2016 Va. Ch. 620">2016, cc. 620<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2016#000620#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2016 VA CH 716"><content><span normalizedCite="2016 Va. Ch. 716">716<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2016#000716#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PV80-004G-K1JB-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 2.2.</desig><title>ADMINISTRATION OF GOVERNMENT</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="subtitle"><heading><desig>SUBTITLE II.</desig><title>ADMINISTRATION OF STATE GOVERNMENT</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="part"><heading><desig>PART B.</desig><title>TRANSACTION OF PUBLIC BUSINESS</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 37.</desig><title>VIRGINIA FREEDOM OF INFORMATION ACT</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Administrative Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NjMxMjc0MUIzQjkzNEM4MEI4NkZGQjVCREJCRDk4OUM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OUM1MUY0NkUzM0VCNDczRTkwNjBDQkE1NEQ1OTg5OTg7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6M0ZEQkQ2NTQxRjFBNEIzMUEzQkNFOTRBMDRCMUY5RDU</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6M0I4QTIzQjQ4MDcxNDczMThDMEUwOEQ0MkYzNEJFRkI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QTkxRkE0MTcyQTY5NEY0Q0FBRDYzRDFCRDcyNzhERjc</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Record Requests</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6REM0NzA5QUQzMTU1NDk3QUIyOTlDOTUyNkM4QTY0ODc7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RjgzODczMjc1N0UxNDFDNUJDNDc0Qzc1NzhCQkJCMzM</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Education Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDkzNUEzQzFBNEZBNEFBREIxNDM5MTc1MUU5QjI4MTY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDBDMzRDODQwQzY3NDNCRDkxNDE1REEyOEFGMzBBNjE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDU1QkREN0FDNThENDhDMTk1MTk4MTQ3OUMzRjAwQjI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification><classificationGroup classificationScheme="indexing-terms"><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem score="90"><className>Governments</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjdEQjE4OUJDMzQxNDNEMEI0RTI1QUFCMzJENjEwRTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></classificationGroup></metadata></legislativeDoc>