<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#349#000033#     2#         1709#">Va. Code Ann. § 33.2-1709</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_33.2-1709"/><heading><desig>§ 33.2-1709.</desig><title>Credit of Commonwealth not pledged</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a"/><heading><desig>A.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Commonwealth of Virginia Toll Revenue Bonds issued under the provisions of this chapter shall not be deemed to constitute a debt of the Commonwealth or a pledge of the full faith and credit of the Commonwealth, but such bonds shall be payable solely from the funds provided therefor from tolls and revenues pursuant to this chapter, from bond proceeds or earnings thereon, and from any other available sources of funds. All such bonds shall state on their face that the Commonwealth is not obligated to pay the same or the interest thereon except from the special fund provided therefor from tolls and revenues under this chapter, from bond proceeds or earnings thereon, and from any other available sources of funds, and that the full faith and credit of the Commonwealth are not pledged to the payment of the principal or interest of such bonds. The issuance of such revenue bonds under the provisions of this chapter shall not directly or indirectly or contingently obligate the Commonwealth to levy or to pledge any form of taxation whatever therefor or to make any appropriation for their payment, other than appropriate available funds derived as revenues from tolls and charges under this chapter or derived from bond proceeds or earnings thereon and from any other available sources of funds.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b"/><heading><desig>B.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Commonwealth of Virginia Transportation Contract Revenue Bonds issued under the provisions of this chapter shall not be deemed to constitute a debt of the Commonwealth or a pledge of the full faith and credit of the Commonwealth, but such bonds shall be payable solely from the funds provided therefor pursuant to this chapter (i) from revenues received pursuant to contracts with a primary highway transportation district or transportation service district or any other alternative mechanism for generation of local revenues for specific funding of a project satisfactory to the Board; (ii) to the extent required, from funds appropriated and allocated, pursuant to the highway allocation formula as provided by law, to the highway construction district in which the project to be financed is located or to the county or counties in which such project is located; (iii) from bond proceeds or earnings thereon; (iv) to the extent required, from other legally available revenues of the Transportation Trust Fund; and (v) from any other available source of funds. All such bonds shall state on their face that the Commonwealth is not obligated to pay the same or the interest thereon except from revenues in clauses (i) and (iii) and that the full faith and credit of the Commonwealth are not pledged to the payment of the principal and interest of such bonds. The issuance of such revenue bonds under the provisions of this chapter shall not directly or indirectly or contingently obligate the Commonwealth to levy or to pledge any form of taxation whatever or to make any appropriation for their payment, other than to appropriate available funds derived as revenues under this chapter from the sources set forth in clauses (i) and (iii). Nothing in this chapter shall be construed to obligate the General Assembly to make any appropriation of the funds set forth in clause (ii) or (iv) for payment of such bonds.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c"/><heading><desig>C.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Commonwealth of Virginia Transportation Revenue Bonds issued under the provisions of this chapter shall not be deemed to constitute a debt of the Commonwealth or a pledge of the full faith and credit of the Commonwealth, but such bonds shall be payable solely from the funds provided therefor pursuant to this chapter (i) from revenues received from the U.S. Route 58 Corridor Development Fund established pursuant to <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 33.2-2300"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 33.2-2300">§ 33.2-2300<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000033#     2#         2300#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, subject to their appropriation by the General Assembly; (ii) to the extent required, from revenues legally available from the Transportation Trust Fund; and (iii) to the extent required, from any other legally available funds that may be appropriated by the General Assembly.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d"/><heading><desig>D.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Commonwealth of Virginia Transportation Revenue Bonds issued under this chapter for Category 1 projects as provided in subdivision 12 of the definition of "project" in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 33.2-1700"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 33.2-1700">§ 33.2-1700<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000033#     2#         1700#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> shall not be deemed to constitute a debt of the Commonwealth or a pledge of the full faith and credit of the Commonwealth. Such bonds shall be payable solely, subject to their appropriation by the General Assembly, (i) first from revenues received from the Northern Virginia Transportation District Fund established pursuant to <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 33.2-2400"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 33.2-2400">§ 33.2-2400<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000033#     2#         2400#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; (ii) to the extent required, from funds appropriated and allocated, pursuant to the highway allocation formula as provided by law, to the highway construction district in which the project to be financed is located or to the city or county in which the project to be financed is located; (iii) to the extent required, from legally available revenues of the Transportation Trust Fund; and (iv) from such other funds that may be appropriated by the General Assembly.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_e"/><heading><desig>E.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Commonwealth of Virginia Transportation Program Revenue Bonds issued under this chapter for projects defined in subdivision 13 of the definition of "project" in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 33.2-1700"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 33.2-1700">§ 33.2-1700<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000033#     2#         1700#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> shall not be deemed to constitute a debt of the Commonwealth or a pledge of the full faith and credit of the Commonwealth. Such bonds shall be payable solely, subject to their appropriation by the General Assembly, (i) first from any revenues received from any Set-aside Fund established by the General Assembly pursuant to <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 58.1-816.1"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 58.1-816.1">§ 58.1-816.1<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000058#     1#        816.1#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; (ii) to the extent required, from revenues received pursuant to any contract with a locality or any alternative mechanism for generation of local revenues for specific funding of a project satisfactory to the Board; (iii) to the extent required, from funds appropriated and allocated, pursuant to the highway allocation formula as provided by law, to the highway construction district in which the project to be financed is located or to the city or county in which the project to be financed is located; (iv) to the extent required, from legally available revenues from the Transportation Trust Fund; and (v) from such other funds that may be appropriated by the General Assembly.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_f"/><heading><desig>F.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Commonwealth of Virginia Federal Highway Reimbursement Anticipation Notes issued under this chapter shall not be deemed to constitute a debt of the Commonwealth or a pledge of the full faith and credit of the Commonwealth, but such obligations shall be payable solely, subject to appropriation by the General Assembly, (i) first from any federal highway reimbursements and any other federal highway assistance received by the Commonwealth; (ii) then, at the discretion of the Board, to the extent required, from legally available revenues of the Transportation Trust Fund; and (iii) then, from such other funds, if any, that are designated by the General Assembly for such purpose.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_g"/><heading><desig>G.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Commonwealth of Virginia Transportation Credit Assistance Revenue Bonds issued under the provisions of this chapter shall not be deemed to constitute a debt of the Commonwealth or a pledge of the full faith and credit of the Commonwealth, but such obligations shall be payable solely, subject to appropriation by the General Assembly, from revenues with respect to or generated by the project being financed thereby and any tolls or other revenues pledged by the Board as security therefor and in accordance with the applicable federal credit assistance authorized with respect to such project by the U.S. Department of Transportation.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_h"/><heading><desig>H.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Commonwealth of Virginia Transportation Capital Projects Revenue Bonds issued under the provisions of this chapter for projects as provided in subdivision 15 of the definition of "project" in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 33.2-1700"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 33.2-1700">§ 33.2-1700<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000033#     2#         1700#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> shall not be deemed to constitute a debt of the Commonwealth or a pledge of the full faith and credit of the Commonwealth, but such bonds shall be payable solely, subject to their appropriation by the General Assembly, (i) from the revenues deposited into the Priority Transportation Fund established pursuant to <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 33.2-1527"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 33.2-1527">§ 33.2-1527<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000033#     2#         1527#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; (ii) to the extent required, from revenues legally available from the Transportation Trust Fund; and (iii) to the extent required, from any other legally available funds.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_i"/><heading><desig>I.</desig></heading><bodyText><p>Commonwealth of Virginia Federal Transportation Grant Anticipation Revenue Notes issued under the provisions of Article 4 (<citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 33.2-1511"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 33.2-1511">§ 33.2-1511<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000033#     2#         1511#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> et seq.) of Chapter 15 and this chapter shall not be deemed to constitute a debt of the Commonwealth or a pledge of the full faith and credit of the Commonwealth, but such notes shall be payable solely, subject to their appropriation by the General Assembly, (i) first from the project-specific reimbursements pursuant to <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 33.2-1520"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 33.2-1520">§ 33.2-1520<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000033#     2#         1520#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; (ii) then, at the discretion of the Board, to the extent required, from legally available revenues of the Transportation Trust Fund; and (iii) then from such other funds, if any, that are designated by the General Assembly for such purpose.</p></bodyText></level><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p>Code 1950, § 33-237; 1970, c. 322, § 33.1-277; 1982, c. 403; 1986, Sp. Sess., c. 13; 1988, cc. 844, 903; 1989, Sp. Sess., cc. 9, 11; <citation normalizedCite="1990 VA CH 710"><content><span normalizedCite="1990 Va. Ch. 710">1990, c. 710<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1990#000710#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1991 VA CH 666"><content><span normalizedCite="1991 Va. Ch. 666">1991, cc. 666<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1991#000666#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1991 VA CH 713"><content><span normalizedCite="1991 Va. Ch. 713">713<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1991#000713#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1993 VA CH 391"><content><span normalizedCite="1993 Va. Ch. 391">1993, cc. 391<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1993#000391#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1993 VA CH 793"><content><span normalizedCite="1993 Va. Ch. 793">793<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1993#000793#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1994 VA CH 233"><content><span normalizedCite="1994 Va. Ch. 233">1994, cc. 233<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1994#000233#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1994 VA CH 520"><content><span normalizedCite="1994 Va. Ch. 520">520<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1994#000520#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1994 VA CH 589"><content><span normalizedCite="1994 Va. Ch. 589">589<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1994#000589#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1994 VA CH 662"><content><span normalizedCite="1994 Va. Ch. 662">662<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1994#000662#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1995 VA CH 354"><content><span normalizedCite="1995 Va. Ch. 354">1995, c. 354<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1995#000354#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2000 VA CH 1019"><content><span normalizedCite="2000 Va. Ch. 1019">2000, cc. 1019<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2000#001019#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2000 VA CH 1044"><content><span normalizedCite="2000 Va. Ch. 1044">1044<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2000#001044#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2004 VA CH 807"><content><span normalizedCite="2004 Va. Ch. 807">2004, c. 807<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2004#000807#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2007 VA CH 896"><content><span normalizedCite="2007 Va. Ch. 896">2007, c. 896<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2007#000896#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2011 VA CH 830"><content><span normalizedCite="2011 Va. Ch. 830">2011, cc. 830<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2011#000830#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2011 VA CH 868"><content><span normalizedCite="2011 Va. Ch. 868">868<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2011#000868#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2014 VA CH 805"><content><span normalizedCite="2014 Va. Ch. 805">2014, c. 805<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2014#000805#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PWB0-004G-K2DG-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 33.2.</desig><title>HIGHWAYS AND OTHER SURFACE TRANSPORTATION SYSTEMS</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="subtitle"><heading><desig>SUBTITLE III.</desig><title>TRANSPORTATION FUNDING AND DEVELOPMENT</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 17.</desig><title>TRANSPORTATION DEVELOPMENT AND REVENUE BOND ACT</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Constitutional Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QkI5QzFFRjAxMEFFNDMxOThENUE1RjVCQUYzQkQ2RjQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OThCMkIwMUI5MDBFNDM2MEJGRTY0QjY5MzY1NEVFMEM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MTlERUYxNzUwQTE1NEIyRkJBRTZCNENDMTQ5QkU3NTM</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Governments</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjdEQjE4OUJDMzQxNDNEMEI0RTI1QUFCMzJENjEwRTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Financing</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Q0QyN0IxRDI1MTE0NDQ3NkEzMzZCMTBCMkE2QkM3RTM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MEY3NUIxODI2RjU2NEY0NzgwMDQyNjFDMEQ1QUExRjM</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Transportation Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RTYzRTk5RDVBQkQ2NDcwQzk2NTU3ODQ5OEE3NDlBNzk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Funding</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QTFFNkIxMEVFQTA2NERDMDhDRUUwNUY2NEQ4MTYyOUM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjVCODE3RDNEMENDNDkxRjg5MzBBNTJFQkNCRDlFOEU</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NTkyRUE5REJENDMwNDE4OTg3OTg5NTg0OEVEOUE3M0E7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjVCODE3RDNEMENDNDkxRjg5MzBBNTJFQkNCRDlFOEU</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification><classificationGroup classificationScheme="indexing-terms"><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem score="90"><className>Transportation</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RTYzRTk5RDVBQkQ2NDcwQzk2NTU3ODQ5OEE3NDlBNzk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></classificationGroup></metadata></legislativeDoc>