<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#349#000038#     2#         5004#">Va. Code Ann. § 38.2-5004</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_38.2-5004"/><heading><desig>§ 38.2-5004.</desig><title>Filing of claims; review by Board of Medicine; review by Department of Health; filing of responses; medical records</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a"/><heading><desig>A.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> 1. In all claims filed under this chapter, the claimant shall file with the Commission a petition, setting forth the following information:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_a"/><heading><desig>a.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The name and address of the legal representative and the basis for his representation of the injured infant;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_b"/><heading><desig>b.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The name and address of the injured infant;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_c"/><heading><desig>c.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The name and address of any physician providing obstetrical services who was present at the birth and the name and address of the hospital at which the birth occurred;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_d"/><heading><desig>d.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A description of the disability for which claim is made;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_e"/><heading><desig>e.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The time and place where the birth-related neurological injury occurred;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_f"/><heading><desig>f.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A brief statement of the facts and circumstances surrounding the birth-related neurological injury and giving rise to the claim;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_g"/><heading><desig>g.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> All available relevant medical records relating to the person who allegedly suffered a birth-related neurological injury and an identification of any unavailable records known to the claimant and the reasons for their unavailability;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_h"/><heading><desig>h.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Appropriate assessments, evaluations, and prognoses and such other records and documents as are reasonably necessary for the determination of the amount of compensation to be paid to, or on behalf of, the injured infant on account of a birth-related neurological injury;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_i"/><heading><desig>i.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Documentation of expenses and services incurred to date, which indicates whether such expenses and services have been paid for, and if so, by whom; and</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_j"/><heading><desig>j.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Documentation of any applicable private or governmental source of services or reimbursement relative to the alleged impairments.</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_j_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The claimant shall furnish the Commission with as many copies of the petition as required for service upon the Program, any physician and hospital named in the petition, the Board of Medicine and the Department of Health, along with a $ 15 filing fee. Upon receipt of the petition the Commission shall immediately serve the Program by service upon the agent designated to accept service on behalf of the Program in the plan of operation by registered or certified mail, and shall mail copies of the petition to any physician and hospital named in the petition, the Board of Medicine and the Department of Health.</p></bodyText></level></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b"/><heading><desig>B.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Upon receipt of the petition or the filing of a claim relating to the conduct of a participating physician, the Department of Health Professions shall investigate the petition or claim, utilizing the same process as it does in investigating complaints filed under any provision contained in Title 54.1. Conduct of health care providers giving rise to disciplinary action shall be referred to the Board of Medicine for action consistent with the authority granted to the Board in Article 2 (<citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 54.1-2911"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 54.1-2911">§ 54.1-2911<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000054#     1#         2911#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> et seq.) of Chapter 29 of Title 54.1. If a notice or order is issued by the Board of Medicine, a copy shall be mailed to the petitioner or claimant.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c"/><heading><desig>C.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Upon receipt of the petition or the filing of a claim relating to the conduct of a participating hospital, the Department of Health shall investigate the petition or claim, utilizing the same process as it does in investigating complaints filed under any provision of Title 32.1. If it determines that there is reason to believe that the alleged injury resulted from, or was aggravated by, substandard care on the part of the hospital at which the birth occurred, it shall take any appropriate action consistent with the authority granted to the Department of Health in Title 32.1.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d"/><heading><desig>D.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The Program shall file a response to the petition and submit relevant written information relating to the issue of whether the injury alleged is a birth-related neurological injury within the meaning of this chapter within 10 days after the date the panel report prepared pursuant to subsection C of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 38.2-5008"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 38.2-5008">§ 38.2-5008<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000038#     2#         5008#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> is filed with the Commission.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_e"/><heading><desig>E.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Any hospital at which a birth occurred, upon receipt of written notice from the legal representative of an injured infant that he intends to file a petition under this chapter, shall promptly deliver to such person all available medical records relating to the infant who allegedly suffered a birth-related neurological injury.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_f"/><heading><desig>F.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> As used in this chapter, fetal monitoring strips, whether printed or in electronic format, shall be deemed to constitute part of the medical records relating to an infant who allegedly suffered a birth-related neurological injury.</p></bodyText></level><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p>1987, c. 540; <citation normalizedCite="1989 VA CH 523"><content><span normalizedCite="1989 Va. Ch. 523">1989, c. 523<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1989#000523#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2003 VA CH 897"><content><span normalizedCite="2003 Va. Ch. 897">2003, c. 897<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2003#000897#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2005 VA CH 50"><content><span normalizedCite="2005 Va. Ch. 50">2005, cc. 50<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2005#000050#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2005 VA CH 52"><content><span normalizedCite="2005 Va. Ch. 52">52<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2005#000052#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2013 VA CH 144"><content><span normalizedCite="2013 Va. Ch. 144">2013, c. 144<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2013#000144#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PT60-004G-K046-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 38.2.</desig><title>INSURANCE</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 50.</desig><title>VIRGINIA BIRTH-RELATED NEUROLOGICAL INJURY COMPENSATION ACT</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classificationGroup classificationScheme="indexing-terms"><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem score="90"><className>Insurance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDM4MzQ2QUYzMTY0NDQzQTkxRDQwRUUzRUM5RDg0OEM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></classificationGroup></metadata></legislativeDoc>