<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#349#000053#     1#          165#">Va. Code Ann. § 53.1-165</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_53.1-165"/><heading><desig>§ 53.1-165.</desig><title>Revocation of parole or postrelease supervision; hearing; procedure for parolee or felon serving period of postrelease supervision in another state; appointment of attorney</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a"/><heading><desig>A.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Whenever any parolee or felon serving a period of postrelease supervision is arrested and recommitted as provided herein, a preliminary hearing to determine probable cause that such parolee has violated one or more of the terms or conditions upon which he was released on parole or postrelease period of supervision shall be held by any hearing officer who has been designated as such by the Director of the Department to conduct such hearings. However, if a nolle prosequi is to be entered in a case where a parole violation is alleged, no preliminary hearing shall be required.</p><p>Upon request of the hearing officer, the attorney for the Commonwealth of the jurisdiction within which such hearings are to be held shall request the circuit court of such jurisdiction to appoint one or more discreet attorneys-at-law to represent parolees in any proceedings held before him. Each attorney so appointed shall be available to serve upon request of the hearing officer. The term of each attorney's appointment shall continue until such time as a successor may be appointed. A hearing officer shall be authorized to issue subpoenas requiring the attendance of witnesses and the production of records, memoranda, papers and other documents before him and to administer oaths and to take testimony thereunder.</p><p>Upon a finding of probable cause by the hearing officer, the Board or its authorized representative shall conduct a hearing, consider the case and act with reference thereto within a reasonable time thereafter. Upon request of the Board, the attorney for the Commonwealth of the jurisdiction within which such hearings are to be held shall request the circuit court of that jurisdiction to appoint one or more discreet attorneys-at-law to represent parolees in proceedings held or to be held before the Board. Each attorney shall be available to serve upon request of the Board. The term of each attorney's appointment shall continue until such time as a successor may be appointed. The Board, in its discretion, may revoke the parole and order the reincarceration of the prisoner for the unserved portion of the term of imprisonment originally imposed upon him, or it may reinstate the parole either upon such terms and conditions as were originally prescribed, or as may be prescribed in addition thereto or in lieu thereof. When a parole violation is based on a new felony conviction for which the individual has been sentenced to two or more years, excluding any time of said sentence which has been suspended, any individual Board member, so authorized by the Board, may after such hearing revoke the individual's parole as otherwise provided herein.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b"/><heading><desig>B.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> In cases in which a parolee or felon serving a period of postrelease supervision is in another state, any hearing officer who has been designated as such by the Director of the Department may be sent to that state to conduct a preliminary hearing to determine probable cause that the parolee has violated one or more of the terms and conditions upon which he was released upon parole.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c"/><heading><desig>C.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Any attorney-at-law appointed pursuant to this section shall be paid as directed by the court making the appointment, from funds appropriated for court costs and expenses, reasonable compensation on an hourly basis and necessary expenses, based upon a report to be furnished to it by such attorney. In the event an attorney-at-law is appointed in another state, he shall be paid out of funds appropriated to the Department.</p></bodyText></level><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p>Code 1950, § 53-262; 1970, c. 648; 1975, c. 292; 1979, cc. 700, 703; 1982, c. 636; 1985, c. 174; 1986, c. 433; <citation normalizedCite="2000 VA CH 767"><content><span normalizedCite="2000 Va. Ch. 767">2000, c. 767<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2000#000767#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PT90-004G-K1T5-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 53.1.</desig><title>PRISONS AND OTHER METHODS OF CORRECTION</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 4.</desig><title>PROBATION AND PAROLE</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="article"><heading><desig>ARTICLE 3.</desig><title>PROCEDURES GOVERNING PAROLE</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Criminal Law &amp; Procedure</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NEU0RkE1OUQwNUQwNDgxODhEODZCMjkzOTg3NThBNzk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OTg0MzAyMENGRjMzNEVDRUI0N0VBMTlCQjU5NTZCOEI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NkFBOUEzNjBDMERGNDRBQzkyQzk5NDlCODc1NDRBQjI</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Q0QwQzJFMDdGNjJDNDI1NkE4MjAzRDFCNjRCMEM0MjU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Rjc1RkU3OTY2QUYyNEM5N0JDRjc4OEZEQ0JFQTQ5OTY</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Parole</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MzU2NUJBMjkzQjE0NEE0OTg3MDQ1QzFDRTI2NUJCRTU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QTFGRjg4NjA3RTg1NDA2RkIzMDk4QzdGREIyQzVGMDk</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Supervised Release</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MTk1NTBBNkYzMDY0NDIyRUE4M0I4MzA3NTU2NTE3NUQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUIzQ0NGRDZERUU3NERCODg2MEZFMDI2RTI0RTA3RTc</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Time Limitations</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QzcwNkI2OTY4MDExNDU5MkE3RDUxRDdCNzczOTNBMEY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Rjc1RkU3OTY2QUYyNEM5N0JDRjc4OEZEQ0JFQTQ5OTY</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></metadata></legislativeDoc>