<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#349#000028#     2#         1300#">Va. Code Ann. § 28.2-1300</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_28.2-1300"/><heading><desig>§ 28.2-1300.</desig><title>Definitions</title></heading><bodyText><p>As used in this chapter, unless the context requires a different meaning:</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Back Bay and its tributaries"</emphasis> means the following, as shown on the United States Geological Survey Quadrangle Sheets for Virginia Beach, North Bay, and Knotts Island: Back Bay north of the Virginia-North Carolina state line; Capsies Creek north of the Virginia-North Carolina state line; Deal Creek; Devil Creek; Nawney Creek; Redhead Bay, Sand Bay, Shipps Bay, North Bay, and the waters connecting them; Beggars Bridge Creek; Muddy Creek; Ashville Bridge Creek; Hells Point Creek; Black Gut; and all coves, ponds and natural waterways adjacent to or connecting with the above-named bodies of water.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"County, city, or town"</emphasis> means the governing body of the county, city, or town.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Governmental activity"</emphasis> means any of the services provided by the Commonwealth or a county, city, or town to its citizens for the purpose of maintaining public facilities, including but not limited to, such services as constructing, repairing and maintaining roads; providing street lights and sewage facilities; supplying and treating water; and constructing public buildings.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Nonvegetated wetlands"</emphasis> means unvegetated lands lying contiguous to mean low water and between mean low water and mean high water, including those unvegetated areas of Back Bay and its tributaries and the North Landing River and its tributaries subject to flooding by normal and wind tides but not hurricane or tropical storm tides.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"North Landing River and its tributaries"</emphasis> means the following, as shown on the United States Geological Survey Quadrangle Sheets for Pleasant Ridge, Creeds, and Fentress: the North Landing River from the Virginia-North Carolina line to Virginia Highway 165 at North Landing Bridge; the Chesapeake and Albemarle Canal from Virginia Highway 165 at North Landing Bridge to the locks at Great Bridge; and all named and unnamed streams, creeks and rivers flowing into the North Landing River and the Chesapeake and Albemarle Canal except West Neck Creek north of Indian River Road, Pocaty River west of Blackwater Road, Blackwater River west of its forks located at a point approximately 6400 feet due west of the point where Blackwater Road crosses the Blackwater River at the village of Blackwater, and Millbank Creek west of Blackwater Road.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Vegetated wetlands"</emphasis> means lands lying between and contiguous to mean low water and an elevation above mean low water equal to the factor one and one-half times the mean tide range at the site of the proposed project in the county, city, or town in question, and upon which is growing any of the following species: saltmarsh cordgrass (<emphasis typeStyle="it">Spartina alterniflora</emphasis>), saltmeadow hay (<emphasis typeStyle="it">Spartina patens</emphasis>), saltgrass (<emphasis typeStyle="it">Distichlis spicata</emphasis>), black needlerush (<emphasis typeStyle="it">Juncus roemerianus</emphasis>), saltwort (<emphasis typeStyle="it">Salicornia</emphasis> spp.), sea lavender (<emphasis typeStyle="it">Limonium </emphasis> spp.), marsh elder (<emphasis typeStyle="it">Iva frutescens</emphasis>), groundsel bush (<emphasis typeStyle="it">Baccharis halimifolia</emphasis>), wax myrtle (<emphasis typeStyle="it">Myrica </emphasis> sp.), sea oxeye (<emphasis typeStyle="it">Borrichia frutescens</emphasis>), arrow arum (<emphasis typeStyle="it">Peltandra virginica</emphasis>), pickerelweed (<emphasis typeStyle="it">Pontederia cordata</emphasis>), big cordgrass (<emphasis typeStyle="it">Spartina cynosuroides</emphasis>), rice cutgrass (<emphasis typeStyle="it">Leersia oryzoides</emphasis>), wildrice (<emphasis typeStyle="it">Zizania aquatica</emphasis>), bulrush (<emphasis typeStyle="it">Scirpus validus</emphasis>), spikerush (<emphasis typeStyle="it">Eleocharis </emphasis> sp.), sea rocket (<emphasis typeStyle="it">Cakile edentula</emphasis>), southern wildrice (<emphasis typeStyle="it">Zizaniopsis miliacea</emphasis>), cattail (<emphasis typeStyle="it">Typha</emphasis> spp.), three-square (<emphasis typeStyle="it">Scirpus</emphasis> spp.), buttonbush (<emphasis typeStyle="it">Cephalanthus occidentalis</emphasis>), bald cypress (<emphasis typeStyle="it">Taxodium distichum</emphasis>), black gum (<emphasis typeStyle="it">Nyssa sylvatica</emphasis>), tupelo (<emphasis typeStyle="it">Nyssa aquatica</emphasis>), dock (<emphasis typeStyle="it">Rumex</emphasis> spp.), yellow pond lily (<emphasis typeStyle="it">Nuphar</emphasis> sp.), marsh fleabane (<emphasis typeStyle="it">Pluchea purpurascens</emphasis>), royal fern (<emphasis typeStyle="it">Osmunda regalis</emphasis>), marsh hibiscus (<emphasis typeStyle="it">Hibiscus moscheutos</emphasis>), beggar's tick (<emphasis typeStyle="it">Bidens</emphasis> sp.), smartweed (<emphasis typeStyle="it">Polygonum</emphasis> sp.), arrowhead (<emphasis typeStyle="it">Sagittaria</emphasis> spp.), sweet flag (<emphasis typeStyle="it">Acorus calamus</emphasis>), water hemp (<emphasis typeStyle="it">Amaranthus cannabinus</emphasis>), reed grass (<emphasis typeStyle="it">Phragmites communis</emphasis>), or switch grass (<emphasis typeStyle="it">Panicum virgatum</emphasis>).</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Vegetated wetlands of Back Bay and its tributaries"</emphasis> or <emphasis typeStyle="it">"vegetated wetlands of the North Landing River and its tributaries"</emphasis> means all marshes subject to flooding by normal and wind tides, but not hurricane or tropical storm tides, and upon which is growing any of the following species: saltmarsh cordgrass (<emphasis typeStyle="it">Spartina alterniflora</emphasis>), saltmeadow hay (<emphasis typeStyle="it">Spartina patens</emphasis>), black needlerush (<emphasis typeStyle="it">Juncus roemerianus</emphasis>), marsh elder (<emphasis typeStyle="it">Iva frutescens</emphasis>), groundsel bush (<emphasis typeStyle="it">Baccharis halimifolia</emphasis>), wax myrtle (<emphasis typeStyle="it">Myrica</emphasis> sp.), arrow arum (<emphasis typeStyle="it">Peltandra virginica</emphasis>), pickerelweed (<emphasis typeStyle="it">Pontederia cordata</emphasis>), big cordgrass (<emphasis typeStyle="it">Spartina cynosuroides</emphasis>), rice cutgrass (<emphasis typeStyle="it">Leersia oryzoides</emphasis>), wildrice (<emphasis typeStyle="it">Zizania aquatica</emphasis>), bulrush (<emphasis typeStyle="it">Scirpus validus</emphasis>), spikerush (<emphasis typeStyle="it">Eleocharis</emphasis> sp.), cattail (<emphasis typeStyle="it">Typha</emphasis> spp.), three-square (<emphasis typeStyle="it">Scirpus</emphasis> spp.), dock (<emphasis typeStyle="it">Rumex</emphasis> sp.), smartweed (<emphasis typeStyle="it">Polygonum</emphasis> sp.), yellow pond lily (<emphasis typeStyle="it">Nuphar</emphasis> sp.), royal fern (<emphasis typeStyle="it">Osmunda regalis</emphasis>), marsh hibiscus (<emphasis typeStyle="it">Hibiscus moscheutos</emphasis>), beggar's tick (<emphasis typeStyle="it">Bidens</emphasis> sp.), arrowhead (<emphasis typeStyle="it">Sagittaria</emphasis> sp.), water hemp (<emphasis typeStyle="it">Amaranthus cannabinus</emphasis>), reed grass (<emphasis typeStyle="it">Phragmites communis</emphasis>), or switch grass (<emphasis typeStyle="it">Panicum virgatum</emphasis>).</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Wetlands"</emphasis> means both vegetated and nonvegetated wetlands.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Wetlands board"</emphasis> or <emphasis typeStyle="it">"board"</emphasis> means a board created pursuant to <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 28.2-1303"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 28.2-1303">§ 28.2-1303<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000028#     2#         1303#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Wetlands zoning ordinance"</emphasis> means the ordinance set forth in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 28.2-1302"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 28.2-1302">§ 28.2-1302<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000028#     2#         1302#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p>1972, c. 711, § 62.1-13.2; 1973, c. 388; 1974, c. 297; 1975, c. 268; 1979, c. 524; 1982, c. 300; <citation normalizedCite="1992 VA CH 836"><content><span normalizedCite="1992 Va. Ch. 836">1992, c. 836<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1992#000836#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PTV0-004G-K41N-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 28.2.</desig><title>FISHERIES AND HABITAT OF THE TIDAL WATERS</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="subtitle"><heading><desig>SUBTITLE III.</desig><title>HABITAT</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 13.</desig><title>WETLANDS</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="article"><heading><desig>ARTICLE 1.</desig><title>GENERAL PROVISIONS</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Environmental Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NzFDRDYyNkI2QjhBNDg3NTkyRjRDRkZEQjlCRkRBQzM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Wetlands Management</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QzY2NjI1NjQ3Qzk2NDE5NzlGQjFDNTkzQjg5QTAyMkQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NTkwMDY1RDExQ0YwNDQ1RTlERUVFMjUzMUI1MkFDOTU</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Governments</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjdEQjE4OUJDMzQxNDNEMEI0RTI1QUFCMzJENjEwRTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Boundaries</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Qzg0MTI1ODBDMUY1NDUzN0JGRUQwMTYwQTlCMzAzRkE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QURCRDNBRjBGRTE0NEFBRUEzNUU1MzFGQjg3MTM4MDI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></metadata></legislativeDoc>