<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#349#000038#     2#       1301.1#">Va. Code Ann. § 38.2-1301.1</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_38.2-1301.1"/><heading><desig>§ 38.2-1301.1.</desig><title>Material transaction disclosures</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a"/><heading><desig>A.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Every insurer domiciled in this Commonwealth shall file a report with the Commission disclosing material acquisitions and dispositions of assets or material nonrenewals, cancellations or revisions of ceded reinsurance agreements unless such acquisitions and dispositions of assets or material nonrenewals, cancellations or revisions of ceded reinsurance agreements have been submitted to the Commission for review, approval or information purposes pursuant to other provisions of Title 38.2 or the rules and regulations of the Commission.</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The report required by this subsection is due within fifteen days after the end of the calendar month in which any of the foregoing transactions occur.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> One complete copy of the report, including any exhibits or other attachments filed as part thereof, shall be filed with the National Association of Insurance Commissioners unless the insurer has applied for and has been granted an exemption from this requirement by the Commission.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b"/><heading><desig>B.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> All reports obtained by or disclosed to the Commission pursuant to this section, shall be given confidential treatment, shall not be subject to subpoena, and shall not be made public by the Commission, the National Association of Insurance Commissioners, or any other person without the prior written consent of the insurer to which it pertains unless the Commission, after giving the insurer which would be affected thereby, notice and an opportunity to be heard, determines that the interest of policyholders, shareholders, or the public will be served by the publication thereof, in which event the Commission may publish all or any part thereof in such manner as it may deem appropriate. Notwithstanding the foregoing, the Commission may at its discretion disclose such reports to (i) a regulatory official of any state or country; (ii) the National Association of Insurance Commissioners, its affiliate or its subsidiary; or (iii) a law-enforcement authority of any state or country. Any such disclosure by the Commission shall not constitute a waiver of confidentiality of any such report.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c"/><heading><desig>C.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> No acquisitions or dispositions of assets need be reported pursuant to subsection A if the acquisitions or dispositions are not material. For purposes of this section, a material acquisition, or the aggregate of any series of related acquisitions during any thirty-day period, or disposition, or the aggregate of any series of related dispositions during any thirty-day period, is one that is nonrecurring and not in the ordinary course of business and involves more than five percent of the reporting insurer's total admitted assets as reported in its most recent statutory statement filed with the Commission.</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Asset acquisitions subject to this section include every purchase, lease, exchange, merger, consolidation, succession, or other acquisition other than the construction or development of real property by or for the reporting insurer or the acquisition of materials for such purpose.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Asset dispositions subject to this section include every sale, lease, exchange, merger, consolidation, mortgage, pledge or hypothecation, assignment, whether for the benefit of creditors or otherwise, abandonment, destruction, or other disposition.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The following information is required to be disclosed in any report of a material acquisition or disposition of assets:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c_3_a"/><heading><desig>a.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Date of the transaction;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c_3_b"/><heading><desig>b.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Manner of acquisition or disposition;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c_3_c"/><heading><desig>c.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Description of the assets involved;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c_3_d"/><heading><desig>d.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Nature and amount of the consideration given or received;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c_3_e"/><heading><desig>e.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Purpose of, or reason for, the transaction;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c_3_f"/><heading><desig>f.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Manner by which the amount of consideration was determined;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c_3_g"/><heading><desig>g.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Gain or loss recognized or realized as a result of the transaction; and</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c_3_h"/><heading><desig>h.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Name of all persons from whom the assets were acquired or to whom they were disposed.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c_4"/><heading><desig>4.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Insurers are required to report material acquisitions and dispositions on a nonconsolidated basis unless the insurer is part of a consolidated group of insurers which utilizes a pooling arrangement or 100 percent reinsurance agreement that affects the solvency and integrity of the insurer's reserves and such insurer ceded substantially all of its direct and assumed business to the pool. An insurer is deemed to have ceded substantially all of its direct and assumed business to a pool if the insurer has less than one million dollars total direct plus assumed written premiums during a calendar year that are not subject to a pooling arrangement and the net income of the business not subject to the pooling arrangement represents less than five percent of the insurer's capital and surplus.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d"/><heading><desig>D.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> No nonrenewals, cancellations or revisions of ceded reinsurance agreements need be reported pursuant to this section if the nonrenewals, cancellations or revisions are not material. For purposes of this section, a material nonrenewal, cancellation or revision is one that affects for property and casualty business, including accident and health business when written as such, more than fifty percent of an insurer's ceded written premium, or for life, annuity and accident and health business, more than fifty percent of the total reserve credit taken for business ceded, on an annualized basis as indicated in the insurer's most recently filed statutory statement; however, no filing is required if the insurer's ceded written premium or the total reserve credit taken for business ceded represents, on an annualized basis, less than ten percent of direct plus assumed written premium or ten percent of the statutory reserve requirement prior to any cession, respectively.</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Subject to the foregoing criteria, a report is to be filed without regard to which party has initiated the nonrenewal, cancellation or revision of ceded reinsurance whenever one or more of the following conditions exist:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d_1_a"/><heading><desig>a.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The entire cession has been cancelled, nonrenewed or revised and ceded indemnity and loss adjustment expense reserves after any nonrenewal, cancellation or revision represent less than fifty percent of the comparable reserves that would have been ceded had the nonrenewal, cancellation or revision not occurred;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d_1_b"/><heading><desig>b.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> An authorized or accredited reinsurer has been replaced on an existing cession by an unauthorizing reinsurer; or</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d_1_c"/><heading><desig>c.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Collateral requirements previously established for unauthorized reinsurers have been reduced; e.g., the requirement to collateralize incurred but not reported (IBNR) claim reserves has been waived with respect to one or more unauthorized reinsurers newly participating in an existing cession.</p><p><pre/>Subject to the materiality criteria, for purposes of the foregoing subdivisions b and c, a report shall be filed if the result of the revision affects more than ten percent of the cession.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The following information is required to be disclosed in any report of a material nonrenewal, cancellation or revision of ceded reinsurance agreements:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d_2_a"/><heading><desig>a.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Effective date of the nonrenewal, cancellation or revision;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d_2_b"/><heading><desig>b.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The description of the transaction with an identification of the initiator thereof;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d_2_c"/><heading><desig>c.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Purpose of, or reason for, the transaction; and</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d_2_d"/><heading><desig>d.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> If applicable, the identity of the replacement reinsurers.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Insurers are required to report all material nonrenewals, cancellations or revisions of ceded reinsurance agreements on a nonconsolidated basis unless the insurer is part of a consolidated group of insurers which utilizes a pooling arrangement or 100 percent reinsurance agreement that affects the solvency and integrity of the insurer's reserves and such insurer ceded substantially all of its direct and assumed business to the pool. An insurer is deemed to have ceded substantially all of its direct and assumed business to a pool if the insurer has less than one million dollars total direct plus assumed written premiums during a calendar year that are not subject to a pooling arrangement and the net income of the business not subject to the pooling arrangement represents less than five percent of the insurer's capital and surplus.</p></bodyText></level></level><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p><citation normalizedCite="1994 VA CH 308"><content><span normalizedCite="1994 Va. Ch. 308">1994, c. 308<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1994#000308#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2001 VA CH 519"><content><span normalizedCite="2001 Va. Ch. 519">2001, c. 519<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2001#000519#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PV00-004G-K0K0-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 38.2.</desig><title>INSURANCE</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 13.</desig><title>REPORTS, RESERVES AND EXAMINATIONS, INSURANCE HOLDING COMPANIES, REINSURANCE INTERMEDIARIES, AND MANAGING GENERAL AGENTS</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="article"><heading><desig>ARTICLE 1.</desig><title>ANNUAL STATEMENTS AND OTHER REPORTS</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>National Association of Insurance Commissioners</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RjBFNEI1QTM2QzNBNDlGNkI3NkQ3MjAxRTI1RDlGRjQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MEFDQTNCQjMxQjJDNEYwOTlEMUEwRUUzNDI5RUY3RjI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Contracts Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QzY0RTZFMzE0RjkwNDdFQUI5M0U5N0ZFMjYyREMyQzU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QTdGQUE3QkZDMDlBNDQ1MTkzRjEzMEQ1OEUwNzdDOTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NjZEOEU3MEJBRUQ2NDNFNzhFRjAxRTk1OEU1QjY2QTc</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Insurance Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDM4MzQ2QUYzMTY0NDQzQTkxRDQwRUUzRUM5RDg0OEM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Cancellation &amp; Nonrenewal</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjhEQjkxRkRCODk0NDMxOTlCOTA3RURGNDIzQjI5MEU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDI3MjQ3NDBDODZENDNCNUJCNzgwNzgwQTBGNDkxRTQ</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Disclosure Obligations</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RjA2NDFCMkQxMDA5NDNDQUIyOUQyQTY0MTQ4OTE4MjI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDI3MjQ3NDBDODZENDNCNUJCNzgwNzgwQTBGNDkxRTQ</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RkU4NDVDMDk5ODlBNEQxNkFGRTFFRTM5RkI1RjBCQ0M7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MEFDQTNCQjMxQjJDNEYwOTlEMUEwRUUzNDI5RUY3RjI</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MTFDNEI4Q0Y0MTk0NDgyRTkzOEY5NDY2ODM1MkJFRUY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QzZFRUM3RDQ3M0Y1NDc1RUE2N0E4M0ZGQjY0MDk1MTY</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NzA4NzhCMTQ4MTk0NDY3NDkzQjM5QjJDMEFGODk1RUM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDI3MjQ3NDBDODZENDNCNUJCNzgwNzgwQTBGNDkxRTQ</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>National Association of Insurance Commissioners</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RjBFNEI1QTM2QzNBNDlGNkI3NkQ3MjAxRTI1RDlGRjQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MEFDQTNCQjMxQjJDNEYwOTlEMUEwRUUzNDI5RUY3RjI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Mergers &amp; Acquisitions Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjRDRTUzQzBCMEIyNDU5QkE4QjFDMEE2Qjg2MUZDOTk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QzZFQzQyQUJEMzIxNEYyRTkyM0M2NDhGN0FGNzhFOTc7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjRDRTUzQzBCMEIyNDU5QkE4QjFDMEE2Qjg2MUZDOTk</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Real Property Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QUUyRTcxRURBNEY2NEE2MDk3QzBCNzRDOEY0NTZDQzk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Assignments</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6ODVCN0FCRTQ3MEE4NEJCRkE3OTRGOUQzODE4RDZENjc7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDU3NDIyNUI2MzczNEUwMzk0M0Y4MkZDQjk2OUUyRTQ</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Merger</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OUNGRkQ4NUQ3NkM4NDE3MEE2QzdEQTAzODlBQ0JFMTE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NTRCMjc5NjMyQ0E1NDM3QkJBN0ZGRjYyNUYzNzE1RDc</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Tax Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OTNEM0E2OEE0RkQyNEY1MDhBQzdGMkQ4ODI4QTJDODE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Reinsurance Agreements</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NjBGMjBCRkRCQzYyNEYxRjgzQzVERkEyOTFGMTc3MEI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjhFOUYzNjI1QTZDNDMxNEEyRUI3NEEwODBGMjNGQjA</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification><classificationGroup classificationScheme="indexing-terms"><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem score="90"><className>Insurance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDM4MzQ2QUYzMTY0NDQzQTkxRDQwRUUzRUM5RDg0OEM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></classificationGroup></metadata></legislativeDoc>