<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#349#000054#     1#         2900#">Va. Code Ann. § 54.1-2900</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_54.1-2900"/><heading><desig>§ 54.1-2900.</desig><title>Definitions</title></heading><bodyText><p>As used in this chapter, unless the context requires a different meaning:</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Acupuncturist"</emphasis> means an individual approved by the Board to practice acupuncture. This is limited to "licensed acupuncturist" which means an individual other than a doctor of medicine, osteopathy, chiropractic or podiatry who has successfully completed the requirements for licensure established by the Board (approved titles are limited to: Licensed Acupuncturist, Lic.Ac., and L.Ac.).</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Auricular acupuncture"</emphasis> means the subcutaneous insertion of sterile, disposable acupuncture needles in predetermined, bilateral locations in the outer ear when used exclusively and specifically in the context of a chemical dependency treatment program.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Board"</emphasis> means the Board of Medicine.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Certified nurse midwife"</emphasis> means an advanced practice registered nurse who is certified in the specialty of nurse midwifery and who is jointly licensed by the Boards of Medicine and Nursing as a nurse practitioner pursuant to <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 54.1-2957"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 54.1-2957">§ 54.1-2957<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000054#     1#         2957#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Certified registered nurse anesthetist"</emphasis> means an advanced practice registered nurse who is certified in the specialty of nurse anesthesia, who is jointly licensed by the Boards of Medicine and Nursing as a nurse practitioner pursuant to <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 54.1-2957"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 54.1-2957">§ 54.1-2957<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000054#     1#         2957#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, and who practices under the supervision of a doctor of medicine, osteopathy, podiatry, or dentistry but is not subject to the practice agreement requirement described in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 54.1-2957"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 54.1-2957">§ 54.1-2957<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000054#     1#         2957#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Genetic counselor"</emphasis> means a person licensed by the Board to engage in the practice of genetic counseling.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Healing arts"</emphasis> means the arts and sciences dealing with the prevention, diagnosis, treatment and cure or alleviation of human physical or mental ailments, conditions, diseases, pain or infirmities.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Medical malpractice judgment"</emphasis> means any final order of any court entering judgment against a licensee of the Board that arises out of any tort action or breach of contract action for personal injuries or wrongful death, based on health care or professional services rendered, or that should have been rendered, by a health care provider, to a patient.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Medical malpractice settlement"</emphasis> means any written agreement and release entered into by or on behalf of a licensee of the Board in response to a written claim for money damages that arises out of any personal injuries or wrongful death, based on health care or professional services rendered, or that should have been rendered, by a health care provider, to a patient.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Nurse practitioner"</emphasis> means an advanced practice registered nurse who is jointly licensed by the Boards of Medicine and Nursing pursuant to <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 54.1-2957"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 54.1-2957">§ 54.1-2957<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000054#     1#         2957#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Occupational therapy assistant"</emphasis> means an individual who has met the requirements of the Board for licensure and who works under the supervision of a licensed occupational therapist to assist in the practice of occupational therapy.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Patient care team"</emphasis> means a multidisciplinary team of health care providers actively functioning as a unit with the management and leadership of one or more patient care team physicians for the purpose of providing and delivering health care to a patient or group of patients.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Patient care team physician"</emphasis> means a physician who is actively licensed to practice medicine in the Commonwealth, who regularly practices medicine in the Commonwealth, and who provides management and leadership in the care of patients as part of a patient care team.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Physician assistant"</emphasis> means an individual who has met the requirements of the Board for licensure and who works under the supervision of a licensed doctor of medicine, osteopathy, or podiatry.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Practice of acupuncture"</emphasis> means the stimulation of certain points on or near the surface of the body by the insertion of needles to prevent or modify the perception of pain or to normalize physiological functions, including pain control, for the treatment of certain ailments or conditions of the body and includes the techniques of electroacupuncture, cupping and moxibustion. The practice of acupuncture does not include the use of physical therapy, chiropractic, or osteopathic manipulative techniques; the use or prescribing of any drugs, medications, serums or vaccines; or the procedure of auricular acupuncture as exempted in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 54.1-2901"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 54.1-2901">§ 54.1-2901<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000054#     1#         2901#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> when used in the context of a chemical dependency treatment program for patients eligible for federal, state or local public funds by an employee of the program who is trained and approved by the National Acupuncture Detoxification Association or an equivalent certifying body.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Practice of athletic training"</emphasis> means the prevention, recognition, evaluation, and treatment of injuries or conditions related to athletic or recreational activity that requires physical skill and utilizes strength, power, endurance, speed, flexibility, range of motion or agility or a substantially similar injury or condition resulting from occupational activity immediately upon the onset of such injury or condition; and subsequent treatment and rehabilitation of such injuries or conditions under the direction of the patient's physician or under the direction of any doctor of medicine, osteopathy, chiropractic, podiatry, or dentistry, while using heat, light, sound, cold, electricity, exercise or mechanical or other devices.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Practice of behavior analysis"</emphasis> means the design, implementation, and evaluation of environmental modifications, using behavioral stimuli and consequences, to produce socially significant improvement in human behavior, including the use of direct observation, measurement, and functional analysis of the relationship between environment and behavior.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Practice of chiropractic"</emphasis> means the adjustment of the 24 movable vertebrae of the spinal column, and assisting nature for the purpose of normalizing the transmission of nerve energy, but does not include the use of surgery, obstetrics, osteopathy or the administration or prescribing of any drugs, medicines, serums or vaccines.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Practice of genetic counseling"</emphasis> means (i) obtaining and evaluating individual and family medical histories to assess the risk of genetic medical conditions and diseases in a patient, his offspring, and other family members; (ii) discussing the features, history, diagnosis, environmental factors, and risk management of genetic medical conditions and diseases; (iii) ordering genetic laboratory tests and other diagnostic studies necessary for genetic assessment; (iv) integrating the results with personal and family medical history to assess and communicate risk factors for genetic medical conditions and diseases; (v) evaluating the patient's and family's responses to the medical condition or risk of recurrence and providing client-centered counseling and anticipatory guidance; (vi) identifying and utilizing community resources that provide medical, educational, financial, and psychosocial support and advocacy; and (vii) providing written documentation of medical, genetic, and counseling information for families and health care professionals.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Practice of medicine or osteopathic medicine"</emphasis> means the prevention, diagnosis and treatment of human physical or mental ailments, conditions, diseases, pain or infirmities by any means or method.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Practice of occupational therapy"</emphasis> means the therapeutic use of occupations for habilitation and rehabilitation to enhance physical health, mental health, and cognitive functioning and includes the evaluation, analysis, assessment, and delivery of education and training in basic and instrumental activities of daily living; the design, fabrication, and application of orthoses (splints); the design, selection, and use of adaptive equipment and assistive technologies; therapeutic activities to enhance functional performance; vocational evaluation and training; and consultation concerning the adaptation of physical, sensory, and social environments.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Practice of podiatry"</emphasis> means the prevention, diagnosis, treatment, and cure or alleviation of physical conditions, diseases, pain, or infirmities of the human foot and ankle, including the medical, mechanical and surgical treatment of the ailments of the human foot and ankle, but does not include amputation of the foot proximal to the transmetatarsal level through the metatarsal shafts. Amputations proximal to the metatarsal-phalangeal joints may only be performed in a hospital or ambulatory surgery facility accredited by an organization listed in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 54.1-2939"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 54.1-2939">§ 54.1-2939<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000054#     1#         2939#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>. The practice includes the diagnosis and treatment of lower extremity ulcers; however, the treatment of severe lower extremity ulcers proximal to the foot and ankle may only be performed by appropriately trained, credentialed podiatrists in an approved hospital or ambulatory surgery center at which the podiatrist has privileges, as described in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 54.1-2939"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 54.1-2939">§ 54.1-2939<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000054#     1#         2939#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>. The Board of Medicine shall determine whether a specific type of treatment of the foot and ankle is within the scope of practice of podiatry.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Practice of radiologic technology"</emphasis> means the application of ionizing radiation to human beings for diagnostic or therapeutic purposes.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Practice of respiratory care"</emphasis> means the (i) administration of pharmacological, diagnostic, and therapeutic agents related to respiratory care procedures necessary to implement a treatment, disease prevention, pulmonary rehabilitative, or diagnostic regimen prescribed by a practitioner of medicine or osteopathic medicine; (ii) transcription and implementation of the written or verbal orders of a practitioner of medicine or osteopathic medicine pertaining to the practice of respiratory care; (iii) observation and monitoring of signs and symptoms, general behavior, general physical response to respiratory care treatment and diagnostic testing, including determination of whether such signs, symptoms, reactions, behavior or general physical response exhibit abnormal characteristics; and (iv) implementation of respiratory care procedures, based on observed abnormalities, or appropriate reporting, referral, respiratory care protocols or changes in treatment pursuant to the written or verbal orders by a licensed practitioner of medicine or osteopathic medicine or the initiation of emergency procedures, pursuant to the Board's regulations or as otherwise authorized by law. The practice of respiratory care may be performed in any clinic, hospital, skilled nursing facility, private dwelling or other place deemed appropriate by the Board in accordance with the written or verbal order of a practitioner of medicine or osteopathic medicine, and shall be performed under qualified medical direction.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Qualified medical direction"</emphasis> means, in the context of the practice of respiratory care, having readily accessible to the respiratory therapist a licensed practitioner of medicine or osteopathic medicine who has specialty training or experience in the management of acute and chronic respiratory disorders and who is responsible for the quality, safety, and appropriateness of the respiratory services provided by the respiratory therapist.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Radiologic technologist"</emphasis> means an individual, other than a licensed doctor of medicine, osteopathy, podiatry, or chiropractic or a dentist licensed pursuant to Chapter 27 (<citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 54.1-2700"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 54.1-2700">§ 54.1-2700<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000054#     1#         2700#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> et seq.), who (i) performs, may be called upon to perform, or is licensed to perform a comprehensive scope of diagnostic or therapeutic radiologic procedures employing ionizing radiation and (ii) is delegated or exercises responsibility for the operation of radiation-generating equipment, the shielding of patient and staff from unnecessary radiation, the appropriate exposure of radiographs, the administration of radioactive chemical compounds under the direction of an authorized user as specified by regulations of the Department of Health, or other procedures that contribute to any significant extent to the site or dosage of ionizing radiation to which a patient is exposed.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Radiologic technologist, limited"</emphasis> means an individual, other than a licensed radiologic technologist, dental hygienist, or person who is otherwise authorized by the Board of Dentistry under Chapter 27 (<citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 54.1-2700"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 54.1-2700">§ 54.1-2700<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000054#     1#         2700#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> et seq.) and the regulations pursuant thereto, who performs diagnostic radiographic procedures employing equipment that emits ionizing radiation that is limited to specific areas of the human body.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Radiologist assistant"</emphasis> means an individual who has met the requirements of the Board for licensure as an advanced-level radiologic technologist and who, under the direct supervision of a licensed doctor of medicine or osteopathy specializing in the field of radiology, is authorized to (i) assess and evaluate the physiological and psychological responsiveness of patients undergoing radiologic procedures; (ii) evaluate image quality, make initial observations, and communicate observations to the supervising radiologist; (iii) administer contrast media or other medications prescribed by the supervising radiologist; and (iv) perform, or assist the supervising radiologist to perform, any other procedure consistent with the guidelines adopted by the American College of Radiology, the American Society of Radiologic Technologists, and the American Registry of Radiologic Technologists.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Respiratory care"</emphasis> means the practice of the allied health profession responsible for the direct and indirect services, including inhalation therapy and respiratory therapy, in the treatment, management, diagnostic testing, control, and care of patients with deficiencies and abnormalities associated with the cardiopulmonary system under qualified medical direction.</p></bodyText><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p>Code 1950, § 54-273; 1950, p. 110; 1958, c. 161; 1960, c. 268; 1966, c. 657; 1970, c. 69; 1973, c. 529; 1975, cc. 508, 512; 1977, c. 127; 1980, c. 157; 1986, c. 439; 1987, cc. 522, 543; 1988, cc. 737, 765; <citation normalizedCite="1991 VA CH 643"><content><span normalizedCite="1991 Va. Ch. 643">1991, c. 643<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1991#000643#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1994 VA CH 803"><content><span normalizedCite="1994 Va. Ch. 803">1994, c. 803<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1994#000803#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1995 VA CH 777"><content><span normalizedCite="1995 Va. Ch. 777">1995, c. 777<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1995#000777#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1996 VA CH 152"><content><span normalizedCite="1996 Va. Ch. 152">1996, cc. 152<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1996#000152#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1996 VA CH 158"><content><span normalizedCite="1996 Va. Ch. 158">158<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1996#000158#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1996 VA CH 470"><content><span normalizedCite="1996 Va. Ch. 470">470<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1996#000470#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1996 VA CH 937"><content><span normalizedCite="1996 Va. Ch. 937">937<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1996#000937#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1996 VA CH 980"><content><span normalizedCite="1996 Va. Ch. 980">980<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1996#000980#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1998 VA CH 319"><content><span normalizedCite="1998 Va. Ch. 319">1998, cc. 319<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1998#000319#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1998 VA CH 557"><content><span normalizedCite="1998 Va. Ch. 557">557<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1998#000557#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1998 VA CH 593"><content><span normalizedCite="1998 Va. Ch. 593">593<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1998#000593#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1999 VA CH 639"><content><span normalizedCite="1999 Va. Ch. 639">1999, cc. 639<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1999#000639#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1999 VA CH 682"><content><span normalizedCite="1999 Va. Ch. 682">682<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1999#000682#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1999 VA CH 747"><content><span normalizedCite="1999 Va. Ch. 747">747<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1999#000747#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1999 VA CH 779"><content><span normalizedCite="1999 Va. Ch. 779">779<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1999#000779#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2000 VA CH 688"><content><span normalizedCite="2000 Va. Ch. 688">2000, cc. 688<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2000#000688#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2000 VA CH 814"><content><span normalizedCite="2000 Va. Ch. 814">814<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2000#000814#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2001 VA CH 533"><content><span normalizedCite="2001 Va. Ch. 533">2001, c. 533<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2001#000533#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2004 VA CH 731"><content><span normalizedCite="2004 Va. Ch. 731">2004, c. 731<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2004#000731#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2007 VA CH 861"><content><span normalizedCite="2007 Va. Ch. 861">2007, c. 861<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2007#000861#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2008 VA CH 64"><content><span normalizedCite="2008 Va. Ch. 64">2008, cc. 64<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2008#000064#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2008 VA CH 89"><content><span normalizedCite="2008 Va. Ch. 89">89<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2008#000089#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2009 VA CH 83"><content><span normalizedCite="2009 Va. Ch. 83">2009, cc. 83<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2009#000083#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2009 VA CH 507"><content><span normalizedCite="2009 Va. Ch. 507">507<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2009#000507#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2010 VA CH 715"><content><span normalizedCite="2010 Va. Ch. 715">2010, cc. 715<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2010#000715#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2010 VA CH 725"><content><span normalizedCite="2010 Va. Ch. 725">725<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2010#000725#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2011 VA CH 121"><content><span normalizedCite="2011 Va. Ch. 121">2011, cc. 121<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2011#000121#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2011 VA CH 187"><content><span normalizedCite="2011 Va. Ch. 187">187<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2011#000187#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2012 VA CH 3"><content><span normalizedCite="2012 Va. Ch. 3">2012, cc. 3<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2012#000003#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2012 VA CH 110"><content><span normalizedCite="2012 Va. Ch. 110">110<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2012#000110#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2012 VA CH 168"><content><span normalizedCite="2012 Va. Ch. 168">168<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2012#000168#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2012 VA CH 213"><content><span normalizedCite="2012 Va. Ch. 213">213<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2012#000213#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2012 VA CH 399"><content><span normalizedCite="2012 Va. Ch. 399">399<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2012#000399#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2014 VA CH 10"><content><span normalizedCite="2014 Va. Ch. 10">2014, cc. 10<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2014#000010#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2014 VA CH 266"><content><span normalizedCite="2014 Va. Ch. 266">266<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2014#000266#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2015 VA CH 302"><content><span normalizedCite="2015 Va. Ch. 302">2015, c. 302<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2015#000302#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2016 VA CH 93"><content><span normalizedCite="2016 Va. Ch. 93">2016, c. 93<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2016#000093#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PV00-004G-K0NX-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 54.1.</desig><title>PROFESSIONS AND OCCUPATIONS</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="subtitle"><heading><desig>SUBTITLE III.</desig><title>PROFESSIONS AND OCCUPATIONS REGULATED BY BOARDS WITHIN THE DEPARTMENT OF HEALTH PROFESSIONS</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 29.</desig><title>MEDICINE AND OTHER HEALING ARTS</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="article"><heading><desig>ARTICLE 1.</desig><title>GENERAL PROVISIONS</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Accreditation</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MzkwMTVGOURFMEQ2NEY2NkIyNjA2MzhGM0Q3QUQ5QzA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MkIwM0E1RTM4NkY5NEU4QjhBM0RCNzc5QjE4RkIzOEI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Criminal Law &amp; Procedure</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NEU0RkE1OUQwNUQwNDgxODhEODZCMjkzOTg3NThBNzk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Procedures</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDU4NEVEMTk0MjdCNEZEMjkwRkIyQkJEQzdBOTk3NkQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6N0Q1RkU0RjMyODE0NDZENkE0RjkyQ0FFODNGNkVGNkY</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Energy &amp; Utilities Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OUUzODAyRDk1QzVFNEZGMEJDM0RGMDYxOTlEMEEzRDA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Licenses &amp; Permits</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MEMwNTcyRkUwODY4NDcyNEE4NEU0Qjc1NzlGMDRGOEM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RkRGQUUxMjkwNTk3NDc4REJDM0I0M0IwNkVGMzVBNzY</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Healthcare Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NkUxMkVDQjJDOEY5NDVDQ0E5NTFEMTlDMjIwNzVERjc7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Accreditation</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MzkwMTVGOURFMEQ2NEY2NkIyNjA2MzhGM0Q3QUQ5QzA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MkIwM0E1RTM4NkY5NEU4QjhBM0RCNzc5QjE4RkIzOEI</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6N0U1NEQ5NkFBQjhENEUyMjhDMjM2MjRFQkVBOTFDODI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MkIwM0E1RTM4NkY5NEU4QjhBM0RCNzc5QjE4RkIzOEI</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NTVDMzIyNkJCMTRBNDI0NUJBOTlBOTYyMjQ0MDkyODU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QTJGRDdFQzgwODczNDI0NDgwMzEyM0JBOEQ2MUVDNjg</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Nursing Facilities</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OTk0NDgxMUUxM0MzNDI5QzhDNEVGNzkwODVFN0MxRDg7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QUVDOEU4Qjg3REQzNEYxNDhCMUNGNzQ5NzNBRTVGNDk</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Personnel Licensing</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6M0VCMTAwM0MwNDA1NEI4OThDNUVEMEIwRTJDQjU2QTM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QTJGRDdFQzgwODczNDI0NDgwMzEyM0JBOEQ2MUVDNjg</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Torts</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDAwOEM2NTEzQkVDNEI4NzlGMEZERUEyRjQwODM4Njg7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Healthcare Providers</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OTYwQjdFN0UwQUY1NEYwNEJGNkRBNTRCMzUwMjM5Q0Q7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjkzQzRCMDhBOTZDNEY4NkE0Q0E1ODk5MDM2MUNGNkI</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Pain &amp; Suffering</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MEE1NDc3MjM4M0JDNEZCMUFGMDc4MzM5MzY4MzZENDU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjJENjFDNDAxREQ4NDY3MkIwOEQ3NkM0OTgwQjMyOEI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Workers' Compensation &amp; SSDI</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NTNGOEUzQTYwRUQ1NEFCN0FGMjg0Rjc5MjI3NjBDMEI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Recreational &amp; Social Activities</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6N0JFQjdEMzU1RjQ4NDRDNzg5RjAxMDE0MTIxRkNCN0E7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NjRFQzcxNzJCMDk1NDAzQzhCMDcxRTRFNTFCQ0ZBN0Q</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification><classificationGroup classificationScheme="indexing-terms"><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem score="90"><className>Businesses &amp; Corporations</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjA4OEVGODBENzY4NDcxM0IyQzA1OTEwQzVDODRBOUE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></classificationGroup></metadata></legislativeDoc>