<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#349#000015#     2#       1636.8#">Va. Code Ann. § 15.2-1636.8</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="hierarchy-note"><note><bodyText><p>This section has more than one version with varying effective dates.  To view a complete list of the versions of this section see Table of Contents.</p></bodyText></note><heading><title>§ 15.2-1636.8. (For applicability, see note) Duties of Board in fixing salaries, expenses, etc</title></heading><bodyText><p>All salaries of such officers shall be as hereinafter provided. The expenses and other allowances of all such officers shall be fixed and determined on or before May 1 of each year. The Board shall, no later than the fifteenth day following final adjournment of the General Assembly of Virginia in each session, provide to such officers and the local governing body of each city and county he represents, an estimate of expenses and other allowances to be fixed by the Board for the next fiscal year. The Board shall, at meetings duly called by the chairman, carefully consider the questionnaires and written requests filed as required by <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 15.2-1636.7"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 15.2-1636.7">§ 15.2-1636.7<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000015#     2#       1636.7#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> and consider the work involved in the discharge of the duties of the respective officers, the extent to which such duties are imposed by actions of the local governing body, the amount expended or proposed to be expended by each for clerks, deputies and other assistants, the efficiency with which the affairs of each such office are conducted, and such other matters as the Board may deem pertinent and material, including the number of local governments served if more than one, including the pay and compensation plan of each political subdivision, if it has one, and the locality's plans for adjustments of salaries and expenses for the ensuing fiscal year, as well as the plan of the Commonwealth for adjustment of state salaries and expenses for such year. The Board shall fix and determine what constitutes a fair and reasonable budget for the participation of the Commonwealth toward the total cost of the office. Such budgets, in the aggregate, shall not contemplate state expenditures in excess of the appropriation available to the Board. Prior to holding any such meeting for the fixing of salaries and expenses as provided in this article, ten days' written notice of the time, place and purpose of such meeting shall be given every officer affected and to the mayor or city manager of the city or to the chairman of the governing body and administrator, executive or manager of the county affected.</p><p>When the salaries, expenses and other allowances for the several counties and cities have been tentatively fixed by the Board they shall notify the governing body of each city and county of the amounts so fixed. Within thirty days thereafter, but not later, the governing body may file with the Compensation Board any objection it may have to such allowances so fixed. When such objection is filed the Board shall fix a time for a hearing on such objection, of which time the governing body as well as the officer affected shall have at least fifteen days' notice. For the purpose of determining the merits of such protest the governing body may designate two members of such body to serve as additional members of the Compensation Board and such additional members shall each have one vote on the Board.</p><p>The chairman of the Board shall record the salary of each such officer, his clerks, assistants and deputies, and the allowances made for other items, and shall promptly notify each such officer of the same with respect to his office.</p><p>In fixing, determining and recording the salaries of the full-time deputy sheriffs mentioned in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 15.2-1609.2"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 15.2-1609.2">§ 15.2-1609.2<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000015#     2#       1609.2#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, the Board shall act solely with reference to establishing an aggregate allowance for personal services to the respective sheriffs for such deputy sheriffs. The annual salary of each such full-time deputy sheriff shall be fixed and determined as provided by <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 15.2-1609.2"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 15.2-1609.2">§ 15.2-1609.2.<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000015#     2#       1609.2#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation></p><p>This section shall be effective on July 1, 1999.</p></bodyText><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p>Code 1950, §§ 14-63, 14-64; 1964, c. 386, § 14.1-51; 1966, c. 688; 1979, cc. 233, 538; 1980, cc. 587, 588; 1983, c. 382; <citation normalizedCite="1989 VA CH 242"><content><span normalizedCite="1989 Va. Ch. 242">1989, c. 242<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1989#000242#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1994 VA CH 780"><content><span normalizedCite="1994 Va. Ch. 780">1994, cc. 780<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1994#000780#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1994 VA CH 792"><content><span normalizedCite="1994 Va. Ch. 792">792<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1994#000792#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1998 VA CH 872"><content><span normalizedCite="1998 Va. Ch. 872">1998, c. 872<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1998#000872#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PV30-004G-K2YK-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 15.2.</desig><title>COUNTIES, CITIES AND TOWNS</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="subtitle"><heading><desig>SUBTITLE II.</desig><title>POWERS OF LOCAL GOVERNMENT</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 16.</desig><title>LOCAL CONSTITUTIONAL OFFICERS, COURTHOUSES AND SUPPLIES</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="article"><heading><desig>ARTICLE 6.1.</desig><title>COMPENSATION BOARD GENERALLY.</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Governments</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjdEQjE4OUJDMzQxNDNEMEI0RTI1QUFCMzJENjEwRTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Administrative Boards</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QTYwRUFCMDc5MzQ5NDEyREFEQkU2NkE2MjRGQTlCNzY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Njg1MkM3RkYyNzIxNEVFRkJFMTI2NUM4NUU1ODdEM0Q</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Duties &amp; Powers</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Njk1NTNGMzM0RTc3NDcyMUI4MENCQUQ1RDhEN0M1RUM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Njg1MkM3RkYyNzIxNEVFRkJFMTI2NUM4NUU1ODdEM0Q</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Finance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjMzOTBBRTg2MUVDNDdDNUE1M0QxNDk1RERCNjNCN0I7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Njg1MkM3RkYyNzIxNEVFRkJFMTI2NUM4NUU1ODdEM0Q</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification><classificationGroup classificationScheme="indexing-terms"><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem score="90"><className>Governments</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjdEQjE4OUJDMzQxNDNEMEI0RTI1QUFCMzJENjEwRTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></classificationGroup></metadata></legislativeDoc>