<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#349#000059#     1#          332#">Va. Code Ann. § 59.1-332</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_59.1-332"/><heading><desig>§ 59.1-332.</desig><title>Conditions on offering items as an inducement to execute</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a"/><heading><desig>A.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> It is unlawful for any person by any means, as part of an advertising program, to offer any item of value as an inducement to the recipient to visit a membership camping operator's campground, attend a sales presentation or contact a salesperson, unless the person clearly discloses in writing in the offer in readily understandable language each of the following:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The name and campground address of the membership camping operator.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A general statement that the advertising program is being conducted by a membership camping operator and the purpose of any requested visit.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A statement of odds, in arabic numerals, of receiving each item offered.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_4"/><heading><desig>4.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The approximate retail value of each item offered.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_5"/><heading><desig>5.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The number of campgrounds that are participating in such advertising program.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_6"/><heading><desig>6.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The restrictions, qualifications and other conditions that must be satisfied before the recipient is entitled to receive the item, including:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_6_a"/><heading><desig>a.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Any deadline, if any, by which the recipient must visit the campground, attend the sales presentation or contact a salesperson in order to receive the item.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_6_b"/><heading><desig>b.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The approximate duration of any visit and sales presentation.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_6_c"/><heading><desig>c.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The date upon which the offer shall terminate and the final date upon which the gifts or prizes are to be awarded.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_6_d"/><heading><desig>d.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Any other conditions, such as minimum age qualification, a financial qualification or a requirement that if the recipient is married both husband and wife must be present in order to receive the item.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_7"/><heading><desig>7.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A statement that the membership camping operator reserves the right to provide a rain check or a substitute or like item, if these rights are reserved.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_8"/><heading><desig>8.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> All other material rules, terms and conditions of the offer or program.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b"/><heading><desig>B.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> It is unlawful for any person making an offer subject to subsection A, or any employee or agent of the person, to offer any item if the person knows or has reason to know that the offered item will not be available in a sufficient quantity based on the reasonably anticipated response to the offer.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c"/><heading><desig>C.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> It is unlawful for any person making an offer subject to subsection A, or any employee or agent of the person, to fail to provide any offered item which any recipient who has responded to the offer in the manner specified in the offer, has performed the requirements disclosed in the offer and has met the qualifications described in the offer is entitled to receive, unless the offered item is not reasonably available and the offer discloses the reservation of a right to provide a rain check or a like or substitute item if the offered item is unavailable.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d"/><heading><desig>D.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> If the person making an offer subject to subsection A is unable to provide an offered item because of limitations of supply, quantity or quality not reasonably foreseeable or controllable by the person making the offer, the person making the offer shall inform the recipient of the recipient's right to receive a rain check for the item offered, unless the person making the offer knows or has a reasonable basis for knowing that the item will not be reasonably available at approximately the same price to the person making the offer, and shall inform the recipient of the recipient's right to at least one of the following additional options:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The person making the offer will provide a like item of equivalent or greater retail value or a rain check for the item. This option must be offered if the offered item is not reasonably available.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The person making the offer will provide a substitute item of equivalent or greater retail value.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The person making the offer will provide a rain check for a like or substitute item.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_e"/><heading><desig>E.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> If a rain check is provided, the person making an offer subject to subsection A shall, within a reasonable time, and in any event not more than ninety days after the rain check is provided, deliver the agreed item to the recipient's address without additional cost or obligation to the recipient, unless the item for which the rain check is provided remains unavailable because of limitations of supply, quantity or quality not reasonably foreseeable or controllable by the person making the offer. If the item is unavailable for these reasons, the person shall, not more than thirty days after the expiration of the aforesaid ninety-day period, deliver a like item of equal or greater retail value or, if the item is not reasonably available to the person at approximately the same price, a substitute item of equal or greater retail value.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_f"/><heading><desig>F.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> On the written request of a recipient who has received or claims a right to receive any offered item, the person making an offer subject to subsection A shall furnish to the recipient sufficient evidence showing that the item provided matches the item randomly or otherwise selected for distribution to that recipient.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_g"/><heading><desig>G.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> It is unlawful for any person making an offer subject to subsection A, or any employee or agent of the person, to:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_g_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Misrepresent the size, quantity, identity or quality of any prize, gift, money or other item of value offered.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_g_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Misrepresent in any manner the odds of receiving any particular gift, prize, amount of money or other item of value.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_g_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Label any offer a "notice of termination" or "notice of cancellation."</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_g_4"/><heading><desig>4.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Materially misrepresent, in any manner, the offer, or program.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_h"/><heading><desig>H.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> If any provision of this section is in conflict with the provisions of the Prizes and Gifts Act (<citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 59.1-415"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 59.1-415">§ 59.1-415<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000059#     1#          415#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> et seq.), the provisions of the Prizes and Gifts Act shall control.</p></bodyText></level><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p>1985, c. 409; <citation normalizedCite="1992 VA CH 545"><content><span normalizedCite="1992 Va. Ch. 545">1992, c. 545<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1992#000545#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PTM0-004G-K0H0-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 59.1.</desig><title>TRADE AND COMMERCE</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 25.</desig><title>VIRGINIA MEMBERSHIP CAMPING ACT</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="article"><heading><desig>ARTICLE 3.</desig><title>PROTECTION OF PURCHASERS</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Contracts Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QzY0RTZFMzE0RjkwNDdFQUI5M0U5N0ZFMjYyREMyQzU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Deliveries</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MTE3MkJDREQ2MThFNERFMEI3QjJBRDBFQTg1QUE0RTU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NTNFRjkzQzZEMEM4NDg2QUJFODE1MzFCMjNDNUY3OTA</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Q0YyRjY1NkZBQjkzNDA0RUFCQzA0RjJEMjhGNTYwN0M7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDMzOTAwOUFFMTFCNEE3Njg4QUEzQTJFOUE1NzE5MkM</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification><classificationGroup classificationScheme="indexing-terms"><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem score="90"><className>Antitrust</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6REEyRTNDM0JGQzYyNEMyOEFGNTAwNUJEOUU1MDg4NjU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></classificationGroup></metadata></legislativeDoc>