<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#349#000063#     2#         1233#">Va. Code Ann. § 63.2-1233</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_63.2-1233"/><heading><desig>§ 63.2-1233.</desig><title>Consent to be executed in juvenile and domestic relations district court; exceptions</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><bodyText><p>When the juvenile and domestic relations district court is satisfied that all requirements of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 63.2-1232"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 63.2-1232">§ 63.2-1232<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000063#     2#         1232#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> have been met with respect to at least one birth parent and the adoptive child is at least in the third calendar day of life, that birth parent or both birth parents, as the case may be, shall execute consent to the proposed adoption in compliance with the provisions of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 63.2-1202"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 63.2-1202">§ 63.2-1202<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000063#     2#         1202#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> while before the juvenile and domestic relations district court in person and in the presence of the prospective adoptive parents. The juvenile and domestic relations district court shall accept the consent of the birth parent(s) and transfer custody of the child to the prospective adoptive parents, pending notification to any nonconsenting birth parent, as described hereinafter.</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> a. The execution of consent before the juvenile and domestic relations district court shall not be required of a birth father if the birth father consents under oath and in writing to the adoption.</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_1_b"/><heading><desig>b.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The consent of a birth father who is not married to the mother of the child at the time of the child's conception or birth shall not be required if the putative father named by the birth mother denies under oath and in writing the paternity of the child or if the putative father did not register with the Putative Father Registry pursuant to Article 7 (<citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 63.2-1249"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 63.2-1249">§ 63.2-1249<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000063#     2#         1249#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> et seq.) of this chapter. If the identity of the birth father is reasonably ascertainable, but the whereabouts of the birth father are not reasonably ascertainable, verification of compliance with the Putative Father Registry shall be provided to the court.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_1_c"/><heading><desig>c.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> When a birth father is required to be given notice, he may be given notice of the adoption by registered or certified mail to his last known address and if he fails to object to the adoption within 15 days of the mailing of such notice, his consent shall not be required. An objection shall be in writing, signed by the objecting party or counsel of record for the objecting party and shall be filed with the clerk of the juvenile and domestic relations district court in which the petition was filed during the business day of the court, within the time period specified in this section. When no timely objection is filed, no hearing on this issue is required. Failure of the objecting party to appear at any scheduled hearing, either in person or by counsel, shall constitute a waiver of such objection.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_1_d"/><heading><desig>d.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The juvenile and domestic relations district court may accept the written consent of the birth father at the time of the child's conception or birth, provided that his identifying information required in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 63.2-1232"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 63.2-1232">§ 63.2-1232<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000063#     2#         1232#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> is filed in writing with the juvenile and domestic relations district court of jurisdiction. Such consent shall advise the birth father of his opportunity for legal representation, shall identify the court in which the case was or is intended to be filed, and shall be presented to the juvenile and domestic relations district court for acceptance. The consent may waive further notice of the adoption proceedings and shall contain the name, address and telephone number of the birth father's legal counsel or an acknowledgment that he was informed of his opportunity to be represented by legal counsel and declined such representation. For good cause shown, the court may dispense with the requirements regarding the filing of the birth father's identifying information pursuant to this subdivision 1. d.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_1_e"/><heading><desig>e.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> In the event that the birth mother's consent is not executed in the juvenile and domestic relations district court, the consent of the birth father shall be executed in the juvenile and domestic relations district court.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_1_f"/><heading><desig>f.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A child born to a married birth mother shall be presumed to be the child of her husband and his consent shall be required, unless the court finds that the father's consent is withheld contrary to the best interests of the child as provided in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 63.2-1205"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 63.2-1205">§ 63.2-1205<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000063#     2#         1205#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> or if his consent is unobtainable. The consent of such presumed father shall be under oath and in writing and may be executed in or out of court. The presumption that the husband is the father of the child may be rebutted by sufficient evidence, satisfactory to the juvenile and domestic relations district court, which would establish by a preponderance of the evidence the paternity of another man or the impossibility or improbability of cohabitation of the birth mother and her husband for a period of at least 300 days preceding the birth of the child, in which case the husband's consent shall not be required. The executed denial of paternity by the putative father shall be sufficient to rebut the presumption that he is the father of the child. If the court is satisfied that the presumption has been rebutted, notice of the adoption shall not be required to be given to the presumed father.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> After the application of the provisions of subdivision 1, if a birth parent is entitled to a hearing, the birth parent shall be given notice of the date and location of the hearing and be given the opportunity to appear before the juvenile and domestic relations district court. Such hearing may occur subsequent to the proceeding wherein the consenting birth parent appeared but may not be held until 15 days after personal service of notice on the nonconsenting birth parent, or if personal service is unobtainable, 10 days after the completion of the execution of an order of publication against such birth parent. The juvenile and domestic relations district court may appoint counsel for the birth parent(s). If the juvenile and domestic relations district court finds that consent is withheld contrary to the best interests of the child, as set forth in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 63.2-1205"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 63.2-1205">§ 63.2-1205<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000063#     2#         1205#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, or is unobtainable, it may grant the petition without such consent and enter an order waiving the requirement of consent of the nonconsenting birth parent and transferring custody of the child to the prospective adoptive parents. No further consent or notice shall be required of a birth parent who fails to appear at any scheduled hearing, either in person or by counsel. If the juvenile and domestic relations district court denies the petition, the juvenile and domestic relations district court shall order that any consent given for the purpose of such placement shall be void and, if necessary, the court shall determine custody of the child as between the birth parents.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Except as provided in subdivisions 4 and 5, if consent cannot be obtained from at least one birth parent, the juvenile and domestic relations district court shall deny the petition and determine custody of the child pursuant to <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 16.1-278.2"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 16.1-278.2">§ 16.1-278.2.<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000016#     1#        278.2#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation></p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_4"/><heading><desig>4.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> If a child has been under the physical care and custody of the prospective adoptive parents and if both birth parents have failed, without good cause, to appear at a hearing to execute consent under this section for which they were given proper notice pursuant to <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 16.1-264"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 16.1-264">§ 16.1-264<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000016#     1#          264#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, the juvenile and domestic relations district court may grant the petition without the consent of either birth parent and enter an order waiving consent and transferring custody of the child to the prospective adoptive parents. Prior to the entry of such an order, the juvenile and domestic relations district court may appoint legal counsel for the birth parents and shall find by clear and convincing evidence (i) that the birth parents were given proper notice of the hearing(s) to execute consent and of the hearing to proceed without their consent; (ii) that the birth parents failed to show good cause for their failure to appear at such hearing(s); and (iii) that pursuant to <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 63.2-1205"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 63.2-1205">§ 63.2-1205<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000063#     2#         1205#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, the consent of the birth parents is withheld contrary to the best interests of the child or is unobtainable. Under this subdivision, the court or the parties may waive the requirement of the simultaneous meeting under <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 63.2-1231"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 63.2-1231">§ 63.2-1231<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000063#     2#         1231#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> and the requirements of subdivisions A 1, A 3, and A 7 of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 63.2-1232"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 63.2-1232">§ 63.2-1232<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000063#     2#         1232#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> where the opportunity for compliance is not reasonably available under the applicable circumstances.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_5"/><heading><desig>5.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> If both birth parents are deceased, the juvenile and domestic relations district court, after hearing evidence to that effect, may grant the petition without the filing of any consent.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_6"/><heading><desig>6.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> No consent shall be required from the birth father of a child placed pursuant to this section when such father is convicted of a violation of subsection A of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 18.2-61"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 18.2-61">§ 18.2-61<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000018#     2#           61#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 18.2-63"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 18.2-63">§ 18.2-63<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000018#     2#           63#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, subsection B of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 18.2-366"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 18.2-366">§ 18.2-366<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000018#     2#          366#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, or an equivalent offense of another state, the United States, or any foreign jurisdiction, and the child was conceived as a result of such violation, nor shall the birth father be entitled to notice of any of the proceedings under this section.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_7"/><heading><desig>7.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> No consent shall be required of a birth father if he denies under oath and in writing the paternity of the child. Such denial of paternity may be withdrawn no more than 10 days after it is executed. Once the child is 10 days old, any executed denial of paternity is final and constitutes a waiver of all rights with the respect to the adoption of the child and cannot be withdrawn.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_8"/><heading><desig>8.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A birth father may consent to the adoption prior to the birth of the child.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_9"/><heading><desig>9.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The juvenile and domestic relations district court shall review each order entered under this section at least annually until such time as the final order of adoption is entered.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_10"/><heading><desig>10.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> When there has been an interstate transfer of the child in a parental placement adoption in compliance with Chapter 10 (<citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 63.2-1000"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 63.2-1000">§ 63.2-1000<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000063#     2#         1000#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> et seq.) of this title, all matters relating to the adoption of the child including, but not limited to, custody and parentage shall be determined in the court of appropriate jurisdiction in the state that was approved for finalization of the adoption by the interstate compact authorities.</p></bodyText></level></level><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p><citation normalizedCite="1989 VA CH 647"><content><span normalizedCite="1989 Va. Ch. 647">1989, c. 647<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1989#000647#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, § 63.1-220.3; <citation normalizedCite="1991 VA CH 364"><content><span normalizedCite="1991 Va. Ch. 364">1991, cc. 364<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1991#000364#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1991 VA CH 602"><content><span normalizedCite="1991 Va. Ch. 602">602<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1991#000602#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1992 VA CH 125"><content><span normalizedCite="1992 Va. Ch. 125">1992, c. 125<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1992#000125#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1993 VA CH 338"><content><span normalizedCite="1993 Va. Ch. 338">1993, cc. 338<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1993#000338#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1993 VA CH 553"><content><span normalizedCite="1993 Va. Ch. 553">553<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1993#000553#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1995 VA CH 772"><content><span normalizedCite="1995 Va. Ch. 772">1995, cc. 772<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1995#000772#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1995 VA CH 826"><content><span normalizedCite="1995 Va. Ch. 826">826<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1995#000826#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1999 VA CH 1028"><content><span normalizedCite="1999 Va. Ch. 1028">1999, c. 1028<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1999#001028#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2000 VA CH 830"><content><span normalizedCite="2000 Va. Ch. 830">2000, c. 830<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2000#000830#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, § 63.1-219.40; <citation normalizedCite="2002 VA CH 747"><content><span normalizedCite="2002 Va. Ch. 747">2002, c. 747<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2002#000747#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2005 VA CH 890"><content><span normalizedCite="2005 Va. Ch. 890">2005, c. 890<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2005#000890#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2006 VA CH 825"><content><span normalizedCite="2006 Va. Ch. 825">2006, cc. 825<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2006#000825#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2006 VA CH 848"><content><span normalizedCite="2006 Va. Ch. 848">848<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2006#000848#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2007 VA CH 606"><content><span normalizedCite="2007 Va. Ch. 606">2007, cc. 606<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2007#000606#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2007 VA CH 623"><content><span normalizedCite="2007 Va. Ch. 623">623<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2007#000623#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2009 VA CH 805"><content><span normalizedCite="2009 Va. Ch. 805">2009, c. 805<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2009#000805#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PVB0-004G-K2P0-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 63.2.</desig><title>WELFARE (SOCIAL SERVICES)</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="subtitle"><heading><desig>SUBTITLE III.</desig><title>SOCIAL SERVICES PROGRAMS</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 12.</desig><title>ADOPTION</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="article"><heading><desig>ARTICLE 3.</desig><title>PARENTAL PLACEMENT ADOPTIONS</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Evidence</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUVGQkU0QjJFMTIzNDNBM0FCNTVEQjAxQTM3RDcwOTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Rebuttal of Presumptions</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6ODBERDk4QUNGOENENDJDMDhGRkRBRjlBNUYxQjU2MUQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MzlDRDFFQTNEQjk5NDZDRTgzNEMyOTMyRjA5Nzk0NTM</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Family Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NEI4M0U5Qzg3RTk0NDdBRUJGNDRGNkZEQkU3RDdFNDU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Biological Parents</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RjY1NzgzMkM1RDlDNDM4OUIwREYyMzM0RjRDQzk1Q0Y7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QzEwNTIwMUU5RDMyNENBOEFGQUNBRkIxRDlDOEVERDI</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Exceptions</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6ODYzM0YyOTJDMzUzNERCNDg0RTgyNzIzOEI0QkNCNEU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QzEwNTIwMUU5RDMyNENBOEFGQUNBRkIxRDlDOEVERDI</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NTQ4ODlEOEU5NjdGNDM3NEE3QTI0NkE2MEYzODZFMzA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QzEwNTIwMUU5RDMyNENBOEFGQUNBRkIxRDlDOEVERDI</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NEMwNkI4NEY2MjQ0NEQ1MEFCRjlDOTUwNDc2MDE4NjY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RjlBMEVFRkQ3M0I4NEE1RTlBQTEyNEFBMkIyN0JGRjY</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QkMyNUZEMTYwQkQ2NDU2MEEyRDBFRDQ3NjBCRkRFMTg7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RUFGQjVEQTU4QTYyNEJENDkxRjM5Qzg4NUFDN0FFNUY</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Interstate Adoptions</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RjY4QThGQTA1MDQxNENFM0E0NEM5NERCMUQyMEVCNjg7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NkQzREUxNDFCODczNDBENEEyREQwN0Y2OTM3OTU2REM</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Marriage</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Rjc2MjFCQjI0MUNCNEYwRkJDM0EzMUVBRjVCNENFRDI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RjI4OUQ3QTU3RTRENDdDMTk4MEMyMzlENDFEQzM0MTI</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Paternity Registries</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUQ0NzlBMDNENDY0NDk3RjhDNkYwQzc5MUZFMjkyOUQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RjlBMEVFRkQ3M0I4NEE1RTlBQTEyNEFBMkIyN0JGRjY</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Putative Father Registries</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6N0VCMjFGOEZDQUVBNEU4NTg5MzI0MDE0NEZFMEM4QzY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NjBDNjAwQTIxMEE4NDY4NTk4MkNCQzE0NUYzRDQwNEQ</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Revocation</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDU1RTM1MzI2NzQ3NDJFODkxRERDMjdDNzA3RUFDNEQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QzEwNTIwMUU5RDMyNENBOEFGQUNBRkIxRDlDOEVERDI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Legal Ethics</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NUNFOUIxOEI1QzlBNDc2NkFFNTM0QjBGMEJGOTQ5OEI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Acceptance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RTE1RkRDMzYyMjAzNEM0MUFEQUIxQzU2NUEzRTJFRTg7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NzZBOTk0RkJDOUY4NDRENjlFMUE5QzVBNzZDMUU5OEU</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification><classificationGroup classificationScheme="indexing-terms"><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem score="90"><className>Public Health &amp; Welfare</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDYwRTY1MDg3MTk5NDUyNkFFRDI1RjJBRERGQ0UxNzI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></classificationGroup></metadata></legislativeDoc>