<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#349#000032#     1#          127#">Va. Code Ann. § 32.1-127</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><note><bodyText><p>This section has more than one version with varying effective dates.  To view a complete list of the versions of this section see Table of Contents.</p></bodyText></note><anchor id="_32.1-127"/><heading><desig>§ 32.1-127.</desig><title>Regulations</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a"/><heading><desig>A.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The regulations promulgated by the Board to carry out the provisions of this article shall be in substantial conformity to the standards of health, hygiene, sanitation, construction and safety as established and recognized by medical and health care professionals and by specialists in matters of public health and safety, including health and safety standards established under provisions of Title XVIII and Title XIX of the Social Security Act, and to the provisions of Article 2 (<citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 32.1-138"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 32.1-138">§ 32.1-138<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000032#     1#          138#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> et seq.).</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b"/><heading><desig>B.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Such regulations:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Shall include minimum standards for (i) the construction and maintenance of hospitals, nursing homes and certified nursing facilities to ensure the environmental protection and the life safety of its patients, employees, and the public; (ii) the operation, staffing and equipping of hospitals, nursing homes and certified nursing facilities; (iii) qualifications and training of staff of hospitals, nursing homes and certified nursing facilities, except those professionals licensed or certified by the Department of Health Professions; (iv) conditions under which a hospital or nursing home may provide medical and nursing services to patients in their places of residence; and (v) policies related to infection prevention, disaster preparedness, and facility security of hospitals, nursing homes, and certified nursing facilities. For purposes of this paragraph, facilities in which five or more first trimester abortions per month are performed shall be classified as a category of "hospital";</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Shall provide that at least one physician who is licensed to practice medicine in this Commonwealth shall be on call at all times, though not necessarily physically present on the premises, at each hospital which operates or holds itself out as operating an emergency service;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> May classify hospitals and nursing homes by type of specialty or service and may provide for licensing hospitals and nursing homes by bed capacity and by type of specialty or service;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_4"/><heading><desig>4.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Shall also require that each hospital establish a protocol for organ donation, in compliance with federal law and the regulations of the Centers for Medicare and Medicaid Services (CMS), particularly 42 C.F.R. § 482.45. Each hospital shall have an agreement with an organ procurement organization designated in CMS regulations for routine contact, whereby the provider's designated organ procurement organization certified by CMS (i) is notified in a timely manner of all deaths or imminent deaths of patients in the hospital and (ii) is authorized to determine the suitability of the decedent or patient for organ donation and, in the absence of a similar arrangement with any eye bank or tissue bank in Virginia certified by the Eye Bank Association of America or the American Association of Tissue Banks, the suitability for tissue and eye donation. The hospital shall also have an agreement with at least one tissue bank and at least one eye bank to cooperate in the retrieval, processing, preservation, storage, and distribution of tissues and eyes to ensure that all usable tissues and eyes are obtained from potential donors and to avoid interference with organ procurement. The protocol shall ensure that the hospital collaborates with the designated organ procurement organization to inform the family of each potential donor of the option to donate organs, tissues, or eyes or to decline to donate. The individual making contact with the family shall have completed a course in the methodology for approaching potential donor families and requesting organ or tissue donation that (a) is offered or approved by the organ procurement organization and designed in conjunction with the tissue and eye bank community and (b) encourages discretion and sensitivity according to the specific circumstances, views, and beliefs of the relevant family. In addition, the hospital shall work cooperatively with the designated organ procurement organization in educating the staff responsible for contacting the organ procurement organization's personnel on donation issues, the proper review of death records to improve identification of potential donors, and the proper procedures for maintaining potential donors while necessary testing and placement of potential donated organs, tissues, and eyes takes place. This process shall be followed, without exception, unless the family of the relevant decedent or patient has expressed opposition to organ donation, the chief administrative officer of the hospital or his designee knows of such opposition, and no donor card or other relevant document, such as an advance directive, can be found;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_5"/><heading><desig>5.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Shall require that each hospital that provides obstetrical services establish a protocol for admission or transfer of any pregnant woman who presents herself while in labor;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_6"/><heading><desig>6.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Shall also require that each licensed hospital develop and implement a protocol requiring written discharge plans for identified, substance-abusing, postpartum women and their infants. The protocol shall require that the discharge plan be discussed with the patient and that appropriate referrals for the mother and the infant be made and documented. Appropriate referrals may include, but need not be limited to, treatment services, comprehensive early intervention services for infants and toddlers with disabilities and their families pursuant to Part H of the Individuals with Disabilities Education Act, <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="20 USC 1471"><content><span normalizedCite="20 U.S.C. 1471">20 U.S.C. § 1471<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1828#123#000020#       1471#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> et seq., and family-oriented prevention services. The discharge planning process shall involve, to the extent possible, the father of the infant and any members of the patient's extended family who may participate in the follow-up care for the mother and the infant. Immediately upon identification, pursuant to <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 54.1-2403.1"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 54.1-2403.1">§ 54.1-2403.1<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000054#     1#       2403.1#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, of any substance-abusing, postpartum woman, the hospital shall notify, subject to federal law restrictions, the community services board of the jurisdiction in which the woman resides to appoint a discharge plan manager. The community services board shall implement and manage the discharge plan;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_7"/><heading><desig>7.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Shall require that each nursing home and certified nursing facility fully disclose to the applicant for admission the home's or facility's admissions policies, including any preferences given;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_8"/><heading><desig>8.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Shall require that each licensed hospital establish a protocol relating to the rights and responsibilities of patients which shall include a process reasonably designed to inform patients of such rights and responsibilities. Such rights and responsibilities of patients, a copy of which shall be given to patients on admission, shall be consistent with applicable federal law and regulations of the Centers for Medicare and Medicaid Services;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_9"/><heading><desig>9.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Shall establish standards and maintain a process for designation of levels or categories of care in neonatal services according to an applicable national or state-developed evaluation system. Such standards may be differentiated for various levels or categories of care and may include, but need not be limited to, requirements for staffing credentials, staff/patient ratios, equipment, and medical protocols;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_10"/><heading><desig>10.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Shall require that each nursing home and certified nursing facility train all employees who are mandated to report adult abuse, neglect, or exploitation pursuant to <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 63.2-1606"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 63.2-1606">§ 63.2-1606<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000063#     2#         1606#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> on such reporting procedures and the consequences for failing to make a required report;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_11"/><heading><desig>11.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Shall permit hospital personnel, as designated in medical staff bylaws, rules and regulations, or hospital policies and procedures, to accept emergency telephone and other verbal orders for medication or treatment for hospital patients from physicians, and other persons lawfully authorized by state statute to give patient orders, subject to a requirement that such verbal order be signed, within a reasonable period of time not to exceed 72 hours as specified in the hospital's medical staff bylaws, rules and regulations or hospital policies and procedures, by the person giving the order, or, when such person is not available within the period of time specified, co-signed by another physician or other person authorized to give the order;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_12"/><heading><desig>12.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Shall require, unless the vaccination is medically contraindicated or the resident declines the offer of the vaccination, that each certified nursing facility and nursing home provide or arrange for the administration to its residents of (i) an annual vaccination against influenza and (ii) a pneumococcal vaccination, in accordance with the most recent recommendations of the Advisory Committee on Immunization Practices of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_13"/><heading><desig>13.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Shall require that each nursing home and certified nursing facility register with the Department of State Police to receive notice of the registration or reregistration of any sex offender within the same or a contiguous zip code area in which the home or facility is located, pursuant to <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 9.1-914"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 9.1-914">§ 9.1-914<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000009#     1#          914#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_14"/><heading><desig>14.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Shall require that each nursing home and certified nursing facility ascertain, prior to admission, whether a potential patient is a registered sex offender, if the home or facility anticipates the potential patient will have a length of stay greater than three days or in fact stays longer than three days;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_15"/><heading><desig>15.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Shall require that each licensed hospital include in its visitation policy a provision allowing each adult patient to receive visits from any individual from whom the patient desires to receive visits, subject to other restrictions contained in the visitation policy including, but not limited to, those related to the patient's medical condition and the number of visitors permitted in the patient's room simultaneously;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_16"/><heading><desig>16.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Shall require that each nursing home and certified nursing facility shall, upon the request of the facility's family council, send notices and information about the family council mutually developed by the family council and the administration of the nursing home or certified nursing facility, and provided to the facility for such purpose, to the listed responsible party or a contact person of the resident's choice up to six times per year. Such notices may be included together with a monthly billing statement or other regular communication. Notices and information shall also be posted in a designated location within the nursing home or certified nursing facility;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_17"/><heading><desig>17.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Shall require that each nursing home and certified nursing facility maintain liability insurance coverage in a minimum amount of $ 1 million, and professional liability coverage in an amount at least equal to the recovery limit set forth in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 8.01-581.15"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 8.01-581.15">§ 8.01-581.15<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000008#    01#       581.15#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, to compensate patients or individuals for injuries and losses resulting from the negligent or criminal acts of the facility. Failure to maintain such minimum insurance shall result in revocation of the facility's license;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_18"/><heading><desig>18.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Shall require each hospital that provides obstetrical services to establish policies to follow when a stillbirth, as defined in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 32.1-69.1"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 32.1-69.1">§ 32.1-69.1<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000032#     1#         69.1#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, occurs that meet the guidelines pertaining to counseling patients and their families and other aspects of managing stillbirths as may be specified by the Board in its regulations; and</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_19"/><heading><desig>19.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Shall require each nursing home to provide a full refund of any unexpended patient funds on deposit with the facility following the discharge or death of a patient, other than entrance-related fees paid to a continuing care provider as defined in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 38.2-4900"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 38.2-4900">§ 38.2-4900<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000038#     2#         4900#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, within 30 days of a written request for such funds by the discharged patient or, in the case of the death of a patient, the person administering the person's estate in accordance with the Virginia Small Estates Act (<citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 64.2-600"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 64.2-600">§ 64.2-600<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000064#     2#          600#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> et seq.).</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c"/><heading><desig>C.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Upon obtaining the appropriate license, if applicable, licensed hospitals, nursing homes, and certified nursing facilities may operate adult day care centers.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d"/><heading><desig>D.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> All facilities licensed by the Board pursuant to this article which provide treatment or care for hemophiliacs and, in the course of such treatment, stock clotting factors, shall maintain records of all lot numbers or other unique identifiers for such clotting factors in order that, in the event the lot is found to be contaminated with an infectious agent, those hemophiliacs who have received units of this contaminated clotting factor may be apprised of this contamination. Facilities which have identified a lot which is known to be contaminated shall notify the recipient's attending physician and request that he notify the recipient of the contamination. If the physician is unavailable, the facility shall notify by mail, return receipt requested, each recipient who received treatment from a known contaminated lot at the individual's last known address.</p></bodyText></level><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p>Code 1950, § 32-301; 1972, c. 36; 1979, c. 711; 1985, c. 335; 1986, c. 135; 1987, c. 224; 1988, cc. 325, 418; <citation normalizedCite="1989 VA CH 434"><content><span normalizedCite="1989 Va. Ch. 434">1989, cc. 434<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1989#000434#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1989 VA CH 618"><content><span normalizedCite="1989 Va. Ch. 618">618<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1989#000618#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1989 VA CH 699"><content><span normalizedCite="1989 Va. Ch. 699">699<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1989#000699#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1992 VA CH 334"><content><span normalizedCite="1992 Va. Ch. 334">1992, cc. 334<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1992#000334#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1992 VA CH 428"><content><span normalizedCite="1992 Va. Ch. 428">428<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1992#000428#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1993 VA CH 335"><content><span normalizedCite="1993 Va. Ch. 335">1993, c. 335<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1993#000335#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1996 VA CH 361"><content><span normalizedCite="1996 Va. Ch. 361">1996, cc. 361<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1996#000361#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1996 VA CH 411"><content><span normalizedCite="1996 Va. Ch. 411">411<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1996#000411#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1997 VA CH 454"><content><span normalizedCite="1997 Va. Ch. 454">1997, c. 454<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1997#000454#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1998 VA CH 450"><content><span normalizedCite="1998 Va. Ch. 450">1998, c. 450<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1998#000450#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2000 VA CH 176"><content><span normalizedCite="2000 Va. Ch. 176">2000, cc. 176<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2000#000176#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2000 VA CH 810"><content><span normalizedCite="2000 Va. Ch. 810">810<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2000#000810#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2001 VA CH 463"><content><span normalizedCite="2001 Va. Ch. 463">2001, c. 463<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2001#000463#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2004 VA CH 762"><content><span normalizedCite="2004 Va. Ch. 762">2004, c. 762<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2004#000762#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2007 VA CH 119"><content><span normalizedCite="2007 Va. Ch. 119">2007, cc. 119<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2007#000119#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2007 VA CH 164"><content><span normalizedCite="2007 Va. Ch. 164">164<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2007#000164#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2007 VA CH 516"><content><span normalizedCite="2007 Va. Ch. 516">516<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2007#000516#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2011 VA CH 406"><content><span normalizedCite="2011 Va. Ch. 406">2011, cc. 406<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2011#000406#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2011 VA CH 412"><content><span normalizedCite="2011 Va. Ch. 412">412<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2011#000412#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2011 VA CH 670"><content><span normalizedCite="2011 Va. Ch. 670">670<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2011#000670#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2013 VA CH 320"><content><span normalizedCite="2013 Va. Ch. 320">2013, c. 320<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2013#000320#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2014 VA CH 320"><content><span normalizedCite="2014 Va. Ch. 320">2014, c. 320<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2014#000320#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2015 VA CH 661"><content><span normalizedCite="2015 Va. Ch. 661">2015, c. 661<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2015#000661#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2016 VA CH 85"><content><span normalizedCite="2016 Va. Ch. 85">2016, c. 85<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2016#000085#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PT30-004G-K3C7-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 32.1.</desig><title>HEALTH</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 5.</desig><title>REGULATION OF MEDICAL CARE FACILITIES AND SERVICES</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="article"><heading><desig>ARTICLE 1.</desig><title>HOSPITAL AND NURSING HOME LICENSURE AND INSPECTION</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Regulation of Nursing Facilities for Disabled &amp; Elderly Persons</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QkI5RTc4N0U1MjU1NDQwMEI1MzhDOThGRTIyNDU1NDU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MTlCM0Q3MTlFNUQ0NDA5OTgwQTEwQjE1M0ZGMTlFQjc</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Estate, Gift &amp; Trust Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OENGNTY0MEQ2RTU2NDA2NTk4QjcyNzI2NTBERUU3NUI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Anatomical Gifts</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDdFQ0I3RTBEQTIwNDQ1NUE1MjQ1RUU1RDU4OTY0RDY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QUIxNTdDNjZBMURENDJFOTkwNzUxMUEyMzdCRUQ0NDg</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Governments</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjdEQjE4OUJDMzQxNDNEMEI0RTI1QUFCMzJENjEwRTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Licenses</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6N0IyQjkyQkVENEM2NDczNzg5MDUwQ0U5RDMzRjlDNUM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QURCRDNBRjBGRTE0NEFBRUEzNUU1MzFGQjg3MTM4MDI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Healthcare Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NkUxMkVDQjJDOEY5NDVDQ0E5NTFEMTlDMjIwNzVERjc7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Advance Directives</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NUY2RUQyMjM2MTYzNDY3RkFGQkZFMEYyNkYzNzY5Rjk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QzlFNTREQzMzODY1NDc3QkI5MzNGNTEwQTkxOTAxNkI</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Do-Not-Resuscitate Orders</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NzNBNDQ1ODMwOTJENEY1MDlDRjI4NkZGRjAyMzVGODA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QzlFNTREQzMzODY1NDc3QkI5MzNGNTEwQTkxOTAxNkI</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MzM1NkIwRTdBNzU3NEExOEJCNjU4NjNFNjEwRTVDMzQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OTJBNUJFODM1QjFDNDQzNThDMEEzQTFFMDc5ODc1OUE</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NTVDMzIyNkJCMTRBNDI0NUJBOTlBOTYyMjQ0MDkyODU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QTJGRDdFQzgwODczNDI0NDgwMzEyM0JBOEQ2MUVDNjg</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6REIzOUJERjYzNEE1NEI2QUFENjZDQTBERkIzNTk0RjY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NjM2NTg4ODQ2MEU0NENDOUE4NzlDN0E2QjM5MjJFQjg</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RkVDNEYwMjNFMDkzNDUyRTg2NjcxQUJFRjZDNjlGREQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjI1NzIwOTY3NUU1NDlFNEJBMTJDM0NDMURCOUU0NTM</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RUFFMjVEMkE4NzA1NEY5QkEzMzQ3MUQ4OEM2OTA1RjU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QzlFNTREQzMzODY1NDc3QkI5MzNGNTEwQTkxOTAxNkI</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Nursing Facilities</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OTk0NDgxMUUxM0MzNDI5QzhDNEVGNzkwODVFN0MxRDg7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QUVDOEU4Qjg3REQzNEYxNDhCMUNGNzQ5NzNBRTVGNDk</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Personnel Licensing</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6M0VCMTAwM0MwNDA1NEI4OThDNUVEMEIwRTJDQjU2QTM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QTJGRDdFQzgwODczNDI0NDgwMzEyM0JBOEQ2MUVDNjg</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Revocation &amp; Suspension</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDUyMkZDNUIzQUExNDY4M0I5QjkzMTVGNTNCQTUwNjI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QTJGRDdFQzgwODczNDI0NDgwMzEyM0JBOEQ2MUVDNjg</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Insurance Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDM4MzQ2QUYzMTY0NDQzQTkxRDQwRUUzRUM5RDg0OEM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Healthcare Providers</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QzdDN0JBMTA5NDNGNDlDQkIyNjRBQ0E2NURGMTc4Qjc7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MTE4N0IyMEQwOEM3NDU5QkIwQzgyNjg1MDE5Q0IyQTE</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Public Health &amp; Welfare Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDYwRTY1MDg3MTk5NDUyNkFFRDI1RjJBRERGQ0UxNzI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Communicable Diseases</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MEZGMDkyRUNCQzQzNDQ0OEE1N0ExOTE1NUYzRUZFMkQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RDEwNjlEODdCNEMyNEY1MjlCRDNEMDkyMTI3QjlBOUI</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MTJEMUIzNEFBMEE0NDUwMTgyOTk5Q0Q5MUQ3NTNDNTM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NjVGRUIzQkI1QTg1NDUxNkJFM0UwN0IxRTVENDlBNTM</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RjM3NDdEQTcwRDVENDFENEI4QUJFMzQ5NzVGMTE1RDA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6REY3QUUxQ0YxMDFENEE3MTg3QTU4QTdBNkRGMEVCMDc</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjBDQjgyQzFCM0JDNEQ0MDgwQTU1N0M1RDA0MzkzMDQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6N0UyRjc1OTQ5RkNDNDRFNDhDNkUyRkFGNTY0MDFCNzE</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RTJGRDg1RERERUU5NEJCNzlCNUMzMUE2N0Q0NUFDNTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Mzc3RTE2MDQ4Nzc5NDRCMkI1QjYyQ0UyM0U5Qzc1QTg</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Hospitals</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6ODg2NTMwRkJDODAxNDMzMjkyNzRGQTVBNDY1NTE2ODc7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RDUwODU3NjY2MUVFNDNFQkEwNTE1Q0E3RkMxM0JBRDQ</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Hospitals</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDI1MTExN0I4RjcyNDkyREE2QTZBNjcwRDg2RjNGNDM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Mzc3RTE2MDQ4Nzc5NDRCMkI1QjYyQ0UyM0U5Qzc1QTg</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Maternity &amp; Children</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QzM4NjUxNjZFQ0M3NDc2Qzg5NzNCRDA0ODgxNjc2Mzg7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MTlCM0Q3MTlFNUQ0NDA5OTgwQTEwQjE1M0ZGMTlFQjc</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Medicaid Act Interpretation</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUE5RTIyRjRCMThDNEJCQ0IxMzcxRTZEQUVEMjdFNjE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QUZBNTU4QUVDNEU4NDUyRkJDNUJCNTZBQjUxRkU3Rjk</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Nursing Facilities</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QkI5RTc4N0U1MjU1NDQwMEI1MzhDOThGRTIyNDU1NDU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NjVGRUIzQkI1QTg1NDUxNkJFM0UwN0IxRTVENDlBNTM</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Nursing Facilities</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RTNCQUI5NDEzQzE0NEIwMUJDRDA0RUI5NkQwRkFFOTg7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RDUwODU3NjY2MUVFNDNFQkEwNTE1Q0E3RkMxM0JBRDQ</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Nursing Facilities</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MEY4M0NBM0I1QzMzNEFGMUI3NjI2MUJDNjc1MjY1NEU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Mzc3RTE2MDQ4Nzc5NDRCMkI1QjYyQ0UyM0U5Qzc1QTg</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification><classificationGroup classificationScheme="indexing-terms"><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem score="90"><className>Healthcare</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NkUxMkVDQjJDOEY5NDVDQ0E5NTFEMTlDMjIwNzVERjc7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></classificationGroup></metadata></legislativeDoc>