<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#142#        55#     79.72#         1#">Va. Code Ann. § 55-79.72:1</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_55-79.72_1"/><heading><desig>§ 55-79.72:1.</desig><title>Termination of condominium</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a"/><heading><desig>A.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> If there is no unit owner other than the declarant, the declarant may unilaterally terminate the condominium.  An instrument terminating a condominium shall become effective upon recordation thereof if the termination instrument has been signed by the declarant.  But this section shall not be construed to nullify, limit, or otherwise affect the validity or enforceability of any agreement renouncing or to renounce, in whole or in part, the right hereby conferred.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b"/><heading><desig>B.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Except in the case of a taking of all the units by eminent domain, if any of the units in the condominium is restricted exclusively to residential use and there is any unit owner other than the declarant, the condominium may be terminated only by the agreement of unit owners of units to which four-fifths of the votes in the unit owners' association appertain, or such larger majority as the condominium instruments may specify.  If none of the units in the condominium is restricted exclusively to residential use, the condominium instruments may specify a majority smaller than the minimum specified in the preceding sentence.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c"/><heading><desig>C.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Agreement of the required majority of unit owners to termination of the condominium shall be evidenced by their execution of a termination agreement, or ratifications thereof, and the same shall become effective when a copy of the termination agreement is recorded together with a certification, signed by the principal officer of the unit owners' association or by such other officer or officers as the condominium instruments may specify, that the requisite majority of the unit owners signed the termination agreement or ratifications thereof.  Unless the termination agreement otherwise provides, prior to recordation of the termination agreement, a unit owner's prior agreement to terminate the condominium may be revoked only with the approval of unit owners of units to which a majority of the votes in the unit owners' association appertain.  The termination agreement shall specify a date after which the termination agreement shall be void if the termination agreement is not recorded. For the purposes of this section, an instrument terminating a condominium and any ratification thereof shall be deemed a condominium instrument subject to the provisions of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 55-79.49"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 55 -79.49">§ 55-79.49.<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#123#000055#     79.49#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation></p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d"/><heading><desig>D.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> In the case of a condominium that contains only units having horizontal boundaries described in the condominium instruments, a termination agreement may provide that all the common elements and units of the condominium shall be sold following termination.  If, pursuant to the termination agreement, any property in the condominium is sold following termination, the termination agreement shall set forth the minimum terms of the sale.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_e"/><heading><desig>E.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> In the case of a condominium that contains any units not having horizontal boundaries described in the condominium instruments, a termination agreement may provide for sale of the common elements. The termination agreement may not require that the units be sold following termination, unless the condominium instruments as originally recorded provide otherwise or all the unit owners consent to the sale.  In the case of a master condominium that contains a unit which is a part of another condominium, a termination agreement for the master condominium shall not terminate the other condominium.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_f"/><heading><desig>F.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> On behalf of the unit owners, the unit owners' association may contract for the disposition of property in the condominium, but the contract shall not be binding on the unit owners until approved pursuant to subsections B and C of this section.  If the termination agreement requires that any property in the condominium be sold following termination, title to the property, upon termination, shall vest in the unit owners' association as trustee for the holders of all interest in the units.  Thereafter, the unit owners' association shall have powers necessary and appropriate to effect the sale.  Until the same has been concluded and the proceeds have been distributed, the unit owners' association shall continue in existence with all the powers the unit owners' association had before termination.  Proceeds of the sale shall be distributed to unit owners and lien holders as their interests may appear, in proportion to the respective interests of the unit owners as provided in subsection I of this section. Unless otherwise specified in the termination agreement, for as long as the unit owners' association holds title to the property, each unit owner or his successor in interest shall have an exclusive right to occupancy of the portion of the property that formerly constituted his unit.  During the period of occupancy by the unit owner or his successor in interest, each unit owner or his successor in interest shall remain liable for any assessment or other obligation imposed on the unit owner by this chapter or the condominium instruments.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_g"/><heading><desig>G.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> If the property that constitutes the condominium is not sold following termination, title to the common elements and, in the case of a condominium containing only units that have horizontal boundaries described in the condominium instruments, title to all the property in the condominium shall vest in the unit owners, upon termination, as tenants in common in proportion to the unit owners' respective interests as provided in subsection I of this section.  Any liens on the units shall shift accordingly.  While the tenancy in common exists, each unit owner or his successor in interest shall have the exclusive right to occupancy of the portion of the property that formerly constituted the unit owner's unit.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_h"/><heading><desig>H.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Following termination of the condominium, the proceeds of any sale of property, together with the assets of the unit owners' association, shall be held by the unit owners' association as trustee for unit owners or lien holders on the units as their interests may appear.  Following termination, any creditor of the unit owners' association who holds a lien on the unit that was recorded before termination may enforce the lien in the same manner as any lien holder.  Any other creditor of the unit owners' association shall be treated as if he had perfected a lien on the units immediately before termination.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_i"/><heading><desig>I.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Unless the condominium instruments as originally recorded or as amended by 100 percent of the unit owners provide otherwise, the respective interests of unit owners referred to in subsections F, G, and H shall be as follows:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_i_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Except as provided in subdivision 2, the respective interests of the unit owners shall be the fair market values of their units, limited common elements, and common element interests immediately before the termination, as determined by one or more independent appraisers selected by the unit owners' association.  The decision of the independent appraisers shall be distributed to the unit owners and become final unless disapproved within thirty days after distribution by unit owners of units to which one-quarter of the votes in the unit owners' association appertain.  The proportion of any unit owner's interest to the interest of all unit owners is determined by dividing the fair market value of that unit owner's unit and common element interest by the total fair market values of all the units and their common element interests.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_i_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> If any unit or limited common element is destroyed to the extent that an appraisal of the fair market value thereof before destruction cannot be made, the interests of all unit owners are the unit owners' respective common element interests immediately before the termination.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_j"/><heading><desig>J.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Except as provided in subsection K, foreclosure or enforcement of a lien or encumbrance against the entire condominium shall not alone terminate the condominium, and foreclosure or enforcement of a lien or encumbrance against a portion of the condominium, other than withdrawable land, shall not withdraw that portion from the condominium.  Foreclosure or enforcement of a lien or encumbrance against withdrawable land shall not alone withdraw the land from the condominium, but the person who takes title to the withdrawable land shall have the right to require from the unit owners' association, upon request, an amendment that excludes the land from the condominium.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_k"/><heading><desig>K.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> If a lien or encumbrance against a portion of the property that comprises the condominium has priority over the condominium instruments and the lien or encumbrance has not been partially released, upon foreclosure, the parties foreclosing the lien or encumbrance may record an instrument that excludes the property subject to the lien or encumbrance from the condominium.</p></bodyText></level><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p><citation normalizedCite="1993 VA CH 667"><content><span normalizedCite="1993 Va. Ch. 667">1993, c. 667<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1993#000667#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PTV0-004G-K4V7-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 55.</desig><title>PROPERTY AND CONVEYANCES</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 4.2.</desig><title>CONDOMINIUM ACT</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="article"><heading><desig>ARTICLE 2.</desig><title>CREATION, ALTERATION AND TERMINATION OF CONDOMINIUMS</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Contracts Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QzY0RTZFMzE0RjkwNDdFQUI5M0U5N0ZFMjYyREMyQzU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Ratification</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6ODRFMTAzOEQ3Qjg5NDM2RThGNEZBMTdEMkY4RkU4OTg7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QkU0NTZDODIxMjQzNDJBQ0IyQjVBOUFFQjg3QUE1NzE</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Estate, Gift &amp; Trust Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OENGNTY0MEQ2RTU2NDA2NTk4QjcyNzI2NTBERUU3NUI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Q0VEQ0U4QTFCMzc1NDkyQjgzMjNBQUJFREFDOEJCOTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NUQ4NThEMTk0MTQ4NDM3N0FGOEM5RkU2QUQ4RjA1MkQ</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RkM5NEM1RTczNTEzNDMwREIzODZFNkU3MDk1RTcxMjI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RUEwMTQ5RDk2OTM4NEIyNDgwNTY2RTNBOUYyOTk1REQ</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Real Property Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QUUyRTcxRURBNEY2NEE2MDk3QzBCNzRDOEY0NTZDQzk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Condominium Associations</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RDVERDgyODZCNDJBNDIxQUI2ODBCOTE5OUE3MDlBQjg7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUMzQTI2Qzg3NkJDNDI5MEI1MTU1QkM0RDlGN0JENUU</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjJCOTVGQkMzRkQzNEQ2RjkzOEFGNzY4QUVBNEUzRTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjQxMkNBNkE1ODE5NDg0NUJDMTkzNzA1NTMwQzRFQ0M</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MkIzQTQ1QTc0REQ4NDUxOTg4MzU0NTMzNTk3ODBEREI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUMzQTI2Qzg3NkJDNDI5MEI1MTU1QkM0RDlGN0JENUU</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDE5OTJEQjEwMzJENEVFMjk3MTcwNDFGRjY0NUVFNjY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RkQ2NkEyQUQwRTRDNEIyNzk2MDhBRUJGRkFFMERDODI</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Leases</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QkNFM0ZCQzgzODg0NERCQzg5MkRBMDFGOEM0QUU4ODY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUMzQTI2Qzg3NkJDNDI5MEI1MTU1QkM0RDlGN0JENUU</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Lien Priorities</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MTIxMTU0NDU3QTVBNEZERUI3QkNFMTA5Q0ExNDg1Njk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDVEQUQ4RkIyOUFGNDA2OTlEODNGQ0Y0RTk1NjE0N0E</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Management</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDQwRTc5MEY0MjE3NDRDRUFCRjFFODhBMUY5NDU2MDA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUMzQTI2Qzg3NkJDNDI5MEI1MTU1QkM0RDlGN0JENUU</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Purchase &amp; Sale</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDNDNTc1MDExODM4NDA0NUEyRjMzNURBMDk0MTQxNTM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUMzQTI2Qzg3NkJDNDI5MEI1MTU1QkM0RDlGN0JENUU</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Tenancies in Common</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QzQ1NTNBRTU4OEVGNDY1REI1RjRFNDNFQTYxRDgwODk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RURDNEUyQzNBMTcwNDU4REJDQTM0NjRFQzI0QjNBQjY</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Termination</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjA1Nzc5Mzg4QkRGNDY4MzhBMjgxM0E5Mzg1ODZCMTU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUMzQTI2Qzg3NkJDNDI5MEI1MTU1QkM0RDlGN0JENUU</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification><classificationGroup classificationScheme="indexing-terms"><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem score="90"><className>Real Property</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QUUyRTcxRURBNEY2NEE2MDk3QzBCNzRDOEY0NTZDQzk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></classificationGroup></metadata></legislativeDoc>