<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#349#000037#     2#          316#">Va. Code Ann. § 37.2-316</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_37.2-316"/><heading><desig>§ 37.2-316.</desig><title>System restructuring; state and community consensus and planning team required</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a"/><heading><desig>A.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> For the purpose of considering any restructuring of the system of mental health services involving an existing state hospital, the Commissioner shall establish a state and community consensus and planning team consisting of Department staff and representatives of the localities served by the state hospital, including local government officials, individuals receiving services, family members of individuals receiving services, advocates, state hospital employees, community services boards, behavioral health authorities, public and private service providers, licensed hospitals, local health department staff, local social services department staff, sheriffs' office staff, area agencies on aging, and other interested persons. In addition, the members of the House of Delegates and the Senate representing the localities served by the affected state hospital may serve on the state and community consensus and planning team for that state hospital. Each state and community consensus and planning team, in collaboration with the Commissioner, shall develop a plan that addresses (i) the types, amounts, and locations of new and expanded community services that would be needed to successfully implement the closure or conversion of the state hospital to any use other than the provision of mental health services, including a six-year projection of the need for inpatient psychiatric beds and related community mental health services; (ii) the development of a detailed implementation plan designed to build community mental health infrastructure for current and future capacity needs; (iii) the creation of new and enhanced community services prior to the closure of the state hospital or its conversion to any use other than the provision of mental health services; (iv) the transition of individuals receiving services in the state hospital to community services in the locality of their residence prior to admission or the locality of their choice after discharge; (v) the resolution of issues relating to the restructuring implementation process, including employment issues involving state hospital employee transition planning and appropriate transitional benefits; and (vi) a six-year projection comparing the cost of the current structure and the proposed structure.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b"/><heading><desig>B.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The Commissioner shall ensure that each plan includes the following components:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A plan for community education;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A plan for the implementation of required community services, including state-of-the-art practice models and any models required to meet the unique characteristics of the area to be served, which may include models for rural areas;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A plan for assuring the availability of adequate staff in the affected communities, including specific strategies for transferring qualified state hospital employees to community services;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_4"/><heading><desig>4.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A plan for assuring the development, funding, and implementation of individualized discharge plans pursuant to <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 37.2-505"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 37.2-505">§ 37.2-505<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000037#     2#          505#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> for individuals discharged as a result of the closure or conversion of the state hospital to any use other than the provision of mental health services; and</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_5"/><heading><desig>5.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A provision for suspending implementation of the plan if the total general funds appropriated to the Department for state hospital and community services decrease in any year of plan implementation by more than 10 percent from the year in which the plan was approved by the General Assembly.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c"/><heading><desig>C.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> At least nine months prior to any proposed state hospital closure or conversion of the state hospital to any use other than the provision of mental health services, the state and community consensus and planning team shall submit a plan to the Joint Commission on Health Care and the Governor for review and recommendation.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d"/><heading><desig>D.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The Joint Commission on Health Care shall make a recommendation to the General Assembly on the plan no later than six months prior to the date of the proposed closure or conversion of the state hospital to any use other than the provision of mental health services.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_e"/><heading><desig>E.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Upon approval of the plan by the General Assembly and the Governor, the Commissioner shall ensure that the plan components required by subsection B are in place and may thereafter perform all tasks necessary to implement the closure or conversion of the state hospital to any use other than the provision of mental health services.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_f"/><heading><desig>F.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Any funds saved by the closure or conversion of the state hospital to any use other than the provision of mental health services and not allocated to individualized services plans for individuals being transferred or discharged as a result of the closure or conversion of the state hospital to any use other than the provision of mental health services shall be invested in the Behavioral Health and Developmental Services Trust Fund established in Article 4 (<citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 37.2-317"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 37.2-317">§ 37.2-317<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000037#     2#          317#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> et seq.).</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_g"/><heading><desig>G.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Nothing in this section shall prevent the Commissioner from leasing unused, vacant space to any public or private organization.</p></bodyText></level><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p><citation normalizedCite="2002 VA CH 803"><content><span normalizedCite="2002 Va. Ch. 803">2002, c. 803<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2002#000803#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, § 37.1-48.2; <citation normalizedCite="2005 VA CH 716"><content><span normalizedCite="2005 Va. Ch. 716">2005, c. 716<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2005#000716#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2009 VA CH 813"><content><span normalizedCite="2009 Va. Ch. 813">2009, cc. 813<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2009#000813#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2009 VA CH 840"><content><span normalizedCite="2009 Va. Ch. 840">840<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2009#000840#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2012 VA CH 476"><content><span normalizedCite="2012 Va. Ch. 476">2012, cc. 476<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2012#000476#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2012 VA CH 507"><content><span normalizedCite="2012 Va. Ch. 507">507<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2012#000507#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PVG0-004G-K52D-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 37.2.</desig><title>BEHAVIORAL HEALTH AND DEVELOPMENTAL SERVICES</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="subtitle"><heading><desig>SUBTITLE 1.</desig><title>GENERAL PROVISIONS</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 3.</desig><title>DEPARTMENT OF BEHAVIORAL HEALTH AND DEVELOPMENTAL SERVICES</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="article"><heading><desig>ARTICLE 3.</desig><title>SYSTEM RESTRUCTURING</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Governments</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjdEQjE4OUJDMzQxNDNEMEI0RTI1QUFCMzJENjEwRTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Duties &amp; Powers</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Njk1NTNGMzM0RTc3NDcyMUI4MENCQUQ1RDhEN0M1RUM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Njg1MkM3RkYyNzIxNEVFRkJFMTI2NUM4NUU1ODdEM0Q</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Employees &amp; Officials</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDNCMDQzRTY3RDY3NDNEOEE4RDg2OUFEOTRBNDREQzg7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Njg1MkM3RkYyNzIxNEVFRkJFMTI2NUM4NUU1ODdEM0Q</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Public Health &amp; Welfare Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDYwRTY1MDg3MTk5NDUyNkFFRDI1RjJBRERGQ0UxNzI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Costs</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MEJERDBGRDQ1OURBNDZGNUFEMjhERkRBMTMzNDJGQjI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RTA2N0I2MjA4MEMwNEExNjlBQzkzRjBGOTAxODRCNkY</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NUVCNTZERDE5OTI4NDJDRUEzMDVFNjQ3NkEyMjI5QUI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MTlCM0Q3MTlFNUQ0NDA5OTgwQTEwQjE1M0ZGMTlFQjc</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NjdDOTFFQjY0OTM1NEUyNEI5OEYwODE0RTA4RENEQkE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RTA2N0I2MjA4MEMwNEExNjlBQzkzRjBGOTAxODRCNkY</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></metadata></legislativeDoc>