<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#349#000058#     1#         1730#">Va. Code Ann. § 58.1-1730</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_58.1-1730"/><heading><desig>§ 58.1-1730.</desig><title>Tax for enhanced 911 service; definitions</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a"/><heading><desig>A.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> As used in this section, unless the context requires a different meaning:</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Access lines"</emphasis> are defined to include residence and business telephone lines and other switched (packet or circuit) lines connecting the customer premises to the public switched telephone network for the transmission of outgoing voice-grade-capable telecommunications services. Centrex, PBX or other multistation telecommunications services will incur an E-911 tax charge on every line or trunk (Network Access Registrar or PBX trunk) that allows simultaneous unrestricted outward dialing to the public switched telephone network. ISDN Primary Rate Interface services will be charged five E-911 tax charges for every ISDN Primary Rate Interface network facility established by the customer. Other channelized services in which each voice-grade channel is controlled by the telecommunications provider shall be charged one tax for each line that allows simultaneous unrestricted outward dialing to the public switched telephone network. Access lines do not include local, state, and federal government lines; access lines used to provide service to users as part of the Virginia Universal Service Plan; interstate and intrastate dedicated WATS lines; special access lines; off-premises extensions; official lines internally provided and used by providers of telecommunications services for administrative, testing, intercept, coin, and verification purposes; and commercial mobile radio service.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Automatic location identification"</emphasis> or <emphasis typeStyle="it">"ALI" </emphasis> means a telephone network capability that enables the automatic display of information defining the geographical location of the telephone used to place a wireline 9-1-1 call.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Automatic number identification"</emphasis> or <emphasis typeStyle="it">"ANI"</emphasis> means a telephone network capability that enables the automatic display of the telephone number used to place a wireline 9-1-1 call.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Centrex"</emphasis> means a business telephone service offered by a local exchange company from a local central office; a normal single line telephone service with added custom calling features including but not limited to intercom, call forwarding, and call transfer.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Communications services provider"</emphasis> means the same as provided in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 58.1-647"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 58.1-647">§ 58.1-647<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000058#     1#          647#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Enhanced 9-1-1 service"</emphasis> or <emphasis typeStyle="it">"E-911"</emphasis> means a service consisting of telephone network features and PSAPs provided for users of telephone systems enabling users to reach a PSAP by dialing the digits "9-1-1." Such service automatically directs 9-1-1 emergency telephone calls to the appropriate PSAPs by selective routing based on the geographical location from which the emergency call originated, and provides the capability for ANI and ALI features.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"ISDN Primary Rate Interface"</emphasis> means 24 bearer channels, each of which is a full 64,000 bits per second. One of the channels is generally used to carry signaling information for the 23 other channels.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Network Access Register"</emphasis> means a central office register associated with Centrex service that is required in order to complete a call involving access to the public switched telephone network outside the confines of that Centrex company. Network Access Register may be incoming, outgoing, or two-way.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"PBX"</emphasis> means public branch exchange and is telephone switching equipment owned by the customer and located on the customer's premises.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"PBX trunk"</emphasis> means a connection of the customer's PBX switch to the central office.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Public safety answering point"</emphasis> or <emphasis typeStyle="it">"PSAP"</emphasis> means a communications facility equipped and staffed on a 24-hour basis to receive and process 911 calls.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b"/><heading><desig>B.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> There is hereby imposed a monthly tax of $ 0.75 on the end user of each access line of the telephone service or services provided by a communications services provider. However, no such tax shall be imposed on federal, state, and local government agencies or on consumers of CMRS, as that term is defined in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 56-484.12"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 56 -484.12">§ 56-484.12.<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#123#000056#    484.12#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> The revenues shall be collected and remitted monthly by the communications services provider to the Department and deposited into the Communications Sales and Use Tax Trust Fund. This tax shall be subject to the notification and jurisdictional provisions of subsection C.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c"/><heading><desig>C.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> If a customer believes that an amount of tax or an assignment of place of primary use or taxing jurisdiction included on a billing is erroneous, the customer shall notify the communications services provider in writing. The customer shall include in this written notification the street address for the customer's place of primary use or taxing jurisdiction, the account name and number for which the customer seeks a correction, a description of the error asserted by the customer, and any other information that the communications services provider reasonably requires to process the request. Within 15 days of receiving a notice under this section, the communications services provider shall review its records within an additional 15 days to determine the customer's taxing jurisdiction. If this review shows that the amount of tax or assignment of place of primary use or taxing jurisdiction is in error, the communications services provider shall correct the error and refund or credit the amount of tax erroneously collected from the customer for a period of up to two years. If this review shows that the amount of tax or assignment of place of primary use or taxing jurisdiction is correct, the communications services provider shall provide a written explanation to the customer. The procedures in this section shall be the first course of remedy available to customers seeking correction of assignment of place of primary use or taxing jurisdiction, or a refund of or other compensation for taxes erroneously collected by the communications services provider, and no cause of action based upon a dispute arising from such taxes shall accrue until a customer has reasonably exercised the rights and procedures set forth in this subsection.</p><p>For the purposes of this subsection, the terms "customer" and "place of primary use" shall have the same meanings provided in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 58.1-647"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 58.1-647">§ 58.1-647<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000058#     1#          647#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d"/><heading><desig>D.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> For the purpose of compensating a communications services provider for accounting for and remitting the tax levied by this section, each communications services provider shall be allowed 3% of the amount of tax revenues due and accounted for in the form of a deduction in submitting the return and remitting the amount due.</p></bodyText></level><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p><citation normalizedCite="2006 VA CH 780"><content><span normalizedCite="2006 Va. Ch. 780">2006, c. 780<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2006#000780#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PVH0-004G-K0B2-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 58.1.</desig><title>TAXATION</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="subtitle"><heading><desig>SUBTITLE I.</desig><title>TAXES ADMINISTERED BY THE DEPARTMENT OF TAXATION</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 17.</desig><title>MISCELLANEOUS TAXES</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="article"><heading><desig>ARTICLE 7.</desig><title>E-911 TAX</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Taxation</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6M0QyRjUyODU2OURFNDJDNEE4NkZCQzRENDE4NEQwODM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6M0E5MjdDNDRFRUIzNEJFNDkyMDk5MThGNTE5M0RFNEU</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Communications Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MEQxMkU0NzE2OEE2NDIxNEE3QzU0NjU2MDRERUNGNDE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDIwREQwM0JENkRCNEFGMDhDN0Y3QzhDMEJGNzczMTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6M0E5MjdDNDRFRUIzNEJFNDkyMDk5MThGNTE5M0RFNEU</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RjRDQTk5ODEyQjNGNDcwMTg2RjgwOTdGNUEyQjRFMTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6ODgzMzVFMEM4REFFNDc0MTg3NUU4OUEwQzE4MDBGRUY</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Taxation</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6M0QyRjUyODU2OURFNDJDNEE4NkZCQzRENDE4NEQwODM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6M0E5MjdDNDRFRUIzNEJFNDkyMDk5MThGNTE5M0RFNEU</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Tax Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OTNEM0E2OEE0RkQyNEY1MDhBQzdGMkQ4ODI4QTJDODE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Exemptions</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MEYzODBDOEMzN0NGNEFBNjk3MEZBRDM4QzVFQTYxMUY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjU1NzhGRDA0MUIyNERDOTlFRjU0M0I3RUE4QzE3MTg</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Imposition of Tax</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Njg2QTVGMUU2NTE4NDgwNjgyNzg3QTY0RDUyRUMyRDE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QkI5NTVGNkFDOEU1NDVGNjhEQTZEOEJDRTIyMzVEODA</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification><classificationGroup classificationScheme="indexing-terms"><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem score="90"><className>Tax</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OTNEM0E2OEE0RkQyNEY1MDhBQzdGMkQ4ODI4QTJDODE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></classificationGroup></metadata></legislativeDoc>