<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#349#000008#    01#       227.17#">Va. Code Ann. § 8.01-227.17</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_8.01-227.17"/><heading><desig>§ 8.01-227.17.</desig><title>Duties and responsibilities of winter sports participants and certain other individuals</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a"/><heading><desig>A.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A winter sports participant has a duty and responsibility to:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Exercise reasonable care in engaging in winter sports at the winter sports area, including, but not limited to, the exercise of reasonable care in:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_1_a"/><heading><desig>a.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Participating in a winter sport at a winter sports area only on designated trails that are not marked "closed" and refraining from participating in a winter sport in any portion of a winter sports area that is not a designated trail or is marked "closed";</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_1_b"/><heading><desig>b.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Knowing the range of his ability to participate in the winter sport in which he is participating and acting within the limits of that ability;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_1_c"/><heading><desig>c.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Being the sole judge of his knowledge of and ability to successfully negotiate any trail or passenger tramway and refraining from negotiating any trail or passenger tramway until obtaining sufficient knowledge and ability to do so;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_1_d"/><heading><desig>d.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Heeding and obeying all warnings, notices, and signs provided by an operator and not altering, defacing, removing, or destroying any such warning, notice, or sign;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_1_e"/><heading><desig>e.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Maintaining control of his speed and course at all times and maintaining a proper lookout so as to be able to avoid other participants and objects;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_1_f"/><heading><desig>f.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Staying clear of any winter sports area vehicle or infrastructure, other than when embarking on or disembarking from a passenger tramway or when present at or in a residential building or other building that is open to the public;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_1_g"/><heading><desig>g.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Wearing retention straps, ski brakes, or other devices to prevent runaway equipment;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_1_h"/><heading><desig>h.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Making a visual inspection of any winter sports area competition terrain and viewing any freestyle terrain the participant intends to use;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_1_i"/><heading><desig>i.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Acting in a safe manner that will avoid contributing to the injury or death of himself or others or the damage to property, including refraining from participating in a winter sport when the participant's ability to do so safely is impaired by the consumption of alcohol or by the use of any narcotic or other drug or while under the influence of alcohol or any narcotic or other drug, or placing, fabricating, or shaping any object in a trail;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_1_j"/><heading><desig>j.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Embarking on a passenger tramway only with the authority of the operator;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_1_k"/><heading><desig>k.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Boarding or dismounting from a passenger tramway only at a designated area;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_1_l"/><heading><desig>l.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Acting in a manner while riding a passenger tramway that is consistent with posted rules and that will not interfere with the proper and safe operation of the passenger tramway;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_1_m"/><heading><desig>m.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Refraining from throwing or expelling any object while riding on a passenger tramway, and from placing an object on or about the uphill track, the entry area, or the exit area of any passenger tramway;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_1_n"/><heading><desig>n.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Crossing the uphill track of a passenger tramway only at designated locations; and</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_1_o"/><heading><desig>o.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> When involved in a winter sports collision or other accident involving another individual who the participant knows or reasonably should know is in need of medical or other assistance, obtaining assistance for that individual, notifying the proper authorities, and not leaving the scene of the collision or accident without giving the participant's personal identification, including his name and local and permanent address, to an employee or representative of the operator or to someone providing assistance to the individual, except for the purpose of obtaining assistance for the individual, in which case the participant shall give his personal identification to an employee or representative of the operator or to someone providing assistance to the individual after obtaining such assistance; and</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> When requested, provide his personal identification to an employee or representative of the winter sports area or operator.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b"/><heading><desig>B.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Each passenger using a passenger tramway with the permission of an operator shall abide by and fulfill each duty and responsibility set forth in subsection A that is applicable to use of a passenger tramway.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c"/><heading><desig>C.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Each participant, and each passenger using a passenger tramway with the permission of an operator, shall be deemed as a matter of law to have seen and understood all postings, signs, and other warnings provided by the winter sports area operator as required by this article.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d"/><heading><desig>D.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> An operator is entitled to assume that each passenger who boards a passenger tramway has sufficient knowledge, ability, and physical dexterity to embark upon, disembark from, and negotiate the passenger tramway. Any passenger who is unfamiliar with the use of a passenger tramway or who believes he does not have sufficient knowledge to embark upon, disembark from, and negotiate a passenger tramway shall ask the operator for instruction on such use or to provide such knowledge. Nothing in this article shall be construed to extend liability to an operator for injury to or death of a participant or other individual or damage to property resulting from a passenger who is unfamiliar with the use of a passenger tramway or believes he does not have sufficient knowledge to embark, disembark from, or negotiate a passenger tramway and does not ask the operator for instruction on such use or to provide such knowledge, or who does not have the ability or physical dexterity to embark upon, disembark from, or negotiate a passenger tramway.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_e"/><heading><desig>E.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Any individual who is not authorized by the operator to use or be present at the winter sports area shall be deemed a trespasser.</p></bodyText></level><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p><citation normalizedCite="2012 VA CH 713"><content><span normalizedCite="2012 Va. Ch. 713">2012, c. 713<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2012#000713#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PVV0-004G-K4Y4-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 8.01.</desig><title>CIVIL REMEDIES AND PROCEDURE</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 3.</desig><title>ACTIONS</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="article"><heading><desig>ARTICLE 25.</desig><title>WINTER SPORTS SAFETY ACT.</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Torts</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDAwOEM2NTEzQkVDNEI4NzlGMEZERUEyRjQwODM4Njg7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MzNEQTg0RkMwMUQ4NDk4NEE0MjY2REUyQjg4REMxMjI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RURCNTc2RTI5NzRDNEQ5Q0ExRDlBQTcxNTVDOEQ3Nzg</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification><classificationGroup classificationScheme="indexing-terms"><classification classificationScheme="legal"/></classificationGroup></metadata></legislativeDoc>