<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#349#000010#     1#        205.1#">Va. Code Ann. § 10.1-205.1</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_10.1-205.1"/><heading><desig>§ 10.1-205.1.</desig><title>Breaks Interstate Park Compact of 1954</title></heading><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_1"/><heading><desig>§ 1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The Governor is hereby authorized and directed to execute, on behalf of the Commonwealth of Virginia, a compact with the Commonwealth of Kentucky, which compact shall be in form substantially as follows:</p><p>BREAKS INTERSTATE PARK COMPACT </p><p>Pursuant to authority granted by an Act of the 83rd Congress of the United States, being Public Law 275, approved August 14, 1953, the Commonwealth of Kentucky and the Commonwealth of Virginia do hereby covenant and agree as follows:</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="article"><anchor id="_i"/><heading><desig>Article I.</desig></heading><bodyText><p>The Commonwealth of Kentucky and the Commonwealth of Virginia agree to create, develop and operate an interstate park to be known as the Breaks Interstate Park, which shall be located along the Russell Fork of the Levisa Fork of the Big Sandy River and on adjacent areas in Pike County, Kentucky, and Dickenson and Buchanan Counties, Virginia. Said park shall be of such area and of such character as may be determined by the Commission created by this Compact.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="article"><anchor id="_ii"/><heading><desig>Article II.</desig></heading><bodyText><p>There is hereby created the Breaks Interstate Park Commission, which shall be a body corporate with the power and duties set forth herein and such additional powers as may be conferred upon it by subsequent action of the appropriate authorities of Kentucky and Virginia. The Commission shall consist of the Director of the Virginia Department of Conservation and Recreation or his designee and the Commissioner of the Kentucky Department of Parks or his designee as voting, ex officio members, and three commissioners from each of the two states, each of whom shall be a citizen of the state he shall represent. Members of the Commission shall be appointed by the Governor. Vacancies shall be filled by the Governor for the unexpired term. The term of the commissioners appointed by the Governor shall be for four years. Their successors shall be appointed for terms of four years each. Each commissioner shall hold office until his successor is appointed and qualified. An officer or employee of the State, a political subdivision or the United States government may be appointed a commissioner under this act.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="article"><anchor id="_iii"/><heading><desig>Article III.</desig></heading><bodyText><p>The Commission created herein shall be a joint corporate instrumentality of both the Commonwealth of Kentucky and the Commonwealth of Virginia for the purpose of effecting the objects of this Compact, and shall be deemed to be performing governmental functions of the two states in the performance of its duties hereunder. The Commission shall have power to sue and be sued, to contract and be contracted with, to use a common seal and to make and adopt suitable by-laws, rules and regulations. The Commission shall have the authority to acquire by gift, purchase or otherwise real estate and other property, and to dispose of such real estate and other property. Each Commonwealth agrees that it will authorize the Commission to exercise the right of eminent domain to acquire property located within each Commonwealth required by the Commission to effectuate the purposes of this Compact.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="article"><anchor id="_iv"/><heading><desig>Article IV.</desig></heading><bodyText><p>The Commission shall select from among its members a chairman and a vice-chairman, and may select from among its members a secretary and treasurer or may designate other persons to fill these positions. It may appoint, and at its pleasure remove or discharge, such officers and legal, clerical, expert and other assistants and employees as may be required to carry the provisions of this Compact into effect, and shall fix and determine their duties, qualifications and compensation. It may establish and maintain one or more offices for the transaction of its business, and may meet at any time or place. A majority of the commissioners present shall constitute a quorum for the transaction of business. The commissioners shall serve without compensation, but shall be paid their expenses incurred in and incident to the performance of their duties. They shall take the oath of office required of officers and their respective states.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="article"><anchor id="_v"/><heading><desig>Article V.</desig></heading><bodyText><p>Each Commonwealth agrees that the officers and departments of each will be authorized to do all things falling within their respective jurisdictions necessary or incidental to the carrying out of the Compact in every particular. The Commission shall be entitled to the services of any State officer or agency in the same manner as any other department or agency of this State. The Commission shall keep accurate records, showing in full its receipts and disbursements, and said records shall be open at any reasonable time to the inspection of such representatives of the two Commonwealths as may be duly constituted for that purpose. The Commission shall submit annually and at other times as required such reports as may be required by the laws of each Commonwealth or by the Governor thereof.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="article"><anchor id="_vi"/><heading><desig>Article VI.</desig></heading><bodyText><p>The cost of acquiring land and other property required in the development and operation of the Breaks Interstate Park and constructing, maintaining and operating improvements and facilities therein and equipping same may be defrayed by funds received from appropriations, gifts, the use of money received as fees or charges for the use of said park and facilities, or by the issuance of revenue bonds, or by a combination of such sources of funds. The Commission may charge for admission to said park, or make other charges deemed appropriate by it and shall have the use of funds so received for park purposes. The Commission is authorized to issue revenue bonds, which shall not be obligations of either state, pursuant to procedures which shall be in substantial compliance with the provisions of laws of either or both states governing the issuance of revenue bonds by governmental agencies.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="article"><anchor id="_vii"/><heading><desig>Article VII.</desig></heading><bodyText><p>All money, securities and other property, real and personal, received by way of gift or otherwise or revenue received from its operations may be retained by the Commission and used for the development, maintenance and operation of the park or for other park purposes.</p><p>The Commission shall not pledge the credit of either Commonwealth except by and with the authority of the General Assembly thereof.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="article"><anchor id="_viii"/><heading><desig>Article VIII.</desig></heading><bodyText><p>This Compact may be amended from time to time by the concurrent action of the two Commonwealth parties hereto.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_2"/><heading><desig>§ 2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> All governmental agencies of the Commonwealth of Virginia are authorized to cooperate with the Breaks Interstate Park Commission, it being the policy of this Commonwealth to perform and carry out the Compact and to accomplish the purposes thereof. The Department of Conservation and Development is authorized to transfer funds available to it to the Breaks Interstate Park Commission with the same effect as if it were expending funds on State parks. The Breaks Interstate Park Commission is authorized to exercise the right of eminent domain on behalf of the Commonwealth of Virginia in acquiring land or other property required in the establishment or enlargement of a Breaks Interstate Park.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_3"/><heading><desig>§ 3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The Compact approved herein and other provisions of this act dependent thereon shall become effective upon the ratification and approval of the Compact by the General Assembly of the Commonwealth of Kentucky and upon approval of this Compact by the Congress of the United States.</p><p>Until such time as the Commonwealth of Kentucky approves the Compact as amended by the first enactment clause hereof, the Compact adopted pursuant to Chapter 37 of the Acts of Assembly of 1954, as amended by Chapter 292 of the Acts of Assembly of 1964, shall prevail.</p></bodyText></level><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p>1954, c. 37; 1964, c. 292; <citation normalizedCite="1994 VA CH 622"><content><span normalizedCite="1994 Va. Ch. 622">1994, c. 622<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1994#000622#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PWC0-004G-K313-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 10.1.</desig><title>CONSERVATION</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="subtitle"><heading><desig>SUBTITLE I.</desig><title>ACTIVITIES ADMINISTERED BY THE DEPARTMENT OF CONSERVATION AND RECREATION</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 2.</desig><title>PARKS AND RECREATION</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="article"><heading><desig>ARTICLE 1.1.</desig><title>INTERSTATE PARKS</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Civil Procedure</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MzUxNjJDMEQ5N0YwNDMzM0JDMjEzM0UzOTYzMzI3OTU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Experts</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RUE5NTI3MzM2NjU2NDkyMjk1MTAxQjk3NTMxRDMxQjU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RUQyRTFGQTg5NEU1NDQzODlBNUNCNUEzNTU5MjkzRTc</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDQ1MzNGQjY0MDg4NEFGNUI1M0MwNTNFRDREQjAwN0U7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RUQyRTFGQTg5NEU1NDQzODlBNUNCNUEzNTU5MjkzRTc</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Governments</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjdEQjE4OUJDMzQxNDNEMEI0RTI1QUFCMzJENjEwRTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Administrative Boards</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QTYwRUFCMDc5MzQ5NDEyREFEQkU2NkE2MjRGQTlCNzY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Njg1MkM3RkYyNzIxNEVFRkJFMTI2NUM4NUU1ODdEM0Q</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification><classificationGroup classificationScheme="indexing-terms"><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem score="90"><className>Environmental &amp; Natural Resources</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NzFDRDYyNkI2QjhBNDg3NTkyRjRDRkZEQjlCRkRBQzM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></classificationGroup></metadata></legislativeDoc>