<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#349#000038#     2#       3412.1#">Va. Code Ann. § 38.2-3412.1</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_38.2-3412.1"/><heading><desig>§ 38.2-3412.1.</desig><title>Coverage for mental health and substance use disorders</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a"/><heading><desig>A.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> As used in this section:</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Adult"</emphasis> means any person who is 19 years of age or older.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Alcohol or drug rehabilitation facility"</emphasis> means a facility in which a state-approved program for the treatment of alcoholism or drug addiction is provided. The facility shall be either (i) licensed by the State Board of Health pursuant to Chapter 5 (<citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 32.1-123"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 32.1-123">§ 32.1-123<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000032#     1#          123#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> et seq.) of Title 32.1 or by the Department of Behavioral Health and Developmental Services pursuant to Article 2 (<citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 37.2-403"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 37.2-403">§ 37.2-403<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000037#     2#          403#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> et seq.) of Chapter 4 of Title 37.2 or (ii) a state agency or institution.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Child or adolescent"</emphasis> means any person under the age of 19 years.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Inpatient treatment"</emphasis> means mental health or substance abuse services delivered on a 24-hour per day basis in a hospital, alcohol or drug rehabilitation facility, an intermediate care facility or an inpatient unit of a mental health treatment center.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Intermediate care facility"</emphasis> means a licensed, residential public or private facility that is not a hospital and that is operated primarily for the purpose of providing a continuous, structured 24-hour per day, state-approved program of inpatient substance abuse services.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Medication management visit"</emphasis> means a visit no more than 20 minutes in length with a licensed physician or other licensed health care provider with prescriptive authority for the sole purpose of monitoring and adjusting medications prescribed for mental health or substance abuse treatment.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Mental health services"</emphasis> or <emphasis typeStyle="it">"mental health benefits"</emphasis> means benefits with respect to items or services for mental health conditions as defined under the terms of the health benefit plan. Any condition defined by the health benefit plan as being or as not being a mental health condition shall be defined to be consistent with generally recognized independent standards of current medical practice.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Mental health treatment center"</emphasis> means a treatment facility organized to provide care and treatment for mental illness through multiple modalities or techniques pursuant to a written plan approved and monitored by a physician, clinical psychologist, or a psychologist licensed to practice in this Commonwealth. The facility shall be (i) licensed by the Commonwealth, (ii) funded or eligible for funding under federal or state law, or (iii) affiliated with a hospital under a contractual agreement with an established system for patient referral.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Outpatient treatment"</emphasis> means mental health or substance abuse treatment services rendered to a person as an individual or part of a group while not confined as an inpatient. Such treatment shall not include services delivered through a partial hospitalization or intensive outpatient program as defined herein.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Partial hospitalization"</emphasis> means a licensed or approved day or evening treatment program that includes the major diagnostic, medical, psychiatric and psychosocial rehabilitation treatment modalities designed for patients with mental, emotional, or nervous disorders, and alcohol or other drug dependence who require coordinated, intensive, comprehensive and multi-disciplinary treatment. Such a program shall provide treatment over a period of six or more continuous hours per day to individuals or groups of individuals who are not admitted as inpatients. Such term shall also include intensive outpatient programs for the treatment of alcohol or other drug dependence which provide treatment over a period of three or more continuous hours per day to individuals or groups of individuals who are not admitted as inpatients.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Substance abuse services"</emphasis> or <emphasis typeStyle="it">"substance use disorder benefits"</emphasis> means benefits with respect to items or services for substance use disorders as defined under the terms of the health benefit plan. Any disorder defined by the health benefit plan as being or as not being a substance use disorder shall be defined to be consistent with generally recognized independent standards of current medical practice.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Treatment"</emphasis> means services including diagnostic evaluation, medical, psychiatric and psychological care, and psychotherapy for mental, emotional or nervous disorders or alcohol or other drug dependence rendered by a hospital, alcohol or drug rehabilitation facility, intermediate care facility, mental health treatment center, a physician, psychologist, clinical psychologist, licensed clinical social worker, licensed professional counselor, licensed substance abuse treatment practitioner, licensed marriage and family therapist or clinical nurse specialist who renders mental health services. Treatment for physiological or psychological dependence on alcohol or other drugs shall also include the services of counseling and rehabilitation as well as services rendered by a state certified alcoholism, drug, or substance abuse counselor or substance abuse counseling assistant, limited to the scope of practice set forth in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 54.1-3507.1"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 54.1-3507.1">§ 54.1-3507.1<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000054#     1#       3507.1#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> or <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 54.1-3507.2"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 54.1-3507.2">54.1-3507.2<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000054#     1#       3507.2#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, respectively, employed by a facility or program licensed to provide such treatment.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b"/><heading><desig>B.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Except as provided in subsections C and D, group and individual health insurance coverage, as defined in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 38.2-3431"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 38.2-3431">§ 38.2-3431<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000038#     2#         3431#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, shall provide mental health and substance use disorder benefits. Such benefits shall be in parity with the medical and surgical benefits contained in the coverage in accordance with the Mental Health Parity and Addiction Equity Act of 2008, P.L. 110-343, even where those requirements would not otherwise apply directly.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c"/><heading><desig>C.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Any grandfathered plan as defined in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 38.2-3438"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 38.2-3438">§ 38.2-3438<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000038#     2#         3438#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> in the small group market shall either continue to provide benefits in accordance with subsection B or continue to provide coverage for inpatient and partial hospitalization mental health and substance abuse services as follows:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Treatment for an adult as an inpatient at a hospital, inpatient unit of a mental health treatment center, alcohol or drug rehabilitation facility or intermediate care facility for a minimum period of 20 days per policy or contract year.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Treatment for a child or adolescent as an inpatient at a hospital, inpatient unit of a mental health treatment center, alcohol or drug rehabilitation facility or intermediate care facility for a minimum period of 25 days per policy or contract year.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Up to 10 days of the inpatient benefit set forth in subdivisions 1 and 2 of this subsection may be converted when medically necessary at the option of the person or the parent, as defined in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 16.1-336"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 16.1-336">§ 16.1-336<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000016#     1#          336#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, of a child or adolescent receiving such treatment to a partial hospitalization benefit applying a formula which shall be no less favorable than an exchange of 1.5 days of partial hospitalization coverage for each inpatient day of coverage. An insurance policy or subscription contract described herein that provides inpatient benefits in excess of 20 days per policy or contract year for adults or 25 days per policy or contract year for a child or adolescent may provide for the conversion of such excess days on the terms set forth in this subdivision.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c_4"/><heading><desig>4.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The limits of the benefits set forth in this subsection shall not be more restrictive than for any other illness, except that the benefits may be limited as set out in this subsection.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c_5"/><heading><desig>5.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> This subsection shall not apply to any excepted benefits policy as defined in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 38.2-3431"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 38.2-3431">§ 38.2-3431<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000038#     2#         3431#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, nor to policies or contracts designed for issuance to persons eligible for coverage under Title XVIII of the Social Security Act, known as Medicare, or any other similar coverage under state or federal governmental plans.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d"/><heading><desig>D.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Any grandfathered plan as defined in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 38.2-3438"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 38.2-3438">§ 38.2-3438<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000038#     2#         3438#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> in the small group market shall also either continue to provide benefits in accordance with subsection B or continue to provide coverage for outpatient mental health and substance abuse services as follows:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A minimum of 20 visits for outpatient treatment of an adult, child or adolescent shall be provided in each policy or contract year.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The limits of the benefits set forth in this subsection shall be no more restrictive than the limits of benefits applicable to physical illness; however, the coinsurance factor applicable to any outpatient visit beyond the first five of such visits covered in any policy or contract year shall be at least 50 percent.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> For the purpose of this section, medication management visits shall be covered in the same manner as a medication management visit for the treatment of physical illness and shall not be counted as an outpatient treatment visit in the calculation of the benefit set forth herein.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d_4"/><heading><desig>4.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> For the purpose of this subsection, if all covered expenses for a visit for outpatient mental health or substance abuse treatment apply toward any deductible required by a policy or contract, such visit shall not count toward the outpatient visit benefit maximum set forth in the policy or contract.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d_5"/><heading><desig>5.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> This subsection shall not apply to any excepted benefits policy as defined in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 38.2-3431"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 38.2-3431">§ 38.2-3431<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000038#     2#         3431#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, nor to policies or contracts designed for issuance to persons eligible for coverage under Title XVIII of the Social Security Act, known as Medicare, or any other similar coverage under state or federal governmental plans.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_e"/><heading><desig>E.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The requirements of this section shall apply to all insurance policies and subscription contracts delivered, issued for delivery, reissued, renewed, or extended, or at any time when any term of the policy or contract is changed or any premium adjustment made.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_f"/><heading><desig>F.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The provisions of this section shall not apply in any instance in which the provisions of this section are inconsistent or in conflict with a provision of Article 6 (<citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 38.2-3438"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 38.2-3438">§ 38.2-3438<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000038#     2#         3438#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> et seq.) of Chapter 34.</p></bodyText></level><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p><citation normalizedCite="1993 VA CH 132"><content><span normalizedCite="1993 Va. Ch. 132">1993, c. 132<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1993#000132#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1995 VA CH 270"><content><span normalizedCite="1995 Va. Ch. 270">1995, c. 270<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1995#000270#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1996 VA CH 41"><content><span normalizedCite="1996 Va. Ch. 41">1996, c. 41<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1996#000041#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1997 VA CH 901"><content><span normalizedCite="1997 Va. Ch. 901">1997, c. 901<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1997#000901#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1999 VA CH 941"><content><span normalizedCite="1999 Va. Ch. 941">1999, c. 941<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1999#000941#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2001 VA CH 460"><content><span normalizedCite="2001 Va. Ch. 460">2001, c. 460<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2001#000460#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2004 VA CH 156"><content><span normalizedCite="2004 Va. Ch. 156">2004, c. 156<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2004#000156#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2006 VA CH 638"><content><span normalizedCite="2006 Va. Ch. 638">2006, c. 638<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2006#000638#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2009 VA CH 813"><content><span normalizedCite="2009 Va. Ch. 813">2009, cc. 813<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2009#000813#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2009 VA CH 840"><content><span normalizedCite="2009 Va. Ch. 840">840<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2009#000840#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2010 VA CH 693"><content><span normalizedCite="2010 Va. Ch. 693">2010, c. 693<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2010#000693#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2013 VA CH 751"><content><span normalizedCite="2013 Va. Ch. 751">2013, c. 751<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2013#000751#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2015 VA CH 649"><content><span normalizedCite="2015 Va. Ch. 649">2015, c. 649<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2015#000649#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PV40-004G-K3TG-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 38.2.</desig><title>INSURANCE</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 34.</desig><title>PROVISIONS RELATING TO ACCIDENT AND SICKNESS INSURANCE</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="article"><heading><desig>ARTICLE 2.</desig><title>MANDATED BENEFITS</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Family Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NEI4M0U5Qzg3RTk0NDdBRUJGNDRGNkZEQkU3RDdFNDU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6REJGM0U3ODNBRTVGNDJGRUI3NENBMkVBNDQyRDhBODU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDlEQ0FFMTZDRDFGNEI0RTlFOTY4ODUwNDVDMjFCQUE</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Healthcare Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NkUxMkVDQjJDOEY5NDVDQ0E5NTFEMTlDMjIwNzVERjc7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6N0U1NEQ5NkFBQjhENEUyMjhDMjM2MjRFQkVBOTFDODI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MkIwM0E1RTM4NkY5NEU4QjhBM0RCNzc5QjE4RkIzOEI</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NTVDMzIyNkJCMTRBNDI0NUJBOTlBOTYyMjQ0MDkyODU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QTJGRDdFQzgwODczNDI0NDgwMzEyM0JBOEQ2MUVDNjg</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Insurance Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDM4MzQ2QUYzMTY0NDQzQTkxRDQwRUUzRUM5RDg0OEM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Policy Delivery</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OUYyOUJCOTEwRjgwNENENUE4M0JFRkZDRDVGMzc4Rjg7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Qjg2NDVEOEQ5Q0IxNEQ0RTg0MTkyQ0ZCMkNENDlBODY</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Public Health &amp; Welfare Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDYwRTY1MDg3MTk5NDUyNkFFRDI1RjJBRERGQ0UxNzI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NUVCNTZERDE5OTI4NDJDRUEzMDVFNjQ3NkEyMjI5QUI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MTlCM0Q3MTlFNUQ0NDA5OTgwQTEwQjE1M0ZGMTlFQjc</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NjdDOTFFQjY0OTM1NEUyNEI5OEYwODE0RTA4RENEQkE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RTA2N0I2MjA4MEMwNEExNjlBQzkzRjBGOTAxODRCNkY</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MTJEMUIzNEFBMEE0NDUwMTgyOTk5Q0Q5MUQ3NTNDNTM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NjVGRUIzQkI1QTg1NDUxNkJFM0UwN0IxRTVENDlBNTM</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjBDQjgyQzFCM0JDNEQ0MDgwQTU1N0M1RDA0MzkzMDQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6N0UyRjc1OTQ5RkNDNDRFNDhDNkUyRkFGNTY0MDFCNzE</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RTJGRDg1RERERUU5NEJCNzlCNUMzMUE2N0Q0NUFDNTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Mzc3RTE2MDQ4Nzc5NDRCMkI1QjYyQ0UyM0U5Qzc1QTg</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Treatment</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QTE3NDlDOUQ4Mzg1NDcxNzhCNzQwNDc2MkEzMTkwRUI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RTA2N0I2MjA4MEMwNEExNjlBQzkzRjBGOTAxODRCNkY</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification><classificationGroup classificationScheme="indexing-terms"><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem score="90"><className>Insurance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDM4MzQ2QUYzMTY0NDQzQTkxRDQwRUUzRUM5RDg0OEM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></classificationGroup></metadata></legislativeDoc>