<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#349#000038#     2#          602#">Va. Code Ann. § 38.2-602</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_38.2-602"/><heading><desig>§ 38.2-602.</desig><title>Definitions</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><bodyText><p>As used in this chapter:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><bodyText><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Adverse underwriting decision"</emphasis> means:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Any of the following actions with respect to insurance transactions involving insurance coverage that is individually underwritten:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_1_a"/><heading><desig>a.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A declination of insurance coverage;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_1_b"/><heading><desig>b.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A termination of insurance coverage;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_1_c"/><heading><desig>c.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Failure of an agent to apply for insurance coverage with a specific insurance institution that an agent represents and that is requested by an applicant;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_1_d"/><heading><desig>d.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> In the case of a property or casualty insurance coverage:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_1_d_1"/><heading><desig>(1)</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Placement by an insurance institution or agent of a risk with a residual market mechanism or an unlicensed insurer; or</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_1_d_2"/><heading><desig>(2)</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The charging of a higher rate on the basis of information that differs from that which the applicant or policyholder furnished; or</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_1_e"/><heading><desig>e.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> In the case of a life or accident and sickness insurance coverage, an offer to insure at higher than standard rates, or with limitations, exceptions or benefits other than those applied for.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Notwithstanding subdivision 1 of this definition, the following actions shall not be considered adverse underwriting decisions, but the insurance institution or agent responsible for their occurrence shall provide the applicant or policyholder with the specific reason or reasons for their occurrence:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_2_a"/><heading><desig>a.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The termination of an individual policy form on a class or statewide basis;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_2_b"/><heading><desig>b.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A declination of insurance coverage solely because such coverage is not available on a class or statewide basis;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_2_c"/><heading><desig>c.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The rescission of a policy.</p></bodyText></level></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><bodyText><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Affiliate"</emphasis> or <emphasis typeStyle="it">"affiliated"</emphasis> means a person that directly, or indirectly through one or more intermediaries, controls, is controlled by, or is under common control with another person.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Agent"</emphasis> shall have the meaning as set forth in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 38.2-1800"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 38.2-1800">§ 38.2-1800<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000038#     2#         1800#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> and shall include surplus lines brokers.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Applicant"</emphasis> means any person who seeks to contract for insurance coverage other than a person seeking group insurance that is not individually underwritten.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Clear and conspicuous notice"</emphasis> means a notice that is reasonably understandable and designed to call attention to the nature and significance of the information in the notice.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Consumer report"</emphasis> means any written, oral, or other communication of information bearing on a natural person's credit worthiness, credit standing, credit capacity, character, general reputation, personal characteristics or mode of living that is used or expected to be used in connection with an insurance transaction.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Consumer reporting agency"</emphasis> means any person who:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_1_seq_2"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Regularly engages, in whole or in part, in the practice of assembling or preparing consumer reports for a monetary fee;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_2_seq_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Obtains information primarily from sources other than insurance institutions; and</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Furnishes consumer reports to other persons.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><bodyText><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Control,"</emphasis> including the terms "controlled by" or "under common control with," means the possession, direct or indirect, of the power to direct or cause the direction of the management and policies of a person, whether through the ownership of voting securities, by contract other than a commercial contract for goods or nonmanagement services, or otherwise, unless the power is the result of an official position with or corporate office held by the person.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Declination of insurance coverage"</emphasis> means a denial, in whole or in part, by an insurance institution or agent of requested insurance coverage.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Financial information"</emphasis> means personal information other than medical record information or records of payment for the provision of health care to an individual.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Financial institution"</emphasis> means any institution the business of which is engaging in financial activities as described in Section 4(k) of the Bank Holding Company Act of 1956 <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="12 USC 1843"><content><span normalizedCite="12 U.S.C. 1843">(12 U.S.C. § 1843<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1828#123#000012#       1843#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> (k)).</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Financial product or service"</emphasis> means any product or service that a financial holding company could offer by engaging in an activity that is financial in nature or incidental to such a financial activity under Section 4(k) of the Bank Holding Company Act of 1956 <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="12 USC 1843"><content><span normalizedCite="12 U.S.C. 1843">(12 U.S.C. § 1843<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1828#123#000012#       1843#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> (k)).</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Individual"</emphasis> means any natural person who:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_1_seq_3"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> In the case of property or casualty insurance, is a past, present, or proposed named insured or certificate holder;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_2_seq_3"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> In the case of life or accident and sickness insurance, is a past, present, or proposed principal insured or certificate holder;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_3_seq_2"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Is a past, present or proposed policyowner;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_4"/><heading><desig>4.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Is a past or present applicant;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_5"/><heading><desig>5.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Is a past or present claimant;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_6"/><heading><desig>6.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Derived, derives, or is proposed to derive insurance coverage under an insurance policy or certificate subject to this chapter;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_7"/><heading><desig>7.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> For the purposes of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 38.2-612.1"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 38.2-612.1">§§ 38.2-612.1<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000038#     2#        612.1#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> and <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 38.2-613"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 38.2-613">38.2-613<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000038#     2#          613#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, is a beneficiary of a life insurance policy;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_8"/><heading><desig>8.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> For the purposes of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 38.2-612.1"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 38.2-612.1">§§ 38.2-612.1<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000038#     2#        612.1#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> and <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 38.2-613"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 38.2-613">38.2-613<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000038#     2#          613#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, is a mortgagor of a mortgage covered under a mortgage guaranty insurance policy; or</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_9"/><heading><desig>9.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> For the purposes of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 38.2-612.1"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 38.2-612.1">§§ 38.2-612.1<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000038#     2#        612.1#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> and <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 38.2-613"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 38.2-613">38.2-613<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000038#     2#          613#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, is an owner of property used as security for an indebtedness for which single interest insurance is required by a lender.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><bodyText><p>Notwithstanding any provision of this definition to the contrary, for purposes of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 38.2-612.1"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 38.2-612.1">§ 38.2-612.1<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000038#     2#        612.1#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, "individual" shall not include any natural person who is covered under an employee benefit plan, group or blanket insurance contract, or group annuity contract when the insurance institution or agent that provides such plan or contract: (i) furnishes the notice required under <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 38.2-604.1"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 38.2-604.1">§ 38.2-604.1<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000038#     2#        604.1#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> to the employee benefit plan sponsor, group or blanket insurance contract holder, or group annuity contract holder; and (ii) does not disclose the financial information of the person to a nonaffiliated third party other than as permitted under <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 38.2-613"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 38.2-613">§ 38.2-613<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000038#     2#          613#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Institutional source"</emphasis> means any person or governmental entity that provides information about an individual to an agent, insurance institution or insurance-support organization, other than:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_1_seq_4"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> An agent;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_2_seq_4"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The individual who is the subject of the information; or</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_3_seq_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A natural person acting in a personal capacity rather than in a business or professional capacity.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><bodyText><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Insurance institution"</emphasis> means any corporation, association, partnership, reciprocal exchange, inter-insurer, Lloyd's type of organization, fraternal benefit society, or other person engaged in the business of insurance, including health maintenance organizations, and health, legal, dental, and optometric service plans.  "Insurance institution" shall not include agents or insurance-support organizations.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Insurance-support organization"</emphasis> means any person who regularly engages, in whole or in part, in the practice of assembling or collecting information about natural persons for the primary purpose of providing the information to an insurance institution or agent for insurance transactions, including (i) the furnishing of consumer reports or investigative consumer reports to an insurance institution or agent for use in connection with an insurance transaction or (ii) the collection of personal information from insurance institutions, agents or other insurance-support organizations for the purpose of detecting or preventing fraud, material misrepresentation or material nondisclosure in connection with insurance underwriting or insurance claim activity. However, the following persons shall not be considered "insurance-support organizations" for purposes of this chapter: agents, governmental institutions, insurance institutions, medical-care institutions and medical professionals.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Insurance transaction"</emphasis> means any transaction involving insurance primarily for personal, family, or household needs rather than business or professional needs that entails:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_1_seq_5"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The determination of an individual's eligibility for an insurance coverage, benefit or payment; or</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_2_seq_5"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The servicing of an insurance application, policy, contract, or certificate.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><bodyText><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Investigative consumer report"</emphasis> means a consumer report or a portion thereof in which information about a natural person's character, general reputation, personal characteristics, or mode of living is obtained through personal interviews with the person's neighbors, friends, associates, acquaintances, or others who may have knowledge concerning such items of information.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Joint marketing agreement"</emphasis> means a formal written contract pursuant to which an insurance institution jointly offers, endorses, or sponsors a financial product or service with another financial institution.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Life insurance"</emphasis> includes annuities.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Medical-care institution"</emphasis> means any facility or institution that is licensed to provide health care services to natural persons, including but not limited to, hospitals, skilled nursing facilities, home-health agencies, medical clinics, rehabilitation agencies, and public-health agencies or health-maintenance organizations.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Medical professional"</emphasis> means any person licensed or certified to provide health care services to natural persons, including but not limited to, a physician, dentist, nurse, chiropractor, optometrist, physical or occupational therapist, social worker, clinical dietitian, clinical psychologist, licensed professional counselor, licensed marriage and family therapist, pharmacist, or speech therapist.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Medical-record information"</emphasis> means personal information that:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_1_seq_6"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Relates to an individual's physical or mental condition, medical history, or medical treatment; and</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_2_seq_6"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Is obtained from a medical professional or medical-care institution, from the individual, or from the individual's spouse, parent, or legal guardian.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><bodyText><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Nonaffiliated third party"</emphasis> means any person who is not an affiliate of an insurance institution but does not mean (i) an agent who is selling or servicing a product on behalf of the insurance institution or (ii) a person who is employed jointly by the insurance institution and the company that is not an affiliate.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Personal information"</emphasis> means any individually identifiable information gathered in connection with an insurance transaction from which judgments can be made about an individual's character, habits, avocations, finances, occupation, general reputation, credit, health, or any other personal characteristics. "Personal information" includes an individual's name and address and medical-record information, but does not include (i) privileged information or (ii) any information that is publicly available.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Policyholder"</emphasis> means any person who:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_1_seq_7"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> In the case of individual property or casualty insurance, is a present named insured;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_2_seq_7"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> In the case of individual life or accident and sickness insurance, is a present policyowner; or</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_3_seq_4"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> In the case of group insurance that is individually underwritten, is a present group certificate holder.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><bodyText><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Policyholder information"</emphasis> means personal information about a policyholder, whether in paper, electronic, or other form, that is maintained by or on behalf of an insurance institution, agent, or insurance-support organization.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Pretext interview"</emphasis> means an interview whereby a person, in an attempt to obtain information about a natural person, performs one or more of the following acts:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_1_seq_8"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Pretends to be someone he or she is not;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_2_seq_8"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Pretends to represent a person he or she is not in fact representing;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_3_seq_5"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Misrepresents the true purpose of the interview; or</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_4_seq_2"/><heading><desig>4.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Refuses to identify himself or herself upon request.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><bodyText><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Privileged information"</emphasis> means any individually identifiable information that (i) relates to a claim for insurance benefits or a civil or criminal proceeding involving an individual, and (ii) is collected in connection with or in reasonable anticipation of a claim for insurance benefits or civil or criminal proceeding involving an individual.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Residual market mechanism"</emphasis> means an association, organization, or other entity defined, described, or provided for in the Virginia Automobile Insurance Plan as set forth in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 38.2-2015"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 38.2-2015">§ 38.2-2015<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000038#     2#         2015#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, or in the Virginia Property Insurance Association as set forth in Chapter 27 (<citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 38.2-2700"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 38.2-2700">§ 38.2-2700<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000038#     2#         2700#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> et seq.) of this title.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Termination of insurance coverage"</emphasis> or <emphasis typeStyle="it">"termination of an insurance policy"</emphasis> means either a cancellation or nonrenewal of an insurance policy other than by the policyholder's request, in whole or in part, for any reason other than the failure to pay a premium as required by the policy.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Unlicensed insurer"</emphasis> means an insurance institution that has not been granted a license by the Commission to transact the business of insurance in Virginia.</p></bodyText></level></level><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p>1981, c. 389, § 38.1-57.5; 1986, c. 562; <citation normalizedCite="2001 VA CH 371"><content><span normalizedCite="2001 Va. Ch. 371">2001, c. 371<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2001#000371#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2003 VA CH 729"><content><span normalizedCite="2003 Va. Ch. 729">2003, c. 729<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2003#000729#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2006 VA CH 638"><content><span normalizedCite="2006 Va. Ch. 638">2006, c. 638<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2006#000638#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PT40-004G-K459-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 38.2.</desig><title>INSURANCE</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 6.</desig><title>INSURANCE INFORMATION AND PRIVACY PROTECTION</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Antitrust &amp; Trade Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6REEyRTNDM0JGQzYyNEMyOEFGNTAwNUJEOUU1MDg4NjU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjA1QTQ0MkNCQTJBNDAzRjg2OTkyM0UwREZENUE5Mjk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OTU3NDQyMkE3MjY5NEU2RDg1MDYzQ0I4RkJCNEMyRkY</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Banking Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjQyMUFCOUJBNURBNEFDREE3MTNCNDk5QkQ4NUM3RjI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Bank Holding Company Act</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDAxNjAxNEMxOEQ5NDNDMkE1RjEyOTAzREZEQThCMkQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDE1NTFGNzBDNTIyNDBEQUE2MkYwNkNCOTAzNjNGNzA</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OUM2ODY2RDZGMjZENDM0MkI5RDA2MjA3NkFDMDdEMTE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QTExQjk4M0RBNjUyNDBDNTgwNjI4MUIzRUU0RDBEMzI</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Insurance Brokerage</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MTI1RTI5QzVFNDRFNEMxRkFFMjE2NkE4NDY5NkQyMkQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDIzQTQ1RkM2RUQ1NEI2RThBMjBGNjU2OEZDOTE4MTQ</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Bank Holding Company Act</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDAxNjAxNEMxOEQ5NDNDMkE1RjEyOTAzREZEQThCMkQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDE1NTFGNzBDNTIyNDBEQUE2MkYwNkNCOTAzNjNGNzA</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Consumer Personal Information</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QzYzNkE2OEY4NDI2NDc4NzhFOURGQUM5NEFFNDc4NjI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDZBQjAwRjNDNUNDNEJGQkE1QjQ1NjJDRTMxNkQyRTA</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Regulation of Nursing Facilities for Disabled &amp; Elderly Persons</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QkI5RTc4N0U1MjU1NDQwMEI1MzhDOThGRTIyNDU1NDU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MTlCM0Q3MTlFNUQ0NDA5OTgwQTEwQjE1M0ZGMTlFQjc</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Surplus Lines Insurers</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RDkzOUFFNDY3RjIwNDQyQzhCMzA0RDU0MDNFQzM2NjI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OUE0QUQ4OUIxOURCNDA3RUEyQkY0NzhBREMxNzk1RTM</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjA4OEVGODBENzY4NDcxM0IyQzA1OTEwQzVDODRBOUE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjQ1NzI5NzRGQUEwNDg1RThBNDE0NTE2MkYzODc3NUQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RUZBNTgwODk0QkRCNDUwQkExNzBFRkU0NkI4MkE5OTU</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Property</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RjlENTVCNDU3NTMwNDA4MThDQTlDNjdBNjhFNjNCNzI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RUZBNTgwODk0QkRCNDUwQkExNzBFRkU0NkI4MkE5OTU</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Contracts Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QzY0RTZFMzE0RjkwNDdFQUI5M0U5N0ZFMjYyREMyQzU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Material Misrepresentations</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6N0I5NDY3NTRCNjFGNDUzOTkyQkFCRDYwQUU4NjBENzg7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NUVEMDJCNUI3RTA0NEI4OEEwRjUzMEIzMkFFNjUzMzM</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Evidence</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUVGQkU0QjJFMTIzNDNBM0FCNTVEQjAxQTM3RDcwOTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Elements</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUMxQTkwQTcxRjRDNEVBRTk4RERCMThEQjE2NkI1RDg7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QzBDMEM3QTE3RUU3NENGQzhEOTBCMEJENkI3QkNDNzI</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NzA2QzU2MkFCMzMzNDgwNkEzMDIzRDE2ODgxRjUzMkY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QzBDMEM3QTE3RUU3NENGQzhEOTBCMEJENkI3QkNDNzI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Family Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NEI4M0U5Qzg3RTk0NDdBRUJGNDRGNkZEQkU3RDdFNDU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6REJGM0U3ODNBRTVGNDJGRUI3NENBMkVBNDQyRDhBODU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDlEQ0FFMTZDRDFGNEI0RTlFOTY4ODUwNDVDMjFCQUE</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Recording</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6ODFCQTkxOUE4NzJDNEM5NUJGQjQxQjg2ODA0QjM5MzA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDlEQ0FFMTZDRDFGNEI0RTlFOTY4ODUwNDVDMjFCQUE</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Healthcare Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NkUxMkVDQjJDOEY5NDVDQ0E5NTFEMTlDMjIwNzVERjc7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Experimental Treatment</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QUNCMUU5MDQ3RUYwNDA0NkE3QzQ2MENFQzhBODYwNDQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NzYzODNGRDdGNkNDNDE4MTlDNTU4REQ1MEE3MUNFOEI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Insurance Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDM4MzQ2QUYzMTY0NDQzQTkxRDQwRUUzRUM5RDg0OEM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Applications</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NEZBMDdDODdCNkMxNEQ0Q0I5NjY4MjkwQ0QzOTA1QTk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Qjg2NDVEOEQ5Q0IxNEQ0RTg0MTkyQ0ZCMkNENDlBODY</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Consumer Personal Information</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QzYzNkE2OEY4NDI2NDc4NzhFOURGQUM5NEFFNDc4NjI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDZBQjAwRjNDNUNDNEJGQkE1QjQ1NjJDRTMxNkQyRTA</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Coverage Notice Requirements</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NEVGQzAxQUFFMDZENDZGRkExMUYwNjI0QTk1NEIxMjA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RDY2OUI1QTkwQkJCNEU4RTlFQTZGNEZERjI3RUFCNTc</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Qjg3NDkyQTRCRTg3NEI1QzgxQzY2QjBBMDI3NENFNDU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RkE2MEIwQkEwRTExNDVGOUJCRDhBRUQ3QTRGNDdDNTI</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QUQxOUQxRUE2MTVFNEMwOThGMzZEQTk5NDlFM0U2RDc7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDZBQjAwRjNDNUNDNEJGQkE1QjQ1NjJDRTMxNkQyRTA</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RTFEMDYzQTAxQTZDNEYzQzkzODFBM0RBODNGNERDRDQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NzVCREFBMEI5RUMxNEVGNzhCNjRCRTNGODY5RTVBMTE</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MzlEMURCMkFEQTNDNDcxQUFGQjFCMzY4OEE1QjIwQkM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OUM1QjU1RTk4NjlCNEIwN0IwRjVBQjNFRjgzMTA4Rjc</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NkZEODJEODNBQkNDNEEzNUI0NUFGM0I1QTM1NzcyOTc7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MzBGREI0QUFERDI3NDU1ODhFREFCRjZDMzNBRDJFOTA</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Guaranty Insurance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6ODY3QTMyOTQ0Qjc0NDA2MUJDODQ3N0ZFQ0QxOUU1RDU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OTVENjU3OTYxOUIxNDA5REFDODZCMDI0NkRDNEEzMUM</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Nonpayment of Premiums</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MTU2MDE4RkM3MUMzNEFEMzhCQzJGRTIxNUJFN0NCRTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RkE2MEIwQkEwRTExNDVGOUJCRDhBRUQ3QTRGNDdDNTI</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Offer &amp; Acceptance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MTNGMjIyRkU5RkJCNDU1RkIwNDMzMDgxMjJBMjNCRkU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Qjg2NDVEOEQ5Q0IxNEQ0RTg0MTkyQ0ZCMkNENDlBODY</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Surplus Lines Insurers</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RDkzOUFFNDY3RjIwNDQyQzhCMzA0RDU0MDNFQzM2NjI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OUE0QUQ4OUIxOURCNDA3RUEyQkY0NzhBREMxNzk1RTM</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Termination of Agency Agreements</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6M0IyODRGRUM2MEY5NDg0QjlBNTA2RkRGNzhBMkY4RDg7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OUM1QjU1RTk4NjlCNEIwN0IwRjVBQjNFRjgzMTA4Rjc</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Labor &amp; Employment Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MTE3QUQwOTA0MUYzNDlCMEFFMjUwRUNDM0RDRkM5QzM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Noncompetition &amp; Nondisclosure Agreements</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NjdFNjk2RkY4MEQ4NDVDQTlEOTg2ODk1MERGQTBEOTQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NTM1Q0JDMkNCMDQ5NENBODg3QjlCQzBCNDQxM0U0ODE</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Public Health &amp; Welfare Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDYwRTY1MDg3MTk5NDUyNkFFRDI1RjJBRERGQ0UxNzI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Nursing Facilities</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QkI5RTc4N0U1MjU1NDQwMEI1MzhDOThGRTIyNDU1NDU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NjVGRUIzQkI1QTg1NDUxNkJFM0UwN0IxRTVENDlBNTM</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification><classificationGroup classificationScheme="indexing-terms"><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem score="90"><className>Insurance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDM4MzQ2QUYzMTY0NDQzQTkxRDQwRUUzRUM5RDg0OEM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></classificationGroup></metadata></legislativeDoc>