<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#349#000037#     2#          508#">Va. Code Ann. § 37.2-508</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_37.2-508"/><heading><desig>§ 37.2-508.</desig><title>Performance contract for mental health, developmental, and substance abuse services</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a"/><heading><desig>A.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The Department shall develop and initiate negotiation of the performance contracts through which it provides funds to community services boards to accomplish the purposes set forth in this chapter. In the case of operating boards, the Department may, notwithstanding any provision of law to the contrary, disburse state and federal funds appropriated to it for mental health, developmental, or substance abuse services directly to the operating board, when that operating board is authorized by the governing body of each city or county that established it to receive such funds. Six months prior to the end of an existing contract or, if no contract exists, six months prior to the beginning of each fiscal year, the Department shall make available to the public the standard performance contract form that it intends to use as the performance contract for that fiscal year and solicit public comments for a period of 60 days. Such contracts shall be for a fixed term and shall provide for annual renewal by the Board if the term exceeds one year.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b"/><heading><desig>B.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Any community services board may apply for the assistance provided in this chapter by submitting to the Department its proposed performance contract together with (i) the approval of its board of directors for operating and administrative policy boards or the comments of the local government department's policy-advisory board and (ii) the approval of the contract by formal vote of the governing body of each city or county that established it. The community services board shall make its proposed performance contract available for public review and solicit public comments for a period of 30 days prior to submitting its proposed contract for the approval of its board of directors for operating and administrative policy boards or the comments of the local government department's policy-advisory board. To avoid disruptions in service continuity and allow sufficient time to complete public review and comment about the contract and negotiation and approval of the contract, the Department may provide semi-monthly payments of state-controlled funds to the community services board. If the governing body of each city or county does not approve the proposed performance contract by September 30 of each year, the performance contract shall be deemed approved or renewed.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c"/><heading><desig>C.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The performance contract shall (i) delineate the responsibilities of the Department and the community services board; (ii) specify conditions that must be met for the receipt of state-controlled funds; (iii) identify the groups of individuals to be served with state-controlled funds; (iv) contain specific outcome measures for individuals receiving services, provider performance measures, satisfaction measures for individuals receiving services, and participation and involvement measures for individuals receiving services and their family members; (v) contain mechanisms that have been identified or developed jointly by the Department and community services board and that will be employed collaboratively by the community services board and the state hospital to manage the utilization of state hospital beds; (vi) establish an enforcement mechanism, should a community services board fail to be in substantial compliance with its performance contract, including notice and appeal processes and provisions for remediation, withholding or reducing funds, methods of repayment of funds, and the Department's exercise of the provisions of subsection E; and (vii) include reporting requirements and information about revenues, costs, services, and individuals receiving services displayed in a consistent, comparable format determined by the Department.</p><p>The Department may provide for performance monitoring in order to determine whether the community services boards are in substantial compliance with their performance contracts.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d"/><heading><desig>D.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> No community services board shall be eligible to receive state-controlled funds for mental health, developmental, or substance abuse services after September 30 of each year unless (i) its performance contract has been approved or renewed by the governing body of each city or county that established it and by the Department; (ii) it provides service, cost, and revenue data and information and aggregate and individual data and information about individuals receiving services, notwithstanding the provisions of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 37.2-400"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 37.2-400">§ 37.2-400<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000037#     2#          400#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> or any regulations adopted thereunder, to the Department in the format prescribed by the Department; and (iii) it uses standardized cost accounting and financial management practices approved by the Department.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_e"/><heading><desig>E.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> If, after unsuccessful use of a remediation process described in the performance contract, a community services board remains in substantial noncompliance with its performance contract with the Department, the Department may, after affording the community services board an adequate opportunity to use the appeal process described in the performance contract, terminate all or a portion of the contract. Using the state-controlled resources associated with that contract, the Department, after consulting with the governing body of each city or county that established the board, may negotiate a performance contract with another board, a behavioral health authority, or a private nonprofit or for-profit organization or organizations to obtain services that were the subject of the terminated performance contract.</p></bodyText></level><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p>1968, c. 477, § 37.1-198; 1970, c. 346; 1972, c. 498; 1976, c. 671; 1980, c. 582; 1986, c. 176; <citation normalizedCite="1998 VA CH 680"><content><span normalizedCite="1998 Va. Ch. 680">1998, c. 680<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1998#000680#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2005 VA CH 75"><content><span normalizedCite="2005 Va. Ch. 75">2005, cc. 75<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2005#000075#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2005 VA CH 716"><content><span normalizedCite="2005 Va. Ch. 716">716<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2005#000716#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2012 VA CH 476"><content><span normalizedCite="2012 Va. Ch. 476">2012, cc. 476<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2012#000476#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2012 VA CH 507"><content><span normalizedCite="2012 Va. Ch. 507">507<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2012#000507#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2012 VA CH 805"><content><span normalizedCite="2012 Va. Ch. 805">805<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2012#000805#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2012 VA CH 836"><content><span normalizedCite="2012 Va. Ch. 836">836<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2012#000836#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PVG0-004G-K53W-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 37.2.</desig><title>BEHAVIORAL HEALTH AND DEVELOPMENTAL SERVICES</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="subtitle"><heading><desig>SUBTITLE 2.</desig><title>BEHAVIORAL HEALTH AND DEVELOPMENTAL SERVICES</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 5.</desig><title>COMMUNITY SERVICES BOARDS</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Contracts Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QzY0RTZFMzE0RjkwNDdFQUI5M0U5N0ZFMjYyREMyQzU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NTA0RUYzODAxQjFBNENCQUFDQ0JERDU0RTIxRTkxQTM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QUQwMUEyNUE3Nzg0NEJGNTg0MkJBNkRBNDUwNjRGRTI</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Substantial Performance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QTI1QTAxMjQ2MDlDNDAyQzg1NDI2RTYyQ0REQzQ2NkE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OTdCODg3NEVGQTY5NENDQ0EzRkEwMzNGOTVBQTE0NEY</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Governments</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjdEQjE4OUJDMzQxNDNEMEI0RTI1QUFCMzJENjEwRTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Administrative Boards</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QTYwRUFCMDc5MzQ5NDEyREFEQkU2NkE2MjRGQTlCNzY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Njg1MkM3RkYyNzIxNEVFRkJFMTI2NUM4NUU1ODdEM0Q</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Finance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjMzOTBBRTg2MUVDNDdDNUE1M0QxNDk1RERCNjNCN0I7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Njg1MkM3RkYyNzIxNEVFRkJFMTI2NUM4NUU1ODdEM0Q</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Public Contracts Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDA5QTlFMDVCQUY0NEY0NUE1QzMyQzA1QkQyQzJGRUY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Cost Accounting Standards</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NjUyODNEQkJCQUFDNDQ2Nzg2NTVENjA3Q0Y3OTMxMUQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RjE3RTFCOTkwQUY3NEYzN0I4RUJCQ0VDQURDOEFGQUE</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></metadata></legislativeDoc>