<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#349#000002#     2#          616#">Va. Code Ann. § 2.2-616</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_2.2-616"/><heading><desig>§ 2.2-616.</desig><title>Legislative declaration</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a"/><heading><desig>A.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> In enacting this chapter, the General Assembly employs its legislative authority to establish that the people of Virginia, acting through their elected officials in Virginia government, have the responsibility and authority to establish policy in and for Virginia pertaining to federal programs mandated in federal statutes.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b"/><heading><desig>B.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The intent of the General Assembly is to assure the primacy of the Commonwealth's legal and political authority to implement in and for Virginia the policy mandated by federal statutes and to vigorously challenge and scrutinize the extent and scope of authority asserted by federal executive branch agencies when federal agency actions and interpretations are inconsistent with Virginia policy and exceed the lawful authority of the federal government or are not required by federal law.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c"/><heading><desig>C.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> In this connection the General Assembly finds and declares that:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The power to implement federal policies in and for Virginia is central to the ability of the people of Virginia to govern themselves under a federal system of government; and</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Any implementation of federal policies in and for Virginia by federal executive branch agencies that is contrary to fundamental notions of federalism and self-determination must be identified and countered.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d"/><heading><desig>D.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The General Assembly further finds and declares that:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> There is an urgent need to modify federal mandates because the implementation of these mandates by the Commonwealth wastes the financial resources of local governments, the citizens of Virginia and the Commonwealth and does not properly respect the rights of the Commonwealth, local governments, and citizens.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The state government has an obligation to the public to do what is necessary to protect the rights of Virginia citizens under federal law while minimizing or eliminating any additional cost or regulatory burden on any citizen of the Commonwealth.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="USCONST AMEND 10"><content><span normalizedCite="U.S. Const. AMEND 10">Tenth Amendment to the United States Constitution<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7492#207#       10 #"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> directs that powers that are not delegated to the United States are reserved to the states or to the people. Virginia, as one of the sovereign states within the Union, has constitutional authority to enact laws protecting the environment of the Commonwealth and safeguarding the public health, safety, and welfare of the citizens of Virginia. However, this authority has too often been ignored by the federal government, as the federal government has intruded more and more into areas that must be left to the states. It is essential that the dilution of the authority of state and local governments be halted and that the provisions of the Tenth Amendment be accorded proper respect.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d_4"/><heading><desig>4.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Current federal regulatory mandates, as reflected in federal administrative regulations, guidelines, and policies, often do not reflect the realities of Virginia and federal regulators frequently do not understand the needs and priorities of the citizens of Virginia.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d_5"/><heading><desig>5.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The citizens of the Commonwealth can create and wish to create innovative solutions to Virginia's problems, but the current manner in which legal challenges to state policies and federal programmatic substitutions of state programs are handled does not allow the Commonwealth the flexibility it needs. It is not possible for the Commonwealth of Virginia to effectively and efficiently implement the provisions of federal statutes unless the burden to prove the insufficiency of the Commonwealth's efforts to implement federal requirements is shifted to the person or agency who asserts such insufficiency.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d_6"/><heading><desig>6.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The provisions of this chapter will better balance the exercise of the powers of the federal government and the powers reserved to the states. In addition, the application of this chapter ultimately will bring about greater protection for the Commonwealth and the nation because it will direct the Commonwealth to implement federal statutes at the least possible cost, thereby freeing more moneys for other needs.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d_7"/><heading><desig>7.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The purpose of this chapter is to ensure that federal mandates implemented in Virginia comply with state policy as established by the General Assembly.</p></bodyText></level></level><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p><citation normalizedCite="1995 VA CH 604"><content><span normalizedCite="1995 Va. Ch. 604">1995, c. 604<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1995#000604#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, § 2.1-796; <citation normalizedCite="2001 VA CH 844"><content><span normalizedCite="2001 Va. Ch. 844">2001, c. 844<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2001#000844#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PV80-004G-K0XS-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 2.2.</desig><title>ADMINISTRATION OF GOVERNMENT</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="subtitle"><heading><desig>SUBTITLE I.</desig><title>ORGANIZATION OF STATE GOVERNMENT</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="part"><heading><desig>PART C.</desig><title>STATE AGENCIES RELATED TO THE GENERAL OPERATION OF GOVERNMENT</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 6.</desig><title>GENERAL PROVISIONS</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="article"><heading><desig>ARTICLE 2.</desig><title>IMPLEMENTATION OF FEDERAL MANDATES ACT</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Governments</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjdEQjE4OUJDMzQxNDNEMEI0RTI1QUFCMzJENjEwRTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Finance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjMzOTBBRTg2MUVDNDdDNUE1M0QxNDk1RERCNjNCN0I7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Njg1MkM3RkYyNzIxNEVFRkJFMTI2NUM4NUU1ODdEM0Q</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OTI0MkYyMDU1OEFCNDczQTgxNTc1NTczREYzMUQ3MzI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QURCRDNBRjBGRTE0NEFBRUEzNUU1MzFGQjg3MTM4MDI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification><classificationGroup classificationScheme="indexing-terms"><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem score="90"><className>Governments</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjdEQjE4OUJDMzQxNDNEMEI0RTI1QUFCMzJENjEwRTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></classificationGroup></metadata></legislativeDoc>