<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#349#000019#     2#       327.11#">Va. Code Ann. § 19.2-327.11</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_19.2-327.11"/><heading><desig>§ 19.2-327.11.</desig><title>Contents and form of the petition based on previously unknown or unavailable evidence of actual innocence</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a"/><heading><desig>A.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The petitioner shall allege categorically and with specificity, under oath, all of the following: (i) the crime for which the petitioner was convicted or the offense for which the petitioner was adjudicated delinquent, and that such conviction or adjudication of delinquency was upon a plea of not guilty; (ii) that the petitioner is actually innocent of the crime for which he was convicted or the offense for which he was adjudicated delinquent; (iii) an exact description of the previously unknown or unavailable evidence supporting the allegation of innocence; (iv) that such evidence was previously unknown or unavailable to the petitioner or his trial attorney of record at the time the conviction or adjudication of delinquency became final in the circuit court; (v) the date the previously unknown or unavailable evidence became known or available to the petitioner, and the circumstances under which it was discovered; (vi) that the previously unknown or unavailable evidence is such as could not, by the exercise of diligence, have been discovered or obtained before the expiration of 21 days following entry of the final order of conviction or adjudication of delinquency by the circuit court; (vii) the previously unknown or unavailable evidence is material and, when considered with all of the other evidence in the current record, will prove that no rational trier of fact would have found proof of guilt or delinquency beyond a reasonable doubt; and (viii) the previously unknown or unavailable evidence is not merely cumulative, corroborative or collateral. Nothing in this chapter shall constitute grounds to delay setting an execution date pursuant to <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 53.1-232.1"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 53.1-232.1">§ 53.1-232.1<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000053#     1#        232.1#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> or to grant a stay of execution that has been set pursuant to clause (iii) or (iv) of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 53.1-232.1"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 53.1-232.1">§ 53.1-232.1<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000053#     1#        232.1#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> or to delay or stay any other appeals following conviction or adjudication of delinquency, or petitions to any court. Human biological evidence may not be used as the sole basis for seeking relief under this writ but may be used in conjunction with other evidence.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b"/><heading><desig>B.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Such petition shall contain all relevant allegations of facts that are known to the petitioner at the time of filing, shall be accompanied by all relevant documents, affidavits and test results, and shall enumerate and include all relevant previous records, applications, petitions, and appeals and their dispositions. The petition shall be filed on a form provided by the Supreme Court. If the petitioner fails to submit a completed form, the Court of Appeals may dismiss the petition or return the petition to the petitioner pending the completion of such form. Any false statement in the petition, if such statement is knowingly or willfully made, shall be a ground for prosecution of perjury as provided for in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 18.2-434"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 18.2-434">§ 18.2-434<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000018#     2#          434#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c"/><heading><desig>C.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> In cases brought by counsel for the petitioner, the Court of Appeals shall not accept the petition unless it is accompanied by a duly executed return of service in the form of a verification that a copy of the petition and all attachments have been served on the attorney for the Commonwealth of the jurisdiction where the conviction or adjudication of delinquency occurred and the Attorney General, or an acceptance of service signed by these officials, or any combination thereof. In cases brought by petitioners pro se, the Court of Appeals shall not accept the petition unless it is accompanied by a certificate that a copy of the petition and all attachments have been sent, by certified mail, to the attorney for the Commonwealth of the jurisdiction where the conviction or adjudication of delinquency occurred and the Attorney General. If the Court of Appeals does not summarily dismiss the petition, it shall so notify in writing the Attorney General, the attorney for the Commonwealth, and the petitioner. The Attorney General shall have 60 days after receipt of such notice in which to file a response to the petition that may be extended for good cause shown; however, nothing shall prevent the Attorney General from filing an earlier response. The response may contain a proffer of any evidence pertaining to the guilt or delinquency or innocence of the petitioner that is not included in the record of the case, including evidence that was suppressed at trial.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d"/><heading><desig>D.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The Court of Appeals may inspect the record of any trial or appellate court action, and the Court may, in any case, award a writ of certiorari to the clerk of the respective court below, and have brought before the Court the whole record or any part of any record. If, in the judgment of the Court, the petition fails to state a claim, or if the assertions of previously unknown or unavailable evidence, even if true, would fail to qualify for the granting of relief under this chapter, the Court may dismiss the petition summarily, without any hearing or a response from the Attorney General.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_e"/><heading><desig>E.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> In any petition filed pursuant to this chapter that is not summarily dismissed, the petitioner is entitled to representation by counsel subject to the provisions of Article 3 (<citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 19.2-157"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 19.2-157">§ 19.2-157<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000019#     2#          157#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> et seq.) and Article 4 (<citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 19.2-163.3"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 19.2-163.3">§ 19.2-163.3<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000019#     2#        163.3#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> et seq.) of Chapter 10. The Court of Appeals may, in its discretion, appoint counsel prior to deciding whether a petition should be summarily dismissed.</p></bodyText></level><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p><citation normalizedCite="2004 VA CH 1024"><content><span normalizedCite="2004 Va. Ch. 1024">2004, c. 1024<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2004#001024#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2013 VA CH 170"><content><span normalizedCite="2013 Va. Ch. 170">2013, cc. 170<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2013#000170#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2013 VA CH 180"><content><span normalizedCite="2013 Va. Ch. 180">180<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2013#000180#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PVF0-004G-K493-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 19.2.</desig><title>CRIMINAL PROCEDURE</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 19.3.</desig><title>ISSUANCE OF WRIT OF ACTUAL INNOCENCE BASED ON NONBIOLOGICAL EVIDENCE</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Criminal Law &amp; Procedure</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NEU0RkE1OUQwNUQwNDgxODhEODZCMjkzOTg3NThBNzk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDIwRjc0N0I2NkE2NDI3QjkyMzI4NjFGNTc5MzQ1NEE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NEU4N0IwOEEwRjdCNEM5MzhCQzE0Njc3NTNFMDVGMTA</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Not Guilty</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6M0IzOTc3MjFGRDI4NDQzNkFFMUI2Mzc1QkRFQjc5QTY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Q0ZBQUEzNzY1ODUwNDJCN0I0RkZFNjBEQjk0QUY5MkU</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Stays of Judgments</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NTcwNkRGNzVDNzJBNDBFMEJENUQxM0IwNEU2RTEyQjk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QTFGRjg4NjA3RTg1NDA2RkIzMDk4QzdGREIyQzVGMDk</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Governments</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjdEQjE4OUJDMzQxNDNEMEI0RTI1QUFCMzJENjEwRTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Clerks of Court</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6REVFMjkzRDI1MkU2NERDNjk3OEUxODY0REYwMUI1NjE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NURENzJGNTEyQzM0NEREQUI2RkVCRTM4RTc1RTZBREU</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification><classificationGroup classificationScheme="indexing-terms"><classification classificationScheme="legal"/></classificationGroup></metadata></legislativeDoc>