<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#349#000004#     1#          111#">Va. Code Ann. § 4.1-111</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_4.1-111"/><heading><desig>§ 4.1-111.</desig><title>Regulations of Board</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a"/><heading><desig>A.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The Board may promulgate reasonable regulations, not inconsistent with this title or the general laws of the Commonwealth, which it deems necessary to carry out the provisions of this title and to prevent the illegal manufacture, bottling, sale, distribution and transportation of alcoholic beverages. The Board may amend or repeal such regulations. Such regulations shall be promulgated, amended or repealed in accordance with the Administrative Process Act (§ 2.2-4000 et seq.) and shall have the effect of law.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b"/><heading><desig>B.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The Board shall promulgate regulations that:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Prescribe what hours and on what days alcoholic beverages shall not be sold by licensees or consumed on any licensed premises, including a provision that mixed beverages may be sold only at such times as wine and beer may be sold.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Require mixed beverage caterer licensees to notify the Board in advance of any event to be served by such licensee.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Maintain the reasonable separation of retailer interests from those of the manufacturers, bottlers, brokers, importers and wholesalers in accordance with <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 4.1-216"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 4.1-216">§ 4.1-216<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000004#     1#          216#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> and in consideration of the established trade customs, quantity and value of the articles or services involved; prevent undue competitive domination of any person by any other person engaged in the manufacture, distribution and sale at retail or wholesale of alcoholic beverages in the Commonwealth; and promote reasonable accommodation of arm's length business transactions.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_4"/><heading><desig>4.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Establish requirements for the form, content, and retention of all records and accounts, including the (i) reporting and collection of taxes required by <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 4.1-236"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 4.1-236">§ 4.1-236<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000004#     1#          236#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> and (ii) the sale of alcoholic beverages in kegs, by all licensees.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_5"/><heading><desig>5.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Require retail licensees to file an appeal from any hearing decision rendered by a hearing officer within 30 days of the date the notice of the decision is sent. The notice shall be sent to the licensee at the address on record with the Board by certified mail, return receipt requested, and by regular mail.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_6"/><heading><desig>6.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Prescribe the terms and conditions under which persons who collect or trade designer or vintage spirit bottles may sell such bottles at auction, provided that (i) the auction is conducted in accordance with the provisions of Chapter 6 (<citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 54.1-600"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 54.1-600">§ 54.1-600<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000054#     1#          600#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> et seq.) of Title 54.1 and (ii) the bottles are unopened and the manufacturers' seals, marks, or stamps affixed to the bottles are intact.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_7"/><heading><desig>7.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Prescribe the terms and conditions under which credit or debit cards may be accepted from licensees for purchases at government stores, including provision for the collection, where appropriate, of related fees, penalties, and service charges.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_8"/><heading><desig>8.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Require that banquet licensees in charge of public events as defined by Board regulations report to the Board the income and expenses associated with the public event on a form prescribed by the Board when the banquet licensee engages another person to organize, conduct or operate the event on behalf of the banquet licensee. Such regulations shall be applicable only to public events where alcoholic beverages are being sold.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_9"/><heading><desig>9.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Provide alternative methods for licensees to maintain and store business records that are subject to Board inspection, including methods for Board-approved electronic and off-site storage.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_10"/><heading><desig>10.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Require off-premises retail licensees to place any premixed alcoholic energy drinks containing one-half of one percent or more of alcohol by volume in the same location where wine and beer are available for sale within the licensed premises.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_11"/><heading><desig>11.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Prescribe the terms and conditions under which mixed beverage licensees may infuse, store, and sell flavored distilled spirits, including a provision that limits infusion containers to a maximum of 20 liters.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_12"/><heading><desig>12.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Prescribe the schedule of proration for refunded license taxes to licensees who qualify pursuant to subsection C of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 4.1-232"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 4.1-232">§ 4.1-232<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000004#     1#          232#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_13"/><heading><desig>13.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Establish reasonable time, place, and manner restrictions on outdoor advertising of alcoholic beverages, not inconsistent with the provisions of this title, so that such advertising does not encourage or otherwise promote the consumption of alcoholic beverages by persons to whom alcoholic beverages may not be lawfully sold. Such regulations shall:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_13_a"/><heading><desig>a.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Restrict outdoor advertising of alcoholic beverages in publicly visible locations consistent with (i) the general prohibition against tied interests between retail licensees and manufacturers or wholesale licensees as provided in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 4.1-215"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 4.1-215">§§ 4.1-215<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000004#     1#          215#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> and <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 4.1-216"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 4.1-216">4.1-216<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000004#     1#          216#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; (ii) the prohibition against manufacturer control of wholesale licensees as set forth in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 4.1-223"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 4.1-223">§ 4.1-223<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000004#     1#          223#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> and Board regulations adopted pursuant thereto; and (iii) the general prohibition against cooperative advertising between manufacturers, wholesalers, or importers and retail licensees as set forth in Board regulation; and</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_13_b"/><heading><desig>b.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Permit (i) any outdoor signage or advertising not otherwise prohibited by this title and (ii) the display of outdoor alcoholic beverage advertising on lawfully erected billboard signs regulated under Chapter 12 (§ 33.2-1200 et seq.) of Title 33.2 where such signs are located on commercial real estate as defined in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 55-526"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 55 -526">§ 55-526<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#123#000055#       526#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, but only in accordance with this title.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_14"/><heading><desig>14.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Prescribe the terms and conditions under which a licensed brewery may manufacture beer pursuant to an agreement with a brand owner not under common control with the manufacturing brewery and sell and deliver the beer so manufactured to the brand owner. The regulations shall require that (i) the brand owner be an entity appropriately licensed as a brewery or beer wholesaler, (ii) a written agreement be entered into by the parties, and (iii) records as deemed appropriate by the Board are maintained by the parties.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_15"/><heading><desig>15.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Prescribe the terms for any "happy hour" conducted by on-premises licensees. Such regulations shall permit on-premises licensees to advertise any alcoholic beverage products featured during a happy hour but prohibit the advertising of any pricing related to such happy hour.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_16"/><heading><desig>16.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Permit retail on-premises licensees to give a gift of one alcoholic beverage to a patron or one bottle of wine to a group of two or more patrons, provided that (i) such gifts only are made to individuals to whom such products may lawfully be sold and (ii) only one such gift is given during any 24-hour period and subject to any Board limitations on the frequency of such gifts.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_17"/><heading><desig>17.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Permit the sale of beer and cider for off-premises consumption in resealable growlers made of glass, ceramic, metal, or other materials approved by the Board, or other resealable containers approved by the Board, with a maximum capacity of 128 fluid ounces or, for metric-sized containers, four liters.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_18"/><heading><desig>18.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Permit the sale of wine for off-premises consumption in resealable growlers made of glass, ceramic, metal, or other materials approved by the Board, or other resealable containers approved by the Board, with a maximum capacity of 64 fluid ounces or, for metric-sized containers, two liters. Wine growlers may be used only by persons licensed to sell wine for both on-premises and off-premises consumption or by gourmet shop licensees. Growlers sold by gourmet shop licensees shall be labeled with (i) the manufacturer's name or trade name, (ii) the place of production, (iii) the net contents in fluid ounces, and (iv) the name and address of the retailer.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_19"/><heading><desig>19.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Permit the sale of wine and beer by retailers licensed to sell beer and wine for both on-premises and off-premises consumption, or by gourmet shop licensees for off-premises consumption in sealed containers made of metal or other materials approved by the Board with a maximum capacity of 32 fluid ounces or, for metric-sized containers, one liter, provided that the alcoholic beverage is placed in the container following an order from the consumer.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_20"/><heading><desig>20.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Permit mixed beverage licensees to premix containers of sangria and other mixed alcoholic beverages and to serve such alcoholic beverages in pitchers, subject to size and quantity limitations established by the Board.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c"/><heading><desig>C.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The Board may promulgate regulations that:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Provide for the waiver of the license tax for an applicant for a banquet license, such waiver to be based on (i) the amount of alcoholic beverages to be provided by the applicant, (ii) the not-for-profit status of the applicant, and (iii) the condition that no profits are to be generated from the event. For the purposes of clause (ii), the applicant shall submit with the application, an affidavit certifying its not-for-profit status. The granting of such waiver shall be limited to two events per year for each applicant.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Establish limitations on the quantity and value of any gifts of alcoholic beverages made in the course of any business entertainment pursuant to subdivision A 22 of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 4.1-325"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 4.1-325">§ 4.1-325<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000004#     1#          325#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> or subsection C of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 4.1-325.2"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 4.1-325.2">§ 4.1-325.2.<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000004#     1#        325.2#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation></p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Provide incentives to licensees with a proven history of compliance with state and federal laws and regulations to encourage licensees to conduct their business and related activities in a manner that is beneficial to the Commonwealth.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d"/><heading><desig>D.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Board regulations shall be uniform in their application, except those relating to hours of sale for licensees.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_e"/><heading><desig>E.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Courts shall take judicial notice of Board regulations.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_f"/><heading><desig>F.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The Board's power to regulate shall be broadly construed.</p></bodyText></level><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p>Code 1950, §§ 4-11, 4-36; 1968, c. 7, §§ 4-98.5, 4-98.14; 1974, c. 460; 1982, c. 145; <citation normalizedCite="1991 VA CH 690"><content><span normalizedCite="1991 Va. Ch. 690">1991, c. 690<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1991#000690#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1992 VA CH 220"><content><span normalizedCite="1992 Va. Ch. 220">1992, c. 220<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1992#000220#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1993 VA CH 433"><content><span normalizedCite="1993 Va. Ch. 433">1993, cc. 433<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1993#000433#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1993 VA CH 866"><content><span normalizedCite="1993 Va. Ch. 866">866<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1993#000866#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1997 VA CH 40"><content><span normalizedCite="1997 Va. Ch. 40">1997, c. 40<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1997#000040#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1998 VA CH 301"><content><span normalizedCite="1998 Va. Ch. 301">1998, c. 301<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1998#000301#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1999 VA CH 98"><content><span normalizedCite="1999 Va. Ch. 98">1999, cc. 98<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1999#000098#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1999 VA CH 641"><content><span normalizedCite="1999 Va. Ch. 641">641<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1999#000641#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2003 VA CH 856"><content><span normalizedCite="2003 Va. Ch. 856">2003, c. 856<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2003#000856#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2008 VA CH 513"><content><span normalizedCite="2008 Va. Ch. 513">2008, c. 513<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2008#000513#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2009 VA CH 122"><content><span normalizedCite="2009 Va. Ch. 122">2009, c. 122<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2009#000122#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2010 VA CH 481"><content><span normalizedCite="2010 Va. Ch. 481">2010, c. 481<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2010#000481#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2011 VA CH 728"><content><span normalizedCite="2011 Va. Ch. 728">2011, c. 728<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2011#000728#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2012 VA CH 376"><content><span normalizedCite="2012 Va. Ch. 376">2012, cc. 376<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2012#000376#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2012 VA CH 760"><content><span normalizedCite="2012 Va. Ch. 760">760<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2012#000760#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2012 VA CH 818"><content><span normalizedCite="2012 Va. Ch. 818">818<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2012#000818#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2015 VA CH 404"><content><span normalizedCite="2015 Va. Ch. 404">2015, cc. 404<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2015#000404#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2015 VA CH 412"><content><span normalizedCite="2015 Va. Ch. 412">412<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2015#000412#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PTX0-004G-K00J-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 4.1.</desig><title>ALCOHOLIC BEVERAGE CONTROL ACT</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 1.</desig><title>DEFINITIONS AND GENERAL PROVISIONS</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Licenses</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MzZGMUE2NUY4MDQ0NEYzQ0IzRTMwMjI0MkFFMjU2NjE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NkUwRDYyOTFBOTE1NDdCMjhGQjI0NjdDQ0M0NzEwMzY</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Communications Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MEQxMkU0NzE2OEE2NDIxNEE3QzU0NjU2MDRERUNGNDE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Advertising</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6REY0NUE2RDU3NTAwNDJENzk0MUMxMjJCODU2RTEzNkU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDcwRjUwMDk0RkU3NDkxMjk4ODU4NzMwOEZDNkIyOTU</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Criminal Law &amp; Procedure</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NEU0RkE1OUQwNUQwNDgxODhEODZCMjkzOTg3NThBNzk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Elements</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QkE1OEZGRERFMTY4NDM5Rjg1MDIyRDlENjY4MzUzQzA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MTU5MUFBMjIzMjAzNDlGN0JEM0M5MzNFNjFGOTQzQjY</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Estate, Gift &amp; Trust Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OENGNTY0MEQ2RTU2NDA2NTk4QjcyNzI2NTBERUU3NUI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NTM0MTFFRkQ3M0E2NEQwREFFMzc3QjBDQjhEQjZEOTM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RkJCNEFGNEQyOEM1NEZBQ0ExREJFNUQyMDM5N0U2Rjg</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Tax Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OTNEM0E2OEE0RkQyNEY1MDhBQzdGMkQ4ODI4QTJDODE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Collection of Taxes</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RTg5OTkxQ0U0RjIwNEY4Qjg2MkQ1OTZCRTM2RDY4MTM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjkxRkVDMkNDMjBGNDdFMkI1RDQ3Nzk4QjgwOTBGQjU</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6M0I0RjYxOUVCQ0NENDE3NjkyQ0E0REVDNDQzMUEwRDA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MTZFRjlERTdEMjk0NEMwNUEzNzVBQUU4OEI4NjdFN0M</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RDlBNDNBN0ZFMUYyNEI0MjlBQjE0QjUyRDkzREE3N0I7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MEM1NzJCQkEzQTc0NDNFRjk3MDk3NjkyNUFCN0VCNTA</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Trademark Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QUY4QzQ2QTdDQjY1NEFGMjlGQjMwMTYzM0FDN0IxRTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OTJGOTE4NkMyQ0M2NDcyQzlGMEQ3RTczNTg0MzBBM0E7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NkUwRDYyOTFBOTE1NDdCMjhGQjI0NjdDQ0M0NzEwMzY</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QTUzRTNENDYwNjJDNDVGNDk3QTY0QkZEMjc4MUEzNTc7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RDVDM0Y3MDdEOTE5NEVCNDgxMDNDMjU0MjcxMzUyMTg</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjI0NDg2MzBERDBDNDYxQ0I4OTVENUI1MDJGN0FFRUU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QkYzRTA5MzU2N0YwNDVGQTg2NUExNjFBMjkxQzcyNzE</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Labels, Packaging &amp; Trade Dress</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NUUwNTU1Q0JCN0I5NEM3Njk4M0Y5Mjk5MTUxODhEODg7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RDE1ODE1RTU0QkU5NDY3MUExRTJCMjYwNjI0MzQ1Q0U</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Licenses</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MzZGMUE2NUY4MDQ0NEYzQ0IzRTMwMjI0MkFFMjU2NjE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NkUwRDYyOTFBOTE1NDdCMjhGQjI0NjdDQ0M0NzEwMzY</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></metadata></legislativeDoc>