<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#349#000046#     2#        320.1#">Va. Code Ann. § 46.2-320.1</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_46.2-320.1"/><heading><desig>§ 46.2-320.1.</desig><title>Other grounds for suspension; nonpayment of child support</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a"/><heading><desig>A.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The Commissioner may enter into an agreement with the Department of Social Services whereby the Department may suspend or refuse to renew the driver's license of any person upon receipt of notice from the Department of Social Services that the person (i) is delinquent in the payment of child support by 90 days or more or in an amount of $ 5,000 or more or (ii) has failed to comply with a subpoena, summons, or warrant relating to paternity or child support proceedings. A suspension or refusal to renew authorized pursuant to this section shall not be effective until 30 days after service on the delinquent obligor of notice of intent to suspend or refusal to renew. The notice of intent shall be served on the obligor by the Department of Social Services (a) by certified mail, return receipt requested, or by electronic means, sent to the obligor's last known addresses as shown in the records of the Department or the Department of Social Services or (b) pursuant to <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 8.01-296"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 8.01-296">§ 8.01-296<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000008#    01#          296#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, or service may be waived by the obligor in accordance with procedures established by the Department of Social Services. The obligor shall be entitled to a judicial hearing if a request for a hearing is made, in writing, to the Department of Social Services within 10 days from service of the notice of intent. Upon receipt of the request for a hearing, the Department of Social Services shall petition the court that entered or is enforcing the order, requesting a hearing on the proposed suspension or refusal to renew. The court shall authorize the suspension or refusal to renew only if it finds that the obligor's noncompliance with the child support order was willful. Upon a showing by the Department of Social Services that the obligor is delinquent in the payment of child support by 90 days or more or in an amount of $ 5,000 or more, the burden of proving that the delinquency was not willful shall rest upon the obligor. The Department shall not suspend or refuse to renew the driver's license until a final determination is made by the court.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b"/><heading><desig>B.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> At any time after service of a notice of intent, the person may petition the juvenile and domestic relations district court in the jurisdiction where he resides for the issuance of a restricted license to be used if the suspension or refusal to renew becomes effective. Upon such petition and a finding of good cause, the court may provide that such person be issued a restricted permit to operate a motor vehicle for any of the purposes set forth in subsection E of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 18.2-271.1"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 18.2-271.1">§ 18.2-271.1.<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000018#     2#        271.1#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> A restricted license issued pursuant to this subsection shall not permit any person to operate a commercial motor vehicle as defined in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 46.2-341.4"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 46.2-341.4">§ 46.2-341.4.<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000046#     2#        341.4#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> The court shall order the surrender of the person's license to operate a motor vehicle, to be disposed of in accordance with the provisions of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 46.2-398"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 46.2-398">§ 46.2-398<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000046#     2#          398#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, and shall forward to the Commissioner a copy of its order entered pursuant to this subsection. The order shall specifically enumerate the restrictions imposed and contain such information regarding the person to whom such a permit is issued as is reasonably necessary to identify him.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c"/><heading><desig>C.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The Department shall not renew a driver's license or terminate a license suspension imposed pursuant to this section until it has received from the Department of Social Services a certification that the person has (i) paid the delinquency in full; (ii) reached an agreement with the Department of Social Services to satisfy the delinquency within a period not to exceed 10 years, and at least one payment representing at least five percent of the total delinquency or $ 600, whichever is greater, has been made pursuant to the agreement; (iii) complied with a subpoena, summons, or warrant relating to a paternity or child support proceeding; or (iv) completed or is successfully participating in an intensive case monitoring program for child support as ordered by a juvenile and domestic relations district court or as administered by the Department of Social Services. Certification by the Department of Social Services shall be made by electronic or telephonic communication and shall be made on the same work day that payment required by clause (i) or (ii) is made.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d"/><heading><desig>D.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> If a person who has entered into an agreement with the Department of Social Services pursuant to clause (ii) of subsection C fails to comply with the requirements of the agreement, the Department of Social Services shall notify the Department of the person's noncompliance and the Department shall suspend or refuse to renew the driver's license of the person until it has received from the Department of Social Services a certification that the person has paid the delinquency in full or has entered into a subsequent agreement with the Department of Social Services to satisfy the delinquency within a period not to exceed seven years and has made at least one payment of $ 1,200 or five percent of the total delinquency, whichever is greater, pursuant to the agreement. If the person fails to comply with the terms of a subsequent agreement reached with the Department of Social Services pursuant to this section, without further notice to the person as provided in the subsequent agreement, the Department of Social Services shall notify the Department of the person's noncompliance, and the Department shall suspend or refuse to renew the driver's license of the person. A person who has failed to comply with the terms of a second or subsequent agreement pursuant to this subsection may be granted a new agreement with the Department of Social Services if the person has made at least one payment of $ 1,800 or five percent of the total delinquency, whichever is greater, and agrees to a repayment schedule of not more than seven years. Upon receipt of certification from the Department of Social Services of the person's satisfaction of these conditions, the Department shall issue a driver's license to the person or reinstate the person's driver's license. Certification by the Department of Social Services shall be made by electronic or telephonic communication and shall be made on the same work day that payment required by this subsection is made.</p></bodyText></level><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p><citation normalizedCite="2012 VA CH 829"><content><span normalizedCite="2012 Va. Ch. 829">2012, c. 829<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2012#000829#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2015 VA CH 506"><content><span normalizedCite="2015 Va. Ch. 506">2015, c. 506<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2015#000506#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2016 VA CH 29"><content><span normalizedCite="2016 Va. Ch. 29">2016, c. 29<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2016#000029#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PVX0-004G-K06J-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 46.2.</desig><title>MOTOR VEHICLES</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="subtitle"><heading><desig>SUBTITLE II.</desig><title>TITLING, REGISTRATION AND LICENSURE</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 3.</desig><title>LICENSURE OF DRIVERS</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="article"><heading><desig>ARTICLE 3.</desig><title>PERSONS NOT TO BE LICENSED</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Licensing &amp; Registration</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NUYwQzU2QTY5NkVBNDBDQUEyOEZGNTA4MDlBNzhCQzU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OTU3NDRDNEM2QUYyNDdGQUE1NEU4NjRGMDRCMUEyNUU</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Family Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NEI4M0U5Qzg3RTk0NDdBRUJGNDRGNkZEQkU3RDdFNDU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Delinquency Proceedings</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RTE4NjRFQzE4QTRGNEQzQzk1MTE0MTY4NzU5N0Q5RDM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QUJCOTZBNkIyQjFFNDI2MDlGN0I2M0I4ODA5NzE5OTk</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RTkwM0NDOUJFQUMzNEY2MjgwOTc3QUFGRUIxQkY3MTQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QTcwM0ZEODVFNjlFNDZCNDlGNDUxMkRFNEU1NDAwMTA</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Q0M4RjlBN0VEQTU2NDU2NDhENzNENDg5Njk0RDJEMzM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NkE1NzFFODFBN0FDNEFBQTk2NzYzN0JEMUI3ODAzRDQ</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NkQzNDVBNDkwRkM2NDY2RkFEOUI2MzZENjREMkRCODg7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QUJCOTZBNkIyQjFFNDI2MDlGN0I2M0I4ODA5NzE5OTk</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6ODkwNDI3MENCRjFDNDEyNDhBRDE3MTZCNTA3QjRDQkE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NzdGNTUxMjhCOUJENDQ5RTlGNTM4RkVFOUIzQ0M1QjE</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Licenses</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NkJFQzlGQkExMUQyNDRFMDk1NjZFRkMyMEM1Mjk1RjI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjczNDFDQjA3RkQ2NDYwN0E0NzhDMTE5RThEMDU3NUI</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Procedures</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6M0I1ODRDN0I3QzQ0NDFEQUIyRTM0REFFQTMzQ0MxMkE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QTcwM0ZEODVFNjlFNDZCNDlGNDUxMkRFNEU1NDAwMTA</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Transportation Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RTYzRTk5RDVBQkQ2NDcwQzk2NTU3ODQ5OEE3NDlBNzk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Licensing &amp; Registration</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NUYwQzU2QTY5NkVBNDBDQUEyOEZGNTA4MDlBNzhCQzU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OTU3NDRDNEM2QUYyNDdGQUE1NEU4NjRGMDRCMUEyNUU</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Reinstatement</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NzIyNDExNjhBNzE0NEY5NkFENzU4NkEzQTBFMTgyNTY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6ODY1RjFBNDEzNUFBNEYzMjhCMjhDRkU1NDlCQ0U3RkU</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Restricted Licenses</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Q0M5M0EyRDQ1NjY0NEFGQTk5MDc3OTA0RDU3RDc2RDE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6ODY1RjFBNDEzNUFBNEYzMjhCMjhDRkU1NDlCQ0U3RkU</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Revocation &amp; Suspension</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QUNDMUM0MDYwNEE1NDZGQkIyNzQyNzQ0RTIzNkFBMzk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6ODY1RjFBNDEzNUFBNEYzMjhCMjhDRkU1NDlCQ0U3RkU</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Revocation &amp; Suspension</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjQ0NDM2QjNFRDgyNDhDNkE5NzRCNTQ3Q0ZBM0EzMzA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NUE5RTcxOUU3RDczNDlDNjgzMkJCMTQwQTkxQzdFNUU</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification><classificationGroup classificationScheme="indexing-terms"><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem score="90"><className>Transportation</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RTYzRTk5RDVBQkQ2NDcwQzk2NTU3ODQ5OEE3NDlBNzk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></classificationGroup></metadata></legislativeDoc>