<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#349#000060#     2#          612#">Va. Code Ann. § 60.2-612</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_60.2-612"/><heading><desig>§ 60.2-612.</desig><title>Benefit eligibility conditions</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><bodyText><p>An unemployed individual shall be eligible to receive benefits for any week only if the Commission finds that:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> He has, in the highest two quarters of earnings within his base period, been paid wages in employment for employers that are equal to not less than the lowest amount appearing in Column A of the "Benefit Table" appearing in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 60.2-602"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 60.2-602">§ 60.2-602<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000060#     2#          602#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> on the line which extends through Division C and on which in Column B of the "Benefit Table" appears his weekly benefit amount. Such wages shall be earned in not less than two quarters.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> a. His total or partial unemployment is not due to a labor dispute in active progress or to shutdown or start-up operations caused by such dispute which exists (i) at the factory, establishment, or other premises, including a vessel, at which he is or was last employed, or (ii) at a factory, establishment or other premises, including a vessel, either within or without this Commonwealth, which (a) is owned or operated by the same employing unit which owns or operates the premises at which he is or was last employed and (b) supplies materials or services necessary to the continued and usual operation of the premises at which he is or was last employed. This subdivision shall not apply if it is shown to the satisfaction of the Commission that:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_2_1"/><heading><desig>(1)</desig></heading><bodyText><p> He is not participating in or financing or directly interested in the labor dispute; and</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_2_2"/><heading><desig>(2)</desig></heading><bodyText><p> He does not belong to a grade or class of workers of which, immediately before the commencement of the labor dispute, there were members employed at the premises, including a vessel, at which the labor dispute occurs, any of whom are participating in or financing or directly interested in the dispute.</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_2_2_b"/><heading><desig>b.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> If separate branches of work which are commonly conducted as separate businesses at separate premises are conducted in separate departments of the same premises, each such department shall, for the purposes of this subdivision, be deemed to be a separate factory, establishment or other premises. Membership in a union, or the payment of regular dues to a bona fide labor organization, however, shall not alone constitute financing a labor dispute.</p></bodyText></level></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> He is not receiving, has not received or is not seeking unemployment benefits under an unemployment compensation law of any other state or of the United States; however, if the appropriate agency of such other state or of the United States finally determines that he is not entitled to such unemployment benefits, this subdivision shall not apply.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_4"/><heading><desig>4.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> He is not on a bona fide paid vacation. If an individual is paid vacation pay for any week in an amount less than the individual's weekly benefit amount his eligibility for benefits shall be computed under the provisions of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 60.2-603"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 60.2-603">§ 60.2-603<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000060#     2#          603#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_5"/><heading><desig>5.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> He has registered for work and thereafter has continued to report at an employment office in accordance with such regulations as the Commission may prescribe. The Commission may, by regulation, waive or alter either or both of the requirements of this subdivision for certain types of cases when it finds that compliance with such requirements would be oppressive, or would be inconsistent with the purposes of this title.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_6"/><heading><desig>6.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> He has made a claim for benefits in accordance with regulations the Commission may prescribe.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_7"/><heading><desig>7.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> a. He is able to work, is available for work, and is actively seeking and unable to obtain suitable work. Every claimant who is totally unemployed shall report to the Commission the names of employers contacted each week in his effort to obtain work. This information may be subject to employer verification by the Commission through a program designed for that purpose. The Commission may determine that registration by a claimant with the Virginia State Job Service may constitute a valid employer contact and satisfy the search for work requirement of this subsection in labor market areas where job opportunities are limited. The Commission may determine that an individual, whose usual and customary means of soliciting work in his occupation is through contact with a single hiring hall which makes contacts with multiple employers on behalf of the claimant, meets the requirement that he be actively seeking and unable to obtain suitable work by contacting that hiring hall alone. In areas of high unemployment, as determined by the Commission, the Commission has the authority to adjust the requirement that he be actively seeking and unable to obtain suitable work.</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_7_b"/><heading><desig>b.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> An individual who leaves the normal labor market area of the individual for the major portion of any week is presumed to be unavailable for work within the meaning of this section. This presumption may be overcome if the individual establishes to the satisfaction of the Commission that the individual has conducted a bona fide search for work and has been reasonably accessible to suitable work in the labor market area in which the individual spent the major portion of the week to which the presumption applies.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_7_c"/><heading><desig>c.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> An individual whose type of work is such that it is performed by individuals working two or more shifts in a 24-hour period shall not be deemed unavailable for work if the individual is currently enrolled in one or more classes of education related to employment or is continuing in a certificate or degree program at an institution of higher education, provided that the enrollment would only limit the individual's availability for one shift and the individual is otherwise available to work any of the other shifts.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_8"/><heading><desig>8.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> He has given notice of resignation to his employer and the employer subsequently made the termination of employment effective prior to the date of termination as given in the notice, but in no case shall unemployment compensation benefits awarded under this subdivision exceed two weeks; provided, that the claimant could not establish good cause for leaving work pursuant to <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 60.2-618"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 60.2-618">§ 60.2-618<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000060#     2#          618#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> and was not discharged for misconduct as provided in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 60.2-618"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 60.2-618">§ 60.2-618<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000060#     2#          618#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_9"/><heading><desig>9.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Beginning January 6, 1991, he has served a waiting period of one week during which he was eligible for benefits under this section in all other respects and has not received benefits, except that only one waiting week shall be required of such individual within any benefit year. For claims filed effective November 28, 1999, and after, this requirement shall be waived for any individual whose unemployment was caused by his employer terminating operations, closing its business or declaring bankruptcy without paying the final wages earned as required by <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 40.1-29"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 40.1-29">§ 40.1-29 of the Code of Virginia<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000040#     1#           29#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>. Notwithstanding any other provision of this title, if an employer who terminates operations, closes its business or declares bankruptcy pays an individual his final wages after the period of time prescribed by <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 40.1-29"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 40.1-29">§ 40.1-29 of the Code of Virginia<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000040#     1#           29#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, such payment shall not be offset against the benefits the individual was otherwise entitled to receive and shall not, under any circumstances, cause such individual to be declared overpaid benefits.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_10"/><heading><desig>10.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> He is not imprisoned or confined in jail.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_11"/><heading><desig>11.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> He participates in reemployment services, such as job search assistance services, if he has been determined to be likely to exhaust regular benefits and need reemployment services pursuant to a profiling system established by the Commission, unless the Commission determines that (i) such claimant has completed such services or (ii) there is good cause for such claimant's failure to participate in such services.</p></bodyText></level></level><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p>Code 1950, § 60-46; 1954, c. 203; 1956, c. 440; 1962, c. 270; 1966, c. 30; 1968, c. 9; 1968, c. 738, § 60.1-52; 1970, c. 104; 1974, c. 264; 1976, c. 708; 1977, c. 445; 1980, c. 463; 1981, c. 606; 1982, c. 265; 1983, c. 359; 1984, c. 458; 1985, c. 563; 1986, c. 480; 1988, c. 521; <citation normalizedCite="1990 VA CH 908"><content><span normalizedCite="1990 Va. Ch. 908">1990, c. 908<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1990#000908#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1993 VA CH 249"><content><span normalizedCite="1993 Va. Ch. 249">1993, c. 249<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1993#000249#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1995 VA CH 436"><content><span normalizedCite="1995 Va. Ch. 436">1995, c. 436<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1995#000436#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2000 VA CH 573"><content><span normalizedCite="2000 Va. Ch. 573">2000, c. 573<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2000#000573#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2004 VA CH 496"><content><span normalizedCite="2004 Va. Ch. 496">2004, c. 496<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2004#000496#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PTS0-004G-K31W-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 60.2.</desig><title>UNEMPLOYMENT COMPENSATION</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 6.</desig><title>BENEFITS</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="article"><heading><desig>ARTICLE 4.</desig><title>ELIGIBILITY CRITERIA</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Bankruptcy Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RDJGRTFGMTM4NkMwNDhEMEE5NUU0QUZCN0QyMjlEREY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Notice</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6M0I3RUMyNUQ1NURDNDVDNEE1RDg1RDBCQTc1NzlBMjA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MkY2NEIzNkU5MTIyNENBQkFBMzgyNDUwODI0NDJBNzA</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Labor &amp; Employment Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MTE3QUQwOTA0MUYzNDlCMEFFMjUwRUNDM0RDRkM5QzM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Benefit Entitlements</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QThGMUM5MDEwMTJCNEU2RjkxMUY5QUFFRTQwMjcyMDk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MEUyNDQ5RTc4RDI2NDc3Q0I3MUE0OEE2NTA3QjYzRkM</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NkQ3NTU4M0UyNTk2NDZCQzhEOTg1MUE5RkY2NzcxRTQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NTc1ODA5RTExMjE1NDRFNThBOTc4RkYyNkM3ODQyMzI</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RUMxMEM5Mzk5NjdBNEQyMDg1NzYzNTNFMTc3QjExNkQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MEUyNDQ5RTc4RDI2NDc3Q0I3MUE0OEE2NTA3QjYzRkM</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MzE4REVFNzc1ODJCNEQyNTk4MThCNzdBNTU4NTExMDg7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDk1NzZDQzBDM0M1NENCOUE1ODc3ODI4QkI3MkYyMEY</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Good Cause Terminations</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QkQzOTgyMzk5QjdCNDNCQ0JBNTA4ODBCNTBDNkI5MTg7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDk1NzZDQzBDM0M1NENCOUE1ODc3ODI4QkI3MkYyMEY</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Voluntary Unemployment</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDkwQzdCODYzOEVBNDY5MUFFREQ2RUIzOUUyQjQ3OUY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDk1NzZDQzBDM0M1NENCOUE1ODc3ODI4QkI3MkYyMEY</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></metadata></legislativeDoc>