<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#349#000008#    01#          399#">Va. Code Ann. § 8.01-399</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_8.01-399"/><heading><desig>§ 8.01-399.</desig><title>Communications between physicians and patients (Supreme Court Rule 2:505 derived from this section)</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a"/><heading><desig>A.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Except at the request or with the consent of the patient, or as provided in this section, no duly licensed practitioner of any branch of the healing arts shall be permitted to testify in any civil action, respecting any information that he may have acquired in attending, examining or treating the patient in a professional capacity.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b"/><heading><desig>B.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> If the physical or mental condition of the patient is at issue in a civil action, the diagnoses, signs and symptoms, observations, evaluations, histories, or treatment plan of the practitioner, obtained or formulated as contemporaneously documented during the course of the practitioner's treatment, together with the facts communicated to, or otherwise learned by, such practitioner in connection with such attendance, examination or treatment shall be disclosed but only in discovery pursuant to the Rules of Court or through testimony at the trial of the action. In addition, disclosure may be ordered when a court, in the exercise of sound discretion, deems it necessary to the proper administration of justice. However, no order shall be entered compelling a party to sign a release for medical records from a health care provider unless the health care provider is not located in the Commonwealth or is a federal facility. If an order is issued pursuant to this section, it shall be restricted to the medical records that relate to the physical or mental conditions at issue in the case. No disclosure of diagnosis or treatment plan facts communicated to, or otherwise learned by, such practitioner shall occur if the court determines, upon the request of the patient, that such facts are not relevant to the subject matter involved in the pending action or do not appear to be reasonably calculated to lead to the discovery of admissible evidence. Only diagnosis offered to a reasonable degree of medical probability shall be admissible at trial.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c"/><heading><desig>C.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> This section shall not (i) be construed to repeal or otherwise affect the provisions of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 65.2-607"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 65.2-607">§ 65.2-607<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000065#     2#          607#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> relating to privileged communications between physicians and surgeons and employees under the Workers' Compensation Act; (ii) apply to information communicated to any such practitioner in an effort unlawfully to procure a narcotic drug, or unlawfully to procure the administration of any such drug; or (iii) prohibit a duly licensed practitioner of the healing arts, or his agents, from disclosing information as required by state or federal law.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d"/><heading><desig>D.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Neither a lawyer nor anyone acting on the lawyer's behalf shall obtain, in connection with pending or threatened litigation, information concerning a patient from a practitioner of any branch of the healing arts without the consent of the patient, except through discovery pursuant to the Rules of Supreme Court as herein provided. However, the prohibition of this subsection shall not apply to:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Communication between a lawyer retained to represent a practitioner of the healing arts, or that lawyer's agent, and that practitioner's employers, partners, agents, servants, employees, co-employees or others for whom, at law, the practitioner is or may be liable or who, at law, are or may be liable for the practitioner's acts or omissions;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Information about a patient provided to a lawyer or his agent by a practitioner of the healing arts employed by that lawyer to examine or evaluate the patient in accordance with Rule 4:10 of the Rules of Supreme Court; or</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Contact between a lawyer or his agent and a nonphysician employee or agent of a practitioner of healing arts for any of the following purposes: (i) scheduling appearances, (ii) requesting a written recitation by the practitioner of handwritten records obtained by the lawyer or his agent from the practitioner, provided the request is made in writing and, if litigation is pending, a copy of the request and the practitioner's response is provided simultaneously to the patient or his attorney, (iii) obtaining information necessary to obtain service upon the practitioner in pending litigation, (iv) determining when records summoned will be provided by the practitioner or his agent, (v) determining what patient records the practitioner possesses in order to summons records in pending litigation, (vi) explaining any summons that the lawyer or his agent caused to be issued and served on the practitioner, (vii) verifying dates the practitioner treated the patient, provided that if litigation is pending the information obtained by the lawyer or his agent is promptly given, in writing, to the patient or his attorney, (viii) determining charges by the practitioner for appearance at a deposition or to testify before any tribunal or administrative body, or (ix) providing to or obtaining from the practitioner directions to a place to which he is or will be summoned to give testimony.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_e"/><heading><desig>E.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A clinical psychologist duly licensed under the provisions of Chapter 36 (<citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 54.1-3600"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 54.1-3600">§ 54.1-3600<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000054#     1#         3600#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> et seq.) of Title 54.1 shall be considered a practitioner of a branch of the healing arts within the meaning of this section.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_f"/><heading><desig>F.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Nothing herein shall prevent a duly licensed practitioner of the healing arts, or his agents, from disclosing any information that he may have acquired in attending, examining or treating a patient in a professional capacity where such disclosure is necessary in connection with the care of the patient, the protection or enforcement of a practitioner's legal rights including such rights with respect to medical malpractice actions, or the operations of a health care facility or health maintenance organization or in order to comply with state or federal law.</p></bodyText></level><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p>Code 1950, § 8-289.1; 1956, c. 446; 1966, c. 673; 1977, c. 617; <citation normalizedCite="1993 VA CH 556"><content><span normalizedCite="1993 Va. Ch. 556">1993, c. 556<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1993#000556#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1996 VA CH 937"><content><span normalizedCite="1996 Va. Ch. 937">1996, cc. 937<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1996#000937#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1996 VA CH 980"><content><span normalizedCite="1996 Va. Ch. 980">980<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1996#000980#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1998 VA CH 314"><content><span normalizedCite="1998 Va. Ch. 314">1998, c. 314<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1998#000314#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2002 VA CH 308"><content><span normalizedCite="2002 Va. Ch. 308">2002, cc. 308<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2002#000308#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2002 VA CH 723"><content><span normalizedCite="2002 Va. Ch. 723">723<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2002#000723#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2005 VA CH 649"><content><span normalizedCite="2005 Va. Ch. 649">2005, cc. 649<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2005#000649#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2005 VA CH 692"><content><span normalizedCite="2005 Va. Ch. 692">692<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2005#000692#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2009 VA CH 714"><content><span normalizedCite="2009 Va. Ch. 714">2009, c. 714<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2009#000714#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PSD0-004G-K0S1-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 8.01.</desig><title>CIVIL REMEDIES AND PROCEDURE</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 14.</desig><title>EVIDENCE</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="article"><heading><desig>ARTICLE 4.</desig><title>WITNESSES GENERALLY</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Civil Procedure</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MzUxNjJDMEQ5N0YwNDMzM0JDMjEzM0UzOTYzMzI3OTU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OTE0MDI1QjZCMDAzNDRDOEI0MUEyM0I5RTYwNzE4QUI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QUZFQzUyMzJCNkQxNDA5RTk4MjlBN0JCREQ1QTJDODk</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Governments</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjdEQjE4OUJDMzQxNDNEMEI0RTI1QUFCMzJENjEwRTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Rule Application &amp; Interpretation</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDNFRkI3NTNERDFGNEZEN0FFMDZEMTI4OEMxODYxQzA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NURENzJGNTEyQzM0NEREQUI2RkVCRTM4RTc1RTZBREU</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Healthcare Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NkUxMkVDQjJDOEY5NDVDQ0E5NTFEMTlDMjIwNzVERjc7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6REIzOUJERjYzNEE1NEI2QUFENjZDQTBERkIzNTk0RjY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NjM2NTg4ODQ2MEU0NENDOUE4NzlDN0E2QjM5MjJFQjg</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Public Health &amp; Welfare Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDYwRTY1MDg3MTk5NDUyNkFFRDI1RjJBRERGQ0UxNzI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NUVCNTZERDE5OTI4NDJDRUEzMDVFNjQ3NkEyMjI5QUI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MTlCM0Q3MTlFNUQ0NDA5OTgwQTEwQjE1M0ZGMTlFQjc</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Torts</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDAwOEM2NTEzQkVDNEI4NzlGMEZERUEyRjQwODM4Njg7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Healthcare Providers</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OTYwQjdFN0UwQUY1NEYwNEJGNkRBNTRCMzUwMjM5Q0Q7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjkzQzRCMDhBOTZDNEY4NkE0Q0E1ODk5MDM2MUNGNkI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification><classificationGroup classificationScheme="indexing-terms"><classification classificationScheme="legal"/></classificationGroup></metadata></legislativeDoc>