<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#349#000059#     1#       284.21#">Va. Code Ann. § 59.1-284.21</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_59.1-284.21"/><heading><desig>§ 59.1-284.21.</desig><title>Aerospace Engine Manufacturing Supplier Cluster Bonus Performance Grant Program; eligible county</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a"/><heading><desig>A.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> As used in this section:</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Affiliate"</emphasis> means the same as such term is defined in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 59.1-284.20"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 59.1-284.20">§ 59.1-284.20.<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000059#     1#       284.20#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation></p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Capital investment"</emphasis> means the same as such term is defined in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 59.1-284.20"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 59.1-284.20">§ 59.1-284.20.<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000059#     1#       284.20#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation></p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Eligible county"</emphasis> means Prince George County.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Grant"</emphasis> means the aerospace engine manufacturing supplier cluster bonus performance grant as described in this section.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Memorandum of understanding"</emphasis> means a performance agreement entered into accordance with a memorandum of understanding entered into on November 20, 2007, among a qualified manufacturer, the Commonwealth, and others setting forth the requirements for capital investment and the creation of new full-time jobs by qualified suppliers that will make the qualified manufacturer eligible for a grant under this section.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"New full-time job"</emphasis> means employment of an indefinite duration in the Commonwealth, created as the direct result of new capital investment, for which the average annual wage is at least equal to the prevailing average annual wage in the applicable locality and for which the standard fringe benefits are paid by the qualified supplier, requiring a minimum of either (i) 35 hours of an employee's time per week for the entire normal year of such supplier's operations, which "normal year" must consist of at least 48 weeks or (ii) 1,680 hours per year. Seasonal or temporary positions, and positions created when a job function is shifted from an existing location in the Commonwealth shall not qualify as new full-time jobs under this section.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Qualified manufacturer"</emphasis> means the same as such term is defined in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 59.1-284.20"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 59.1-284.20">§ 59.1-284.20.<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000059#     1#       284.20#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation></p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Qualified supplier"</emphasis> means a manufacturer, assembler, distributor, or service provider on a qualified supplier list that (i) first begins doing business at a location within the Commonwealth or (ii) expands its business at a location within the Commonwealth subsequent to a qualified manufacturer commencing construction of a manufacturing, assembly, and testing facility in an eligible county. A "qualified supplier" shall deliver or provide ancillary parts, tools, or other components used by the qualified manufacturer within the Commonwealth or provide ancillary services within the Commonwealth for such qualified manufacturer. A qualified supplier shall not be an affiliate of a qualified manufacturer.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Qualified supplier cluster"</emphasis> means the aggregate of qualified suppliers.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Qualified supplier list"</emphasis> means a list of prospective qualified suppliers submitted by a qualified manufacturer to the Secretary no less frequently than annually.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Secretary"</emphasis> means the Secretary of Commerce and Trade or his designee.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b"/><heading><desig>B.</desig></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Any qualified manufacturer who attracted a qualified supplier on its qualified supplier list (i) first beginning to do business at a location within the Commonwealth subsequent to the qualified manufacturer commencing construction in an eligible county or (ii) expanding its business at a location within the Commonwealth subsequent to the qualified manufacturer commencing construction in an eligible county shall be eligible for a grant under this section. However, no grant shall be paid to the qualified manufacturer unless the qualified supplier cluster (all of which qualified suppliers are on the qualified supplier list) subsequent to the qualified manufacturer commencing construction in an eligible county makes the aggregate capital investment and meets the new full-time job requirements as set forth in this section. The grants under this section (a) shall be paid, subject to appropriation by the General Assembly, from a fund entitled the Aerospace Engine Manufacturing Supplier Cluster Grant Fund, which Fund is hereby established on the books of the Comptroller, (b) shall not exceed $ 5 million in the aggregate, and (c) shall be paid, as provided in this section, to the qualified manufacturer subject to the conditions of this section being met.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> If the qualified supplier cluster has, subsequent to the qualified manufacturer commencing construction in an eligible county, (i) created and substantially retained at least 150 new full-time jobs within the Commonwealth, (ii) made and substantially retained at least $ 25 million worth of capital investment within the Commonwealth, and (iii) made a written certification to the Secretary that its decision to create such new full-time jobs and make such capital investment was based in part by the location of the qualified manufacturer and was in part for a purpose of providing ancillary parts, tools, or other components used by the qualified manufacturer within the Commonwealth or for providing ancillary services within the Commonwealth for such qualified manufacturer, then a grant payment in the amount of $ 2.5 million shall be paid to the qualified manufacturer as provided in subsection E. If the qualified supplier cluster has, subsequent to the qualified manufacturer commencing construction in an eligible county, (a) created and substantially retained at least 300 new full-time jobs within the Commonwealth, (b) made and substantially retained at least $ 50 million worth of capital investment within the Commonwealth, and (c) made a written certification to the Secretary that its decision to create such new full-time jobs and make such capital investment was based in part by the location of the qualified manufacturer and was in part for a purpose of providing ancillary parts, tools, or other components used by the qualified manufacturer within the Commonwealth or for providing ancillary services within the Commonwealth for such qualified manufacturer, then an aggregate amount of $ 5 million in grants shall be paid to the qualified manufacturer as provided in subsection E. In no case, however, shall the aggregate amount of grants payable to all qualified manufacturers pursuant to this section exceed $ 5 million and in no case shall more than $ 2.5 million in grants pursuant to this section be paid in a fiscal year. Upon receipt of such written certification by the qualified supplier cluster, the Secretary shall promptly notify the qualified manufacturer of the same for purposes of applying for a grant under this section.</p><p><pre/>The memorandum of understanding may provide that a qualified manufacturer shall be eligible for a reduced grant payment if at least 100 new full-time jobs have been created and substantially retained and at least one-third of the full $ 50 million capital investment has been made and substantially retained by the qualified supplier cluster. As described in the memorandum of understanding, in such case the reduction in the grant payments shall be proportional to the reduction in the new full-time jobs created and substantially retained and the reduction in the capital investment. Further, the memorandum of understanding may provide for deferred grant payments if the capital investment and the new full-time jobs have been met, but a substantial reduction occurs in the capital investment or new full-time job requirements between the date such requirements were met and the date the grant payment is to be made.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c"/><heading><desig>C.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> If grants to be paid to qualified manufacturers under this section exceed the aggregate amount of grants payable in a fiscal year, each eligible qualified manufacturer's grant for the year shall equal the amount of the grant to which the qualified manufacturer would otherwise be entitled multiplied by a fraction. The numerator of the fraction shall equal the amount of the grant payable in the fiscal year, and the denominator shall equal the aggregate dollar amount of requests for grants to which all qualified manufacturers otherwise would be eligible for such fiscal year.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d"/><heading><desig>D.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Any qualified manufacturer applying for a grant under this section shall provide evidence, satisfactory to the Secretary, of (i) the number of new full-time jobs created and substantially retained by a qualified supplier on a qualified supplier list as described in subdivision B 2, and (ii) the aggregate capital investment made and substantially retained by a qualified supplier on a qualified supplier list as described in subdivision B 2. The application and evidence shall be filed with the Secretary in person or by mail by between July 1 and August 31.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_e"/><heading><desig>E.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Within 30 days after filing of the application described in subsection D, the Secretary shall certify to (i) the Comptroller and (ii) each qualified manufacturer the amount of the grant to which such qualified manufacturer is entitled under this section. Payment of such grant shall be made by check issued by the Treasurer of Virginia on warrant of the Comptroller, and such payment shall be made in the fiscal year that immediately follows the fiscal year in which the qualified manufacturer had applied for the grant.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_f"/><heading><desig>F.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> As a condition of receipt of a grant, a qualified manufacturer shall make available to the Secretary or his designee for inspection upon his request all relevant and applicable documents to determine the aggregate number of new full-time jobs created by the qualified supplier cluster as described in subdivision B 2, the average wages paid for such jobs, the prevailing average wage in the localities in which such jobs are located, and the aggregate amount of capital investment made by the qualified supplier cluster as described in subdivision B 2.</p><p>The Comptroller shall not draw any warrants to issue checks for any grant under this section without a specific legislative appropriation. All such documents appropriately identified by the qualified manufacturer shall be considered confidential and proprietary.</p></bodyText></level><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p><citation normalizedCite="2008 VA CH 256"><content><span normalizedCite="2008 Va. Ch. 256">2008, cc. 256<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2008#000256#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2008 VA CH 630"><content><span normalizedCite="2008 Va. Ch. 630">630<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2008#000630#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PVJ0-004G-K151-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 59.1.</desig><title>TRADE AND COMMERCE</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 22.5.</desig><title>AEROSPACE ENGINE MANUFACTURING PERFORMANCE GRANT PROGRAM</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Governments</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjdEQjE4OUJDMzQxNDNEMEI0RTI1QUFCMzJENjEwRTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Finance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjMzOTBBRTg2MUVDNDdDNUE1M0QxNDk1RERCNjNCN0I7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Njg1MkM3RkYyNzIxNEVFRkJFMTI2NUM4NUU1ODdEM0Q</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Trade Secrets Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RkE5RkIzRDg2MDIzNDY1Mjg0OURCRDlFNTQ3NkE0NDA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Customer Lists</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RDZCMzk3NjJDMThENEVCMUJDQTY4RTc5QzU2RUYzNEM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjE2MENCRUYyNTQ4NDVGOTg0QUM5MUU5Q0ExRUU3NkY</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification><classificationGroup classificationScheme="indexing-terms"><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem score="90"><className>Antitrust</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6REEyRTNDM0JGQzYyNEMyOEFGNTAwNUJEOUU1MDg4NjU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></classificationGroup></metadata></legislativeDoc>