<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#349#000019#     2#       163.03#">Va. Code Ann. § 19.2-163.03</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_19.2-163.03"/><heading><desig>§ 19.2-163.03.</desig><title>Qualifications for court-appointed counsel</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a"/><heading><desig>A.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Initial qualification requirements. An attorney seeking to represent an indigent accused in a criminal case, in addition to being a member in good standing of the Virginia State Bar, shall meet the specific criteria required for each type or level of case. The following criteria shall be met for qualification and subsequent court appointment:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Misdemeanor case. To initially qualify to serve as counsel appointed pursuant to <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 19.2-159"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 19.2-159">§ 19.2-159<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000019#     2#          159#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> for an indigent defendant charged with a misdemeanor, the attorney shall:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_1_i"/><heading><desig>(i)</desig></heading><bodyText><p> if an active member of the Virginia State Bar for less than one year, have completed six hours of MCLE-approved continuing legal education developed by the Indigent Defense Commission, or</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_1_ii"/><heading><desig>(ii)</desig></heading><bodyText><p> if an active member of the Virginia State Bar for one year or more, either complete the six hours of approved continuing legal education developed by the Commission, or certify to the Commission that he has represented, in a district court within the past year, four or more defendants charged with misdemeanors, or</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_1_iii"/><heading><desig>(iii)</desig></heading><bodyText><p> be qualified pursuant to this section to serve as counsel for an indigent defendant charged with a felony.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Felony case.</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_2_a"/><heading><desig>a.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> To initially qualify to serve as counsel appointed pursuant to <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 19.2-159"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 19.2-159">§ 19.2-159<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000019#     2#          159#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> for an indigent defendant charged with a felony, the attorney shall (i) have completed the six hours of MCLE-approved continuing legal education developed by the Commission, and (ii) certify that he has participated as either lead counsel or co-counsel in four felony cases from their beginning through to their final resolution, including appeals, if any.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_2_b"/><heading><desig>b.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> If the attorney has been an active member of the Virginia State Bar for more than one year and certifies that he has participated, within the past year, as lead counsel in four felony cases through to their final resolution, including appeals, if any, the requirement to complete six hours of continuing legal education and the requirement to participate as co-counsel shall be waived.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_2_c"/><heading><desig>c.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> If the attorney has been an active member of the Virginia State Bar for more than one year and certifies that he has participated, within the past five years, as lead counsel in five felony cases through to their final resolution, including appeals, if any, the requirement to participate as either lead counsel or co-counsel in four felony cases within the past year shall be waived.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Juvenile and domestic relations case.</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_3_a"/><heading><desig>a.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> To initially qualify to serve as appointed counsel in a juvenile and domestic relations district court pursuant to subdivision C 2 of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 16.1-266"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 16.1-266">§ 16.1-266<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000016#     1#          266#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, the attorney shall (i) have completed the six hours of MCLE-approved continuing legal education developed by the Commission, (ii) have completed four additional hours of MCLE-approved continuing legal education on representing juveniles developed by the Commission, and (iii) certify that he has participated as either lead counsel or co-counsel in four cases involving juveniles in a juvenile and domestic relations district court.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_3_b"/><heading><desig>b.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> If the attorney has been an active member of the Virginia State Bar for more than one year and certifies that he has, within the past year, been lead counsel in four cases involving juveniles in juvenile and domestic relations district court, the requirement to complete the 10 hours of continuing legal education shall be waived.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_3_c"/><heading><desig>c.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> If the attorney has been an active member of the Virginia State Bar for more than one year and certifies that he has participated, within the past five years in five cases involving juveniles in a juvenile and domestic relations district court, the requirement to participate as either lead counsel or co-counsel in four juvenile cases shall be waived.</p></bodyText></level></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b"/><heading><desig>B.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Requalification requirements. After initially qualifying as provided in subsection A, an attorney shall maintain his eligibility for certification biennially by notifying the Commission of completion of at least six hours of Commission and MCLE-approved continuing legal education. The Commission shall provide information on continuing legal education programs that have been approved.</p><p>In addition, to maintain eligibility to accept court appointments under subdivision C 2 of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 16.1-266"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 16.1-266">§ 16.1-266<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000016#     1#          266#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, an attorney shall complete biennially thereafter four additional hours of MCLE-approved continuing legal education on representing juveniles, certified by the Commission.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c"/><heading><desig>C.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Waiver and exceptions. The Commission or the court before which a matter is pending, may, in its discretion, waive the requirements set out in this section for individuals who otherwise demonstrate their level of training and experience. A waiver of such requirements pursuant to this subsection shall not form the basis for a claim of error at trial, on appeal, or in any habeas corpus proceeding.</p></bodyText></level><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p><citation normalizedCite="2004 VA CH 884"><content><span normalizedCite="2004 Va. Ch. 884">2004, cc. 884<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2004#000884#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2004 VA CH 921"><content><span normalizedCite="2004 Va. Ch. 921">921<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2004#000921#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2006 VA CH 708"><content><span normalizedCite="2006 Va. Ch. 708">2006, c. 708<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2006#000708#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2007 VA CH 571"><content><span normalizedCite="2007 Va. Ch. 571">2007, c. 571<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2007#000571#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PVD0-004G-K3T4-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 19.2.</desig><title>CRIMINAL PROCEDURE</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 10.</desig><title>DISABILITY OF JUDGE OR ATTORNEY FOR COMMONWEALTH; COURT- APPOINTED COUNSEL; INTERPRETERS; TRANSCRIPTS</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="article"><heading><desig>ARTICLE 3.1.</desig><title>INDIGENT DEFENSE</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Public Health &amp; Welfare Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDYwRTY1MDg3MTk5NDUyNkFFRDI1RjJBRERGQ0UxNzI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Legal Aid</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OTg4RkU3NTE3RTE4NENDRDkzNDlEQjJCQjYzNkU3RUQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDZDNTZENUNCRjVBNEY4OEIyQzVBNjRDRTcyOEQ4NDQ</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification><classificationGroup classificationScheme="indexing-terms"><classification classificationScheme="legal"/></classificationGroup></metadata></legislativeDoc>