<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#349#000059#     1#       284.20#">Va. Code Ann. § 59.1-284.20</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_59.1-284.20"/><heading><desig>§ 59.1-284.20.</desig><title>Aerospace Engine Manufacturing Performance Grant Program; eligible county</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a"/><heading><desig>A.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> As used in this section:</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Affiliate"</emphasis> means with respect to any person, any other person directly or indirectly controlling, controlled by, or under common control with such person. For purposes of this definition, "control" (including "controlled by" and "under common control with") shall mean the power, directly or indirectly, to direct or cause the direction of the management and policies of such person whether through ownership or voting securities or by contract or otherwise.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Capital investment"</emphasis> means an investment in real property, tangible personal property, or both, within the Commonwealth that is capitalized.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Eligible county"</emphasis> means Prince George County.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Grant"</emphasis> means the aerospace engine manufacturing performance grant as described in this section.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Manufacture of aerospace engines"</emphasis> means (i) the manufacture or assembly and test of aircraft engines and engine parts; (ii) the design or development of aircraft engines and engine parts; or (iii) the manufacturing activities of a private company described under 2007 index number 336412 of the North American Industry Classification System.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Memorandum of understanding"</emphasis> means a performance agreement entered into accordance with a memorandum of understanding entered into on November 20, 2007, among a qualified manufacturer, the Commonwealth, and others setting forth the requirements for capital investment and the creation of new full-time jobs that will make the qualified manufacturer eligible for a grant under this section.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"New full-time job"</emphasis> means employment of an indefinite duration in an eligible county, created as the direct result of new capital investment, for which the average annual wage is at least equal to the prevailing average annual wage in an eligible county and for which the standard fringe benefits are paid by the qualified manufacturer, requiring a minimum of either (i) 35 hours of an employee's time per week for the entire normal year of such manufacturer's operations, which "normal year" must consist of at least 48 weeks or (ii) 1,680 hours per year. Seasonal or temporary positions, and positions created when a job function is shifted from an existing location in the Commonwealth shall not qualify as new full-time jobs under this section. Other positions, which may or may not be of indefinite duration, including supplemental employees of affiliates, subsidiaries, joint ventures, contractors, or subcontractors may be considered new full-time jobs, if so designated in the memorandum of understanding between such manufacturer, the Commonwealth, and others as such memorandum of understanding was in effect on November 20, 2007.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Qualified manufacturer"</emphasis> means a manufacturer that (i) is expected to make a capital investment of at least $ 500 million by June 30, 2023, in an eligible county related to the manufacture of aerospace engines and (ii) is expected to create at least 540 jobs in an eligible county for the manufacture of aerospace engines or activities ancillary or supportive of such manufacture.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Secretary"</emphasis> means the Secretary of Commerce and Trade or his designee.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b"/><heading><desig>B.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Any qualified manufacturer that, after July 1, 2008, first begins operations in an eligible county shall be eligible to receive a grant each fiscal year beginning with the Commonwealth's fiscal year starting on July 1, 2013, and ending with the Commonwealth's fiscal year starting on July 1, 2022, unless such time frame is extended in accordance with subsection E. The grants under this section (i) shall be paid, subject to appropriation by the General Assembly, from a fund entitled the Aerospace Engine Manufacturing Performance Grant Fund, which Fund is hereby established on the books of the Comptroller, (ii) shall not exceed $ 35 million in the aggregate, and (iii) shall be paid to the qualified manufacturer during each fiscal year contingent upon the qualified manufacturer meeting the requirements for the aggregate (a) number of new full-time jobs created and the substantial retention of the same and (b) amount of the capital investment made and substantially retained as set forth in the memorandum of understanding.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c"/><heading><desig>C.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> If grants to be paid to qualified manufacturers under this section in a fiscal year exceed the aggregate amount available in the Aerospace Engine Manufacturing Performance Grant Fund for that year, each qualified manufacturer's grants for the year shall equal the amount of grants to which the qualified manufacturer would otherwise be eligible multiplied by a fraction. The numerator of the fraction shall equal the aggregate amount available for payment from the Aerospace Engine Manufacturing Performance Grant Fund for that fiscal year, and the denominator shall equal the aggregate dollar amount of grants to which all qualified manufacturers otherwise would be eligible for such fiscal year.</p><p>The aggregate amount of the grants payable under this section shall be subject to the following requirements and limitations:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Grants shall be awarded after July 1, 2013, and before July 1, 2023, unless such time frame is extended in accordance with subsection E.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The amount of the grant to be paid in each fiscal year shall be conditional upon the qualified manufacturer meeting the requirements for the (i) aggregate number of new full-time jobs created and the substantial retention of the same throughout the calendar year that immediately precedes the end of such fiscal year, and (ii) aggregate amount of the capital investment made and substantially retained as of the last day of the calendar year that immediately precedes the end of such fiscal year as set forth in the memorandum of understanding entered into on November 20, 2007. Grants shall be paid based upon such requirements as agreed to on November 20, 2007, regardless if such memorandum of understanding is later modified, amended, superseded, or otherwise changed.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The aggregate amount of grants that may be awarded in a particular fiscal year shall not exceed the following:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c_3_a"/><heading><desig>a.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> $ 5.5 million for the Commonwealth's fiscal year beginning July 1, 2013;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c_3_b"/><heading><desig>b.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> $ 11 million, less the total amount of grants previously awarded pursuant to this subsection, for the Commonwealth's fiscal year beginning July 1, 2014;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c_3_c"/><heading><desig>c.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> $ 14 million, less the total amount of grants previously awarded pursuant to this subsection, for the Commonwealth's fiscal year beginning July 1, 2015;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c_3_d"/><heading><desig>d.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> $ 17 million, less the total amount of grants previously awarded pursuant to this subsection, for the Commonwealth's fiscal year beginning July 1, 2016;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c_3_e"/><heading><desig>e.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> $ 20 million, less the total amount of grants previously awarded pursuant to this subsection, for the Commonwealth's fiscal year beginning July 1, 2017;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c_3_f"/><heading><desig>f.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> $ 23 million, less the total amount of grants previously awarded pursuant to this subsection, for the Commonwealth's fiscal year beginning July 1, 2018;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c_3_g"/><heading><desig>g.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> $ 26 million, less the total amount of grants previously awarded pursuant to this subsection, for the Commonwealth's fiscal year beginning July 1, 2019;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c_3_h"/><heading><desig>h.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> $ 29 million, less the total amount of grants previously awarded pursuant to this subsection, for the Commonwealth's fiscal year beginning July 1, 2020;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c_3_i"/><heading><desig>i.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> $ 32 million, less the total amount of grants previously awarded pursuant to this subsection, for the Commonwealth's fiscal year beginning July 1, 2021; and</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c_3_j"/><heading><desig>j.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> $ 35 million, less the total amount of grants previously awarded pursuant to this subsection, for the Commonwealth's fiscal year beginning July 1, 2022.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c_4"/><heading><desig>4.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Grants provided by this section shall not exceed $ 35 million in the aggregate.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d"/><heading><desig>D.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Any qualified manufacturer applying for a grant under this section shall provide evidence, satisfactory to the Secretary, of (i) the aggregate number of new full-time jobs created and the substantial retention of the same throughout the calendar year that immediately precedes the end of the fiscal year in which the grant is to be paid, and (ii) the aggregate amount of the capital investment made and substantially retained as of the last day of the calendar year that immediately precedes the end of the fiscal year in which the grant is to be paid. The application and evidence shall be filed with the Secretary in person or by mail no later than April 1 each year following the calendar year in which the qualified manufacturer meets such aggregate new full-time job requirements and aggregate capital investment. Failure to meet the filing deadline shall result in a deferral of a scheduled grant payment set forth in subsection C. For filings by mail, the postmark cancellation shall govern the date of the filing determination.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_e"/><heading><desig>E.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The memorandum of understanding may provide that if a grant payment has been deferred for any reason, including the initial failure to meet the aggregate capital investment and the aggregate new full-time job requirements set forth in the memorandum of understanding or the occurrence of any substantial reduction in such new full-time job requirements or capital investment requirements after such requirements have been met but before the grant payment has been made, payment in a subsequent fiscal year for which such requirements have been met for the immediately preceding calendar year shall include both the deferred payment and the scheduled grant payment as provided in subsection C.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_f"/><heading><desig>F.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Within 30 days after the filing deadline in subsection D, the Secretary shall certify to (i) the Comptroller and (ii) each qualified manufacturer the amount of the grant to which such qualified manufacturer is entitled under this section for payment in the current fiscal year. Payment of such grant shall be made by check issued by the Treasurer of Virginia on warrant of the Comptroller by June 30 of such fiscal year.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_g"/><heading><desig>G.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> As a condition of receipt of a grant, a qualified manufacturer shall make available to the Secretary or his designee for inspection upon his request all relevant and applicable documents to determine whether the qualified manufacturer has met the requirements for the receipt of grants as set forth in this section and subject to the memorandum of understanding. The Comptroller shall not draw any warrants to issue checks for the grant program under this section without a specific appropriation for the same. All such documents appropriately identified by the qualified manufacturer shall be considered confidential and proprietary.</p></bodyText></level><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p><citation normalizedCite="2008 VA CH 256"><content><span normalizedCite="2008 Va. Ch. 256">2008, cc. 256<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2008#000256#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2008 VA CH 630"><content><span normalizedCite="2008 Va. Ch. 630">630<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2008#000630#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PVJ0-004G-K150-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 59.1.</desig><title>TRADE AND COMMERCE</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 22.5.</desig><title>AEROSPACE ENGINE MANUFACTURING PERFORMANCE GRANT PROGRAM</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Governments</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjdEQjE4OUJDMzQxNDNEMEI0RTI1QUFCMzJENjEwRTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Finance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjMzOTBBRTg2MUVDNDdDNUE1M0QxNDk1RERCNjNCN0I7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Njg1MkM3RkYyNzIxNEVFRkJFMTI2NUM4NUU1ODdEM0Q</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Real Property Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QUUyRTcxRURBNEY2NEE2MDk3QzBCNzRDOEY0NTZDQzk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Public Entities</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RjYyQkY4N0Y5QjJDNDkxQkFGNkIwMTEyQ0Y2MzY4MTQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RURDNjE0NDUzN0QxNDE4OTg0OERFMzU4MzFCNUU1NUI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification><classificationGroup classificationScheme="indexing-terms"><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem score="90"><className>Antitrust</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6REEyRTNDM0JGQzYyNEMyOEFGNTAwNUJEOUU1MDg4NjU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></classificationGroup></metadata></legislativeDoc>