<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#349#000006#     2#         1158#">Va. Code Ann. § 6.2-1158</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_6.2-1158"/><heading><desig>§ 6.2-1158.</desig><title>Acquisitions by out-of-state savings institution</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a"/><heading><desig>A.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Any out-of-state savings institution that is insured by the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation or other federal insurance agency, may acquire a Virginia savings institution holding company or a Virginia savings institution with the approval of the Commission. Such savings institution shall submit to the Commission an application for approval of such acquisition, which application may be approved if the Commission:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Determines that the laws of the state in which the savings institution making the acquisition has its principal place of business do not prohibit or unfairly impede a Virginia savings institution meeting the criteria in this article from acquiring savings institutions or savings institution holding companies in that state;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Determines that the laws of the state in which the savings institution making the acquisition has its principal place of business permit such savings institution to be acquired by the Virginia savings institution holding company or Virginia savings institution sought to be acquired;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Determines that the Virginia savings institution sought to be acquired has been in existence and continuously operating for more than two years or that all of the Virginia savings institution subsidiaries of the Virginia savings institution holding company sought to be acquired have been in existence and continuously operating for more than two years. The Commission may approve the acquisition by a savings institution of all or substantially all of the shares of a savings institution organized solely for the purpose of facilitating the acquisition of a savings institution that has been in existence and continuously operating as a savings institution for more than two years; and</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_4"/><heading><desig>4.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Makes the acquisition subject to any conditions, restrictions, requirements or other limitations that would apply to the acquisition by a Virginia savings institution of a savings institution or savings institution holding company in the state where the savings institution making the acquisition has its principal place of business but that would not apply to the acquisition of a savings institution or savings institution holding company in such state by a savings institution located in that state.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b"/><heading><desig>B.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> An out-of-state savings institution that is insured by the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation or other federal insurance agency and that has previously acquired a Virginia savings institution or Virginia savings institution holding company may acquire any additional Virginia savings institution or Virginia savings institution holding company with the approval of the Commission. Such savings institution shall submit to the Commission an application for approval of such acquisition, which application may be approved if the Commission:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Determines that the Virginia savings institution sought to be acquired has been in existence and continuously operating for more than two years. The Commission may approve the acquisition by a savings institution of all or substantially all of the shares of a savings institution organized solely for the purpose of facilitating the acquisition of a savings institution that has been in existence and continuously operating as a savings institution for more than two years; and</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Makes the acquisition subject to any conditions, restrictions, requirements or other limitations that would apply to the acquisition by a Virginia savings institution of a savings institution or a savings institution holding company in the state where the savings institution making the acquisition has its principal place of business but that would not apply to the acquisition of a savings institution or a savings institution holding company in such state by a savings institution located in that state.</p></bodyText></level></level><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p>1985, c. 425, § 6.1-194.98; 1986, c. 500; <citation normalizedCite="1990 VA CH 3"><content><span normalizedCite="1990 Va. Ch. 3">1990, c. 3<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1990#000003#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1994 VA CH 353"><content><span normalizedCite="1994 Va. Ch. 353">1994, c. 353<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1994#000353#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2010 VA CH 794"><content><span normalizedCite="2010 Va. Ch. 794">2010, c. 794<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2010#000794#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PVS0-004G-K3VC-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 6.2.</desig><title>FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS AND SERVICES</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="subtitle"><heading><desig>SUBTITLE II.</desig><title>DEPOSITORY INSTITUTIONS AND TRUST ORGANIZATIONS</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 11.</desig><title>SAVINGS INSTITUTIONS</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="article"><heading><desig>ARTICLE 5.</desig><title>FOREIGN SAVINGS INSTITUTIONS; ACQUISITIONS BY OUT-OF-STATE SAVINGS INSTITUTIONS OR OUT-OF-STATE SAVINGS INSTITUTION HOLDING COMPANIES.</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Foreign Insurers</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjlGMEIzREZGNUFENERBRUJBRDg5NjgxQTlEOTE1N0Y7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OUE0QUQ4OUIxOURCNDA3RUEyQkY0NzhBREMxNzk1RTM</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjA4OEVGODBENzY4NDcxM0IyQzA1OTEwQzVDODRBOUE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDc1MERFNzE3ODExNDEyMDgwM0RDMTdBRjUxMDQwQUQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NkU1RUZCODkyMDJCNDgzODlDREYzQkNBQkZDNTNBMzc</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Insurance Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDM4MzQ2QUYzMTY0NDQzQTkxRDQwRUUzRUM5RDg0OEM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Foreign Insurers</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjlGMEIzREZGNUFENERBRUJBRDg5NjgxQTlEOTE1N0Y7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OUE0QUQ4OUIxOURCNDA3RUEyQkY0NzhBREMxNzk1RTM</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification><classificationGroup classificationScheme="indexing-terms"><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem score="90"><className>Banking &amp; Finance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjQyMUFCOUJBNURBNEFDREE3MTNCNDk5QkQ4NUM3RjI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></classificationGroup></metadata></legislativeDoc>