<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#349#000033#     2#         2916#">Va. Code Ann. § 33.2-2916</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_33.2-2916"/><heading><desig>§ 33.2-2916.</desig><title>Transfer to City of Richmond</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a"/><heading><desig>A.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> If the City of Richmond has rendered financial assistance or contributed in any manner to the cost of construction of a limited access highway by the Authority within or partly within and partly without the corporate limits of the City of Richmond, and the Authority has issued bonds for the construction of such limited access highway, then, when all such bonds, including refunding bonds, and the interest thereon have been paid or a sufficient amount of cash or United States government securities have been deposited and dedicated to the payment of all such bonds and the interest to the maturity or redemption date thereof in trust for the benefit of the holders of such bonds, all property, real and personal, acquired in connection with such limited access highway within the City of Richmond shall be transferred by the Authority to the City as compensation to the City for the financial assistance rendered by the City to the Authority in connection with the construction or acquisition of such limited access highway. Such highway shall upon the acceptance thereof by the City become a part of the street or highway system of the City and shall thereafter be maintained and operated as a limited access highway by the City. The governing body of the City of Richmond shall have the power to fix, revise, charge, and collect tolls for transit over such limited access highway and as compensation for other uses that may be made thereof. The proceeds from such tolls and compensation shall be first used to reimburse the City of Richmond and the Counties of Henrico and Chesterfield for any funds or expenditures made by each of them pursuant to contracts or agreements authorized by <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 33.2-2913"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 33.2-2913">§ 33.2-2913<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000033#     2#         2913#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> for which reimbursement has not been made, and then for the operation, maintenance, improvement, expansion, or extension of such limited access highway and to increase its utility and benefits and for the construction, reconstruction, maintenance, and operation of other projects or highways connected with such limited access highway or with the federal or state highway systems, and for such purpose the City of Richmond shall succeed to all the functions and shall have all the powers conferred on the Authority by this chapter.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b"/><heading><desig>B.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> If the Authority constructs a limited access highway project partly within and partly without the corporate limits of the City of Richmond, any extension thereof shall be constructed or acquired only when approved by the unanimous vote of all members of the board of directors or by a vote of three-fourths of the directors and approval by the City Council of the City of Richmond and the Boards of Supervisors of the Counties of Henrico and Chesterfield. If the Authority has issued bonds for the purpose of constructing such project or for the purpose of constructing or acquiring such extensions when all such bonds, including any refunding bonds, and the interest thereon have been paid or a sufficient amount of cash or United States government securities have been deposited and dedicated to the payment thereof in trust for the benefit of holders of such bonds, all property, real and personal, acquired in connection with such project or extension thereof not required to be transferred to the City of Richmond pursuant to subsection A shall be transferred by the Authority to the political subdivisions in which such property is located at the time of such transfer at no cost to such political subdivisions in the event the subdivisions adopt a resolution accepting such property. If not accepted by such subdivisions within 30 days from the offer of the property by the Authority, then the Authority shall transfer such property to the Commonwealth Transportation Board. If such property is accepted by the political subdivision where the property is located, the governing body of such subdivision shall have the power to fix, revise, charge, and collect tolls for transit over such limited access highway project or extension and as compensation for other uses that may be made thereof. The proceeds from such tolls and compensation shall be used first to reimburse the City of Richmond and the Counties of Henrico and Chesterfield for any funds or expenditures made by each of them pursuant to contracts or agreements authorized by <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 33.2-2913"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 33.2-2913">§ 33.2-2913<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000033#     2#         2913#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> for which reimbursement has not been made and then for the operation, maintenance, improvement, expansion, or extension of such limited access highway project and to increase its utility and benefits and for the construction, reconstruction, maintenance, and operation of other projects or highways connected with such limited access highway or with the state or federal highway systems and for such purpose such political subdivisions shall succeed to all the functions and shall have all the powers conferred on the Authority by this chapter with respect to such property.</p></bodyText></level><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p><citation normalizedCite="2009 VA CH 471"><content><span normalizedCite="2009 Va. Ch. 471">2009, c. 471<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2009#000471#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, § 15.2-7016; <citation normalizedCite="2014 VA CH 805"><content><span normalizedCite="2014 Va. Ch. 805">2014, c. 805<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2014#000805#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2015 VA CH 256"><content><span normalizedCite="2015 Va. Ch. 256">2015, c. 256<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2015#000256#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PWC0-004G-K2P1-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 33.2.</desig><title>HIGHWAYS AND OTHER SURFACE TRANSPORTATION SYSTEMS</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="subtitle"><heading><desig>SUBTITLE IV.</desig><title>LOCAL AND REGIONAL TRANSPORTATION</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 29.</desig><title>RICHMOND METROPOLITAN TRANSPORTATION AUTHORITY</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Governments</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjdEQjE4OUJDMzQxNDNEMEI0RTI1QUFCMzJENjEwRTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Administrative Boards</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QTYwRUFCMDc5MzQ5NDEyREFEQkU2NkE2MjRGQTlCNzY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Njg1MkM3RkYyNzIxNEVFRkJFMTI2NUM4NUU1ODdEM0Q</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Bridges &amp; Roads</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RTBBOTc0NTk5Nzg4NEM4MEI5REUxMTc4OEY4RDIwQzA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MEY3NUIxODI2RjU2NEY0NzgwMDQyNjFDMEQ1QUExRjM</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Duties &amp; Powers</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Njk1NTNGMzM0RTc3NDcyMUI4MENCQUQ1RDhEN0M1RUM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Njg1MkM3RkYyNzIxNEVFRkJFMTI2NUM4NUU1ODdEM0Q</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Elections</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RTlGMTIwRjY1ODQ4NDQyRUE1MkJFMUQwMTE1MDhGQjY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Njg1MkM3RkYyNzIxNEVFRkJFMTI2NUM4NUU1ODdEM0Q</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Finance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjMzOTBBRTg2MUVDNDdDNUE1M0QxNDk1RERCNjNCN0I7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Njg1MkM3RkYyNzIxNEVFRkJFMTI2NUM4NUU1ODdEM0Q</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Financing</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Q0QyN0IxRDI1MTE0NDQ3NkEzMzZCMTBCMkE2QkM3RTM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MEY3NUIxODI2RjU2NEY0NzgwMDQyNjFDMEQ1QUExRjM</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Transportation Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RTYzRTk5RDVBQkQ2NDcwQzk2NTU3ODQ5OEE3NDlBNzk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Funding</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QTFFNkIxMEVFQTA2NERDMDhDRUUwNUY2NEQ4MTYyOUM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjVCODE3RDNEMENDNDkxRjg5MzBBNTJFQkNCRDlFOEU</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NTkyRUE5REJENDMwNDE4OTg3OTg5NTg0OEVEOUE3M0E7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjVCODE3RDNEMENDNDkxRjg5MzBBNTJFQkNCRDlFOEU</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification><classificationGroup classificationScheme="indexing-terms"><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem score="90"><className>Transportation</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RTYzRTk5RDVBQkQ2NDcwQzk2NTU3ODQ5OEE3NDlBNzk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></classificationGroup></metadata></legislativeDoc>