<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#349#000060#     2#          631#">Va. Code Ann. § 60.2-631</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_60.2-631"/><heading><desig>§ 60.2-631.</desig><title>Board of Review</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a"/><heading><desig>A.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The Commissioner, in his discretion, is hereby authorized to appoint a Board of Review consisting of three members, one of whom shall be designated chairman for a term of six years. The terms of the members first taking office shall be two, four, and six years, respectively, as designated by the Commissioner at the time of the appointment. Vacancies shall be filled by appointment by the Commissioner for the unexpired term. During his term of membership on the Board no member shall serve as an officer or committee member of any political organization. The members of the Board shall be compensated in a manner determined by the Commission. The Commission shall furnish the Board such stenographic and clerical assistance as the Board may require. All compensation of the members of the Board and all necessary expenses for the operation thereof shall be paid out of the administrative fund provided for in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 60.2-306"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 60.2-306">§§ 60.2-306<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000060#     2#          306#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> through <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 60.2-309"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 60.2-309">60.2-309<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000060#     2#          309#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> and <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 60.2-311"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 60.2-311">§§ 60.2-311<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000060#     2#          311#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> through <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 60.2-313"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 60.2-313">60.2-313<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000060#     2#          313#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>. The Commissioner may at any time, after notice and hearing, remove any member for cause. The Commissioner may, after thirty days' notice to the members of the Board and upon a finding that the Board is no longer needed, abolish the same.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b"/><heading><desig>B.</desig></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The Board shall meet upon the call of the chairman. It shall have the same powers and perform the same functions vested in the Commission in this title for review of decisions by an appeal tribunal, including the power to administer oaths and affirmations, take depositions, certify to official acts, and issue subpoenas to compel the attendance of witnesses and the production of books, papers, correspondence, memoranda and other records deemed necessary as evidence in connection with disputed claims.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The Board may hold its hearings in the county or city where the claimant was last employed, except that hearings involving the provisions of subdivision 2 of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 60.2-612"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 60.2-612">§ 60.2-612<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000060#     2#          612#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> shall be held in the county or city where the claimant was last employed. When the same or substantially similar evidence is relevant and material to matters in issue in claims by more than one individual or in claims by a single individual with respect to two or more weeks of unemployment, the same time and place for considering each such claim may be fixed, hearings thereon jointly conducted, and a single record of the proceedings made.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c"/><heading><desig>C.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The Commission may issue such regulations as it deems necessary for the procedure of the Board in the conduct of its hearings. During the time the Board is organized under authority of the Commissioner, the Commission shall have no jurisdiction under <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 60.2-622"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 60.2-622">§ 60.2-622<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000060#     2#          622#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>. Any decision of the Board shall become final ten days after the date of notification or mailing and judicial review shall be permitted the claimant, the Commission or any interested party claiming to be aggrieved. In any judicial action involving any such decision the Commission shall be represented by the Office of the Attorney General. Any decision of the Board from which no judicial review is sought within the time prescribed in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 60.2-625"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 60.2-625">§ 60.2-625<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000060#     2#          625#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> shall be conclusive against any party to the hearing before the Board and the Commission in any subsequent judicial proceedings involving liability for taxes under this title.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d"/><heading><desig>D.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Within the time specified in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 60.2-625"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 60.2-625">§ 60.2-625<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000060#     2#          625#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> the Commission, or any party to the proceedings before the Board, may obtain judicial review by filing in the circuit court of the county or city in which the individual who filed the claim was last employed, in the Commonwealth, a petition for review of such decision. In any such proceeding any other party to the proceeding shall be made a party respondent. The Commission shall be deemed to be a party to any such proceeding. The petition need not be verified. A copy of such petition shall be served upon the Commission and each party to the proceeding held before the Board at least thirty days prior to the placing of the petition upon the docket. The mailing of a copy of such petition to each party at his last known address shall be sufficient service. The Commission shall file along with its petition or answer a certified copy of the record of the case, including all documents and papers and a transcript of all testimony taken in the matter, together with the Board's findings, conclusions and decision therein.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_e"/><heading><desig>E.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> In any proceeding under this section the Board's findings of facts, if supported by the evidence and in the absence of fraud, shall be conclusive and the jurisdiction of the court shall be confined to questions of law. The court may order additional evidence to be taken by the Board, which such additional evidence, findings of fact or conclusions, together with the additional transcript of the record, shall be certified by the chairman of the Board and filed by him with the court. Such petition for review shall be heard in a summary manner and shall have preference over all other cases on the docket, except cases in which the Commonwealth is a party.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_f"/><heading><desig>F.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> An appeal may be taken from the decision of such court to the Court of Appeals in conformity with Part Five A of the Rules of Supreme Court and other applicable laws. From any such decision involving (i) the provisions of § 60.2-612 or <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 60.2-618"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 60.2-618">§ 60.2-618<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000060#     2#          618#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, (ii) whether an employing unit constitutes an employer or (iii) whether services performed for or in connection with the business of an employing unit constitute employment for such employing unit, the Court of Appeals shall have jurisdiction to review such decision regardless of the amount involved in any claim for benefits. It shall not be necessary, in any proceeding before the Board, to enter exceptions to its ruling, and no bond shall be required upon any appeal to any court. Upon the final determination of such judicial proceeding, the Board shall enter an order in accordance with such determination.</p></bodyText></level><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p>Code 1950, § 60-57; 1966, c. 30; 1968, c. 738, § 60.1-69; 1974, c. 466; 1984, c. 703; 1986, c. 480.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PTM0-004G-K0S8-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 60.2.</desig><title>UNEMPLOYMENT COMPENSATION</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 6.</desig><title>BENEFITS</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="article"><heading><desig>ARTICLE 5.</desig><title>CLAIMS ADJUDICATION</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Administrative Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NjMxMjc0MUIzQjkzNEM4MEI4NkZGQjVCREJCRDk4OUM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NjVBRkUwQTA0NDY3NDI3MkEwODI3RTY3MEZCOEI3REQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NUFFOUVFN0QyOEY2NDM0QjlDNTBFRTFERkFFMTA1Njk</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Standing</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NUU1RTE2NDk5MjE3NDVCNzlBN0M0OTE2NDJBNzk1OUQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RDQ2OTA3NjY4NjgyNEYyQjhBN0E1M0VFQkM3QzQ1MDQ</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Civil Procedure</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MzUxNjJDMEQ5N0YwNDMzM0JDMjEzM0UzOTYzMzI3OTU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OERBNTNFRjI0M0U3NDkyRkEyMkE5ODcyQUFEMzlFOUE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NjQ1NzExM0JCM0M2NDU0NkE2NDk2QUYwNEQ5NzE4NjE</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Governments</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjdEQjE4OUJDMzQxNDNEMEI0RTI1QUFCMzJENjEwRTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Administrative Boards</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QTYwRUFCMDc5MzQ5NDEyREFEQkU2NkE2MjRGQTlCNzY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Njg1MkM3RkYyNzIxNEVFRkJFMTI2NUM4NUU1ODdEM0Q</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Claims By &amp; Against</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjlEMDZENzJDMDZCNDBBOEFBOTJFMDE5Q0Q4RENEMDM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Njg1MkM3RkYyNzIxNEVFRkJFMTI2NUM4NUU1ODdEM0Q</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Labor &amp; Employment Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MTE3QUQwOTA0MUYzNDlCMEFFMjUwRUNDM0RDRkM5QzM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RUMxMEM5Mzk5NjdBNEQyMDg1NzYzNTNFMTc3QjExNkQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MEUyNDQ5RTc4RDI2NDc3Q0I3MUE0OEE2NTA3QjYzRkM</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></metadata></legislativeDoc>