<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#349#000038#     2#         1415#">Va. Code Ann. § 38.2-1415</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_38.2-1415"/><heading><desig>§ 38.2-1415.</desig><title>Obligations of domestic governmental entities</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a"/><heading><desig>A.</desig></heading><bodyText><p>United States obligations. A domestic insurer may invest in any bonds, notes, warrants, and other evidences of indebtedness which are direct obligations of the United States or for which the full faith and credit of the United States are pledged for the payment of principal and interest.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b"/><heading><desig>B.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> United States agencies obligations. A domestic insurer may invest in any bonds, notes, warrants and other evidence of indebtedness which are direct obligations for the payment of money, issued by an agency or instrumentality of the United States, or obligations for the payment of money to the extent guaranteed or insured as to the payment of principal and interest by an agency or instrumentality of the United States.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c"/><heading><desig>C.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> State government obligations. A domestic insurer may invest in direct, general obligations of any state of the United States for the payment of money, or obligations for the payment of money to the extent guaranteed or insured as to the payment of principal and interest by any state of the United States, on the following conditions:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The state has the power to levy taxes for the prompt payment of the principal and interest of its obligations;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The state is not in default in the payment of principal or interest on any of its direct, guaranteed or insured obligations as of the date of investment;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> An insurer shall not invest under this subsection more than five percent of its admitted assets in obligations issued or guaranteed by any one state; and</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c_4"/><heading><desig>4.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> An insurer shall not invest under this subsection more than thirty percent of its admitted assets.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d"/><heading><desig>D.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Local government obligations. A domestic insurer may invest in direct, general obligations of any political subdivision, of any state of the United States, for the payment of money, or obligations for the payment of money, to the extent guaranteed as to the payment of principal and interest, by any such political subdivision, on the following conditions:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The obligations are payable or guaranteed from ad valorem taxes;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Such political subdivision is not in default in the payment of principal or interest on any of its direct or guaranteed obligations;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> No investment shall be made under this subsection in obligations which are secured only by special assessments for local improvements;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d_4"/><heading><desig>4.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> An insurer shall not invest more than five percent of its admitted assets in obligations issued or guaranteed by any one such political subdivision; and</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d_5"/><heading><desig>5.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> An insurer shall not invest more than thirty percent of its admitted assets under this subsection.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_e"/><heading><desig>E.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Anticipation obligations. An insurer may invest in the anticipation obligations of any political subdivision of any state, all within the United States, including but not limited to bond anticipation notes, tax anticipation notes, preliminary loan anticipation notes, revenue anticipation notes and construction anticipation notes, for the payment of money within twelve months from the issuance of the obligation, on the following conditions:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_e_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The anticipation notes must be a direct obligation of the issuer under conditions set forth in subsection D of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 38.2-1415"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 38.2-1415">§ 38.2-1415<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000038#     2#         1415#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_e_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The political subdivision is not in default in the payment of the principal or interest on any of its direct general obligations or any obligation guaranteed by such political subdivision;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_e_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The anticipation funds shall be specifically pledged to secure the obligation;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_e_4"/><heading><desig>4.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> An insurer shall not invest more than two percent of its admitted assets in the anticipation obligations issued by any one such political subdivision; and</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_e_5"/><heading><desig>5.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> An insurer shall not invest more than ten percent of its admitted assets under this subsection.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_f"/><heading><desig>F.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> State or municipal revenue obligations. A domestic insurer may invest in obligations of any state of the United States, a political subdivision thereof, or a public instrumentality of any one or more of the foregoing, for the payment of money, on the following conditions:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_f_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The obligations are payable from revenues or earnings of a public utility of such state, political subdivision, or public instrumentality which are specifically pledged therefor;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_f_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The law under which the obligations are issued requires that rates for service shall be charged and collected at all times such that they will produce sufficient revenue or earnings which, together with any other revenues or moneys pledged, are sufficient to pay all operating and maintenance charges of the public utility and all principal and interest on such obligations;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_f_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> No prior or parity obligations payable from the revenues or earnings of that public utility are in default as of the date of the investment;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_f_4"/><heading><desig>4.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> An insurer shall not invest under this subsection more than two percent of its admitted assets in the revenue obligations issued in connection with any one facility;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_f_5"/><heading><desig>5.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> An insurer shall not invest under this subsection more than two percent of its admitted assets in revenue obligations payable from revenue or earning sources which are the contractual responsibility of any one single credit risk; and</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_f_6"/><heading><desig>6.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> An insurer shall not invest under this subsection more than twenty-five percent of its admitted assets.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_g"/><heading><desig>G.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Other revenue obligations of state and local governments. A domestic insurer may invest in other state and local government revenue obligations of any state of the United States, a political subdivision thereof, or a public instrumentality of any of the foregoing, for the payment of money, on the following conditions:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_g_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The obligations are payable from revenues or earnings, excluding revenues or earnings from public utilities, specifically pledged therefor by such state, political subdivision, or public instrumentality;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_g_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> An insurer shall not invest under this subsection more than two percent of its admitted assets in the revenue obligations issued in connection with any one facility;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_g_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> No prior or parity obligation of the same issuer payable from revenues or earnings from the same source has been in default as to principal or interest during the five years next preceding the date of such investment, but the issuer need not have been in existence for that period, and obligations acquired under this subsection may have been newly issued;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_g_4"/><heading><desig>4.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> An insurer shall not invest under this subsection more than two percent of its admitted assets in revenue obligations payable from sources which are the contractual responsibility of any one single credit risk; and</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_g_5"/><heading><desig>5.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> An insurer shall not invest under this subsection more than twenty-five percent of its admitted assets.</p></bodyText></level></level><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p>1983, c. 457, § 38.1-217.18; 1986, c. 562; <citation normalizedCite="1992 VA CH 588"><content><span normalizedCite="1992 Va. Ch. 588">1992, c. 588<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1992#000588#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1998 VA CH 414"><content><span normalizedCite="1998 Va. Ch. 414">1998, c. 414<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1998#000414#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PT40-004G-K4D3-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 38.2.</desig><title>INSURANCE</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 14.</desig><title>INVESTMENTS</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="article"><heading><desig>ARTICLE 2.</desig><title>CATEGORY 1 INVESTMENTS</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Contracts Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QzY0RTZFMzE0RjkwNDdFQUI5M0U5N0ZFMjYyREMyQzU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QUNCM0E5RTA5QUFBNDNDNzgxMjQ1RTZFQzYzQkMyMDk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MTg5OTE0NDQzNTJCNERDRkI3NDZEMzdBMjREMERGRDM</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MTU3QjVFNDgwM0Q5NEEwOEFEMTc2QTNDNzVGMEJGOEE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RkQyOUVFMzQ2Q0IwNDY1OEJFMjJCQjI0MjM3NkYzOTk</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Governments</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjdEQjE4OUJDMzQxNDNEMEI0RTI1QUFCMzJENjEwRTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Finance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjMzOTBBRTg2MUVDNDdDNUE1M0QxNDk1RERCNjNCN0I7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Njg1MkM3RkYyNzIxNEVFRkJFMTI2NUM4NUU1ODdEM0Q</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification><classificationGroup classificationScheme="indexing-terms"><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem score="90"><className>Insurance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDM4MzQ2QUYzMTY0NDQzQTkxRDQwRUUzRUM5RDg0OEM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></classificationGroup></metadata></legislativeDoc>