<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#123#000055#      59.3#">Va. Code Ann. § 55-59.3</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_55-59.3"/><heading><desig>§ 55-59.3.</desig><title>Contents of advertisements of sale</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a"/><heading><desig>A.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The advertisement of sale under any deed of trust, in addition to such other matters as may be required by such deed of trust or by the trustee, in his discretion, shall set forth a description of the property to be sold, which description need not be as extensive as that contained in the deed of trust, and shall identify the property by street address, if any, or, if none, shall give the general location of the property with reference to streets, routes, or known landmarks. Where available, tax map identification may be used but is not required. The advertisement shall also include the time, place and terms of sale and shall give the name or names of the trustee or trustees. It shall set forth the name, address and telephone number of such person (either a trustee or the party secured or his agent or attorney) as may be able to respond to inquiries concerning the sale.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b"/><heading><desig>B.</desig></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> If the property being sold is a time-share estate or estates, the advertisement of sale required under subsection A of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 55-59.2"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 55 -59.2">§ 55-59.2<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#123#000055#      59.2#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> shall set forth, in addition to such other matters as the trustee finds appropriate, (i) a description of the specific time-share estate or estates to be sold, which description also shall include (a) the name of the time-share project and (b) the street address of the time-share project, or if no street address, the general location of the time-share project with reference to streets, routes, or known landmarks; (ii) the date, time, place, and terms of sale; (iii) the name of the trustee; and (iv) the name, address, and telephone number of the representative, agent, or attorney who is authorized to respond to inquiries concerning the sale and give additional information concerning the time-share estate or estates to be sold.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> In lieu of the requirements of subdivision 1, the advertisement shall set forth (i) the name of the time-share project in which the time-share estate or estates to be sold are contained; (ii) the street address of the time-share project in which the time-share estate or estates to be sold are contained, or if no street address, the general location of the time-share project with reference to streets, routes, or known landmarks; (iii) the date, time, place, and terms of sale; (iv) the name of the trustee; and (v) the name, address, and telephone number of the representative, agent, or attorney who is authorized to respond to inquiries concerning the sale and give additional information concerning the time-share estate or estates to be sold, including providing, upon request, in either hard copy or electronic form, a schedule of the time-share estate or estates to be sold. In addition, the advertisement shall contain a website address where a description of the specific time-share estate or estates to be sold is displayed.</p></bodyText></level></level><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p>1979, c. 12; <citation normalizedCite="2015 VA CH 23"><content><span normalizedCite="2015 Va. Ch. 23">2015, cc. 23<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2015#000023#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2015 VA CH 401"><content><span normalizedCite="2015 Va. Ch. 401">401<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2015#000401#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PTC0-004G-K2MD-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 55.</desig><title>PROPERTY AND CONVEYANCES</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 4.</desig><title>FORM AND EFFECT OF DEEDS AND COVENANTS; LIENS</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="article"><heading><desig>ARTICLE 2.</desig><title>FORM AND EFFECT OF DEEDS OF TRUST; SALES THEREUNDER; ASSIGNMENTS; RELEASES</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Real Property Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QUUyRTcxRURBNEY2NEE2MDk3QzBCNzRDOEY0NTZDQzk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Property Descriptions</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RTdGRkVBNTFFMjdCNDhGOEFEM0RBNENEREEwMUE3NkM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDMyNDNGQ0VGOUM5NDBDQzk1N0RFM0I2OTU2QzBBMzU</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Timeshares</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OTQ2MTA5RjlGODA0NDhFMEIzMEE2NDI4ODRBM0Y3MDU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjQxMkNBNkE1ODE5NDg0NUJDMTkzNzA1NTMwQzRFQ0M</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification><classificationGroup classificationScheme="indexing-terms"><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem score="90"><className>Real Property</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QUUyRTcxRURBNEY2NEE2MDk3QzBCNzRDOEY0NTZDQzk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></classificationGroup></metadata></legislativeDoc>