<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#349#000006#     2#         1816#">Va. Code Ann. § 6.2-1816</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_6.2-1816"/><heading><desig>§ 6.2-1816.</desig><title>Required and prohibited business methods</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><bodyText><p>Each licensee shall comply with the following requirements:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Each payday loan shall be evidenced by a written loan agreement, which shall be signed by the borrower and a person authorized by the licensee to sign such agreements and dated the same day the loan is made and disbursed. The loan agreement shall set forth, at a minimum: (i) the principal amount of the loan; (ii) the interest and any fee charged; (iii) the annual percentage rate, which shall be stated using that term, applicable to the transaction calculated in accordance with Consumer Financial Protection Bureau Regulation Z (12 C.F.R. Part 1026); (iv) evidence of receipt from the borrower of a check, dated as of the date that the loan is due, as security for the loan, stating the amount of the check; (v) an agreement by the licensee not to present the check for payment or deposit until the date the loan is due, which date shall produce a loan term of at least two times the borrower's pay cycle and after which date interest shall not accrue on the amount advanced at a greater rate than six percent per year; (vi) an agreement by the licensee that the borrower shall have the right to cancel the loan transaction at any time before the close of business on the next business day following the date of the transaction by paying to the licensee, in the form of cash or other good funds instrument, the amount advanced to the borrower; and (vii) an agreement that the borrower shall have the right to prepay the loan prior to maturity by paying the licensee the principal amount advanced and any accrued and unpaid interest, fees, and charges.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The licensee shall give a duplicate original of the loan agreement to the borrower at the time of the transaction.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A licensee shall not obtain any agreement from the borrower (i) giving the licensee or any third person power of attorney or authority to confess judgment for the borrower; (ii) authorizing the licensee or any third party to bring suit against the borrower in a court outside the Commonwealth; or (iii) waiving any right the borrower has under this chapter.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_4"/><heading><desig>4.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A licensee shall not require or accept more than one check from a borrower as security for any loan.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_5"/><heading><desig>5.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A licensee shall not cause any person to be obligated to the licensee in any capacity at any time in the principal amount of more than $ 500.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_6"/><heading><desig>6.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A licensee shall not (i) refinance, renew or extend any payday loan; (ii) make a loan to a person if the loan would cause the person to have more than one payday loan from any licensee outstanding at the same time; (iii) make a loan to a borrower on the same day that a borrower paid or otherwise satisfied in full a previous payday loan; (iv) make a payday loan to a person within 90 days following the date that the person has paid or otherwise satisfied in full a payday loan through an extended payment plan as provided in subdivision 26; (v) make a payday loan to a person within 45 days following the date that the person has paid or otherwise satisfied in full a fifth payday loan made within a period of 180 days as provided in subdivision 27 a; or (vi) make a payday loan to a person within the longer of (a) 90 days following the date that the person has paid or otherwise satisfied in full an extended term loan or (b) 150 days following the date that the person enters into an extended term loan, as provided in subdivision 27 b.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_7"/><heading><desig>7.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A licensee shall not cause a borrower to be obligated upon more than one loan at any time.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_8"/><heading><desig>8.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A check accepted by a licensee as security for any loan shall be dated as of the date the loan is due.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_9"/><heading><desig>9.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Notwithstanding any provision of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 8.01-226.10"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 8.01-226.10">§ 8.01-226.10<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000008#    01#       226.10#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> to the contrary, a licensee shall not threaten, or cause to be instigated, criminal proceedings against a borrower if a check given as security for a loan is dishonored. In addition to any other remedies available at law, a licensee that knowingly violates this prohibition shall pay the affected borrower a civil monetary penalty equal to three times the amount of the dishonored check.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_10"/><heading><desig>10.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A licensee shall not take an interest in any property other than a check payable to the licensee as security for a loan.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_11"/><heading><desig>11.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A licensee shall not make a loan to a borrower to enable the borrower to pay for any other product or service sold at the licensee's office location.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_12"/><heading><desig>12.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Loan proceeds shall be disbursed in cash or by the licensee's business check. No fee shall be charged by the licensee or an affiliated check casher for cashing a loan proceeds check.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_13"/><heading><desig>13.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A check given as security for a loan shall not be negotiated to a third party.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_14"/><heading><desig>14.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Upon receipt of a check given as security for a loan, the licensee shall stamp the check with an endorsement stating: "This check is being negotiated as part of a payday loan pursuant to Chapter 18 (<citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 6.2-1800"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 6.2-1800">§ 6.2-1800<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000006#     2#         1800#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> et seq.) of Title 6.2 of the Code of Virginia, and any holder of this check takes it subject to all claims and defenses of the maker."</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_15"/><heading><desig>15.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Before entering into a payday loan, the licensee shall provide each borrower with a pamphlet, in form consistent with regulations adopted by the Commission, explaining in plain language the rights and responsibilities of the borrower and providing a toll-free number at the Commission for assistance with complaints.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_16"/><heading><desig>16.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Before disbursing funds pursuant to a payday loan, a licensee shall provide a clear and conspicuous printed notice to the borrower indicating that a payday loan is not intended to meet long-term financial needs and that the borrower should use a payday loan only to meet short-term cash needs.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_17"/><heading><desig>17.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A borrower shall be permitted to make partial payments, in increments of not less than $ 5, on the loan at any time prior to maturity, without charge. The licensee shall give the borrower signed, dated receipts for each payment made, which shall state the balance due on the loan. Upon repayment of the loan in full, the licensee shall mark the original loan agreement with the word "paid" or "canceled," return it to the borrower, and retain a copy in its records.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_18"/><heading><desig>18.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Each licensee shall conspicuously post in each approved office a schedule of fees and interest charges, with examples using a $ 300 loan payable in 14 days and 30 days.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_19"/><heading><desig>19.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Any advertising materials used to promote payday loans that includes the amount of any payment, expressed either as a percentage or dollar amount, or the amount of any finance charge, shall also include a statement of the interest, fees and charges, expressed as an annual percentage rate, payable using as an example a $ 300 loan payable in 14 and 30 days.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_20"/><heading><desig>20.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> In any print media advertisement, including any web page, used to promote payday loans, the disclosure statements shall be conspicuous. "Conspicuous" shall have the meaning set forth in subdivision (a)(14) of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 59.1-501.2"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 59.1-501.2">§ 59.1-501.2.<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000059#     1#        501.2#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> If a single advertisement consists of multiple pages, folds, or faces, the disclosure requirement applies only to one page, fold, or face. In a television advertisement used to promote payday loans, the visual disclosure legend shall include 20 scan lines in size. In a radio advertisement or advertisement communicated by telephone used to promote payday loans, the disclosure statement shall last at least two seconds and the statement shall be spoken so that its contents may be easily understood.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_21"/><heading><desig>21.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A licensee or affiliate shall not knowingly make a payday loan to a person who is a member of the military services of the United States or the spouse or other dependent of a member of the military services of the United States. Prior to making a payday loan, every licensee or affiliate shall inquire of every prospective borrower if he is a member of the military services of the United States or the spouse or other dependent of a member of the military services of the United States. The loan documents shall include verification that the borrower is not a member of the military services of the United States or the spouse or other dependent of a member of the military services of the United States.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_22"/><heading><desig>22.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> In collecting or attempting to collect a payday loan, a licensee shall comply with the restrictions and prohibitions applicable to debt collectors contained in the Fair Debt Collection Practices Act <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="15 USC 1692"><content><span normalizedCite="15 U.S.C. 1692">(15 U.S.C. § 1692<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1828#123#000015#       1692#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> et seq.) regarding harassment or abuse, false or misleading misrepresentations, and unfair practices in collections.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_23"/><heading><desig>23.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A licensee may not file or initiate a legal proceeding of any kind against a borrower until 60 days after the date of default on a payday loan, during which period the licensee and borrower may voluntarily enter into a repayment arrangement.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_24"/><heading><desig>24.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A licensee shall not obtain authorization to electronically debit a borrower's deposit account in connection with any payday loan.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_25"/><heading><desig>25.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A licensee may not engage in any unfair, misleading, deceptive, or fraudulent acts or practices in the conduct of its business.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_26"/><heading><desig>26.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A borrower may pay any outstanding payday loan from any licensee by means of an extended payment plan as follows:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_26_a"/><heading><desig>a.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A borrower shall not be eligible to enter into more than one extended payment plan in any 12-month period.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_26_b"/><heading><desig>b.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> To enter into an extended payment plan with respect to a payday loan, the borrower shall agree in a written and signed document to repay the amount owed in at least four equal installments over an aggregate term of at least 60 days. Interest shall not accrue on the indebtedness during the term of the extended payment plan. The borrower may prepay an extended payment plan in full at any time without penalty. If the borrower fails to pay the amount owed under the extended payment plan when due, then the licensee may immediately accelerate the unpaid loan balance.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_26_c"/><heading><desig>c.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> If the borrower enters into an extended payment plan, then no licensee may make a payday loan to the borrower until a waiting period of 90 days shall have elapsed from the date that the borrower pays or satisfies in full the balance of the loan under the terms of the extended payment plan.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_26_d"/><heading><desig>d.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> At each approved office, the licensee shall post a notice in at least 24-point bold type, in a form established or approved by the Commission, informing persons that they may be eligible to enter into an extended payment plan.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_26_e"/><heading><desig>e.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The licensee shall provide oral notice to any borrower who is eligible to enter into an extended payment plan, at the time a payday loan is made, which notice shall inform the borrower of his ability to pay the payday loan by means of an extended payment plan. The information contained in the notice shall be in a form provided by the Bureau.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_27"/><heading><desig>27.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> In addition to the other conditions set forth in this chapter, the fifth payday loan that is made to any person within a period of 180 days shall be made only in compliance with, at the option of the borrower, either of the following:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_27_a"/><heading><desig>a.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The fifth payday loan is made upon the same terms and conditions otherwise applicable to payday loans under the terms of this chapter, except that (i) no licensee may make a payday loan to such borrower during a period of 45 days following the date such fifth payday loan is paid or otherwise satisfied in full and (ii) the borrower may elect, at any time on or before its due date, to repay such fifth payday loan by means of an extended payment plan as provided in subdivision 26 b; or</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_27_b"/><heading><desig>b.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The fifth payday loan is made in the form of an extended term loan. An extended term loan is a loan that complies with the terms and conditions otherwise applicable to payday loans under the terms of this chapter except that (i) the principal amount of the loan, and any interest and fees permitted by <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 6.2-1817"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 6.2-1817">§ 6.2-1817<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000006#     2#         1817#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, shall be payable in four equal installments over a payment period of 60 days following the date the loan is made and (ii) no licensee may make a payday loan to such borrower during the longer of (a) 90 days following the date the extended term loan is paid or otherwise satisfied in full or (b) 150 days following the date the extended term loan is made.</p></bodyText></level></level></level><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p><citation normalizedCite="2002 VA CH 897"><content><span normalizedCite="2002 Va. Ch. 897">2002, c. 897<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2002#000897#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, § 6.1-459; <citation normalizedCite="2003 VA CH 593"><content><span normalizedCite="2003 Va. Ch. 593">2003, c. 593<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2003#000593#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2004 VA CH 295"><content><span normalizedCite="2004 Va. Ch. 295">2004, c. 295<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2004#000295#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2005 VA CH 571"><content><span normalizedCite="2005 Va. Ch. 571">2005, c. 571<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2005#000571#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2008 VA CH 849"><content><span normalizedCite="2008 Va. Ch. 849">2008, cc. 849<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2008#000849#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2008 VA CH 876"><content><span normalizedCite="2008 Va. Ch. 876">876<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2008#000876#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2010 VA CH 794"><content><span normalizedCite="2010 Va. Ch. 794">2010, c. 794<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2010#000794#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2016 VA CH 501"><content><span normalizedCite="2016 Va. Ch. 501">2016, c. 501<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2016#000501#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PVT0-004G-K45S-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 6.2.</desig><title>FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS AND SERVICES</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="subtitle"><heading><desig>SUBTITLE III.</desig><title>OTHER REGULATED PROVIDERS OF FINANCIAL SERVICES</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 18.</desig><title>PAYDAY LENDERS</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Banking Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjQyMUFCOUJBNURBNEFDREE3MTNCNDk5QkQ4NUM3RjI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjlBMzc1NTg4M0Y3NEE4OThGM0JGRjY0M0EwQjZDMEI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjQ5MjFEMDQ4QjQ2NDM1QUE4NjA4RDc2N0RBNTZGOTc</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Unfair Practices</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MEYxM0EzNUQ1NTNDNDgwOEFDOEMzMUQyNjA4Q0UxODI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjQ5MjFEMDQ4QjQ2NDM1QUE4NjA4RDc2N0RBNTZGOTc</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Civil Procedure</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MzUxNjJDMEQ5N0YwNDMzM0JDMjEzM0UzOTYzMzI3OTU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Judgments by Confession</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6ODA0OUMzQTE4NkE2NEM3QjhBNDI3N0M4MTRERUMwNkI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUQ5QkE1Nzk0MEM2NDJEQzgyNTlEQzZFMDY1MzIyQkU</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Communications Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MEQxMkU0NzE2OEE2NDIxNEE3QzU0NjU2MDRERUNGNDE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Sponsorship Identifications</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RTYwNzNCRDk4Mzc0NEM5RUIyMjM4MEI1MTYzOTBBN0I7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjQ3MzdDMEM4NDEwNDg3OUI5NEMyN0E5REE4MENGRjQ</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Contracts Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QzY0RTZFMzE0RjkwNDdFQUI5M0U5N0ZFMjYyREMyQzU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Claims to Instruments</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OUIxQzQ2NTBGODlDNDI1NUIzMkUwQjhERERFREI2NjM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDE0RTBDNTU5RUI0NDM1RTk0NjI0NjAzMjkwQTkyMkQ</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Q0YyRjY1NkZBQjkzNDA0RUFCQzA0RjJEMjhGNTYwN0M7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDMzOTAwOUFFMTFCNEE3Njg4QUEzQTJFOUE1NzE5MkM</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6REM4OThDMTQwNjI4NDVBRTg2OUJBRjlFNUY1MTk4MTQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MkUyQjY4NDMwRDBFNDVEQ0E4N0Y3M0Y0QkU2MzI3Rjc</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Q0E5QTc3QzA5M0VENDlDMjhBQTczMDYzQ0E1NjJDRjY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjQwQTlFQTY4QzNENDhGQzgxN0E4RkFBRUFDRDdCRjQ</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Real Property Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QUUyRTcxRURBNEY2NEE2MDk3QzBCNzRDOEY0NTZDQzk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Fair Debt Collection Practices Act</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6M0VERDZFM0VDNDAwNEMxMTg2NkJDQzg5MzQ1N0U2NzM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QkY0QjUyNzVCQUQ0NDRDRUFDNDk5QTZBQThGNTg1MzU</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification><classificationGroup classificationScheme="indexing-terms"><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem score="90"><className>Banking &amp; Finance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjQyMUFCOUJBNURBNEFDREE3MTNCNDk5QkQ4NUM3RjI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></classificationGroup></metadata></legislativeDoc>