<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#123#000055#     376.1#">Va. Code Ann. § 55-376.1</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_55-376.1"/><heading><desig>§ 55-376.1.</desig><title>Possibility of reverter</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a"/><heading><desig>A.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A possibility of reverter contained in a reverter deed for a time-share estate subject to reverter is valid, enforceable in law and in equity, and shall operate to transfer title to the time-share estate from each grantee therein back to the developer provided the following conditions are satisfied:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The reverter deed from the developer contains the possibility of reverter by insertion of the language required by subsection E;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A grantee in the reverter deed is in default and has been provided thereafter with at least two written notices to this effect with no less than a 10-calendar day right to cure in each notice;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A grantee in the reverter deed has been provided with no less than 30 calendar days within which to cure the default before exercise of the possibility of reverter occurs;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_4"/><heading><desig>4.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> At the time of exercise of the possibility of reverter, the developer is the sole holder of the note and the sole beneficiary under the deed of trust;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_5"/><heading><desig>5.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The exercise by the developer of the possibility of reverter is evidenced by an affidavit duly recorded where the reverter deed was recorded which contains the following information:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_5_a"/><heading><desig>a.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A description of the time-share project and time-share estate and a statement that upon recordation of the affidavit, title to such time-share estate reverts back to the developer;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_5_b"/><heading><desig>b.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A description and recitation of the reverter deed which contained the possibility of reverter and a reference of when and where such deed was recorded and its recording information;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_5_c"/><heading><desig>c.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A recitation that the purchaser defaulted in or violated a consumer document and failed to cure such default or violation within a period of no less than 30 calendar days;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_5_d"/><heading><desig>d.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A description of the note and deed of trust with a recitation that (i) the developer is the sole holder of the note and the sole beneficiary under the deed of trust, (ii) such note is cancelled and declared void, and (iii) such deed of trust is automatically released;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_5_e"/><heading><desig>e.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A recitation that such purchaser's rights and entitlements in the time-share estate, the time-share project and the time-share program are extinguished effective the date of recordation of the affidavit;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_5_f"/><heading><desig>f.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The signature of a duly authorized representative of the developer verified under oath as to its truth of the statements contained therein; and</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_6"/><heading><desig>6.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A copy of the recorded affidavit described in subdivision A 5 is sent by the developer to each purchaser at his address as maintained by developer or the association, along with the statement from the developer explaining the consequences of such affidavit with emphasis on subparts a, d and e of subdivision A 5.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b"/><heading><desig>B.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The recordation of the affidavit referred to in subdivision A 5 shall automatically:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Transfer title to the time-share estate from each grantee in the reverter deed to the developer without the need of a deed to the developer or consent from such grantee;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Declare null and void and act as an automatic release of the deed of trust or mortgage given by such grantee to finance a portion of the purchase price of the time-share estate with no deficiency resulting;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Void and act as an automatic release of any debt from such grantee to the developer arising out of the purchase or financing of the time-share estate as evidenced by the note; and</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_4"/><heading><desig>4.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Extinguish any ownership or other property right or entitlements such grantee has in and to the time-share estate, the time-share project and the time-share program.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c"/><heading><desig>C.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The clerk of court shall record such affidavit in the land books where the time-share project is located indexing the purchaser in the grantor indices and the developer in the grantee indices. For indexing purposes only, the purchaser shall be referred to as the grantor and the developer as the grantee. The cost of recording the affidavit shall be limited to the clerk's fee only.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d"/><heading><desig>D.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> In the exercise of the possibility of reverter, the developer shall be liable to the purchaser for his failure to comply with the provisions of this section; however, such failure shall not operate to defeat or diminish the transfer of title to the time-share estate from each grantee in the reverter deed to the developer upon recordation of the affidavit referred to in subdivision A 5. The developer's liability shall be limited to the amount paid by such purchaser towards the purchase price of the time-share estate exclusive of interest and closing costs but without offset for the purchaser's utilization of the time-share program. The court shall award court costs and reasonable attorney's fees to the prevailing party.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_e"/><heading><desig>E.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The reverter deed shall contain the following statement in order to possess the possibility of reverter. The opening phrase shall be in bold face, 10-point type as follows:</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it"> Loss of Time-Share Estate.</emphasis> Developer has inserted into this deed a "possibility of reverter." By this concept, should a grantee of this reverter deed default in or violate an obligation imposed by a consumer document for a period of at least 60 days and fail to cure such violation or default within no less than 30 calendar days thereafter, title to the time-share will revert back to the developer upon the developer recording an affidavit to this effect where this reverter deed is recorded. Only the developer can elect to exercise the possibility of reverter. Each grantee in this reverter deed will be sent at least two notices of default or violation within the 30-day period with no less than 10 days to cure in each instance. The notice will be sent to the address of each grantee maintained at the office of the developer or the association. After the cure period has lapsed and the developer records the affidavit, title to the time-share estate will automatically vest in the developer and any note executed by grantee will be deemed canceled and any recorded deed of trust securing such note shall be automatically released. The possibility of reverter will itself lapse and become null and void at the soonest to occur of the following: (i) the deed of trust is released of record, (ii) a statement that the deed of trust is released of record is executed and recorded by the developer with a date of when the possibility of reverter was or is to lapse, or (iii) when the time-share program terminates pursuant to either the Virginia Real Estate Time-Share Act or the time-share instrument which created such program.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_f"/><heading><desig>F.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The filing of the affidavit referred to in subdivision A 5 shall not result in the requirement of any filing under Chapter 12 (<citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 64.2-1200"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 64.2-1200">§ 64.2-1200<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000064#     2#         1200#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> et seq.) of Title 64.2.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_g"/><heading><desig>G.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Any possibility of reverter not otherwise exercised by the developer pursuant to this section shall itself lapse and become null and void at the soonest to occur of the following: (i) the deed of trust is released of record, (ii) a statement that the deed of trust is released of record is executed and recorded by the developer with a date of when the possibility of reverter was or is to lapse, or (iii) when the time-share program terminates pursuant to either this chapter or the time-share instrument.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_h"/><heading><desig>H.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> In exercising the possibility of reverter, the developer shall be entitled to retain as liquidated damages all monies paid by the purchaser in conformity with any consumer document.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_i"/><heading><desig>I.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The exercise of the possibility of reverter shall not operate to diminish or eliminate (i) any debt of the purchaser to the time-share association or other third party occasioned by ownership of the time-share estate or participation in the time-share program or (ii) any recorded lien junior in priority to the deed of trust lien referred to in this section.</p></bodyText></level><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p><citation normalizedCite="2004 VA CH 143"><content><span normalizedCite="2004 Va. Ch. 143">2004, c. 143<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2004#000143#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PVD0-004G-K3SD-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 55.</desig><title>PROPERTY AND CONVEYANCES</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 21.</desig><title>THE VIRGINIA REAL ESTATE TIME-SHARE ACT</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="article"><heading><desig>ARTICLE 3.</desig><title>PROTECTION OF PURCHASERS</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Governments</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjdEQjE4OUJDMzQxNDNEMEI0RTI1QUFCMzJENjEwRTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Clerks of Court</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6REVFMjkzRDI1MkU2NERDNjk3OEUxODY0REYwMUI1NjE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NURENzJGNTEyQzM0NEREQUI2RkVCRTM4RTc1RTZBREU</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Real Property Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QUUyRTcxRURBNEY2NEE2MDk3QzBCNzRDOEY0NTZDQzk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Construction Loans</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RDNGMDlENjQ4NUYyNEM0MEIxRTAwMjAyRTdFRUNBRkY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MTY1MzRERDhBMDZCNDFBMDk0QUEwRjcyN0ZFNEY3REM</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjJCOTVGQkMzRkQzNEQ2RjkzOEFGNzY4QUVBNEUzRTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjQxMkNBNkE1ODE5NDg0NUJDMTkzNzA1NTMwQzRFQ0M</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RTFGMjExMUY0Njc1NEMxNDhDREVDMDIyMUNENzc5RDg7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDQzNzlERkQ2MUVDNDRENzlDQ0Q1Q0MyQzgxOEE3Q0M</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Liability of Developers &amp; Vendors</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6N0QxNkYzMTc4RjYzNDNFMzk3RkI1NTNGMzVFNTJCQzc7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjJFMEE0QjUxMkVGNEMzMkI1MDZBQ0REREYyRkQ4RTU</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Reversions &amp; Reverter</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUJENjRGMTg1QUVFNEQwMzlBQUI5NzdFMjA4RTJFOTY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RDYwODMxODEzOTIxNDY1QTg1MDY2RUI5M0Y4NjhEQ0U</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Timeshares</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OTQ2MTA5RjlGODA0NDhFMEIzMEE2NDI4ODRBM0Y3MDU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjQxMkNBNkE1ODE5NDg0NUJDMTkzNzA1NTMwQzRFQ0M</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification><classificationGroup classificationScheme="indexing-terms"><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem score="90"><className>Real Property</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QUUyRTcxRURBNEY2NEE2MDk3QzBCNzRDOEY0NTZDQzk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></classificationGroup></metadata></legislativeDoc>