<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#349#000015#     2#         2204#">Va. Code Ann. § 15.2-2204</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_15.2-2204"/><heading><desig>§ 15.2-2204.</desig><title>Advertisement of plans, ordinances, etc.; joint public hearings; written notice of certain amendments</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a"/><heading><desig>A.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Plans or ordinances, or amendments thereof, recommended or adopted under the powers conferred by this chapter need not be advertised in full, but may be advertised by reference. Every such advertisement shall contain a descriptive summary of the proposed action and a reference to the place or places within the locality where copies of the proposed plans, ordinances or amendments may be examined.</p><p>The local planning commission shall not recommend nor the governing body adopt any plan, ordinance or amendment thereof until notice of intention to do so has been published once a week for two successive weeks in some newspaper published or having general circulation in the locality; however, the notice for both the local planning commission and the governing body may be published concurrently. The notice shall specify the time and place of hearing at which persons affected may appear and present their views, not less than five days nor more than 21 days after the second advertisement appears in such newspaper. The local planning commission and governing body may hold a joint public hearing after public notice as set forth hereinabove. If a joint hearing is held, then public notice as set forth above need be given only by the governing body. The term "two successive weeks" as used in this paragraph shall mean that such notice shall be published at least twice in such newspaper with not less than six days elapsing between the first and second publication. After enactment of any plan, ordinance or amendment, further publication thereof shall not be required.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b"/><heading><desig>B.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> When a proposed amendment of the zoning ordinance involves a change in the zoning map classification of 25 or fewer parcels of land, then, in addition to the advertising as required by subsection A, written notice shall be given by the local planning commission, or its representative, at least five days before the hearing to the owner or owners, their agent or the occupant, of each parcel involved; to the owners, their agent or the occupant, of all abutting property and property immediately across the street or road from the property affected, including those parcels which lie in other localities of the Commonwealth; and, if any portion of the affected property is within a planned unit development, then to such incorporated property owner's associations within the planned unit development that have members owning property located within 2,000 feet of the affected property as may be required by the commission or its agent. However, when a proposed amendment to the zoning ordinance involves a tract of land not less than 500 acres owned by the Commonwealth or by the federal government, and when the proposed change affects only a portion of the larger tract, notice need be given only to the owners of those properties that are adjacent to the affected area of the larger tract. Notice sent by registered or certified mail to the last known address of such owner as shown on the current real estate tax assessment books or current real estate tax assessment records shall be deemed adequate compliance with this requirement. If the hearing is continued, notice shall be remailed. Costs of any notice required under this chapter shall be taxed to the applicant.</p><p>When a proposed amendment of the zoning ordinance involves a change in the zoning map classification of more than 25 parcels of land, or a change to the applicable zoning ordinance text regulations that decreases the allowed dwelling unit density of any parcel of land, then, in addition to the advertising as required by subsection A, written notice shall be given by the local planning commission, or its representative, at least five days before the hearing to the owner, owners, or their agent of each parcel of land involved, provided, however, that written notice of such changes to zoning ordinance text regulations shall not have to be mailed to the owner, owners, or their agent of lots shown on a subdivision plat approved and recorded pursuant to the provisions of Article 6 (<citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 15.2-2240"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 15.2-2240">§ 15.2-2240<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000015#     2#         2240#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> et seq.) where such lots are less than 11,500 square feet. One notice sent by first class mail to the last known address of such owner as shown on the current real estate tax assessment books or current real estate tax assessment records shall be deemed adequate compliance with this requirement, provided that a representative of the local commission shall make affidavit that such mailings have been made and file such affidavit with the papers in the case. Nothing in this subsection shall be construed as to invalidate any subsequently adopted amendment or ordinance because of the inadvertent failure by the representative of the local commission to give written notice to the owner, owners or their agent of any parcel involved.</p><p>The governing body may provide that, in the case of a condominium or a cooperative, the written notice may be mailed to the unit owners' association or proprietary lessees' association, respectively, in lieu of each individual unit owner.</p><p>Whenever the notices required hereby are sent by an agency, department or division of the local governing body, or their representative, such notices may be sent by first class mail; however, a representative of such agency, department or division shall make affidavit that such mailings have been made and file such affidavit with the papers in the case.</p><p>A party's actual notice of, or active participation in, the proceedings for which the written notice provided by this section is required shall waive the right of that party to challenge the validity of the proceeding due to failure of the party to receive the written notice required by this section.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c"/><heading><desig>C.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> When a proposed comprehensive plan or amendment thereto; a proposed change in zoning map classification; or an application for special exception for a change in use or to increase by greater than 50 percent of the bulk or height of an existing or proposed building, but not including renewals of previously approved special exceptions, involves any parcel of land located within one-half mile of a boundary of an adjoining locality of the Commonwealth, then, in addition to the advertising and written notification as required by this section, written notice shall also be given by the local commission, or its representative, at least 10 days before the hearing to the chief administrative officer, or his designee, of such adjoining locality.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d"/><heading><desig>D.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> When (i) a proposed comprehensive plan or amendment thereto, (ii) a proposed change in zoning map classification, or (iii) an application for special exception for a change in use involves any parcel of land located within 3,000 feet of a boundary of a military base, military installation, military airport, excluding armories operated by the Virginia National Guard, or licensed public-use airport then, in addition to the advertising and written notification as required by this section, written notice shall also be given by the local commission, or its representative, at least 30 days before the hearing to the commander of the military base, military installation, military airport, or owner of such public-use airport, and the notice shall advise the military commander or owner of such public-use airport of the opportunity to submit comments or recommendations.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_e"/><heading><desig>E.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The adoption or amendment prior to July 1, 1996, of any plan or ordinance under the authority of prior acts shall not be declared invalid by reason of a failure to advertise or give notice as may be required by such act or by this chapter, provided a public hearing was conducted by the governing body prior to such adoption or amendment. Every action contesting a decision of a locality based on a failure to advertise or give notice as may be required by this chapter shall be filed within 30 days of such decision with the circuit court having jurisdiction of the land affected by the decision. However, any litigation pending prior to July 1, 1996, shall not be affected by the 1996 amendment to this section.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_f"/><heading><desig>F.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Notwithstanding any contrary provision of law, general or special, the City of Richmond may cause such notice to be published in any newspaper of general circulation in the city.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_g"/><heading><desig>G.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> When a proposed comprehensive plan or amendment of an existing plan designates or alters previously designated corridors or routes for electric transmission lines of 150 kilovolts or more, written notice shall also be given by the local planning commission, or its representative, at least 10 days before the hearing to each electric utility with a certificated service territory that includes all or any part of such designated electric transmission corridors or routes.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_h"/><heading><desig>H.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> When any applicant requesting a written order, requirement, decision, or determination from the zoning administrator, other administrative officer, or a board of zoning appeals that is subject to the appeal provisions contained in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 15.2-2311"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 15.2-2311">§ 15.2-2311<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000015#     2#         2311#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> or <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 15.2-2314"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 15.2-2314">15.2-2314<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000015#     2#         2314#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, is not the owner or the agent of the owner of the real property subject to the written order, requirement, decision or determination, written notice shall be given to the owner of the property within 10 days of the receipt of such request. Such written notice shall be given by the zoning administrator or other administrative officer or, at the direction of the administrator or officer, the requesting applicant shall be required to give the owner such notice and to provide satisfactory evidence to the zoning administrator or other administrative officer that the notice has been given. Written notice mailed to the owner at the last known address of the owner as shown on the current real estate tax assessment books or current real estate tax assessment records shall satisfy the notice requirements of this subsection.</p><p>This subsection shall not apply to inquiries from the governing body, planning commission, or employees of the locality made in the normal course of business.</p></bodyText></level><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p>Code 1950, § 15-961.4; 1962, c. 407, § 15.1-431; 1964, c. 632; 1968, cc. 354, 714; 1973, cc. 117, 334; 1974, cc. 100, 570; 1975, c. 641; 1976, c. 642; 1977, c. 65; 1982, c. 291; <citation normalizedCite="1990 VA CH 61"><content><span normalizedCite="1990 Va. Ch. 61">1990, c. 61<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1990#000061#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1992 VA CH 353"><content><span normalizedCite="1992 Va. Ch. 353">1992, cc. 353<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1992#000353#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1992 VA CH 757"><content><span normalizedCite="1992 Va. Ch. 757">757<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1992#000757#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1993 VA CH 128"><content><span normalizedCite="1993 Va. Ch. 128">1993, cc. 128<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1993#000128#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1993 VA CH 734"><content><span normalizedCite="1993 Va. Ch. 734">734<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1993#000734#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1994 VA CH 774"><content><span normalizedCite="1994 Va. Ch. 774">1994, c. 774<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1994#000774#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1995 VA CH 178"><content><span normalizedCite="1995 Va. Ch. 178">1995, c. 178<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1995#000178#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1996 VA CH 613"><content><span normalizedCite="1996 Va. Ch. 613">1996, cc. 613<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1996#000613#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1996 VA CH 667"><content><span normalizedCite="1996 Va. Ch. 667">667<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1996#000667#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1997 VA CH 587"><content><span normalizedCite="1997 Va. Ch. 587">1997, c. 587<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1997#000587#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2001 VA CH 406"><content><span normalizedCite="2001 Va. Ch. 406">2001, c. 406<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2001#000406#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2002 VA CH 634"><content><span normalizedCite="2002 Va. Ch. 634">2002, c. 634<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2002#000634#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2004 VA CH 539"><content><span normalizedCite="2004 Va. Ch. 539">2004, cc. 539<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2004#000539#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2004 VA CH 799"><content><span normalizedCite="2004 Va. Ch. 799">799<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2004#000799#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2005 VA CH 514"><content><span normalizedCite="2005 Va. Ch. 514">2005, c. 514<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2005#000514#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2007 VA CH 761"><content><span normalizedCite="2007 Va. Ch. 761">2007, cc. 761<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2007#000761#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2007 VA CH 813"><content><span normalizedCite="2007 Va. Ch. 813">813<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2007#000813#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2011 VA CH 457"><content><span normalizedCite="2011 Va. Ch. 457">2011, c. 457<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2011#000457#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2012 VA CH 548"><content><span normalizedCite="2012 Va. Ch. 548">2012, c. 548<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2012#000548#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2013 VA CH 149"><content><span normalizedCite="2013 Va. Ch. 149">2013, cc. 149<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2013#000149#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2013 VA CH 213"><content><span normalizedCite="2013 Va. Ch. 213">213<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2013#000213#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PSK0-004G-K33H-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 15.2.</desig><title>COUNTIES, CITIES AND TOWNS</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="subtitle"><heading><desig>SUBTITLE II.</desig><title>POWERS OF LOCAL GOVERNMENT</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 22.</desig><title>PLANNING, SUBDIVISION OF LAND AND ZONING</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="article"><heading><desig>ARTICLE 1.</desig><title>GENERAL PROVISIONS</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Comprehensive &amp; General Plans</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RDQ4MjdBMDYzNTJCNENGRjlEQjI1MzI3NEM3ODdFMDQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6REM3NjlCMTNCRkNCNDc1Mzk5MzlGNjBBN0I2N0NENDU</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjA4OEVGODBENzY4NDcxM0IyQzA1OTEwQzVDODRBOUE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MTFDNUE2QkIzNDRENEMwMjlBRUJCQ0IyNURDNjIxNjE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QTNCQUY4MUFBQzI2NEY1QzhENjQzNDZDRjRERTcwNDQ</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Energy &amp; Utilities Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OUUzODAyRDk1QzVFNEZGMEJDM0RGMDYxOTlEMEEzRDA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Electricity Transmission</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6M0FEMjU2NjgxQUJCNDYwOEE2RTU4OUUxOEYxNjQ5MDc7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjMwQzNCRThDRjkwNDY0QjlFNDJFQzY5QzVCMEE0MTY</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Environmental Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NzFDRDYyNkI2QjhBNDg3NTkyRjRDRkZEQjlCRkRBQzM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Comprehensive &amp; General Plans</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RDQ4MjdBMDYzNTJCNENGRjlEQjI1MzI3NEM3ODdFMDQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6REM3NjlCMTNCRkNCNDc1Mzk5MzlGNjBBN0I2N0NENDU</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Governments</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjdEQjE4OUJDMzQxNDNEMEI0RTI1QUFCMzJENjEwRTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Ordinances &amp; Regulations</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NjQ1MzRDRUY1OTZBNDRDNTlDODQzRDRCMUFCNDc2RTU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Njg1MkM3RkYyNzIxNEVFRkJFMTI2NUM4NUU1ODdEM0Q</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Real Property Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QUUyRTcxRURBNEY2NEE2MDk3QzBCNzRDOEY0NTZDQzk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Comprehensive Plans</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6ODA5NDE1RkQ5NThCNEREQThEOTYxRjQwMzU0ODcyREM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NjcyQTdEMEUxODYyNDY0OThFQTg1NUNGMjFBMTkxQ0M</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NzIxOUEwNTk5MTZCNEM3ODgxNjAzMkQ3MzIxMzQ1OUE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Nzg5NTlBMjdCREU3NDE1OTg1QjFCODExQkZENkM1Nzk</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Local Regulations</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NUE4NDYxMTk4MEI0NDlDODgyODIxNzBDMjAyOTZENkM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Nzg5NTlBMjdCREU3NDE1OTg1QjFCODExQkZENkM1Nzk</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Ordinances</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDYxNkVDMTk2RTI1NDg2NEJGRDFCN0I4Qjk4MEJFMkU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NjcyQTdEMEUxODYyNDY0OThFQTg1NUNGMjFBMTkxQ0M</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Planned Unit Developments</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6ODY2N0Y0QTEyQzhBNEYxNjg2MTNFNzQ3REJDNzhGOEU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NjcyQTdEMEUxODYyNDY0OThFQTg1NUNGMjFBMTkxQ0M</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Variances</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RkIxOThDMjUxN0JFNEEwNkI3MDNEMTA2NzdBMzU5REI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NjcyQTdEMEUxODYyNDY0OThFQTg1NUNGMjFBMTkxQ0M</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Tax Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OTNEM0E2OEE0RkQyNEY1MDhBQzdGMkQ4ODI4QTJDODE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Assessments</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjIwOUNEOUU1RUQ5NEU3OTkyNUQxRjJFNkIzQjY3OTQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjkxRkVDMkNDMjBGNDdFMkI1RDQ3Nzk4QjgwOTBGQjU</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MEMzQzdEM0Q2NEEyNDg5RDhDMEE3NDAwMDNGOUU2MkM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MEI0QjM4RDg1M0IxNDk1RDkwOTVGMEMxRTQxQTg1ODU</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Transportation Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RTYzRTk5RDVBQkQ2NDcwQzk2NTU3ODQ5OEE3NDlBNzk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OEU3MENGNDYyQkM0NEM3MTk4RTk3NDE1QjRGMEU1MDc7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QzdDOUIxNEQzQzA5NEM0Q0E5RjlERDVFNzIzNEQyQzA</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Zoning</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QzNBMzYzNzc2RDE1NENCQkExMzFENjMzNEJERDMzOTM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QzdDOUIxNEQzQzA5NEM0Q0E5RjlERDVFNzIzNEQyQzA</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification><classificationGroup classificationScheme="indexing-terms"><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem score="90"><className>Governments</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjdEQjE4OUJDMzQxNDNEMEI0RTI1QUFCMzJENjEwRTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></classificationGroup></metadata></legislativeDoc>