<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#349#000046#     2#         1240#">Va. Code Ann. § 46.2-1240</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_46.2-1240"/><heading><desig>§ 46.2-1240.</desig><title>Definitions</title></heading><bodyText><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Disabled parking sign"</emphasis> means any sign used to identify parking spaces for use by vehicles bearing valid organizational, permanent, or temporary removable windshield placards, disabled parking license plates, or disabled parking license plates issued under <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 46.2-739"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 46.2-739">§ 46.2-739<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000046#     2#          739#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>. All disabled parking signs shall be erected and maintained in accordance with signage requirements specified in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 36-99.11"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 36 -99.11">§ 36-99.11.<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#123#000036#     99.11#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation></p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Organizational removable windshield placard"</emphasis> means a two-sided, hooked placard which includes on each side: (i) the international symbol of access at least three inches in height, centered on the placard, and shown in white on a green background; (ii) the name of the institution or organization; (iii) an identification number; (iv) an expiration date imprinted on the placard and indicated by a month and year hole-punch system or an alternative system designed by the Department; (v) a misuse hotline number designated by the Department; (vi) a warning of the penalties for placard misuse; and (vii) the seal or identifying symbol of the issuing authority.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Permanent removable windshield placard"</emphasis> means a two-sided, hooked placard which includes on each side: (i) the international symbol of access at least three inches in height, centered on the placard, and shown in white on a blue background; (ii) an identification number; (iii) an expiration date imprinted on the placard and indicated by a month and year hole-punch system or an alternative system designed by the Department; (iv) a misuse hotline number designated by the Department; (v) a warning of the penalties for placard misuse; and (vi) the seal or other identifying symbol of the issuing authority. All holders of permanent removable windshield placards shall be required to carry the Disabled Parking Placard Identification Card issued with the placard by the Department and present it to law-enforcement officials upon request.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Person with a disability that limits or impairs his ability to walk or that creates a concern for his safety while walking"</emphasis> means a person who, as determined by a licensed physician, podiatrist, or chiropractor: (i) cannot walk 200 feet without stopping to rest; (ii) cannot walk without the use of or assistance from a brace, cane, crutch, another person, prosthetic device, wheelchair, or other assistive device; (iii) is restricted by lung disease to such an extent that his forced (respiratory) expiratory volume for one second, when measured by spirometry, is less than one liter, or when at rest, his arterial oxygen tension is less than 60 millimeters of mercury on room air; (iv) uses portable oxygen; (v) has a cardiac condition to the extent that his functional limitations are classified in severity as Class III or Class IV according to standards set by the American Heart Association; (vi) is severely limited in his ability to walk due to an arthritic, neurological, or orthopedic condition; (vii) has some other debilitating condition that, in the view of a licensed physician, podiatrist, or chiropractor, limits or impairs his ability to walk; (viii) has been diagnosed with a mental or developmental amentia or delay that impairs judgment including, but not limited to, an autism spectrum disorder; (ix) has been diagnosed with Alzheimer's disease or another form of dementia; (x) is legally blind or deaf; or (xi) has some other condition that, in the view of a licensed physician creates a safety concern while walking because of impaired judgment or other physical, developmental, or mental limitation. For the purposes of this definition, a determination of a disability by a podiatrist or chiropractor shall be limited to those conditions specified in items (i), (ii), (vi) or (vii) of this definition.</p><p>Any licensed physician, nurse practitioner, physician assistant, podiatrist, or chiropractor who signs a certification that states that an applicant is disabled under clause (vii) of this definition shall specify, in a space provided on the certification form, the medical condition that limits or impairs the applicant's ability to walk. Any licensed physician, licensed nurse practitioner, or licensed physician assistant who signs a certification that states that an applicant is disabled under clause (xi) of this definition shall specify, in a space provided on the certification form, the physical, developmental, or mental condition that creates the safety concern.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Temporary removable windshield placard"</emphasis> means a two-sided, hooked placard which includes on each side: (i) the international symbol of access at least three inches in height, centered on the placard, and shown in white on a red background; (ii) an identification number; (iii) an expiration date imprinted on the placard and indicated by a month and year hole-punch system or an alternative system designed by the Department; (iv) a misuse hotline number; (v) a warning of the penalties for placard misuse; and (vi) the seal or other identifying symbol of the issuing authority.</p></bodyText><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p><citation normalizedCite="1997 VA CH 783"><content><span normalizedCite="1997 Va. Ch. 783">1997, cc. 783<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1997#000783#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1997 VA CH 904"><content><span normalizedCite="1997 Va. Ch. 904">904<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1997#000904#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1999 VA CH 188"><content><span normalizedCite="1999 Va. Ch. 188">1999, c. 188<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1999#000188#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2002 VA CH 108"><content><span normalizedCite="2002 Va. Ch. 108">2002, c. 108<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2002#000108#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2003 VA CH 992"><content><span normalizedCite="2003 Va. Ch. 992">2003, c. 992<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2003#000992#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2005 VA CH 276"><content><span normalizedCite="2005 Va. Ch. 276">2005, c. 276<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2005#000276#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2007 VA CH 715"><content><span normalizedCite="2007 Va. Ch. 715">2007, c. 715<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2007#000715#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2010 VA CH 47"><content><span normalizedCite="2010 Va. Ch. 47">2010, c. 47<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2010#000047#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PV20-004G-K2D7-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 46.2.</desig><title>MOTOR VEHICLES</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="subtitle"><heading><desig>SUBTITLE III.</desig><title>OPERATION</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 12.1.</desig><title>PARKING FOR PERSONS WITH DISABILITIES</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Healthcare Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NkUxMkVDQjJDOEY5NDVDQ0E5NTFEMTlDMjIwNzVERjc7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6N0U1NEQ5NkFBQjhENEUyMjhDMjM2MjRFQkVBOTFDODI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MkIwM0E1RTM4NkY5NEU4QjhBM0RCNzc5QjE4RkIzOEI</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NTVDMzIyNkJCMTRBNDI0NUJBOTlBOTYyMjQ0MDkyODU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QTJGRDdFQzgwODczNDI0NDgwMzEyM0JBOEQ2MUVDNjg</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Transportation Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RTYzRTk5RDVBQkQ2NDcwQzk2NTU3ODQ5OEE3NDlBNzk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Disabled Vehicles</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OTRCRkU4OUEzMkMwNDUzRTkzMTk4QTk1NzU1NTA1MDg7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RUI2RkNERjc3QTRCNEEyRkI5QkQwRTRFMzFBQkUxMjA</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Issuance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OUZBRDAyRDY3M0FCNDIwRUFFQkRDRjQ2RTQ2MzlBNTg7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Q0RCNjRFQjZDREJFNDlGNzk4NTJEODI1Q0ZBODBGRDI</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Medical Certificates</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjY3QTUzRTU4QkQzNEU2RjhCRTMwQTBDRUNCMzI2QTE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MTlGNDIzOTFCOTE4NDc1NEJGQUY0NUJCRUNDMDhEODg</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification><classificationGroup classificationScheme="indexing-terms"><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem score="90"><className>Transportation</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RTYzRTk5RDVBQkQ2NDcwQzk2NTU3ODQ5OEE3NDlBNzk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></classificationGroup></metadata></legislativeDoc>