<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#349#000064#     2#          428#">Va. Code Ann. § 64.2-428</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_64.2-428"/><heading><desig>§ 64.2-428.</desig><title>Distribution of assets by fiduciaries in satisfaction of pecuniary bequests or transfers in trust of pecuniary amount</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a"/><heading><desig>A.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Where a will or trust agreement authorizes or directs the fiduciary to satisfy wholly or partly in kind a pecuniary bequest or transfer in trust of a pecuniary amount, unless the instrument shall otherwise expressly provide, the assets selected by the fiduciary for that purpose shall be valued at their respective values on the date of their distribution.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b"/><heading><desig>B.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Whenever a fiduciary under the provisions of a will or other governing instrument is required to satisfy a pecuniary bequest or transfer in trust in favor of the testator's or donor's spouse and is authorized to satisfy such bequest or transfer by selection and distribution of assets in kind, and the will or other governing instrument further provides that the assets to be so distributed shall or may be valued by some standard other than their fair market value on the date of distribution, the fiduciary, unless the will or other governing instrument otherwise specifically directs, shall distribute assets, including cash, in a manner that is fairly representative of appreciation or depreciation in the value of all property available for distribution in satisfaction of such pecuniary bequest or transfer. This subsection shall not prevent a fiduciary from carrying out the provisions of the will or other governing instrument that require the fiduciary, in order to implement such a bequest or transfer, to distribute assets, including cash, having an aggregate fair market value at the date of distribution amounting to no less than the amount of the pecuniary bequest or transfer as finally determined for federal estate tax purposes.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c"/><heading><desig>C.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Any fiduciary having discretionary powers under a will or other governing instrument with respect to the selection of assets to be distributed in satisfaction of a pecuniary bequest or transfer in trust in favor of the testator's or donor's spouse shall be authorized to enter into agreements with the Commissioner of Internal Revenue of the U.S. Department of the Treasury and other taxing authorities requiring the fiduciary to exercise the fiduciary's discretion so that cash and other properties distributed in satisfaction of such bequest or transfer in trust will be fairly representative of the appreciation or depreciation in value of all property then available for distribution in satisfaction of such bequest or transfer in trust, and any such agreement heretofore entered into after April 1, 1964, is hereby validated. Any such fiduciary shall be authorized to enter into any other agreement not in conflict with the express terms of the will or other governing instrument that may be necessary or advisable in order to secure for federal estate tax purposes the appropriate marital deduction available under the Internal Revenue Code, and to do and perform all acts incident to securing such deduction.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d"/><heading><desig>D.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Where a will or trust agreement directs the fiduciary to satisfy a pecuniary or fractional bequest or transfer in trust of a pecuniary amount or fractional share in favor of the testator's or donor's spouse with amounts or assets having a value equal to the maximum marital deduction available under the Internal Revenue Code, the interest of such spouse shall vest immediately upon the testator's death in the case of a will, and upon the execution of the trust agreement in the case of a trust, regardless of when the exact amount of the bequest or transfer is finally determined.</p></bodyText></level><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p>Code 1950, § 64-71.2; 1966, c. 441; 1968, c. 656, § 64.1-74; 1978, c. 481; <citation normalizedCite="2012 VA CH 614"><content><span normalizedCite="2012 Va. Ch. 614">2012, c. 614<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2012#000614#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PVX0-004G-K0BS-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 64.2.</desig><title>WILLS, TRUSTS, AND FIDUCIARIES</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="subtitle"><heading><desig>SUBTITLE II.</desig><title>WILLS AND DECEDENTS' ESTATES</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 4.</desig><title>WILLS</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="article"><heading><desig>ARTICLE 3.</desig><title>CONSTRUCTION AND EFFECT.</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Governments</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjdEQjE4OUJDMzQxNDNEMEI0RTI1QUFCMzJENjEwRTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Fiduciaries</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RDRDQjYwNDkxREQ4NDE4Nzk4QzY0QTIyMzYzOTM0REQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjdEQjE4OUJDMzQxNDNEMEI0RTI1QUFCMzJENjEwRTA</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Tax Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OTNEM0E2OEE0RkQyNEY1MDhBQzdGMkQ4ODI4QTJDODE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NENDMDE3NzA0OEUzNEYwRDlGMUZFODYzMDhFMkQzRkM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MTZDRDdCMEZBNjE0NEMwMDhDMjAxOEU2ODc5OEE4QTU</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NzFFOTlEQTA2RUIyNDBDRDg1RjE0MTcyOUU1RURGQTk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDlFOUI3MDc5MEEzNDYzNDlEQzBDQjRGRERFNThDRjA</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification><classificationGroup classificationScheme="indexing-terms"><classification classificationScheme="legal"/></classificationGroup></metadata></legislativeDoc>