<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#349#000015#     2#         5158#">Va. Code Ann. § 15.2-5158</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_15.2-5158"/><heading><desig>§ 15.2-5158.</desig><title>Additional powers of community development authorities</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a"/><heading><desig>A.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Each community development authority created under this article, in addition to the powers provided in Article 3 (<citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 15.2-5110"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 15.2-5110">§ 15.2-5110<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000015#     2#         5110#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> et seq.) of Chapter 51 of this title, may:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Subject to any statutory or regulatory jurisdiction and permitting authority of all applicable governmental bodies and agencies having authority with respect to any area included therein, finance, fund, plan, establish, acquire, construct or reconstruct, enlarge, extend, equip, operate, and maintain the infrastructure improvements enumerated in the ordinance or resolution establishing the district, as necessary or desirable for development or redevelopment within or affecting the district or to meet the increased demands placed upon the locality as a result of development or redevelopment within or affecting the district, including, but not limited to:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_1_a"/><heading><desig>a.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Roads, bridges, parking facilities, curbs, gutters, sidewalks, traffic signals, storm water management and retention systems, gas and electric lines and street lights within or serving the district which meet or exceed the specifications of the locality in which the roads are located.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_1_b"/><heading><desig>b.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Parks and facilities for indoor and outdoor recreational, cultural and educational uses; entrance areas; security facilities; fencing and landscaping improvements throughout the district.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_1_c"/><heading><desig>c.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Fire prevention and control systems, including fire stations, water mains and plugs, fire trucks, rescue vehicles and other vehicles and equipment.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_1_d"/><heading><desig>d.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> School buildings and related structures, which may be leased, sold or donated to the school district, for use in the educational system when authorized by the local governing body and the school board.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_1_e"/><heading><desig>e.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Infrastructure and recreational facilities for age-restricted active adult communities, and any other necessary infrastructure improvements as provided above, with a minimum population approved under local zoning laws of 1,000 residents. Such development may include security facilities and systems or measures which control or restrict access to such community and its improvements.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Issue revenue bonds of the development authority as provided in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 15.2-5125"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 15.2-5125">§ 15.2-5125<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000015#     2#         5125#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, including but not limited to refunding bonds, subject to such limitation in amount, and terms and conditions regarding capitalized interest, reserve funds, contingent funds, and investment restrictions, as may be established in the ordinance or resolution establishing the district, for all costs associated with the improvements enumerated in subdivision 1 of this subsection. Such revenue bonds shall be payable solely from revenues received by the development authority. The revenue bonds issued by a development authority shall not require the consent of the locality, except where consent is specifically required by the provisions of the resolution authorizing the collection of revenues and/or the trust agreement securing the same, and shall not be deemed to constitute a debt, liability, or obligation of any other political subdivision, and shall not impact upon the debt capacity of any other political subdivision.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Request annually that the locality levy and collect a special tax on taxable real property within the development authority's jurisdiction to finance the services and facilities provided by the authority. Notwithstanding the provisions of Article 4 (<citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 58.1-3229"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 58.1-3229">§ 58.1-3229<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000058#     1#         3229#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> et seq.) of Chapter 32 of Title 58.1, any such special tax imposed by the locality shall be levied upon the assessed fair market value of the taxable real property. Unless requested by every property owner within the proposed district, the rate of the special tax shall not be more than $.25 per $ 100 of the assessed fair market value of any taxable real estate or the assessable value of taxable leasehold property as specified by <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 58.1-3203"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 58.1-3203">§ 58.1-3203<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000058#     1#         3203#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>. The proceeds of the special taxes collected shall be kept in a separate account and be used only for the purposes provided in this chapter. All revenues received by the locality from such special tax shall be paid over to the development authority for its use pursuant to this chapter subject to annual appropriation. No other funds of the locality shall be loaned or paid to the development authority without the prior approval of the local governing body.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_4"/><heading><desig>4.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Provide special services, including: garbage and trash removal and disposal, street cleaning, snow removal, extra security personnel and equipment, recreational management and supervision, and grounds keeping.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_5"/><heading><desig>5.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Finance the services and facilities it provides to abutting property within the district by special assessment thereon imposed by the local governing body. All assessments pursuant to this section shall be subject to the laws pertaining to assessments under Article 2 (§ 15.2-2404 et seq.) of Chapter 24; provided that any other provision of law notwithstanding, (i) the taxes or assessments shall not exceed the full cost of the improvements, including without limitation the legal, financial and other directly attributable costs of creating the district and the planning, designing, operating and financing of the improvements which include administration of the collection and payment of the assessments and reserve funds permitted by applicable law; (ii) the taxes or assessments may be imposed upon abutting land which is later subdivided in accordance with the terms of the ordinance forming the district, in amounts which do not exceed the peculiar benefits of the improvements to the abutting land as subdivided; and (iii) the taxes or assessments may be made subject to installment payments for up to 40 years in an amount calculated to cover principal, interest and administrative costs in connection with any financing by the authority, without a penalty for prepayment. Notwithstanding any other provision of law, any assessments made pursuant to this section may be made effective as a lien upon a specified date, by ordinance, but such assessments may not thereafter be modified in a manner inconsistent with the terms of the debt instruments financing the improvements. All assessments pursuant to this section may also be made subject to installment payments and other provisions allowed for local assessments under this section or under Article 2 of Chapter 24. All revenues received by the locality pursuant to any such special assessments which the locality elects to impose upon request of the development authority shall be paid over to the development authority for its use under this chapter, subject to annual appropriation, and may be used for no other purposes.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_6"/><heading><desig>6.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Fix, charge, and collect rates, fees, and charges for the use of, or the benefit derived from, the services and/or facilities provided, owned, operated, or financed by the authority benefiting property within the district. Such rates, fees, and charges may be charged to and collected by such persons and in such manner as the authority may determine from (i) any person contracting for the services or using the facilities and/or (ii) the owners, tenants, or customers of the real estate and improvements that are served by, or benefit from the use of, any such services or facilities, in such manner as shall be authorized by the authority in connection with the provision of such services or facilities.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_7"/><heading><desig>7.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Purchase development rights that will be dedicated as easements for conservation, open space or other purposes pursuant to the Open-Space Land Act (<citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 10.1-1700"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 10.1-1700">§ 10.1-1700<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000010#     1#         1700#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> et seq.). For purposes of this subdivision, "development rights" means the level and quantity of development permitted by the zoning ordinance expressed in terms of housing units per acre, floor area ratio or equivalent local measure. An authority shall not use the power of condemnation to acquire development rights.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_8"/><heading><desig>8.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Subject to any statutory or regulatory jurisdiction and permitting authority of all applicable governmental bodies and agencies having authority with respect to any area included therein, finance and fund the acquisition of land within the district. All financing authority and methods provided by subsections 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, and 7 shall be permitted for the acquisition of land as provided herein.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_9"/><heading><desig>9.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Any special tax levied pursuant to subdivision 3 and any special assessment imposed pursuant to subdivision 5, whether previously or hereafter levied or imposed, constitute a lien on real estate ranking on parity with real estate taxes, and any such delinquent special tax or delinquent special assessment may be collected in accordance with the procedures set forth in Article 4 (<citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 58.1-3965"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 58.1-3965">§ 58.1-3965<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000058#     1#         3965#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> et seq.) of Chapter 39 of Title 58.1, provided that the enforcement of the lien for any special assessment under subdivision 5 made subject to installment payments shall be limited to the installment payments due or past due at the time the lien is enforced through sale in accordance with Article 4 (<citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 58.1-3965"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 58.1-3965">§ 58.1-3965<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000058#     1#         3965#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> et seq.) of Chapter 39 of Title 58.1, and any sale to enforce payment of any delinquent taxes, assessments, or other levies shall not extinguish installment payments that are not yet due.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b"/><heading><desig>B.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Nothing contained in this chapter shall relieve the local governing body of its general obligations to provide services and facilities to the district to the same extent as would otherwise be provided were the district not formed.</p></bodyText></level><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p><citation normalizedCite="1993 VA CH 850"><content><span normalizedCite="1993 Va. Ch. 850">1993, c. 850<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1993#000850#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, § 15.1-1250.03; <citation normalizedCite="1995 VA CH 402"><content><span normalizedCite="1995 Va. Ch. 402">1995, c. 402<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1995#000402#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1997 VA CH 363"><content><span normalizedCite="1997 Va. Ch. 363">1997, cc. 363<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1997#000363#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1997 VA CH 587"><content><span normalizedCite="1997 Va. Ch. 587">587<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1997#000587#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2000 VA CH 724"><content><span normalizedCite="2000 Va. Ch. 724">2000, cc. 724<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2000#000724#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2000 VA CH 747"><content><span normalizedCite="2000 Va. Ch. 747">747<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2000#000747#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2004 VA CH 637"><content><span normalizedCite="2004 Va. Ch. 637">2004, c. 637<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2004#000637#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2005 VA CH 547"><content><span normalizedCite="2005 Va. Ch. 547">2005, c. 547<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2005#000547#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2009 VA CH 473"><content><span normalizedCite="2009 Va. Ch. 473">2009, c. 473<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2009#000473#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2015 VA CH 39"><content><span normalizedCite="2015 Va. Ch. 39">2015, c. 39<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2015#000039#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PV30-004G-K2NJ-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 15.2.</desig><title>COUNTIES, CITIES AND TOWNS</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="subtitle"><heading><desig>SUBTITLE IV.</desig><title>OTHER GOVERNMENTAL ENTITIES</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 51.</desig><title>VIRGINIA WATER AND WASTE AUTHORITIES ACT</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="article"><heading><desig>ARTICLE 6.</desig><title>COMMUNITY DEVELOPMENT AUTHORITIES</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Contracts Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QzY0RTZFMzE0RjkwNDdFQUI5M0U5N0ZFMjYyREMyQzU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Legal Titles</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MkRFNEM1NDVDREQ1NDhFQzgzREY3MzU4QUQxNzBFOEI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjI4MTgxNTUxNDFDNEU1MUIxODlGQjgwMjYwNkQ2RDg</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Education Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDkzNUEzQzFBNEZBNEFBREIxNDM5MTc1MUU5QjI4MTY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NjA2NDg3NzhDRjYxNDNFMTk0NkY5OTdFRjhGMjBGMUY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QTU5MTJDNDBCQkU0NEY2MEIyREVGRkM0Qzg1NjY5RTQ</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NUJBMkUxQjc0M0QyNEJFQkEwQjQ4MDMzMEUxNTBGQTE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjZBQUM2RjM4QkI4NDlFMkFCNTBDMzJGNDg0MTgxOUU</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Energy &amp; Utilities Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OUUzODAyRDk1QzVFNEZGMEJDM0RGMDYxOTlEMEEzRDA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NEFGODVDQ0YxOEU1NEU5OThGMDAzNzk5RDlENjc0MTY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RjFGM0IxMEExQzRGNEM3OEI0Mjg2QzVGMDlENDk3QUQ</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Environmental Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NzFDRDYyNkI2QjhBNDg3NTkyRjRDRkZEQjlCRkRBQzM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Transportation</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RjNEOUYyRTIzRUQwNERDRUI0QkZEMTBENjBCRjVGRDg7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NzY4MTI1MkI1NTcyNEM1NEI5MEQyNjc1QTQzOEI4QzY</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Governments</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjdEQjE4OUJDMzQxNDNEMEI0RTI1QUFCMzJENjEwRTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Community Redevelopment</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NUMwM0U5RjhBRkQ1NEQ5Qzk0RDk2QUJDNEU2NTVCQjE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MEY3NUIxODI2RjU2NEY0NzgwMDQyNjFDMEQ1QUExRjM</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Finance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjMzOTBBRTg2MUVDNDdDNUE1M0QxNDk1RERCNjNCN0I7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Njg1MkM3RkYyNzIxNEVFRkJFMTI2NUM4NUU1ODdEM0Q</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Financing</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Q0QyN0IxRDI1MTE0NDQ3NkEzMzZCMTBCMkE2QkM3RTM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MEY3NUIxODI2RjU2NEY0NzgwMDQyNjFDMEQ1QUExRjM</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Public Health &amp; Welfare Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDYwRTY1MDg3MTk5NDUyNkFFRDI1RjJBRERGQ0UxNzI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Community &amp; Economic Development</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MEUxOUMwOTFCRDdFNEVFOUJFMjE2RDE0NERDOTM0QjY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDZDNTZENUNCRjVBNEY4OEIyQzVBNjRDRTcyOEQ4NDQ</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Real Property Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QUUyRTcxRURBNEY2NEE2MDk3QzBCNzRDOEY0NTZDQzk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Construction Loans</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RDNGMDlENjQ4NUYyNEM0MEIxRTAwMjAyRTdFRUNBRkY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MTY1MzRERDhBMDZCNDFBMDk0QUEwRjcyN0ZFNEY3REM</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6N0FCNUNDRTZCRDg5NDc4QjhBQjYyMzczQzVDMDZENjU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NjkyMjE3M0YxQTQ1NEU2MzgxNTdFRDYzRjBFN0Q4MDU</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Tax Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OTNEM0E2OEE0RkQyNEY1MDhBQzdGMkQ4ODI4QTJDODE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Assessments</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjIwOUNEOUU1RUQ5NEU3OTkyNUQxRjJFNkIzQjY3OTQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjkxRkVDMkNDMjBGNDdFMkI1RDQ3Nzk4QjgwOTBGQjU</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Collection of Taxes</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RTg5OTkxQ0U0RjIwNEY4Qjg2MkQ1OTZCRTM2RDY4MTM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjkxRkVDMkNDMjBGNDdFMkI1RDQ3Nzk4QjgwOTBGQjU</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QzQzNERBRTAxRDI0NDg4OUI1NzY1RjU4Q0IzRDVDODc7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjkxRkVDMkNDMjBGNDdFMkI1RDQ3Nzk4QjgwOTBGQjU</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MEMzQzdEM0Q2NEEyNDg5RDhDMEE3NDAwMDNGOUU2MkM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MEI0QjM4RDg1M0IxNDk1RDkwOTVGMEMxRTQxQTg1ODU</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RTc0QzJDRUM0OTI1NDkyQTgyQzExM0RFMDAwRTAzOEI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RUE2N0VFNDM5OUY4NENCQjlDQjQ1NjdGMkU4NkFFREQ</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Tax Liens</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NzlBODVCRkY5RUYwNDRBMkI1QjIxMjYzMTYwMDgwRkY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjkxRkVDMkNDMjBGNDdFMkI1RDQ3Nzk4QjgwOTBGQjU</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Tax Liens</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjJGOEQ1RjczMkRDNDZFRjlCQzdDQ0NBMzIwRTlGNEM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RUE2N0VFNDM5OUY4NENCQjlDQjQ1NjdGMkU4NkFFREQ</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Valuation of Real Property</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MTBBN0VCQThGOUZENEE4RThEQzAxMUM2QTRCNUU4NjM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MEI0QjM4RDg1M0IxNDk1RDkwOTVGMEMxRTQxQTg1ODU</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Transportation Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RTYzRTk5RDVBQkQ2NDcwQzk2NTU3ODQ5OEE3NDlBNzk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Street Cleaning</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6M0M2RDFDNTUwREE5NDU2Q0FDNkE5MUVFNzM3QzcyOUE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjVCODE3RDNEMENDNDkxRjg5MzBBNTJFQkNCRDlFOEU</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification><classificationGroup classificationScheme="indexing-terms"><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem score="90"><className>Governments</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjdEQjE4OUJDMzQxNDNEMEI0RTI1QUFCMzJENjEwRTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></classificationGroup></metadata></legislativeDoc>