<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#123#000030#       101#">Va. Code Ann. § 30-101</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_30-101"/><heading><desig>§ 30-101.</desig><title>Definitions</title></heading><bodyText><p>As used in this chapter, unless the context requires a different meaning:</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Advisory agency"</emphasis> means any board, commission, committee or post which does not exercise any sovereign power or duty, but is appointed by a governmental agency or officer or is created by law for the purpose of making studies or recommendations, or advising or consulting with a governmental agency.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Business"</emphasis> means a corporation, partnership, sole proprietorship, firm, enterprise, franchise, association, trust or foundation, or any other individual or entity carrying on a business or profession, whether or not for profit.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Candidate"</emphasis> means a person who seeks or campaigns for election to the General Assembly in a general, primary, or special election and who is qualified to have his name placed on the ballot for the office. The candidate shall become subject to the provisions of this section upon the filing of a statement of qualification pursuant to <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 24.2-501"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 24.2-501">§ 24.2-501<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000024#     2#          501#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>. The State Board of Elections shall notify each such candidate of the provisions of this chapter.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Contract"</emphasis> means any agreement to which a governmental agency is a party, or any agreement on behalf of a governmental agency that involves the payment of money appropriated by the General Assembly or a political subdivision, whether or not such agreement is executed in the name of the Commonwealth, or some political subdivision thereof. "Contract" includes a subcontract only when the contract of which it is a part is with the legislator's own governmental agency.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Council"</emphasis> means the Virginia Conflict of Interest and Ethics Advisory Council established in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 30-355"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 30 -355">§ 30-355<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#123#000030#       355#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Financial institution"</emphasis> means any bank, trust company, savings institution, industrial loan association, consumer finance company, credit union, broker-dealer as defined in subsection A of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 13.1-501"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 13.1-501">§ 13.1-501<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000013#     1#          501#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, or investment company or advisor registered under the federal Investment Advisors Act or Investment Company Act of 1940.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Gift"</emphasis> means any gratuity, favor, discount, entertainment, hospitality, loan, forbearance, or other item having monetary value. It includes services as well as gifts of transportation, lodgings and meals, whether provided in-kind, by purchase of a ticket, payment in advance, or reimbursement after the expense has been incurred. "Gift" does not include (i) any offer of a ticket, coupon, or other admission or pass unless the ticket, coupon, admission, or pass is used; (ii) honorary degrees; (iii) any athletic, merit, or need-based scholarship or any other financial aid awarded by a public or private school, institution of higher education, or other educational program pursuant to such school, institution, or program's financial aid standards and procedures applicable to the general public; (iv) a campaign contribution properly received and reported pursuant to Chapter 9.3 (<citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 24.2-945"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 24.2-945">§ 24.2-945<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000024#     2#          945#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> et seq.) of Title 24.2; (v) any gift related to the private profession or occupation of a legislator or of a member of his immediate family; (vi) food or beverages consumed while attending an event at which the filer is performing official duties related to his public service; (vii) food and beverages received at or registration or attendance fees waived for any event at which the filer is a featured speaker, presenter, or lecturer; (viii) unsolicited awards of appreciation or recognition in the form of a plaque, trophy, wall memento, or similar item that is given in recognition of public, civic, charitable, or professional service; (ix) a devise or inheritance; (x) travel disclosed pursuant to the Campaign Finance Disclosure Act (<citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 24.2-945"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 24.2-945">§ 24.2-945<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000024#     2#          945#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> et seq.); (xi) travel paid for or provided by the government of the United States, any of its territories, or any state or any political subdivision of such state; (xii) travel provided to facilitate attendance by a legislator at a regular or special session of the General Assembly, a meeting of a legislative committee or commission, or a national conference where attendance is approved by the House Committee on Rules or its Chairman or the Senate Committee on Rules or its Chairman; (xiii) travel related to an official meeting of the Commonwealth, its political subdivisions, or any board, commission, authority, or other entity, or any charitable organization established pursuant to <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="26 USC 501"><content><span normalizedCite="26 U.S.C. 501">§ 501(c)(3) of the Internal Revenue Code<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#29854#1127#00000000501#1#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> affiliated with such entity, to which such person has been appointed or elected or is a member by virtue of his office or employment; (xiv) gifts with a value of less than $ 20; or (xv) gifts from relatives or personal friends. For the purpose of this definition, "relative" means the donee's spouse, child, uncle, aunt, niece, nephew, or first cousin; a person to whom the donee is engaged to be married; the donee's or his spouse's parent, grandparent, grandchild, brother, sister, step-parent, step-grandparent, step-grandchild, step-brother, or step-sister; or the donee's brother's or sister's spouse. For the purpose of this definition, "personal friend" does not include any person that the filer knows or has reason to know is (a) a lobbyist registered pursuant to Article 3 (<citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 2.2-418"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 2.2-418">§ 2.2-418<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000002#     2#          418#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> et seq.) of Chapter 4 of Title 2.2 or (b) a lobbyist's principal as defined in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 2.2-419"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 2.2-419">§ 2.2-419<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000002#     2#          419#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Governmental agency"</emphasis> means each component part of the legislative, executive or judicial branches of state and local government, including each office, department, authority, post, commission, committee, and each institution or board created by law to exercise some regulatory or sovereign power or duty as distinguished from purely advisory powers or duties.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Immediate family"</emphasis> means (i) a spouse and (ii) any other person who resides in the same household as the legislator and who is a dependent of the legislator.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Legislator"</emphasis> means a member of the General Assembly.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Personal interest"</emphasis> means a financial benefit or liability accruing to a legislator or to a member of his immediate family. Such interest shall exist by reason of (i) ownership in a business if the ownership interest exceeds three percent of the total equity of the business; (ii) annual income that exceeds, or may reasonably be anticipated to exceed, $ 5,000 from ownership in real or personal property or a business; (iii) salary, other compensation, fringe benefits, or benefits from the use of property, or any combination thereof, paid or provided by a business or governmental agency that exceeds, or may reasonably be anticipated to exceed, $ 5,000 annually; (iv) ownership of real or personal property if the interest exceeds $ 5,000 in value and excluding ownership in a business, income, or salary, other compensation, fringe benefits or benefits from the use of property; (v) personal liability incurred or assumed on behalf of a business if the liability exceeds three percent of the asset value of the business; or (vi) an option for ownership of a business or real or personal property if the ownership interest will consist of clause (i) or (iv).</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Personal interest in a contract"</emphasis> means a personal interest that a legislator has in a contract with a governmental agency, whether due to his being a party to the contract or due to a personal interest in a business that is a party to the contract.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Personal interest in a transaction"</emphasis> means a personal interest of a legislator in any matter considered by the General Assembly. Such personal interest exists when an officer or employee or a member of his immediate family has a personal interest in property or a business, or represents or provides services to any individual or business and such property, business or represented or served individual or business (i) is the subject of the transaction or (ii) may realize a reasonably foreseeable direct or indirect benefit or detriment as a result of the action of the agency considering the transaction. A "personal interest in a transaction" exists only if the legislator or member of his immediate family or an individual or business represented or served by the legislator is affected in a way that is substantially different from the general public or from persons comprising a profession, occupation, trade, business or other comparable and generally recognizable class or group of which he or the individual or business he represents or serves is a member.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Transaction"</emphasis> means any matter considered by the General Assembly, whether in a committee, subcommittee, or other entity of the General Assembly or before the General Assembly itself, on which official action is taken or contemplated.</p></bodyText><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p>1987, Sp. Sess., c. 1, § 2.1-639.31; <citation normalizedCite="1994 VA CH 724"><content><span normalizedCite="1994 Va. Ch. 724">1994, c. 724<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1994#000724#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1996 VA CH 77"><content><span normalizedCite="1996 Va. Ch. 77">1996, c. 77<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1996#000077#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2001 VA CH 844"><content><span normalizedCite="2001 Va. Ch. 844">2001, c. 844<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2001#000844#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2014 VA CH 792"><content><span normalizedCite="2014 Va. Ch. 792">2014, cc. 792<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2014#000792#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2014 VA CH 804"><content><span normalizedCite="2014 Va. Ch. 804">804<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2014#000804#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2015 VA CH 763"><content><span normalizedCite="2015 Va. Ch. 763">2015, cc. 763<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2015#000763#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2015 VA CH 777"><content><span normalizedCite="2015 Va. Ch. 777">777<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2015#000777#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2016 VA CH 773"><content><span normalizedCite="2016 Va. Ch. 773">2016, cc. 773<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2016#000773#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2016 VA CH 774"><content><span normalizedCite="2016 Va. Ch. 774">774<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2016#000774#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PWD0-004G-K36T-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 30.</desig><title>GENERAL ASSEMBLY</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 13.</desig><title>GENERAL ASSEMBLY CONFLICTS OF INTERESTS ACT</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="article"><heading><desig>ARTICLE 1.</desig><title>GENERAL PROVISIONS</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Banking Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjQyMUFCOUJBNURBNEFDREE3MTNCNDk5QkQ4NUM3RjI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Conflicts of Interest</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RkY5Nzc3RjcyRDJGNDM3QjlCOEU4NEFFOTUwMEREREM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OTIwRkFGMEQzODhCNDk2RUIzQzc3MjdBOUNEMzJGMzc</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Federal Credit Unions</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MzU5NTEzOTI2M0JCNDhBOTgzNzFERUQ3OUYzNTJFMTk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RTc3MUQ5Rjg4MjYzNENDQzk2QjQ0NzA5RjFDNzY0RDk</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NUVDRTQwRDQxRTlBNDhBQzk5REVDMzA2OTY2OTdBRjc7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RTc3MUQ5Rjg4MjYzNENDQzk2QjQ0NzA5RjFDNzY0RDk</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Investment Company Act</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RUFCMEJBODBDMDRENEQ4NDkwNTlCNDg4Q0FFQjFGNzI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDE1NTFGNzBDNTIyNDBEQUE2MkYwNkNCOTAzNjNGNzA</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Federal Credit Unions</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MzU5NTEzOTI2M0JCNDhBOTgzNzFERUQ3OUYzNTJFMTk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjQyMUFCOUJBNURBNEFDREE3MTNCNDk5QkQ4NUM3RjI</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Investment Company Act</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RUFCMEJBODBDMDRENEQ4NDkwNTlCNDg4Q0FFQjFGNzI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDE1NTFGNzBDNTIyNDBEQUE2MkYwNkNCOTAzNjNGNzA</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjA4OEVGODBENzY4NDcxM0IyQzA1OTEwQzVDODRBOUE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RjI3QTdDNjdBOUE1NDg2MTk5Q0ZGNEQ1MDUyRjBFN0Q7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Njg2NjY4ODFGMkM4NDBERjg2ODkwNEMyNTM4QTgyQjk</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Criminal Law &amp; Procedure</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NEU0RkE1OUQwNUQwNDgxODhEODZCMjkzOTg3NThBNzk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Elements</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6N0M5OTIwNEFBMDRFNEUyM0ExNDM1NzIzNkVEQzIyMkU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUEzNjQ1N0ZENDY1NEM4MkFFQ0E0NUUwRDA2NkI2NkY</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NEE0ODk3QjNEODNDNDdBNEI4ODRGRDZCNjI5QUFBMjY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUEzNjQ1N0ZENDY1NEM4MkFFQ0E0NUUwRDA2NkI2NkY</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Education Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDkzNUEzQzFBNEZBNEFBREIxNDM5MTc1MUU5QjI4MTY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Athletic Scholarships</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RDJBRTc3QTBFOUJBNDBENTg5MEY5MjBFMDU5NDEyOTY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Njk4RUMyMDg4ODMwNDIwNUI1NEQwMDE0OUU3REYyOTM</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Estate, Gift &amp; Trust Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OENGNTY0MEQ2RTU2NDA2NTk4QjcyNzI2NTBERUU3NUI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NTM0MTFFRkQ3M0E2NEQwREFFMzc3QjBDQjhEQjZEOTM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RkJCNEFGNEQyOEM1NEZBQ0ExREJFNUQyMDM5N0U2Rjg</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Governments</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjdEQjE4OUJDMzQxNDNEMEI0RTI1QUFCMzJENjEwRTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Administrative Boards</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QTYwRUFCMDc5MzQ5NDEyREFEQkU2NkE2MjRGQTlCNzY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Njg1MkM3RkYyNzIxNEVFRkJFMTI2NUM4NUU1ODdEM0Q</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Finance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjMzOTBBRTg2MUVDNDdDNUE1M0QxNDk1RERCNjNCN0I7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Njg1MkM3RkYyNzIxNEVFRkJFMTI2NUM4NUU1ODdEM0Q</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Securities Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RkFFMTQ3ODhCRDYyNDkyN0IwQkEyQzRCRDlFMEM5ODc7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Activities</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QTcxQkI4NjMyMjc0NDUxQjgwNDEwNTlFNzhGNkQ3QzQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NEZBNjUwRkEwQjJGNDgzQzlEMzMyNEE1RDAyOTY4RkE</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Adviser Eligibility</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjAzQUEyREY1NDRGNEEzNTg5RjIzNDI2QjkyNzk2QjU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NEZBNjUwRkEwQjJGNDgzQzlEMzMyNEE1RDAyOTY4RkE</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Definitions</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDFBOEVBMDJCODU3NDg0RDgxNkQ5MDU3MjAxRjBERUY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NEZBNjUwRkEwQjJGNDgzQzlEMzMyNEE1RDAyOTY4RkE</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Exemptions, Recordkeeping &amp; Registration</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjkwNDgyRTNBNTNDNDlEMzgxNUY5NTcwRTA3MzQxMjY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6ODQ2M0Q5NUExRUZENEY2NDkzMzlDMDVFNjFCNTY3MTQ</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NTBGQTg1QUM3RDIwNDI2NjhCNjFBNjZDNkYwMzE5QkQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NEZBNjUwRkEwQjJGNDgzQzlEMzMyNEE1RDAyOTY4RkE</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Unregistered Company Transactions</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6M0VGM0UyRDEzRTZFNDYwMEE0RDQwNkREOTI2MDkxNDg7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NEZBNjUwRkEwQjJGNDgzQzlEMzMyNEE1RDAyOTY4RkE</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Torts</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDAwOEM2NTEzQkVDNEI4NzlGMEZERUEyRjQwODM4Njg7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Comparative Fault &amp; Contributory Negligence</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjA2QjlGN0Q5NDIwNDQ3NDg5NzU5MzVGNjYwOTEzNDk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MTEzNjUzREVEOURGNDE3MEEwQURENDBCMTBDOUVBNEI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification><classificationGroup classificationScheme="indexing-terms"><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem score="90"><className>Governments</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjdEQjE4OUJDMzQxNDNEMEI0RTI1QUFCMzJENjEwRTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></classificationGroup></metadata></legislativeDoc>