<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#349#000054#     1#         2353#">Va. Code Ann. § 54.1-2353</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_54.1-2353"/><heading><desig>§ 54.1-2353.</desig><title>Protection of the interests of associations; appointment of receiver for common interest community manager</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a"/><heading><desig>A.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A common interest community manager owes a fiduciary duty to the associations to which it provides management services with respect to the manager's handling the funds or the records of each association. All funds deposited with the common interest community manager shall be handled in a fiduciary capacity and shall be kept in a separate fiduciary trust account or accounts in an FDIC-insured financial institution separate from the assets of the common interest community manager. The funds shall be the property of the association and shall be segregated for each depository in the records of the common interest community manager in a manner that permits the funds to be identified on an association basis. All records having administrative or fiscal value to the association that a common interest community manager holds, maintains, compiles, or generates on behalf of a common interest community are the property of the association. A common interest community manager may retain and dispose of association records in accordance with a policy contained in the contract between the common interest community manager and the association. Within a reasonable time after a written request for any such records, the common interest community manager shall provide copies of the requested records to the association at the association's expense. The common interest community manager shall return all association records that it retains and any originals of legal instruments or official documents that are in the possession of the common interest community manager to the association within a reasonable time after termination of the contract for management services without additional cost to the association. Records maintained in electronic format may be returned in such format.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b"/><heading><desig>B.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> If the Board has reasonable cause to believe that a common interest community manager is unable to properly discharge its fiduciary responsibilities to an association to which it provides management services, the Board may submit an ex parte petition to the circuit court of the city or county wherein the common interest community manager maintains an office or is doing business for the issuance of an order authorizing the immediate inspection by and production to representatives of the petitioner of any records, documents, and physical or other evidence belonging to the subject common interest community manager. The court may issue such order without notice to the common interest community manager if the petition, supported by affidavit of the petitioner and such other evidence as the court may require, shows reasonable cause to believe that such action is required to prevent immediate loss of property of one or more of the associations to which the subject common interest community manager provides management services. The court may also temporarily enjoin further activity by the common interest community manager and take such further action as shall be necessary to conserve, protect, and disburse the funds involved, including the appointment of a receiver. The papers filed with the court pursuant to this subsection shall be placed under seal.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c"/><heading><desig>C.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> If the Board has reasonable cause to believe that a common interest community manager is unable to properly discharge its fiduciary responsibilities to an association to which it provides management services, the Board may file a petition with the circuit court of the county or city wherein the subject common interest community manager maintains an office or is doing business. The petition may seek the following relief: (i) an injunction prohibiting the withdrawal of any bank deposits or the disposition of any other assets belonging to or subject to the control of the subject common interest community manager; and (ii) the appointment of a receiver for all or part of the funds or property of the subject common interest community manager. The subject common interest community manager shall be given notice of the time and place of the hearing on the petition and an opportunity to offer evidence. The court, in its discretion, may require a receiver appointed pursuant to this section to post bond, with or without surety. The papers filed with the court under this subsection shall be placed under seal until such time as the court grants an injunction or appoints a receiver. The court may issue an injunction, appoint a receiver, or provide such other relief as the court may consider proper if, after a hearing, the court finds that such relief is necessary or appropriate to prevent loss of property of one or more of the associations to which the subject common interest community manager provides management services.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d"/><heading><desig>D.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> In any proceeding under subsection C, any person or entity known to the Board to be indebted to or having in his possession property, real or personal, belonging to or subject to the control of the subject common interest community manager's business and which property the Board reasonably believes may become part of the receivership assets, shall be served with a copy of the petition and notice of the time and place of the hearing.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_e"/><heading><desig>E.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The court shall describe the powers and duties of the receiver in its appointing order, which may be amended from time to time. The receiver shall, unless otherwise ordered by the court in the appointing order, (i) prepare and file with the Board a list of all associations managed by the subject common interest community manager; (ii) notify in writing all of the associations to which the subject common interest community manager provides management services of the appointment, and take whatever action the receiver deems appropriate to protect the interests of the associations until such time as the associations have had an opportunity to obtain a successor common interest community manager; (iii) facilitate the transfer of records and information to such successor common interest community manager; (iv) identify and take control of all bank accounts, including without limitation trust and operating accounts, over which the subject common interest community manager had signatory authority in connection with its management business; (v) prepare and submit an accounting of receipts and disbursements and account balances of all funds under the receiver's control for submission to the court within four months of the appointment and annually thereafter until the receivership is terminated by the court; (vi) attempt to collect any accounts receivable related to the subject common interest community manager's business; (vii) identify and attempt to recover any assets wrongfully diverted from the subject common interest community manager's business, or assets acquired with funds wrongfully diverted from the subject common interest community manager's business; (viii) terminate the subject common interest community manager's business; (ix) reduce to cash all of the assets of the subject common interest community manager; (x) determine the nature and amount of all claims of creditors of the subject common interest community manager, including associations to which the subject common interest community manager provided management services; and (xi) prepare and file with the court a report of such assets and claims proposing a plan for the distribution of funds in the receivership to such creditors in accordance with the provisions of subsection F.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_f"/><heading><desig>F.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Upon the court's approval of the receiver's report referenced in subsection E, at a hearing after such notice as the court may require to creditors, the receiver shall distribute the assets of the common interest community manager and funds in the receivership first to clients whose funds were or ought to have been held in a fiduciary capacity by the subject common interest community manager, then to the receiver for fees, costs, and expenses awarded pursuant to subsection G, and thereafter to the creditors of the subject common interest community manager, and then to the subject common interest community manager or its successors in interest.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_g"/><heading><desig>G.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A receiver appointed pursuant to this section shall be entitled, upon proper application to the court in which the appointment was made, to recover an award of reasonable fees, costs, and expenses. If there are not sufficient nonfiduciary funds to pay the award, then the shortfall shall be paid by the Common Interest Community Management Recovery Fund as a cost of administering the Fund pursuant to <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 55-530.1"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 55 -530.1">§ 55-530.1<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#123#000055#     530.1#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, to the extent that the said Fund has funds available. The Fund shall have a claim against the subject common interest community manager for the amount paid.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_h"/><heading><desig>H.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The court may determine whether any assets under the receiver's control should be returned to the subject common interest community manager.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_i"/><heading><desig>I.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> If the Board shall find that any common interest community manager is insolvent, that its merger into another common interest community manager is desirable for the protection of the associations to which such common interest community manager provides management services, and that an emergency exists, and, if the board of directors of such insolvent common interest community manager shall approve a plan of merger of such common interest community manager into another common interest community manager, compliance with the requirements of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 13.1-718"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 13.1-718">§ 13.1-718<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000013#     1#          718#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> shall be dispensed with as to such insolvent common interest community manager and the approval by the Board of such plan of merger shall be the equivalent of approval by the holders of more than two-thirds of the outstanding shares of such insolvent common interest community manager for all purposes of Article 12 (<citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 13.1-715.1"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 13.1-715.1">§ 13.1-715.1<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000013#     1#        715.1#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> et seq.) of Chapter 9 of Title 13.1. If the Board finds that a common interest community manager is insolvent, that the acquisition of its assets by another common interest community manager is in the best interests of the associations to which such common interest community manager provides management services, and that an emergency exists, it may, with the consent of the boards of directors of both common interest community managers as to the terms and conditions of such transfer, including the assumption of all or certain liabilities, enter an order transferring some or all of the assets of such insolvent common interest community manager to such other common interest community manager, and no compliance with the provisions of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 13.1-723"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 13.1-723">§§ 13.1-723<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000013#     1#          723#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> and <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 13.1-724"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 13.1-724">13.1-724<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000013#     1#          724#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> shall be required, nor shall <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 13.1-730"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 13.1-730">§§ 13.1-730<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000013#     1#          730#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> through <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 13.1-741"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 13.1-741">13.1-741<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000013#     1#          741#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> be applicable to such transfer. In the case either of such a merger or of such a sale of assets, the Board shall provide that prompt notice of its finding of insolvency and of the merger or sale of assets be sent to the stockholders of record of the insolvent common interest community manager for the purpose of providing such shareholders an opportunity to challenge the finding that the common interest community manager is insolvent. The relevant books and records of such insolvent common interest community manager shall remain intact and be made available to such shareholders for a period of 30 days after such notice is sent. The Board's finding of insolvency shall become final if a hearing before the Board is not requested by any such shareholder within such 30-day period. If, after such hearing, the Board finds that such common interest community manager was solvent, it shall rescind its order entered pursuant to this subsection and the merger or transfer of assets shall be rescinded. But if, after such hearing, the Board finds that such common interest community manager was insolvent, its order shall be final.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_j"/><heading><desig>J.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The provisions of this chapter are declared to be remedial. The purpose of this chapter is to protect the interests of associations adversely affected by common interest community managers who have breached their fiduciary duty. The provisions of this chapter shall be liberally administered in order to protect those interests and thereby the public's interest in the quality of management services provided by Virginia common interest community managers.</p></bodyText></level><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p><citation normalizedCite="2008 VA CH 851"><content><span normalizedCite="2008 Va. Ch. 851">2008, cc. 851<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2008#000851#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2008 VA CH 871"><content><span normalizedCite="2008 Va. Ch. 871">871<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2008#000871#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2011 VA CH 334"><content><span normalizedCite="2011 Va. Ch. 334">2011, cc. 334<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2011#000334#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2011 VA CH 605"><content><span normalizedCite="2011 Va. Ch. 605">605<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2011#000605#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PVK0-004G-K19K-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 54.1.</desig><title>PROFESSIONS AND OCCUPATIONS</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="subtitle"><heading><desig>SUBTITLE II.</desig><title>PROFESSIONS AND OCCUPATIONS REGULATED BY THE DEPARTMENT OF PROFESSIONAL AND OCCUPATIONAL REGULATION AND BOARDS WITHIN THE DEPARTMENT</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 23.3.</desig><title>COMMON INTEREST COMMUNITIES</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Civil Procedure</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MzUxNjJDMEQ5N0YwNDMzM0JDMjEzM0UzOTYzMzI3OTU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Appointment of Receivers</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RTBFM0VDMEU5RjRBNDRCM0I1OTEyNUE1RDZCRTU1RTk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NjhGMDdBOTgwNEU1NEU4Mzk0NTRGRkZEMUI5OTI1OEE</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Duties of Receivers</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QUVERDk4M0MzRjc5NDk2RThDQTIyREI1OUNDMUVEMUE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NjhGMDdBOTgwNEU1NEU4Mzk0NTRGRkZEMUI5OTI1OEE</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RjBGMURCNjIxMzhDNDdCMTkyM0NFNzRGNDQ4REFCMjk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NEExRkUyMUYxQThBNDNDMDg4MzBBNjFCMENGMjVGRjI</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OEUzMEY1NDc0QUFBNDdFRkE3NjQ3MkRENTg4Nzg2OTE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NjhGMDdBOTgwNEU1NEU4Mzk0NTRGRkZEMUI5OTI1OEE</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Powers of Receivers</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6ODMzNDBEQTc5NjdDNDE2NEFGNEU1MjZDMDEyNDEwQzY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NjhGMDdBOTgwNEU1NEU4Mzk0NTRGRkZEMUI5OTI1OEE</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Preliminary &amp; Temporary Injunctions</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OEVGRDY3MENGNzU0NDM5MzlFODczNUY4NUQxMTE3NDg7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RTg4NzU0QUVDMEFGNEE2NzhCNzQyMDM5RjQ3NTRDMDM</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Termination of Receivership</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6REQ1RkVDRjEyQjBBNDE5QUFCRTcxNkE3NkZDRkMyOTE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NjhGMDdBOTgwNEU1NEU4Mzk0NTRGRkZEMUI5OTI1OEE</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Contracts Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QzY0RTZFMzE0RjkwNDdFQUI5M0U5N0ZFMjYyREMyQzU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Fiduciary Responsibilities</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6N0FEQzAxRUI5N0MxNDMwOUI5MkRCMTIyRjlEMTU2MDQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NENFMTEyRkM1NTVBNDRCMDgwQTEyRjk1OTcwNjUwNUQ</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Governments</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjdEQjE4OUJDMzQxNDNEMEI0RTI1QUFCMzJENjEwRTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Administrative Boards</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QTYwRUFCMDc5MzQ5NDEyREFEQkU2NkE2MjRGQTlCNzY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Njg1MkM3RkYyNzIxNEVFRkJFMTI2NUM4NUU1ODdEM0Q</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Fiduciaries</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RDRDQjYwNDkxREQ4NDE4Nzk4QzY0QTIyMzYzOTM0REQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjdEQjE4OUJDMzQxNDNEMEI0RTI1QUFCMzJENjEwRTA</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Real Property Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QUUyRTcxRURBNEY2NEE2MDk3QzBCNzRDOEY0NTZDQzk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjJCOTVGQkMzRkQzNEQ2RjkzOEFGNzY4QUVBNEUzRTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjQxMkNBNkE1ODE5NDg0NUJDMTkzNzA1NTMwQzRFQ0M</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification><classificationGroup classificationScheme="indexing-terms"><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem score="90"><className>Businesses &amp; Corporations</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjA4OEVGODBENzY4NDcxM0IyQzA1OTEwQzVDODRBOUE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></classificationGroup></metadata></legislativeDoc>