<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#349#000037#     2#          100#">Va. Code Ann. § 37.2-100</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_37.2-100"/><heading><desig>§ 37.2-100.</desig><title>Definitions</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><bodyText><p>As used in this title, unless the context requires a different meaning:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><bodyText><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Abuse"</emphasis> means any act or failure to act by an employee or other person responsible for the care of an individual in a facility or program operated, licensed, or funded by the Department, excluding those operated by the Department of Corrections, that was performed or was failed to be performed knowingly, recklessly, or intentionally, and that caused or might have caused physical or psychological harm, injury, or death to an individual receiving care or treatment for mental illness, intellectual disability, or substance abuse. Examples of abuse include acts such as:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Rape, sexual assault, or other criminal sexual behavior;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Assault or battery;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Use of language that demeans, threatens, intimidates, or humiliates the individual;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_4"/><heading><desig>4.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Misuse or misappropriation of the individual's assets, goods, or property;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_5"/><heading><desig>5.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Use of excessive force when placing an individual in physical or mechanical restraint;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_6"/><heading><desig>6.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Use of physical or mechanical restraints on an individual that is not in compliance with federal and state laws, regulations, and policies, professionally accepted standards of practice, or his individualized services plan; and</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_7"/><heading><desig>7.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Use of more restrictive or intensive services or denial of services to punish an individual or that is not consistent with his individualized services plan.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><bodyText><p><pre/><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Administrative policy community services board"</emphasis> or <emphasis typeStyle="it">"administrative policy board"</emphasis> means the public body organized in accordance with the provisions of Chapter 5 (<citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 37.2-500"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 37.2-500">§ 37.2-500<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000037#     2#          500#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> et seq.) that is appointed by and accountable to the governing body of each city and county that established it to set policy for and administer the provision of mental health, developmental, and substance abuse services. The "administrative policy community services board" or "administrative policy board" denotes the board, the members of which are appointed pursuant to <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 37.2-501"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 37.2-501">§ 37.2-501<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000037#     2#          501#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> with the powers and duties enumerated in subsection A of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 37.2-504"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 37.2-504">§ 37.2-504<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000037#     2#          504#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> and <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 37.2-505"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 37.2-505">§ 37.2-505<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000037#     2#          505#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>. Mental health, developmental, and substance abuse services are provided through local government staff or through contracts with other organizations and providers.</p><p><pre/><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Behavioral health authority"</emphasis> or <emphasis typeStyle="it">"authority"</emphasis> means a public body and a body corporate and politic organized in accordance with the provisions of Chapter 6 (<citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 37.2-600"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 37.2-600">§ 37.2-600<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000037#     2#          600#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> et seq.) that is appointed by and accountable to the governing body of the city or county that established it for the provision of mental health, developmental, and substance abuse services. "Behavioral health authority" or "authority" also includes the organization that provides these services through its own staff or through contracts with other organizations and providers.</p><p><pre/><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Behavioral health services"</emphasis> means the full range of mental health and substance abuse services.</p><p><pre/><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Board"</emphasis> means the State Board of Behavioral Health and Developmental Services.</p><p><pre/><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Commissioner"</emphasis> means the Commissioner of Behavioral Health and Developmental Services.</p><p><pre/><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Community services board"</emphasis> means the public body established pursuant to <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 37.2-501"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 37.2-501">§ 37.2-501<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000037#     2#          501#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> that provides mental health, developmental, and substance abuse services within each city and county that established it; the term "community services board" shall include administrative policy community services boards, operating community services boards, and local government departments with policy-advisory community services boards.</p><p><pre/><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Department"</emphasis> means the Department of Behavioral Health and Developmental Services.</p><p><pre/><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Developmental disability"</emphasis> means a severe, chronic disability of an individual that (i) is attributable to a mental or physical impairment, or a combination of mental and physical impairments, other than a sole diagnosis of mental illness; (ii) is manifested before the individual reaches 22 years of age; (iii) is likely to continue indefinitely; (iv) results in substantial functional limitations in three or more of the following areas of major life activity: self-care, receptive and expressive language, learning, mobility, self-direction, capacity for independent living, or economic self-sufficiency; and (v) reflects the individual's need for a combination and sequence of special interdisciplinary or generic services, individualized supports, or other forms of assistance that are of lifelong or extended duration and are individually planned and coordinated. An individual from birth to age nine, inclusive, who has a substantial developmental delay or specific congenital or acquired condition may be considered to have a developmental disability without meeting three or more of the criteria described in clauses (i) through (v) if the individual, without services and supports, has a high probability of meeting those criteria later in life.</p><p><pre/><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Developmental services"</emphasis> means planned, individualized, and person-centered services and supports provided to individuals with intellectual disability for the purpose of enabling these individuals to increase their self-determination and independence, obtain employment, participate fully in all aspects of community life, advocate for themselves, and achieve their fullest potential to the greatest extent possible.</p><p><pre/><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Facility"</emphasis> means a state or licensed hospital, training center, psychiatric hospital, or other type of residential or outpatient mental health or developmental services facility. When modified by the word "state," "facility" means a state hospital or training center operated by the Department, including the buildings and land associated with it.</p><p><pre/><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Family member"</emphasis> means an immediate family member of an individual receiving services or the principal caregiver of that individual. A principal caregiver is a person who acts in the place of an immediate family member, including other relatives and foster care providers, but does not have a proprietary interest in the care of the individual receiving services.</p><p><pre/><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Hospital,"</emphasis> when not modified by the words "state" or "licensed," means a state hospital and a licensed hospital that provides care and treatment for persons with mental illness.</p><p><pre/><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Individual receiving services"</emphasis> or <emphasis typeStyle="it">"individual"</emphasis> means a current direct recipient of public or private mental health, developmental, or substance abuse treatment, rehabilitation, or habilitation services and includes the terms "consumer," "patient," "resident," "recipient," or "client."</p><p><pre/><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Intellectual disability"</emphasis> means a disability, originating before the age of 18 years, characterized concurrently by (i) significant subaverage intellectual functioning as demonstrated by performance on a standardized measure of intellectual functioning, administered in conformity with accepted professional practice, that is at least two standard deviations below the mean and (ii) significant limitations in adaptive behavior as expressed in conceptual, social, and practical adaptive skills.</p><p><pre/><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Licensed hospital"</emphasis> means a hospital or institution, including a psychiatric unit of a general hospital, that is licensed pursuant to the provisions of this title.</p><p><pre/><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Mental health services"</emphasis> means planned individualized interventions intended to reduce or ameliorate mental illness or the effects of mental illness through care, treatment, counseling, rehabilitation, medical or psychiatric care, or other supports provided to individuals with mental illness for the purpose of enabling these individuals to increase their self-determination and independence, obtain remunerative employment, participate fully in all aspects of community life, advocate for themselves, and achieve their fullest potential to the greatest extent possible.</p><p><pre/><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Mental illness"</emphasis> means a disorder of thought, mood, emotion, perception, or orientation that significantly impairs judgment, behavior, capacity to recognize reality, or ability to address basic life necessities and requires care and treatment for the health, safety, or recovery of the individual or for the safety of others.</p><p><pre/><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Neglect"</emphasis> means failure by a person or a program or facility operated, licensed, or funded by the Department, excluding those operated by the Department of Corrections, responsible for providing services to do so, including nourishment, treatment, care, goods, or services necessary to the health, safety, or welfare of an individual receiving care or treatment for mental illness, intellectual disability, or substance abuse.</p><p><pre/><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Operating community services board"</emphasis> or <emphasis typeStyle="it">"operating board"</emphasis> means the public body organized in accordance with the provisions of Chapter 5 (<citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 37.2-500"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 37.2-500">§ 37.2-500<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000037#     2#          500#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> et seq.) that is appointed by and accountable to the governing body of each city and county that established it for the direct provision of mental health, developmental, and substance abuse services. The "operating community services board" or "operating board" denotes the board, the members of which are appointed pursuant to <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 37.2-501"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 37.2-501">§ 37.2-501<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000037#     2#          501#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> with the powers and duties enumerated in subsection A of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 37.2-504"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 37.2-504">§ 37.2-504<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000037#     2#          504#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> and <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 37.2-505"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 37.2-505">§ 37.2-505<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000037#     2#          505#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>. "Operating community services board" or "operating board" also includes the organization that provides such services, through its own staff or through contracts with other organizations and providers.</p><p><pre/><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Performance contract"</emphasis> means the annual agreement negotiated and entered into by a community services board or behavioral health authority with the Department through which it provides state and federal funds appropriated for mental health, developmental, and substance abuse services to that community services board or behavioral health authority.</p><p><pre/><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Policy-advisory community services board"</emphasis> or <emphasis typeStyle="it">"policy-advisory board"</emphasis> means the public body organized in accordance with the provisions of Chapter 5 that is appointed by and accountable to the governing body of each city or county that established it to provide advice on policy matters to the local government department that provides mental health, developmental, and substance abuse services pursuant to subsection A of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 37.2-504"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 37.2-504">§ 37.2-504<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000037#     2#          504#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> and <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 37.2-505"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 37.2-505">§ 37.2-505<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000037#     2#          505#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>. The "policy-advisory community services board" or "policy-advisory board" denotes the board, the members of which are appointed pursuant to <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 37.2-501"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 37.2-501">§ 37.2-501<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000037#     2#          501#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> with the powers and duties enumerated in subsection B of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 37.2-504"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 37.2-504">§ 37.2-504<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000037#     2#          504#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p><p><pre/><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Service area"</emphasis> means the city or county or combination of cities and counties or counties or cities that is served by a community services board or behavioral health authority or the cities and counties that are served by a state facility.</p><p><pre/><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Special justice"</emphasis> means a person appointed by a chief judge of a judicial circuit for the purpose of performing the duties of a judge pursuant to <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 37.2-803"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 37.2-803">§ 37.2-803<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000037#     2#          803#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p><p><pre/><emphasis typeStyle="it">"State hospital"</emphasis> means a hospital, psychiatric institute, or other institution operated by the Department that provides care and treatment for persons with mental illness.</p><p><pre/><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Substance abuse"</emphasis> means the use of drugs, enumerated in the Virginia Drug Control Act (<citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 54.1-3400"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 54.1-3400">§ 54.1-3400<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000054#     1#         3400#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> et seq.), without a compelling medical reason or alcohol that (i) results in psychological or physiological dependence or danger to self or others as a function of continued and compulsive use or (ii) results in mental, emotional, or physical impairment that causes socially dysfunctional or socially disordering behavior and (iii), because of such substance abuse, requires care and treatment for the health of the individual. This care and treatment may include counseling, rehabilitation, or medical or psychiatric care.</p><p><pre/><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Training center"</emphasis> means a facility operated by the Department that provides training, habilitation, or other individually focused supports to persons with intellectual disability.</p></bodyText></level></level><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p>Code 1950, §§ 37-1.1, 37-34.2:1, 37-254.1; 1950, pp. 899, 935; 1954, c. 668; 1958, c. 556; 1960, c. 133; 1964, cc. 483, 640; 1968, c. 477, <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 37.1-1"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 37.1-1">§ 37.1-1<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000037#     1#            1#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; 1972, cc. 635, 639; 1973, c. 465; 1974, c. 301; 1976, cc. 671, 767, § 37.1-203; 1979, c. 54; 1980, c. 582; 1982, c. 50; 1983, c. 538; 1984, c. 209; 1987, c. 413; <citation normalizedCite="1994 VA CH 939"><content><span normalizedCite="1994 Va. Ch. 939">1994, c. 939<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1994#000939#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1995 VA CH 693"><content><span normalizedCite="1995 Va. Ch. 693">1995, c. 693<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1995#000693#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, § 15.1-1677; <citation normalizedCite="1996 VA CH 861"><content><span normalizedCite="1996 Va. Ch. 861">1996, c. 861<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1996#000861#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1997 VA CH 587"><content><span normalizedCite="1997 Va. Ch. 587">1997, c. 587<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1997#000587#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, § 37.1-243; <citation normalizedCite="1998 VA CH 680"><content><span normalizedCite="1998 Va. Ch. 680">1998, cc. 680<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1998#000680#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1998 VA CH 724"><content><span normalizedCite="1998 Va. Ch. 724">724<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1998#000724#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, § 37.1-194.1; <citation normalizedCite="1999 VA CH 969"><content><span normalizedCite="1999 Va. Ch. 969">1999, c. 969<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1999#000969#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2005 VA CH 716"><content><span normalizedCite="2005 Va. Ch. 716">2005, c. 716<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2005#000716#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2009 VA CH 813"><content><span normalizedCite="2009 Va. Ch. 813">2009, cc. 813<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2009#000813#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2009 VA CH 840"><content><span normalizedCite="2009 Va. Ch. 840">840<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2009#000840#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2012 VA CH 476"><content><span normalizedCite="2012 Va. Ch. 476">2012, cc. 476<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2012#000476#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2012 VA CH 507"><content><span normalizedCite="2012 Va. Ch. 507">507<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2012#000507#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2015 VA CH 750"><content><span normalizedCite="2015 Va. Ch. 750">2015, c. 750<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2015#000750#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PVG0-004G-K51H-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 37.2.</desig><title>BEHAVIORAL HEALTH AND DEVELOPMENTAL SERVICES</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="subtitle"><heading><desig>SUBTITLE 1.</desig><title>GENERAL PROVISIONS</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 1.</desig><title>DEFINITIONS</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Governments</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjdEQjE4OUJDMzQxNDNEMEI0RTI1QUFCMzJENjEwRTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Administrative Boards</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QTYwRUFCMDc5MzQ5NDEyREFEQkU2NkE2MjRGQTlCNzY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Njg1MkM3RkYyNzIxNEVFRkJFMTI2NUM4NUU1ODdEM0Q</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUYzRDgzNzg0MTBGNEYyN0FFMzFCRTY5MjA1MTc2Q0Q7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MEY3NUIxODI2RjU2NEY0NzgwMDQyNjFDMEQ1QUExRjM</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Licenses</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6N0IyQjkyQkVENEM2NDczNzg5MDUwQ0U5RDMzRjlDNUM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QURCRDNBRjBGRTE0NEFBRUEzNUU1MzFGQjg3MTM4MDI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Healthcare Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NkUxMkVDQjJDOEY5NDVDQ0E5NTFEMTlDMjIwNzVERjc7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6N0U1NEQ5NkFBQjhENEUyMjhDMjM2MjRFQkVBOTFDODI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MkIwM0E1RTM4NkY5NEU4QjhBM0RCNzc5QjE4RkIzOEI</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NTVDMzIyNkJCMTRBNDI0NUJBOTlBOTYyMjQ0MDkyODU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QTJGRDdFQzgwODczNDI0NDgwMzEyM0JBOEQ2MUVDNjg</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Public Health &amp; Welfare Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDYwRTY1MDg3MTk5NDUyNkFFRDI1RjJBRERGQ0UxNzI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Advocacy &amp; Protection</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MkY5MTQxNUU5OTVDNEQ1MjgzQjdGREJFNEEzMDBGMDU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NUQyOEY5MEQ0Mzc1NEU5REJDQkM5OTk0OTlBRkIwMDk</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NjdDOTFFQjY0OTM1NEUyNEI5OEYwODE0RTA4RENEQkE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RTA2N0I2MjA4MEMwNEExNjlBQzkzRjBGOTAxODRCNkY</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjUxOERFOUQyQTJCNEJFRUI4NzcwRTREQTA5NkIwNjE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDMyMjg5MDFFMDI5NEI1RUIzMUIzMTQyRjhFMDAxM0M</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Rehabilitation</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NkY3QTlDNUZFOTFDNENGNzlDRUQ0MTNGNjk2MzU2NDY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NjhBRDBBMTY1RjVDNEI5Q0E5QjNDOTcyNDY2NjU3MUM</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Treatment</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QTE3NDlDOUQ4Mzg1NDcxNzhCNzQwNDc2MkEzMTkwRUI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RTA2N0I2MjA4MEMwNEExNjlBQzkzRjBGOTAxODRCNkY</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></metadata></legislativeDoc>