<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#349#000051#     5#          173#">Va. Code Ann. § 51.5-173</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_51.5-173"/><heading><desig>§ 51.5-173.</desig><title>Services for individuals</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a"/><heading><desig>A.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Vocational rehabilitation services provided by the Department shall address comprehensively the individual needs of each client to the maximum extent possible with resources available to the Department, through the following:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> An assessment for determining eligibility and vocational needs by qualified personnel, including, if appropriate, an assessment by personnel skilled in rehabilitation technology;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Counseling and guidance, including information and support services to assist an individual in exercising informed choice, and referral necessary to help applicants or clients to secure needed services from other agencies;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Diagnosis and treatment of physical or mental impairments, including:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_3_a"/><heading><desig>a.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Corrective surgery or therapeutic treatment necessary to correct or substantially modify a physical or mental condition that constitutes a substantial impediment to employment, but that is of such a nature that correction or modification may reasonably be expected to eliminate or reduce such impediment to employment within a reasonable length of time;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_3_b"/><heading><desig>b.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Necessary hospitalization in connection with surgery or treatment;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_3_c"/><heading><desig>c.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Prosthetic and orthotic devices;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_3_d"/><heading><desig>d.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Eyeglasses and visual services as prescribed by qualified personnel who meet state licensure laws and who are selected by the client;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_3_e"/><heading><desig>e.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Special services including transplantation and dialysis, artificial kidneys, and supplies necessary for the treatment of clients with end-stage renal disease; and</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_3_f"/><heading><desig>f.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Diagnosis and treatment for mental and emotional disorders by qualified personnel who meet state licensure laws;</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_4"/><heading><desig>4.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Vocational and other training services, including the provision of personal and vocational-adjustment services, books, tools, and other training materials, except that no training services provided at institutions of higher education shall be paid for with funds under this article unless maximum efforts have been made to secure grant assistance in whole or part from other funding sources;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_5"/><heading><desig>5.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Maintenance for additional costs incurred while participating in an assessment for determining eligibility and vocational rehabilitation needs or while receiving services under an individualized plan for employment;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_6"/><heading><desig>6.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Transportation, including adequate training in the use of public transportation vehicles and systems that is provided in connection with the provision of any other services described in this section and needed by the client to achieve an employment outcome;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_7"/><heading><desig>7.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Services to members of a client's family when such services are necessary to assist the client to achieve an employment outcome;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_8"/><heading><desig>8.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Interpreter services provided by qualified personnel for clients who are deaf or hard of hearing and reader services for clients determined to be blind, after an examination by qualified personnel who meet state licensure laws;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_9"/><heading><desig>9.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Rehabilitation technology, including telecommunications and sensory and other technological aids and devices;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_10"/><heading><desig>10.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Job-related services, including job search and assistance, job retention services, follow-up services, and follow-along services;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_11"/><heading><desig>11.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Specific post-employment services necessary to assist the client to retain, regain, or advance in employment;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_12"/><heading><desig>12.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Occupational licenses, tools, equipment, and initial stocks and supplies;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_13"/><heading><desig>13.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> On-the-job or other related personal assistance services provided while a client is receiving other services described in this section;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_14"/><heading><desig>14.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Supported employment services which include providing a rehabilitation or other human services agency staff person to assist in job placement, job site training, and job follow-through for the disabled employee;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_15"/><heading><desig>15.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Technical assistance and other consultation services to conduct market analyses, develop business plans, and otherwise provide resources, to the extent such resources are authorized to be provided through the statewide workforce investment system, to eligible clients pursuing self-employment or telecommuting or establishing a small business operation as an employment outcome;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_16"/><heading><desig>16.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Transition services for students with disabilities that facilitate the transition from school to post-secondary life, such as the achievement of an employment outcome in competitive integrated employment or pre-employment transition services;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_17"/><heading><desig>17.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Customized employment for an individual with a significant disability in a competitive integrated setting that is based on the strengths, needs, interests, and abilities of the individual and the business needs of the employer; and</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_18"/><heading><desig>18.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Encouragement of qualified individuals who are eligible to receive services to pursue advanced training in the fields of science, technology, engineering, mathematics (including computer science fields), medicine, law, or business.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b"/><heading><desig>B.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Written standards shall be established by the Commissioner detailing the scope and nature of each vocational rehabilitation service authorized herein, the conditions, criteria and procedures under which each service may be provided, and the use of entitlements and other benefits to access these services, when appropriate.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c"/><heading><desig>C.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> In providing the foregoing services, the Department shall determine whether comparable services and benefits are available under any other program unless such a determination would interrupt or delay the progress of the client toward achieving the employment outcome identified in the individualized plan for employment, an immediate job placement, or the provision of such service to any client at extreme medical risk.</p></bodyText></level><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p>1985, c. 421, §§ 51.01-18, 51.5-18; <citation normalizedCite="1989 VA CH 181"><content><span normalizedCite="1989 Va. Ch. 181">1989, c. 181<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1989#000181#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1992 VA CH 755"><content><span normalizedCite="1992 Va. Ch. 755">1992, c. 755<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1992#000755#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2001 VA CH 483"><content><span normalizedCite="2001 Va. Ch. 483">2001, c. 483<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2001#000483#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2002 VA CH 46"><content><span normalizedCite="2002 Va. Ch. 46">2002, c. 46<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2002#000046#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2012 VA CH 803"><content><span normalizedCite="2012 Va. Ch. 803">2012, cc. 803<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2012#000803#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2012 VA CH 835"><content><span normalizedCite="2012 Va. Ch. 835">835<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2012#000835#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2016 VA CH 27"><content><span normalizedCite="2016 Va. Ch. 27">2016, c. 27<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2016#000027#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PVX0-004G-K03G-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 51.5.</desig><title>PERSONS WITH DISABILITIES</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 14.</desig><title>DEPARTMENT FOR AGING AND REHABILITATIVE SERVICES</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="article"><heading><desig>ARTICLE 11.</desig><title>VOCATIONAL REHABILITATION.</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Public Health &amp; Welfare Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDYwRTY1MDg3MTk5NDUyNkFFRDI1RjJBRERGQ0UxNzI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Rehabilitation</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NkY3QTlDNUZFOTFDNENGNzlDRUQ0MTNGNjk2MzU2NDY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NjhBRDBBMTY1RjVDNEI5Q0E5QjNDOTcyNDY2NjU3MUM</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></metadata></legislativeDoc>