<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#123#000030#       310#">Va. Code Ann. § 30-310</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_30-310"/><heading><desig>§ 30-310.</desig><title>Review of incentive packages</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a"/><heading><desig>A.</desig></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The Commission shall review individual incentive packages, including but not limited to packages offering tax incentives, for economic development projects (including but not limited to MEI projects) for which (i) one or more of the incentives in the incentive package is not authorized under current law or an amendment by the General Assembly is being sought to one or more currently existing incentives included as part of the incentive package or (ii) the aggregate amount of incentives to be provided by the Commonwealth in the incentive package including grants, tax incentives such as credits and exemptions, general or nongeneral funds, proceeds from bonds, rights to lease property at below fair market value, or any other incentives from the Commonwealth is in excess of $ 10 million in value. The Commission shall recommend approval or denial of such packages to the General Assembly. Factors that shall be considered by the Commission in its review shall include, but not be limited to (i) return on investment, (ii) the time frame for repayment of incentives to the Commonwealth, (iii) average wages of the jobs created by the prospective MEI project or other economic development project, (iv) the amount of capital investment that is required, and (v) the need for enhanced employment opportunities in the prospective location of the prospective MEI project or other economic development project.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> a. Any time a proposed individual incentive package is to be considered by the Commission, materials outlining (i) the value of the proposed incentives, (ii) assumed return on investment, (iii) the time frame for repayment of incentives to the Commonwealth, (iv) average wages of the jobs created by the prospective MEI project or other economic development project, (v) the amount of capital investment that is required, and (vi) the need for enhanced employment opportunities in the prospective location of the prospective MEI project or other economic development project, shall be provided to the Commission members not less than 48 hours prior to the scheduled Commission meeting.</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_2_b"/><heading><desig>b.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The timing of any request for an endorsement of a proposed individual incentive package should be scheduled so that the MEI Commission could, at its discretion, have up to seven days subsequent to the presentation of the incentive package prior to endorsing or rejecting such proposal.</p></bodyText></level></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b"/><heading><desig>B.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> An affirmative vote by three of the five members of the Commission from the House of Delegates and two of the three members of the Commission from the Senate shall be required to endorse any incentive package, including but not limited to packages offering tax incentives, for economic development projects (including but not limited to MEI projects) for which (i) one or more of the incentives in the incentive package is not authorized under current law or an amendment by the General Assembly is being sought to one or more currently existing incentives included as part of the incentive package or (ii) the aggregate amount of incentives to be provided by the Commonwealth in the incentive package including grants, tax incentives such as credits and exemptions, general or nongeneral funds, proceeds from bonds, rights to lease property at below fair market value, or any other incentives from the Commonwealth is in excess of $ 10 million in value.</p></bodyText></level><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p><citation normalizedCite="2009 VA CH 246"><content><span normalizedCite="2009 Va. Ch. 246">2009, cc. 246<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2009#000246#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2009 VA CH 311"><content><span normalizedCite="2009 Va. Ch. 311">311<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2009#000311#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2010 VA CH 543"><content><span normalizedCite="2010 Va. Ch. 543">2010, cc. 543<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2010#000543#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2010 VA CH 716"><content><span normalizedCite="2010 Va. Ch. 716">716<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2010#000716#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2013 VA CH 806"><content><span normalizedCite="2013 Va. Ch. 806">2013, c. 806<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2013#000806#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2015 VA CH 761"><content><span normalizedCite="2015 Va. Ch. 761">2015, c. 761<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2015#000761#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PVN0-004G-K2V5-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 30.</desig><title>GENERAL ASSEMBLY</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 47.</desig><title>MEI PROJECT APPROVAL COMMISSION</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Public Health &amp; Welfare Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDYwRTY1MDg3MTk5NDUyNkFFRDI1RjJBRERGQ0UxNzI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Community &amp; Economic Development</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MEUxOUMwOTFCRDdFNEVFOUJFMjE2RDE0NERDOTM0QjY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDZDNTZENUNCRjVBNEY4OEIyQzVBNjRDRTcyOEQ4NDQ</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification><classificationGroup classificationScheme="indexing-terms"><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem score="90"><className>Governments</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjdEQjE4OUJDMzQxNDNEMEI0RTI1QUFCMzJENjEwRTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></classificationGroup></metadata></legislativeDoc>