<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#349#000038#     2#         1329#">Va. Code Ann. § 38.2-1329</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_38.2-1329"/><heading><desig>§ 38.2-1329.</desig><title>Registration of insurers that are members of holding company system</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a"/><heading><desig>A.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Each insurer licensed to do business in the Commonwealth that is a member of an insurance holding company system shall register with the Commission.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b"/><heading><desig>B.</desig></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> This section shall not apply to any foreign insurer subject to disclosure requirements and standards adopted by statute or regulation in the jurisdiction of its domicile that are substantially similar to those contained in this section, subsection A of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 38.2-1330"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 38.2-1330">§ 38.2-1330<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000038#     2#         1330#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, subsection D of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 38.2-1330"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 38.2-1330">§ 38.2-1330<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000038#     2#         1330#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 38.2-1330.1"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 38.2-1330.1">§ 38.2-1330.1<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000038#     2#       1330.1#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, and either (i) a provision substantially similar to subsection B of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 38.2-1330"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 38.2-1330">§ 38.2-1330<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000038#     2#         1330#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> or (ii) a provision such as the following: "Each registered insurer shall keep current the information required to be disclosed in its registration statement by reporting all material changes or additions within 15 days after the end of the month in which it learns of each change or addition."</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Any insurer that is subject to registration under this section shall register within 15 days after it becomes subject to registration, and annually thereafter by April 30 of each year for the previous calendar year, unless the Commission for good cause shown extends the time for registration, and then within the extended time.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Any licensed insurer that is a member of an insurance holding company system but not subject to registration under this section may be required by the Commission to furnish a copy of the registration statement, or other information filed by the insurer, with the insurance regulatory authority of its domiciliary jurisdiction.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c"/><heading><desig>C.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Each insurer subject to registration under this section shall file a registration statement on a form provided by the Commission. Such statement shall contain current information on:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The capital structure, general financial condition, ownership, and management of the insurer and any person controlling the insurer;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The identity of every member of the insurance holding company system;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The following agreements in force, continuing relationships and transactions currently outstanding between the insurer and its affiliates:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c_3_a"/><heading><desig>a.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Loans, other investments, or purchases, sales or exchanges of securities of the affiliates by the insurer or of the insurer by its affiliates;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c_3_b"/><heading><desig>b.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Purchases, sales, or exchanges of assets;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c_3_c"/><heading><desig>c.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Transactions not in the ordinary course of business;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c_3_d"/><heading><desig>d.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Guarantees or undertakings for the benefit of an affiliate that result in an actual contingent exposure of the insurer's assets to liability, other than insurance contracts entered into in the ordinary course of the insurer's business;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c_3_e"/><heading><desig>e.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> All management and service contracts and all cost-sharing arrangements;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c_3_f"/><heading><desig>f.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Reinsurance agreements or other risk-sharing arrangements;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c_3_g"/><heading><desig>g.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Dividends and other distributions to shareholders; and</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c_3_h"/><heading><desig>h.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Consolidated tax allocation agreements;</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c_4"/><heading><desig>4.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Any pledge of the insurer's stock, including stock of any subsidiary or controlling affiliate, for a loan made to any member of the insurance holding company system;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c_5"/><heading><desig>5.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> If requested by the Commission, financial statements of or within an insurance holding company system, including all affiliates. Financial statements may include but are not limited to annual audited financial statements filed with the SEC pursuant to the Securities Act of 1933, as amended, or the Securities Exchange Act of 1934, as amended. An insurer required to file financial statements pursuant to this subdivision may satisfy the request by providing the Commission with the most recently filed parent corporation financial statements that have been filed with the SEC;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c_6"/><heading><desig>6.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Other matters relating to transactions between registered insurers and any affiliates which may be included from time to time in any registration forms adopted or approved by the Commission;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c_7"/><heading><desig>7.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Statements that the corporate governance and internal controls are managed under the direction of the insurer's board of directors in a manner consistent with <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 13.1-673"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 13.1-673">§ 13.1-673<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000013#     1#          673#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> or <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 13.1-853"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 13.1-853">§ 13.1-853<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000013#     1#          853#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> as applicable, and that the insurer's officers or senior management have approved, implemented, and continue to maintain and monitor corporate governance and internal control procedures; and</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c_8"/><heading><desig>8.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Any other information required by the Commission by rule or regulation.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d"/><heading><desig>D.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> All registration statements shall contain a summary outlining all items in the current registration statement representing changes from the prior registration statement.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_e"/><heading><desig>E.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> If information is not material for the purposes of this section, it need not be disclosed on the registration statement filed pursuant to subsection C. Unless the Commission prescribes otherwise, sales, purchases, exchanges, loans or extensions of credit, investments, or guarantees involving one-half of one percent or less of an insurer's admitted assets as of the immediately preceding December 31 shall not be deemed material for purposes of this section.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_f"/><heading><desig>F.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Each registered insurer shall report all additional material transactions with affiliates and any material changes in previously reported material transactions with affiliates on amendment forms provided by the Commission. Each insurer shall make its report within 15 days after the end of the month in which it learns of each additional material transaction or material change in material transaction. Subject to <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 38.2-1330.1"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 38.2-1330.1">§ 38.2-1330.1<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000038#     2#       1330.1#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, each insurer shall report to the Commission all dividends and other distributions to shareholders within five business days following their declaration, and such declaration shall confer no rights upon shareholders until:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_f_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The Commission has approved the payment of such dividend or distribution; or</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_f_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Thirty days after the Commission has received written notice of the declaration thereof and has not within such period disapproved such payment.</p><p><pre/>Each registered insurer shall also keep current the information required by subsection C by filing an amendment to its registration statement within 120 days after the end of each fiscal year of the ultimate controlling person of the insurance holding company system.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_g"/><heading><desig>G.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The Commission shall terminate the registration of any insurer that demonstrates it no longer is a member of an insurance holding company system.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_h"/><heading><desig>H.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The Commission may require or allow two or more affiliated insurers subject to registration under this section to file a consolidated registration statement or consolidated reports amending their consolidated registration statement or their individual registration statements.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_i"/><heading><desig>I.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The Commission may allow an insurer that is authorized to do business in this Commonwealth and that is part of an insurance holding company system to register on behalf of any affiliated insurer required to register under subsection A and to file all information and material required to be filed under this section.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_j"/><heading><desig>J.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The provisions of this section shall not apply to any insurer, information, or transaction if and to the extent that the Commission by rule, regulation, or order shall exempt the same from the provisions of this section.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_k"/><heading><desig>K.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Any person may file with the Commission a disclaimer of affiliation with any authorized insurer. The disclaimer shall fully disclose all material relationships and bases for affiliation between the person and the insurer as well as the basis for disclaiming the affiliation. A disclaimer of affiliation shall be deemed to have been granted unless the Commission, within 30 days following receipt of a complete disclaimer, notifies the filing party the disclaimer is disallowed. In the event of disallowance, the disclaiming party may request a hearing. The disclaiming party shall be relieved of its duty to register under this section if approval of the disclaimer has been granted by the Commission or if the disclaimer is deemed to have been approved.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_l"/><heading><desig>L.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The ultimate controlling person of every insurer subject to registration shall also file an annual enterprise risk report. The report shall be appropriate to the nature, scale, and complexity of the operations of the insurance holding company system, and shall, to the best of the ultimate controlling person's knowledge and belief, identify the material risks within the insurance holding company system that could pose enterprise risk to the insurer. The report shall be filed with the insurance commissioner, director, or superintendent of the lead state of the insurance holding company system as determined by the procedures within the Financial Analysis Handbook adopted by the NAIC.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_m"/><heading><desig>M.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The failure to file a registration statement or any summary of the registration statement or enterprise risk filing required by this section within the time specified for filing shall be a violation of this section.</p></bodyText></level><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p>1973, c. 505, § 38.1-178.2; 1977, c. 414; 1986, c. 562; <citation normalizedCite="1992 VA CH 588"><content><span normalizedCite="1992 Va. Ch. 588">1992, c. 588<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1992#000588#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2000 VA CH 46"><content><span normalizedCite="2000 Va. Ch. 46">2000, c. 46<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2000#000046#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2006 VA CH 577"><content><span normalizedCite="2006 Va. Ch. 577">2006, c. 577<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2006#000577#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2009 VA CH 717"><content><span normalizedCite="2009 Va. Ch. 717">2009, c. 717<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2009#000717#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2014 VA CH 309"><content><span normalizedCite="2014 Va. Ch. 309">2014, c. 309<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2014#000309#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PV50-004G-K4FW-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 38.2.</desig><title>INSURANCE</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 13.</desig><title>REPORTS, RESERVES AND EXAMINATIONS, INSURANCE HOLDING COMPANIES, REINSURANCE INTERMEDIARIES, AND MANAGING GENERAL AGENTS</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="article"><heading><desig>ARTICLE 5.</desig><title>INSURANCE HOLDING COMPANIES</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Foreign Insurers</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjlGMEIzREZGNUFENERBRUJBRDg5NjgxQTlEOTE1N0Y7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OUE0QUQ4OUIxOURCNDA3RUEyQkY0NzhBREMxNzk1RTM</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Insurance Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDM4MzQ2QUYzMTY0NDQzQTkxRDQwRUUzRUM5RDg0OEM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Foreign Insurers</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjlGMEIzREZGNUFENERBRUJBRDg5NjgxQTlEOTE1N0Y7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OUE0QUQ4OUIxOURCNDA3RUEyQkY0NzhBREMxNzk1RTM</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Materiality</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RjI5OTc3NEI1M0IzNDQzRjlFNTk0QTc2MkZEQUVCMDg7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MEVBQUY4MEE4MTAxNEFDREJBRDYzMjdDOTZDMjM4NTI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Tax Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OTNEM0E2OEE0RkQyNEY1MDhBQzdGMkQ4ODI4QTJDODE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Distributions by S Corporations</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6M0EwOTdBODVGQUIyNEM5OEJDOUU3MTdGQzY0MDRCOEU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Mzc5NjFFQjM2M0U3NEQ2NUI5RjMyNzFDRjU5NEY4NjI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification><classificationGroup classificationScheme="indexing-terms"><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem score="90"><className>Insurance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDM4MzQ2QUYzMTY0NDQzQTkxRDQwRUUzRUM5RDg0OEM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></classificationGroup></metadata></legislativeDoc>