<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#123#000023#       9.3#">Va. Code Ann. § 23-9.3</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_23-9.3"/><heading><desig>§ 23-9.3.</desig><title>(Repealed effective October 1, 2016) State Council of Higher Education for Virginia created; purpose; membership; terms; officers</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a"/><heading><desig>A.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> There is hereby created a State Council of Higher Education for Virginia, hereinafter sometimes referred to as the Council. The purpose of the Council shall be, through the exercise of the powers and performance of the duties set forth in this chapter, to advocate and promote the development and operation of an educationally and economically sound, vigorous, progressive, and coordinated system of higher education in the Commonwealth of Virginia and to lead state-level strategic planning and policy development and implementation based on research and analysis and in accordance with <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 23-38.87:10"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 23 -38.87:10">§ 23-38.87:10<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#142#        23#     38.87#        10#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> and subsection B of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 23-38.88"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 23 -38.88">§ 23-38.88.<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#123#000023#     38.88#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> The Council shall also seek to facilitate collaboration among institutions of higher education that will enhance quality and create operational efficiencies and shall work with institutions of higher education and their boards on board development.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b"/><heading><desig>B.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The Council shall be composed of persons selected from the Commonwealth at large without regard to political affiliation but with due consideration of geographical representation. Appointees shall have demonstrated experience, knowledge, and understanding of higher education and workforce needs. Appointees shall be selected for their ability and all appointments shall be of such nature as to aid the work of the Council and to inspire the highest degree of cooperation and confidence. No officer, employee, trustee, or member of the governing board of any institution of higher education, employee of the Commonwealth, member of the General Assembly, or member of the State Board of Education shall be eligible for appointment to the Council except as specified in this section. All members of the Council shall be deemed members at large charged with the responsibility of serving the best interests of the whole Commonwealth. No member shall act as the representative of any particular region or of any particular institution of higher education.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c"/><heading><desig>C.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The Council shall consist of 13 members: 12 members appointed by the Governor and subject to confirmation by the General Assembly at its next regular session and one ex officio member. At least one appointee shall have served as a president or chief executive of a public institution of higher education in the Commonwealth. At least one member shall be a sitting Virginia school superintendent, either at the state or local level. The President of the Virginia Economic Development Partnership shall serve ex officio with voting privileges. All terms shall begin July 1. Members shall be appointed for four-year terms, except that appointments to fill vacancies occurring shall be for the unexpired term.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d"/><heading><desig>D.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> No person having served on the Council for two terms of four years shall be eligible for reappointment to the Council for two years thereafter.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_e"/><heading><desig>E.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The Council shall elect a chairman and a vice-chairman from its own membership and appoint a secretary and such other officers as it deems necessary or advisable and shall prescribe their duties and term of office.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_f"/><heading><desig>F.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> At each meeting, the Council shall involve the presidents of the public institutions of higher education in its agenda. The presidents shall present information and comment on issues of common interest. The presidents shall choose presenters to the Council from among themselves who reflect the diversity of the institutions.</p><p>At each meeting, the Council may involve other groups, including the presidents of private, nonprofit institutions of higher education, in its agenda.</p></bodyText></level><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p>1956, c. 311; 1964, c. 597; 1970, c. 117; 1972, c. 210; 1974, c. 544; 1980, c. 728; <citation normalizedCite="1991 VA CH 590"><content><span normalizedCite="1991 Va. Ch. 590">1991, c. 590<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1991#000590#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2013 VA CH 605"><content><span normalizedCite="2013 Va. Ch. 605">2013, c. 605<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2013#000605#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PT00-004G-K1RP-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 23.</desig><title>EDUCATIONAL INSTITUTIONS</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 1.1.</desig><title>STATE COUNCIL OF HIGHER EDUCATION</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classificationGroup classificationScheme="indexing-terms"><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem score="90"><className>Education</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDkzNUEzQzFBNEZBNEFBREIxNDM5MTc1MUU5QjI4MTY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></classificationGroup></metadata></legislativeDoc>