<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#349#000004#     1#          506#">Va. Code Ann. § 4.1-506</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_4.1-506"/><heading><desig>§ 4.1-506.</desig><title>Notice of intent to terminate</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a"/><heading><desig>A.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Except as provided in subsection F, a brewery shall provide a wholesaler at least ninety days' prior written notice of any intent to amend, terminate, cancel or not renew any agreement. The notice, a copy of which shall be mailed at the same time to the Board, shall state all the reasons for the intended amendment, termination, cancellation or nonrenewal.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b"/><heading><desig>B.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Where the reason relates to a condition or conditions which may be rectified by action of the wholesaler, he shall have sixty days in which to take such action and shall, within the sixty-day period, give written notice to the brewery if and when such action is taken. A copy of the notice shall be mailed at the same time to the Board. If such condition has been rectified by action of the wholesaler, then the proposed amendment, termination, cancellation or nonrenewal shall be void and without legal effect. However, where the brewery contends that action on the part of the wholesaler has not rectified one or more of such conditions the brewery shall within fifteen days after the expiration of such sixty-day period request a hearing before the Board to determine if the condition has been rectified by action of the wholesaler.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c"/><heading><desig>C.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Where the reason relates to a condition which may not be rectified by the wholesaler within the sixty-day period, the wholesaler may request a hearing before the Board to determine if there is good cause for the amendment, termination, cancellation or nonrenewal of the agreement.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d"/><heading><desig>D.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Upon request in writing within the ninety-day period provided in subsection A from such brewery or wholesaler for a hearing, the Board shall, after notice and hearing, determine if the action of the wholesaler has rectified the condition or, as the case may be, if good cause exists for the amendment, termination, cancellation or nonrenewal of the agreement.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_e"/><heading><desig>E.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> In any proceeding brought pursuant to this section in which the existence of good cause is an issue, the brewery shall have the burden of proving the existence of good cause. Where a petition is made to the Board in a timely manner for a determination, the agreement in question shall continue in effect pending the Board's decision and any judicial review thereof, except in any case in which the Board makes a finding that there is good cause, as defined in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 4.1-505"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 4.1-505">§ 4.1-505<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000004#     1#          505#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, for the amendment, termination, cancellation, or nonrenewal, in which case the brewery may, unless otherwise ordered by a court of record, discontinue the agreement in question.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_f"/><heading><desig>F.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> No notice shall be required and an agreement may be immediately amended, terminated, cancelled or allowed to expire if the reason for the amendment, termination, cancellation or nonrenewal is:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_f_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The bankruptcy or receivership of the wholesaler;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_f_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> An assignment for the benefit of creditors or similar disposition of the assets of the business other than the creation of a security interest in the assets of a wholesaler for the purpose of securing financing in the ordinary course of business; or</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_f_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Revocation of the wholesaler's license.</p></bodyText></level></level><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p>1978, c. 579, § 4-118.8; 1985, c. 549; <citation normalizedCite="1993 VA CH 866"><content><span normalizedCite="1993 Va. Ch. 866">1993, c. 866<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1993#000866#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1997 VA CH 183"><content><span normalizedCite="1997 Va. Ch. 183">1997, c. 183<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1997#000183#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PTY0-004G-K054-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 4.1.</desig><title>ALCOHOLIC BEVERAGE CONTROL ACT</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 5.</desig><title>BEER FRANCHISE ACT</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Administrative Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NjMxMjc0MUIzQjkzNEM4MEI4NkZGQjVCREJCRDk4OUM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Factual Determinations</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NTEzN0UxMTVEMEJGNEE2OTkxQzgyRkEyQTFGNENDMzQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RDQ2OTA3NjY4NjgyNEYyQjhBN0E1M0VFQkM3QzQ1MDQ</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></metadata></legislativeDoc>