<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#123#000023#    38.112#">Va. Code Ann. § 23-38.112</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_23-38.112"/><heading><desig>§ 23-38.112.</desig><title>(Repealed effective October 1, 2016) Acquisition, possession, operation, and disposition of property; acceptance of grants and loans</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a"/><heading><desig>A.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Nothing in this subsection shall limit or reduce the authority granted to a covered institution in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 23-38.109"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 23 -38.109">§§ 23-38.109<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#123#000023#    38.109#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> and <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 23-38.113"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 23 -38.113">23-38.113<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#123#000023#    38.113#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, which shall govern the planning, design, construction, and implementation of capital projects and leases by covered institutions. In order to continue its mission as a public institution of higher education:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A covered institution may continue to hold, possess, operate, and dispose of any property, real or personal, tangible or intangible, that such covered institution held, possessed, or operated prior to its effective date of the initial Management Agreement as follows:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_1_a"/><heading><desig>a.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> If the property is real property, including land, buildings, and any improvements to land or buildings, and it was acquired or constructed in whole or in part with general fund appropriations or proceeds from a general obligation bond issue under Article X, Section 9(a) or 9(b) of the Constitution of Virginia, the covered institution (i) shall hold, possess, and operate such property in accordance with the institution's enabling legislation, with this subchapter, and with any policies adopted by the governing body of the institution pursuant thereto, and (ii) shall dispose of such property in accordance with general law applicable to state-owned property and with the institution's enabling legislation.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_1_b"/><heading><desig>b.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> If the property is real property, including land, buildings, and any improvements to land or buildings, and it was acquired or constructed either (i) entirely with nongeneral fund appropriations or proceeds from a nongeneral fund revenue bond issue under Article X, Section 9(c) or 9(d) of the Constitution of Virginia, or (ii) entirely with funds other than funds appropriated by the General Assembly or proceeds from a general obligation bond issue under Article X, Section 9(a) or 9(b) of the Constitution of Virginia, the covered institution shall hold, possess, operate, and dispose of such property in accordance with the institution's enabling legislation, notwithstanding the approval requirements of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 23-77.1"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 23 -77.1">§ 23-77.1<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#123#000023#      77.1#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, with this subchapter, and with any policies adopted by the governing body of the institution pursuant thereto.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_1_c"/><heading><desig>c.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> If the property is personal property, the covered institution shall hold, possess, operate, and dispose of such property in accordance with the institution's enabling legislation, with this subchapter, and with any policies adopted by the governing body of the institution pursuant thereto.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> After the effective date of the initial Management Agreement as provided in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 23-38.88"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 23 -38.88">§ 23-38.88<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#123#000023#     38.88#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, a covered institution may acquire any real property, construct improvements thereon in accordance with <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 23-38.109"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 23 -38.109">§ 23-38.109<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#123#000023#    38.109#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, and acquire any personal property, tangible or intangible, and hold, possess, operate, and dispose of such real and personal property as follows:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_2_a"/><heading><desig>a.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> If the property is real property, including land, buildings, and improvements to land or buildings, and it is acquired or constructed with funds appropriated by the General Assembly for that purpose or with proceeds from a general obligation bond issue under Article X, Section 9(a) or 9(b) of the Constitution of Virginia, the covered institution (i) shall hold, possess, and operate such property in accordance with the institution's enabling legislation, with this subchapter, and with any policies adopted by the governing body of the institution pursuant thereto, and (ii) shall dispose of such property in accordance with general law applicable to state-owned property and with the covered institution's enabling legislation.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_2_b"/><heading><desig>b.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> If the property is real property, including land, buildings, and improvements to land or buildings, and the property is acquired with any funds in the covered institution's possession, other than any funds appropriated by the General Assembly or proceeds from a general obligation bond issue under Article, X, Section 9(a) or 9(b) of the Constitution of Virginia, the institution shall hold, possess, operate, dispose of, and otherwise deal with such property, or any right, easement, estate, or interest therein, acquired by purchase, exchange, gift, assignment, transfer, foreclosure, lease, bequest, devise, operation of law, or other means, in accordance with the covered institution's enabling legislation, notwithstanding the approval requirements of § 23-77.1, with this subchapter, and with any policies adopted by the governing body of the institution pursuant thereto.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_2_c"/><heading><desig>c.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> If the property is personal property, the institution shall hold, possess, operate, and dispose of such property in accordance with the institution's enabling legislation, with this subchapter, and with any policies adopted by the governing body of the institution pursuant thereto.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> With the approval of the Governor or as otherwise provided by law, and consistent with the provisions of subdivisions 1 and 2 of this subsection, a covered institution may sell, assign, encumber, mortgage, demolish, or otherwise dispose of any project or any other property, real or personal, tangible or intangible, or any right, easement, estate, or interest therein, or any deed of trust or mortgage lien interest owned by it, under its control or custody or in its possession, and may release or relinquish any right, title, claim, lien, interest, easement, or demand however acquired, including any equity or right of redemption in property foreclosed by it; and</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_4"/><heading><desig>4.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> May do any of the foregoing by public or private transaction.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b"/><heading><desig>B.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A covered institution may accept loans, grants, contributions, or other assistance from the federal government, the Commonwealth or any political subdivision thereof, or from any other public or private source to carry out its mission as a public institution of higher education of the Commonwealth and any of the purposes of this subchapter. A covered institution may enter into any agreement or contract regarding or relating to the acceptance, use, or repayment of any such loan, grant, contribution, or assistance, and may enter into such other agreements with any such entity in furtherance of the purposes of this subchapter. Counties, cities, and towns are hereby authorized to lend or donate money or other property to a covered institution for any of its purposes. Any local government making the grant or loan may restrict the use of the grant or loan to a specific project, within or without that locality.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c"/><heading><desig>C.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Notwithstanding the provisions of this chapter, no covered institution shall take action with regard to any property, real or personal, if such action would be deemed to be in violation of any requirement or covenant contained in any outstanding bonds, notes, or other evidences of indebtedness.</p></bodyText></level><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p><citation normalizedCite="2005 VA CH 933"><content><span normalizedCite="2005 Va. Ch. 933">2005, cc. 933<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2005#000933#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2005 VA CH 945"><content><span normalizedCite="2005 Va. Ch. 945">945<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2005#000945#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PVG0-004G-K4YC-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 23.</desig><title>EDUCATIONAL INSTITUTIONS</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 4.10.</desig><title>RESTRUCTURED HIGHER EDUCATION FINANCIAL AND ADMINISTRATIVE OPERATIONS ACT</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="subchapter"><heading><desig>SUBCHAPTER 3.</desig><title>ALTERNATIVE AUTHORITY FOR COVERED INSTITUTIONS</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="article"><heading><desig>ARTICLE 5.</desig><title>CAPITAL PROJECTS; PROCUREMENT; PROPERTY GENERALLY</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Administrative Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NjMxMjc0MUIzQjkzNEM4MEI4NkZGQjVCREJCRDk4OUM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NUMwRjNCRUQ4NUI2NEIwMkI1RTcyRUEzRDgxMEZCMDQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6REJGNjMzRTJDMDRGNDM0Mjg3QjAxNTE2MDU2RjlDMDY</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Contracts Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QzY0RTZFMzE0RjkwNDdFQUI5M0U5N0ZFMjYyREMyQzU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Personal Property</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6ODQzNUIwM0U1NzgzNDkyRDg0MTVFQzRBMUQ2RDM2RDE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QzY0RTZFMzE0RjkwNDdFQUI5M0U5N0ZFMjYyREMyQzU</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Education Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDkzNUEzQzFBNEZBNEFBREIxNDM5MTc1MUU5QjI4MTY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Construction &amp; Repair</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDM1MTA5QTJCQTk3NDNENzg0MkY2QjJFMjYxQjYzQTk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QTU5MTJDNDBCQkU0NEY2MEIyREVGRkM0Qzg1NjY5RTQ</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Governments</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjdEQjE4OUJDMzQxNDNEMEI0RTI1QUFCMzJENjEwRTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Types of Statutes</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6ODM0MTQxODNGMEIyNDI0QkE5NTYzMEJBM0E4NTJBM0U7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Q0M3QUYzNjlBN0UzNEVBMDk4OEIyMzdBMDlGQzA2RjI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Real Property Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QUUyRTcxRURBNEY2NEE2MDk3QzBCNzRDOEY0NTZDQzk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Assignments</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6ODVCN0FCRTQ3MEE4NEJCRkE3OTRGOUQzODE4RDZENjc7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDU3NDIyNUI2MzczNEUwMzk0M0Y4MkZDQjk2OUUyRTQ</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QzM1MEY0QkQzMjRCNEY3Q0IxMDdBN0U5RUFEMzZERTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QThCNUQyMTcxQjZENEE3QTk4NjIyRDhBMkNBNUI3RDI</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OUMxMzhDNkRFNkYxNEVCQzkxMzEzQTgyRjA3QzBEODA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6N0ZFMkU1NEFCMjY5NDY0MjhBNTE5Njk1QjZCNTkzMzI</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Rental Property Management</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NUM2MkQ2QTk3RTE5NEFCQjhBN0UzQkJGMkU0OTIyMjA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NTk0MkNDNEVCNEUyNDc5NTgxMDMyMzBEMUVFOTU1RTU</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Termination of Easements</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjkzNEZGNkREQzFCNERBREJDODlCMzJDNjIwRjVDMjI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6REY1N0QwQTgyRjkyNEQ2M0FDMDhDQzJCRTM1QTM4NTk</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification><classificationGroup classificationScheme="indexing-terms"><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem score="90"><className>Education</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDkzNUEzQzFBNEZBNEFBREIxNDM5MTc1MUU5QjI4MTY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></classificationGroup></metadata></legislativeDoc>