<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#349#000059#     1#          392#">Va. Code Ann. § 59.1-392</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_59.1-392"/><heading><desig>§ 59.1-392.</desig><title>Percentage retained; tax</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a"/><heading><desig>A.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Any person holding an operator's license to operate a horse racetrack or satellite facility in the Commonwealth pursuant to this chapter shall be authorized to conduct pari-mutuel wagering on horse racing subject to the provisions of this chapter and the conditions and regulations of the Commission.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b"/><heading><desig>B.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> On pari-mutuel pools generated by wagering at the racetrack on live horse racing conducted within the Commonwealth, involving win, place and show wagering, the licensee shall retain a percentage amount approved by the Commission as jointly requested by a recognized majority horsemen's group and a licensee and the legitimate breakage, out of which shall be paid one and one-quarter percent to be distributed as follows: one percent to the Commonwealth as a license tax and one-quarter percent to the locality in which the racetrack is located. The remainder of the retainage shall be paid as provided in subsection D, provided, however, that if the percentage amount approved by the Commission is other than 18 percent, the amounts provided in subdivisions D 1, 2 and 3 shall be adjusted by the proportion that the approved percentage amount bears to 18 percent.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c"/><heading><desig>C.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> On pari-mutuel pools generated by wagering at each Virginia satellite facility on live horse racing conducted within the Commonwealth, involving win, place and show wagering, the licensee shall retain a percentage amount approved by the Commission as jointly requested by a recognized majority horsemen's group and a licensee and the legitimate breakage, out of which shall be paid one and one-quarter percent to be distributed as follows: three-quarters percent to the Commonwealth as a license tax, one-quarter percent to the locality in which the satellite facility is located, and one-quarter percent to the locality in which the racetrack is located. The remainder of the retainage shall be paid as provided in subsection D; provided, however, that if the percentage amount approved by the Commission is other than 18 percent, the amounts provided in subdivisions D 1, 2 and 3 shall be adjusted by the proportion that the approved percentage amount bears to 18 percent.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d"/><heading><desig>D.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> On pari-mutuel pools generated by wagering at the racetrack and each Virginia satellite facility on live horse racing conducted within the Commonwealth, involving win, place and show wagering, the licensee shall retain a percentage amount approved by the Commission as jointly requested by a recognized majority horsemen's group and a licensee and the legitimate breakage, out of which shall be paid:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Eight percent as purses or prizes to the participants in such race meeting;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Seven and one-half percent, and all of the breakage and the proceeds of pari-mutuel tickets unredeemed 180 days from the date on which the race was conducted, to the operator;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> One percent to the Virginia Breeders Fund;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d_4"/><heading><desig>4.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Fifteen one-hundredths percent to the Virginia-Maryland Regional College of Veterinary Medicine;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d_5"/><heading><desig>5.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Five one-hundredths percent to the Virginia Horse Center Foundation;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d_6"/><heading><desig>6.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Five one-hundredths percent to the Virginia Horse Industry Board; and</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d_7"/><heading><desig>7.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The remainder of the retainage shall be paid as appropriate under subsection B or C.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_e"/><heading><desig>E.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> On pari-mutuel pools generated by wagering at the racetrack on live horse racing conducted within the Commonwealth involving wagering other than win, place and show wagering, the licensee shall retain a percentage amount approved by the Commission as jointly requested by a recognized majority horsemen's group and a licensee and the legitimate breakage, out of which shall be paid two and three-quarters percent to be distributed as follows: two and one-quarter percent to the Commonwealth as a license tax, and one-half percent to the locality in which the racetrack is located. The remainder of the retainage shall be paid as provided in subsection G; provided, however, that if the percentage amount approved by the Commission is other than 22 percent, the amounts provided in subdivisions G 1, 2 and 3 shall be adjusted by the proportion that the approved percentage amount bears to 22 percent.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_f"/><heading><desig>F.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> On pari-mutuel pools generated by wagering at each Virginia satellite facility on live horse racing conducted within the Commonwealth involving wagering other than win, place and show wagering, the licensee shall retain a percentage amount approved by the Commission as jointly requested by a recognized majority horsemen's group and a licensee and the legitimate breakage, out of which shall be paid two and three-quarters percent to be distributed as follows: one and three-quarters percent to the Commonwealth as a license tax, one-half percent to the locality in which the satellite facility is located, and one-half percent to the locality in which the racetrack is located. The remainder of the retainage shall be paid as provided in subsection G; provided, however, that if the percentage amount approved by the Commission is other than 22 percent, the amounts provided in subdivisions G 1, 2 and 3 shall be adjusted by the proportion that the approved percentage amount bears to 22 percent.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_g"/><heading><desig>G.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> On pari-mutuel pools generated by wagering at the racetrack and each Virginia satellite facility on live horse racing conducted within the Commonwealth involving wagering other than win, place and show wagering, the licensee shall retain a percentage amount approved by the Commission as jointly requested by a recognized majority horsemen's group and a licensee and the legitimate breakage, out of which shall be paid:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_g_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Nine percent as purses or prizes to the participants in such race meeting;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_g_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Nine percent, and the proceeds of the pari-mutuel tickets unredeemed 180 days from the date on which the race was conducted, to the operator;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_g_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> One percent to the Virginia Breeders Fund;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_g_4"/><heading><desig>4.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Fifteen one-hundredths percent to the Virginia-Maryland Regional College of Veterinary Medicine;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_g_5"/><heading><desig>5.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Five one-hundredths percent to the Virginia Horse Center Foundation;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_g_6"/><heading><desig>6.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Five one-hundredths percent to the Virginia Horse Industry Board; and</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_g_7"/><heading><desig>7.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The remainder of the retainage shall be paid as appropriate under subsection E or F.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_h"/><heading><desig>H.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> On pari-mutuel wagering generated by simulcast horse racing transmitted from jurisdictions outside the Commonwealth, the licensee may, with the approval of the Commission, commingle pools with the racetrack where the transmission emanates or establish separate pools for wagering within the Commonwealth. All simulcast horse racing in this subsection must comply with the Interstate Horse Racing Act of 1978 <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="15 USC 3001"><content><span normalizedCite="15 U.S.C. 3001">(15 U.S.C. § 3001<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1828#123#000015#       3001#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> et seq.).</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_i"/><heading><desig>I.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> On pari-mutuel pools generated by wagering at the racetrack on simulcast horse racing transmitted from jurisdictions outside the Commonwealth, involving win, place and show wagering, the licensee shall retain one and one-quarter percent of such pool to be distributed as follows: three-quarters percent to the Commonwealth as a license tax, and one-half percent to the Virginia locality in which the racetrack is located.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_j"/><heading><desig>J.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> On pari-mutuel pools generated by wagering at each Virginia satellite facility on simulcast horse racing transmitted from jurisdictions outside the Commonwealth, involving win, place and show wagering, the licensee shall retain one and one-quarter percent of such pool to be distributed as follows: three-quarters percent to the Commonwealth as a license tax, one-quarter percent to the locality in which the satellite facility is located, and one-quarter percent to the Virginia locality in which the racetrack is located.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_k"/><heading><desig>K.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> On pari-mutuel pools generated by wagering at the racetrack and each Virginia satellite facility on simulcast horse racing transmitted from jurisdictions outside the Commonwealth, involving win, place and show wagering, the licensee shall retain one and thirty one-hundredths percent of such pool to be distributed as follows:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_k_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> One percent of the pool to the Virginia Breeders Fund;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_k_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Fifteen one-hundredths percent to the Virginia-Maryland Regional College of Veterinary Medicine;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_k_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Five one-hundredths percent to the Virginia Horse Center Foundation;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_k_4"/><heading><desig>4.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Five one-hundredths percent to the Virginia Horse Industry Board; and</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_k_5"/><heading><desig>5.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Five one-hundredths percent to the Virginia Thoroughbred Association for the promotion of breeding in the Commonwealth.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_l"/><heading><desig>L.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> On pari-mutuel pools generated by wagering at the racetrack on simulcast horse racing transmitted from jurisdictions outside the Commonwealth, involving wagering other than win, place and show wagering, the licensee shall retain two and three-quarters percent of such pool to be distributed as follows: one and three-quarters percent to the Commonwealth as a license tax, and one percent to the Virginia locality in which the racetrack is located.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_m"/><heading><desig>M.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> On pari-mutuel pools generated by wagering at each Virginia satellite facility on simulcast horse racing transmitted from jurisdictions outside the Commonwealth, involving wagering other than win, place and show wagering, the licensee shall retain two and three-quarters percent of such pool to be distributed as follows: one and three-quarters percent to the Commonwealth as a license tax, one-half percent to the locality in which the satellite facility is located, and one-half percent to the Virginia locality in which the racetrack is located.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_n"/><heading><desig>N.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> On pari-mutuel pools generated by wagering at the racetrack and each Virginia satellite facility on simulcast horse racing transmitted from jurisdictions outside the Commonwealth, involving wagering other than win, place and show wagering, the licensee shall retain one and thirty one-hundredths percent of such pool to be distributed as follows:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_n_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> One percent of the pool to the Virginia Breeders Fund;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_n_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Fifteen one-hundredths percent to the Virginia-Maryland Regional College of Veterinary Medicine;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_n_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Five one-hundredths percent to the Virginia Horse Center Foundation;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_n_4"/><heading><desig>4.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Five one-hundredths percent to the Virginia Horse Industry Board; and</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_n_5"/><heading><desig>5.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Five one-hundredths percent to the Virginia Thoroughbred Association for the promotion of breeding in the Commonwealth.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_o"/><heading><desig>O.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Moneys payable to the Commonwealth shall be deposited in the general fund. Gross receipts for license tax purposes under Chapter 37 (<citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 58.1-3700"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 58.1-3700">§ 58.1-3700<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000058#     1#         3700#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> et seq.) of Title 58.1 shall not include pari-mutuel wagering pools and license taxes authorized by this section.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_p"/><heading><desig>P.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> All payments by the licensee to the Commonwealth or any locality shall be made within five days from the date on which such wagers are received by the licensee. All payments by the licensee to the Virginia Breeders Fund shall be made to the Commission within five days from the date on which such wagers are received by the licensee. All payments by the licensee to the Virginia-Maryland Regional College of Veterinary Medicine, the Virginia Horse Center Foundation, the Virginia Horse Industry Board, and the Virginia Thoroughbred Association shall be made by the first day of each quarter of the calendar year. All payments made under this section shall be used in support of the policy of the Commonwealth to sustain and promote the growth of a native industry.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_q"/><heading><desig>Q.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> If a satellite facility is located in more than one locality, any amount a licensee is required to pay under this section to the locality in which the satellite facility is located shall be prorated in equal shares among those localities.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_r"/><heading><desig>R.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Any contractual agreement between a licensee and other entities concerning the distribution of the remaining portion of the retainage under subsections I through N shall be subject to the approval of the Commission.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_s"/><heading><desig>S.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The recognized majority horsemen's group racing at a licensed race meeting may, subject to the approval of the Commission, withdraw for administrative costs associated with serving the interests of the horsemen an amount not to exceed two percent of the amount in the horsemen's account.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_t"/><heading><desig>T.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The legitimate breakage from each pari-mutuel pool for both live racing and simulcast horse racing shall be distributed as follows:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_t_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Seventy percent to be retained by the licensee to be used for capital improvements that are subject to approval of the Commission; and</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_t_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Thirty percent to be deposited in the Racing Benevolence Fund, administered jointly by the licensee and the recognized majority horsemen's group racing at a licensed race meeting, to be disbursed with the approval of the Commission for gambling addiction and substance abuse counseling, recreational, educational or other related programs.</p></bodyText></level></level><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p>1988, c. 855; <citation normalizedCite="1991 VA CH 591"><content><span normalizedCite="1991 Va. Ch. 591">1991, c. 591<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1991#000591#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1992 VA CH 820"><content><span normalizedCite="1992 Va. Ch. 820">1992, c. 820<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1992#000820#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1995 VA CH 217"><content><span normalizedCite="1995 Va. Ch. 217">1995, c. 217<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1995#000217#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1998 VA CH 608"><content><span normalizedCite="1998 Va. Ch. 608">1998, cc. 608<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1998#000608#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1998 VA CH 619"><content><span normalizedCite="1998 Va. Ch. 619">619<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1998#000619#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2000 VA CH 1031"><content><span normalizedCite="2000 Va. Ch. 1031">2000, c. 1031<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2000#001031#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2007 VA CH 61"><content><span normalizedCite="2007 Va. Ch. 61">2007, c. 61<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2007#000061#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2011 VA CH 732"><content><span normalizedCite="2011 Va. Ch. 732">2011, c. 732<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2011#000732#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2015 VA CH 731"><content><span normalizedCite="2015 Va. Ch. 731">2015, cc. 731<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2015#000731#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2015 VA CH 751"><content><span normalizedCite="2015 Va. Ch. 751">751<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2015#000751#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PV40-004G-K3H3-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 59.1.</desig><title>TRADE AND COMMERCE</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 29.</desig><title>HORSE RACING AND PARI-MUTUEL WAGERING</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="article"><heading><desig>ARTICLE 5.</desig><title>TAXATION AND AUDIT</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Gaming &amp; Lotteries</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NzJGRTBFOEMyOENBNDQ5MTg1NTA2NDdFQjhCNzhERjI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6M0JFMDdFQkREMkFENDRFMEFGRkJEQ0E4OTg1NEM5RTc</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Taxation</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6M0QyRjUyODU2OURFNDJDNEE4NkZCQzRENDE4NEQwODM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6M0E5MjdDNDRFRUIzNEJFNDkyMDk5MThGNTE5M0RFNEU</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Communications Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MEQxMkU0NzE2OEE2NDIxNEE3QzU0NjU2MDRERUNGNDE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Taxation</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6M0QyRjUyODU2OURFNDJDNEE4NkZCQzRENDE4NEQwODM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6M0E5MjdDNDRFRUIzNEJFNDkyMDk5MThGNTE5M0RFNEU</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Governments</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjdEQjE4OUJDMzQxNDNEMEI0RTI1QUFCMzJENjEwRTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Gaming &amp; Lotteries</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NzJGRTBFOEMyOENBNDQ5MTg1NTA2NDdFQjhCNzhERjI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QURCRDNBRjBGRTE0NEFBRUEzNUU1MzFGQjg3MTM4MDI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Tax Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OTNEM0E2OEE0RkQyNEY1MDhBQzdGMkQ4ODI4QTJDODE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Audits &amp; Investigations</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RDg3ODgwMDY2NTQwNEY2OEFFQjhDRENCNkE1RTU2MjY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjkxRkVDMkNDMjBGNDdFMkI1RDQ3Nzk4QjgwOTBGQjU</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Torts</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDAwOEM2NTEzQkVDNEI4NzlGMEZERUEyRjQwODM4Njg7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MkQwMTc0MUU5MzkxNEMwQzhEQkU0QjA2REQzQzNGMTc7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RjMzQjNFQ0U1MDdFNEQzMjg0MTA0MTY4MUZCQTZBM0U</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Swimming Areas</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NzVBQUUxODAzRThENEIxRTk4M0U4OUEzNTgwNURBQzE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MzQ0MzhGMDJGM0I2NDEzRkEyRjk1QTUxQUI0NTlCOTQ</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Transportation Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RTYzRTk5RDVBQkQ2NDcwQzk2NTU3ODQ5OEE3NDlBNzk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6M0RGOEU0NUFFOTU3NDUxNjhEOEIxMDE2NUU1NzRDQUQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6ODY1RjFBNDEzNUFBNEYzMjhCMjhDRkU1NDlCQ0U3RkU</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification><classificationGroup classificationScheme="indexing-terms"><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem score="90"><className>Antitrust</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6REEyRTNDM0JGQzYyNEMyOEFGNTAwNUJEOUU1MDg4NjU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></classificationGroup></metadata></legislativeDoc>