<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#349#000028#     2#          508#">Va. Code Ann. § 28.2-508</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_28.2-508"/><heading><desig>§ 28.2-508.</desig><title>Prohibited area for patent tongs; penalty</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><bodyText><p>It is unlawful for any person to use or employ patent tongs to take or catch oysters from the public rocks, beds, or shoals in the following areas:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> In the Piankatank River and its tributaries above a line beginning at the extreme westernmost point on a wooden jetty (point "A") on the south property line of lot 9-A owned by E. B. Bottom and lot 8-A of Gwynn's Island Estate subdivision, Mathews County (Deed Book 55; page No.  279), said point located north 57 degrees 07', west 176.00 feet from the east side of said lot 8-A and 9-A. Said point is located on the extreme northwest section of Gwynn's Island known as Cherry Point, Mathews County; thence 71 degrees 00' west approximately 10,140 feet, to a survey point known as the Stove R, located on the extreme south end of Stove Point, Middlesex County; thence north 38 degrees 00' east approximately 14,960 feet to point "X," or the east gable of hotel, located on the extreme easternmost point of Stingray Point, Middlesex County. This area is to include all of Piankatank River and its tributaries from Cherry Point of Gwynn's Island to Stove Point in Middlesex County, and all of the area of Jackson Creek and its tributaries from Stove Point to Stingray Point;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> In the Rappahannock River and its tributaries, above a line drawn from the southernmost point of Belle Island, which line begins at latitude 37 degrees 46' 37" north, longitude 76 degrees 35' 40" west; thence south 27 degrees 47' 25.82" west 14,292.65 feet to the easternmost point of Punchbowl Point, which is located at latitude 37 degrees 44' 32" and longitude 76 degrees 37' 03" west;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Beginning on the south shore of the James River at Pig Point, located at the east mouth of Nansemond River opposite the westernmost tank of two tanks on Pig Point; thence in a northerly direction to a light at the extreme north end of abandoned Pig Point pier; thence in a northerly direction to a fish trap buoy designated as N "H11" located on the northeast side of the Fish Trap Reservation; thence in a northwest direction along the northeast boundary of the Fish Trap Reservation along a line of buoys designated as C "1" and C "H15"; buoy C "H15" being located on the east side of an area set aside in subdivision 5 of this section prohibiting the use of patent tongs in James River; thence following in a southwest direction along the area described in subdivision 5 of this section to Cooper's Creek, located on the south side of James River in Isle of Wight County. In addition to this described area, the use of patent tongs shall be prohibited in Batten Bay and its tributaries, Chuckatuck Creek and its tributaries, and Nansemond River and its tributaries;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_4"/><heading><desig>4.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> In the Mobjack Bay and its tributaries above a line beginning at Bush Point on the south side of the mouth of the Severn River, Gloucester County; thence in a northeasterly direction across the mouth of the Severn River to Seven Cedar Point; thence in a southeasterly direction to buoy S "1"; thence in an east southeasterly direction to a point of land on the northwest side of the mouth of Pepper Creek in Mathews County;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_5"/><heading><desig>5.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> In the James River and its tributaries above a line drawn from Cooper's Creek in Isle of Wight County on the south side of James River to a line in a northeasterly direction across James River to the Newport News municipal water tank located on Warwick Boulevard between 59th Street and 60th Street in the City of Newport News;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_6"/><heading><desig>6.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> In the Corrotoman River above a line beginning at point on Corrotoman Point, which line begins at latitude 37 degrees 39' 56" north, longitude 76 degrees 28' 21" west; thence north 70 degrees 02' 46.79"; thence west 4,338.37 feet to a point on Millenbeck Point which is located at latitude 37 degrees 40' 10" north and longitude 76 degrees 29' 12" west. This line, as described, is to include all of the Corrotoman River and its tributaries from Corrotoman Point to Millenbeck Point.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><bodyText><p>A violation of this section is a Class 1 misdemeanor.</p></bodyText></level><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p>Code 1950, §§ 28-93, 28-93.1, 28-93.2; 1954, c. 38; 1958, cc. 182, 476; 1960, c. 517; 1962, c. 406, § 28.1-83; 1968, c. 747; 1978, c. 208; 1980, c. 325; 1981, c. 52; 1986, c. 254; <citation normalizedCite="1992 VA CH 836"><content><span normalizedCite="1992 Va. Ch. 836">1992, c. 836<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1992#000836#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PV40-004G-K3KX-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 28.2.</desig><title>FISHERIES AND HABITAT OF THE TIDAL WATERS</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="subtitle"><heading><desig>SUBTITLE II.</desig><title>TIDAL FISHERIES</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 5.</desig><title>OYSTERS AND CLAMS</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="article"><heading><desig>ARTICLE 2.</desig><title>FISHING FOR OYSTERS AND CLAMS; DEVICE RESTRICTIONS</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Real Property Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QUUyRTcxRURBNEY2NEE2MDk3QzBCNzRDOEY0NTZDQzk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Fishing</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Rjk5MEU1MjBBODdGNDIxMzlGRTAzMjczQ0VDQzg5NzQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NjkyMjE3M0YxQTQ1NEU2MzgxNTdFRDYzRjBFN0Q4MDU</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></metadata></legislativeDoc>