<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#349#000004#     1#          208#">Va. Code Ann. § 4.1-208</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_4.1-208"/><heading><desig>§ 4.1-208.</desig><title>Beer licenses</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a"/><heading><desig>A.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The Board may grant the following licenses relating to beer:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Brewery licenses, which shall authorize the licensee to manufacture beer and to sell and deliver or ship the beer so manufactured, in accordance with Board regulations, in closed containers to (i) persons licensed to sell the beer at wholesale; (ii) persons licensed to sell beer at retail for the purpose of resale within a theme or amusement park owned and operated by the brewery or a parent, subsidiary or a company under common control of such brewery, or upon property of such brewery or a parent, subsidiary or a company under common control of such brewery contiguous to such premises, or in a development contiguous to such premises owned and operated by such brewery or a parent, subsidiary or a company under common control of such brewery; and (iii) persons outside the Commonwealth for resale outside the Commonwealth. Such license shall also authorize the licensee to sell at retail the brands of beer that the brewery owns at premises described in the brewery license for on-premises consumption and in closed containers for off-premises consumption.</p><p><pre/>Such license may also authorize individuals holding a brewery license to (a) operate a facility designed for and utilized exclusively for the education of persons in the manufacture of beer, including sampling by such individuals of beer products, within a theme or amusement park located upon the premises occupied by such brewery, or upon property of such person contiguous to such premises, or in a development contiguous to such premises owned and operated by such person or a wholly owned subsidiary or (b) offer samples of the brewery's products to individuals visiting the licensed premises, provided that such samples shall be provided only to individuals for consumption on the premises of such facility or licensed premises and only to individuals to whom such products may be lawfully sold.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Limited brewery licenses, to breweries that manufacture no more than 15,000 barrels of beer per calendar year, provided that (i) the brewery is located on a farm in the Commonwealth on land zoned agricultural and owned or leased by such brewery or its owner and (ii) agricultural products, including barley, other grains, hops, or fruit, used by such brewery in the manufacture of its beer are grown on the farm. The licensed premises shall be limited to the portion of the farm on which agricultural products, including barley, other grains, hops, or fruit, used by such brewery in the manufacture of its beer are grown and that is contiguous to the premises of such brewery where the beer is manufactured, exclusive of any residence and the curtilage thereof. However, the Board may, with notice to the local governing body in accordance with the provisions of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 4.1-230"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 4.1-230">§ 4.1-230<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000004#     1#          230#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, also approve other portions of the farm to be included as part of the licensed premises. For purposes of this subdivision, "land zoned agricultural" means (a) land zoned as an agricultural district or classification or (b) land otherwise permitted by a locality for limited brewery use. For purposes of this subdivision, "land zoned agricultural" does not include land zoned "residential conservation." Except for the limitation on land zoned "residential conservation," nothing in this definition shall otherwise limit or affect local zoning authority.</p><p><pre/>Limited brewery licensees shall be treated as breweries for all purposes of this title except as otherwise provided in this subdivision.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Bottlers' licenses, which shall authorize the licensee to acquire and receive deliveries and shipments of beer in closed containers and to bottle, sell and deliver or ship it, in accordance with Board regulations to (i) wholesale beer licensees for the purpose of resale, (ii) owners of boats registered under the laws of the United States sailing for ports of call of a foreign country or another state, and (iii) persons outside the Commonwealth for resale outside the Commonwealth.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_4"/><heading><desig>4.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Wholesale beer licenses, which shall authorize the licensee to acquire and receive deliveries and shipments of beer and to sell and deliver or ship the beer from one or more premises identified in the license, in accordance with Board regulations, in closed containers to (i) persons licensed under this chapter to sell such beer at wholesale or retail for the purpose of resale, (ii) owners of boats registered under the laws of the United States sailing for ports of call of a foreign country or another state, and (iii) persons outside the Commonwealth for resale outside the Commonwealth.</p><p><pre/>No wholesale beer licensee shall purchase beer for resale from a person outside the Commonwealth who does not hold a beer importer's license unless such wholesale beer licensee holds a beer importer's license and purchases beer for resale pursuant to the privileges of such beer importer's license.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_5"/><heading><desig>5.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Beer importers' licenses, which shall authorize persons licensed within or outside the Commonwealth to sell and deliver or ship beer into the Commonwealth, in accordance with Board regulations, in closed containers, to persons in the Commonwealth licensed to sell beer at wholesale for the purpose of resale.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_6"/><heading><desig>6.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Retail on-premises beer licenses to:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_6_a"/><heading><desig>a.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Hotels, restaurants, and clubs, which shall authorize the licensee to sell beer, either with or without meals, only in dining areas and other designated areas of such restaurants, or in dining areas, private guest rooms, and other designated areas of such hotels or clubs, for consumption only in such rooms and areas. For purposes of this subdivision, "other designated areas" includes outdoor dining areas, whether or not contiguous to the licensed premises, which may have more than one means of ingress and egress to an adjacent public thoroughfare, provided that such outdoor dining areas are under the control of the licensee and approved by the Board. Such noncontiguous designated areas shall not be approved for any retail license issued pursuant to subdivision A 5 of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 4.1-201"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 4.1-201">§ 4.1-201<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000004#     1#          201#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_6_b"/><heading><desig>b.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Persons operating dining cars, buffet cars, and club cars of trains, which shall authorize the licensee to sell beer, either with or without meals, in the dining cars, buffet cars, and club cars so operated by them for on-premises consumption when carrying passengers.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_6_c"/><heading><desig>c.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Persons operating sight-seeing boats, or special or charter boats, which shall authorize the licensee to sell beer, either with or without meals, on such boats operated by them for on-premises consumption when carrying passengers.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_6_d"/><heading><desig>d.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Grocery stores located in any town or in a rural area outside the corporate limits of any city or town, which shall authorize the licensee to sell beer for on-premises consumption in such establishments. No license shall be granted unless it appears affirmatively that a substantial public demand for such licensed establishment exists and that public convenience and the purposes of this title will be promoted by granting the license.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_6_e"/><heading><desig>e.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Persons operating food concessions at coliseums, stadia, or similar facilities, which shall authorize the licensee to sell beer, in paper, plastic, or similar disposable containers, during the performance of professional sporting exhibitions, events or performances immediately subsequent thereto, to patrons within all seating areas, concourses, walkways, concession areas, and additional locations designated by the Board in such coliseums, stadia, or similar facilities, for on-premises consumption. Upon authorization of the licensee, any person may keep and consume his own lawfully acquired alcoholic beverages on the premises in all areas and locations covered by the license.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_6_f"/><heading><desig>f.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Persons operating food concessions at any outdoor performing arts amphitheater, arena or similar facility which has seating for more than 3,500 persons and is located in Albemarle, Augusta, Pittsylvania, Nelson, or Rockingham Counties. Such license shall authorize the licensee to sell beer during the performance of any event, in paper, plastic or similar disposable containers to patrons within all seating areas, concourses, walkways, concession areas, or similar facilities, for on-premises consumption. Upon authorization of the licensee, any person may keep and consume his own lawfully acquired alcoholic beverages on the premises in all areas and locations covered by the license.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_6_g"/><heading><desig>g.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Persons operating food concessions at exhibition or exposition halls, convention centers or similar facilities located in any county operating under the urban county executive form of government or any city which is completely surrounded by such county, which shall authorize the licensee to sell beer during the event, in paper, plastic or similar disposable containers to patrons or attendees within all seating areas, exhibition areas, concourses, walkways, concession areas, and such additional locations designated by the Board in such facilities, for on-premises consumption. Upon authorization of the licensee, any person may keep and consume his own lawfully acquired alcoholic beverages on the premises in all areas and locations covered by the license. For purposes of this subsection, "exhibition or exposition halls" and "convention centers" mean facilities conducting private or public trade shows or exhibitions in an indoor facility having in excess of 100,000 square feet of floor space.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_7"/><heading><desig>7.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Retail off-premises beer licenses, which shall authorize the licensee to sell beer in closed containers for off-premises consumption.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_8"/><heading><desig>8.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Retail off-premises brewery licenses to persons holding a brewery license which shall authorize the licensee to sell beer at the place of business designated in the brewery license, in closed containers which shall include growlers and other reusable containers, for off-premises consumption.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_9"/><heading><desig>9.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Retail on-and-off premises beer licenses to persons enumerated in subdivisions 6 a and 6 d, which shall accord all the privileges conferred by retail on-premises beer licenses and in addition, shall authorize the licensee to sell beer in closed containers for off-premises consumption.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b"/><heading><desig>B.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Any farm winery or limited brewery that, prior to July 1, 2016, (i) holds a valid license granted by the Alcoholic Beverage Control Board (the Board) in accordance with this title and (ii) is in compliance with the local zoning ordinance as an agricultural district or classification or as otherwise permitted by a locality for farm winery or limited brewery use shall be allowed to continue such use as provided in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 15.2-2307"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 15.2-2307">§ 15.2-2307<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000015#     2#         2307#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, notwithstanding (a) the provisions of this section or (b) a subsequent change in ownership of the farm winery or limited brewery on or after July 1, 2016, whether by transfer, acquisition, inheritance, or other means. Any such farm winery or limited brewery located on land zoned residential conservation prior to July 1, 2016 may expand any existing building or structure and the uses thereof so long as specifically approved by the locality by special exception. Any such farm winery or limited brewery located on land zoned residential conservation prior to July 1, 2016 may construct a new building or structure so long as specifically approved by the locality by special exception. All such licensees shall comply with the requirements of this title and Board regulations for renewal of such license or the issuance of a new license in the event of a change in ownership of the farm winery or limited brewery on or after July 1, 2016.</p></bodyText></level><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p>Code 1950, § 4-25; 1952, c. 535; 1956, c. 520; 1962, c. 532; 1964, c. 210; 1970, cc. 627, 723; 1972, c. 679; 1973, c. 343; 1974, c. 267; 1975, c. 408; 1976, cc. 134, 447, 496, 703; 1977, c. 439; 1978, c. 190; 1979, c. 258; 1980, cc. 526, 528; 1981, cc. 410, 412; 1982, c. 66; 1984, c. 200; 1987, c. 365; 1988, c. 893; <citation normalizedCite="1989 VA CH 42"><content><span normalizedCite="1989 Va. Ch. 42">1989, c. 42<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1989#000042#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1990 VA CH 707"><content><span normalizedCite="1990 Va. Ch. 707">1990, c. 707<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1990#000707#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1991 VA CH 628"><content><span normalizedCite="1991 Va. Ch. 628">1991, c. 628<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1991#000628#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1992 VA CH 215"><content><span normalizedCite="1992 Va. Ch. 215">1992, cc. 215<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1992#000215#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1992 VA CH 350"><content><span normalizedCite="1992 Va. Ch. 350">350<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1992#000350#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1993 VA CH 828"><content><span normalizedCite="1993 Va. Ch. 828">1993, cc. 828<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1993#000828#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1993 VA CH 866"><content><span normalizedCite="1993 Va. Ch. 866">866<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1993#000866#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1994 VA CH 585"><content><span normalizedCite="1994 Va. Ch. 585">1994, c. 585<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1994#000585#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1995 VA CH 497"><content><span normalizedCite="1995 Va. Ch. 497">1995, cc. 497<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1995#000497#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1995 VA CH 518"><content><span normalizedCite="1995 Va. Ch. 518">518<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1995#000518#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1995 VA CH 544"><content><span normalizedCite="1995 Va. Ch. 544">544<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1995#000544#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1995 VA CH 570"><content><span normalizedCite="1995 Va. Ch. 570">570<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1995#000570#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1996 VA CH 443"><content><span normalizedCite="1996 Va. Ch. 443">1996, cc. 443<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1996#000443#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1996 VA CH 604"><content><span normalizedCite="1996 Va. Ch. 604">604<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1996#000604#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1997 VA CH 489"><content><span normalizedCite="1997 Va. Ch. 489">1997, cc. 489<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1997#000489#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1997 VA CH 646"><content><span normalizedCite="1997 Va. Ch. 646">646<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1997#000646#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1997 VA CH 662"><content><span normalizedCite="1997 Va. Ch. 662">662<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1997#000662#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2000 VA CH 1047"><content><span normalizedCite="2000 Va. Ch. 1047">2000, c. 1047<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2000#001047#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2003 VA CH 329"><content><span normalizedCite="2003 Va. Ch. 329">2003, cc. 329<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2003#000329#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2003 VA CH 1029"><content><span normalizedCite="2003 Va. Ch. 1029">1029<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2003#001029#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2003 VA CH 1030"><content><span normalizedCite="2003 Va. Ch. 1030">1030<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2003#001030#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2006 VA CH 845"><content><span normalizedCite="2006 Va. Ch. 845">2006, c. 845<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2006#000845#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2007 VA CH 813"><content><span normalizedCite="2007 Va. Ch. 813">2007, cc. 813<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2007#000813#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2007 VA CH 870"><content><span normalizedCite="2007 Va. Ch. 870">870<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2007#000870#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2007 VA CH 932"><content><span normalizedCite="2007 Va. Ch. 932">932<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2007#000932#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2012 VA CH 619"><content><span normalizedCite="2012 Va. Ch. 619">2012, c. 619<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2012#000619#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2014 VA CH 365"><content><span normalizedCite="2014 Va. Ch. 365">2014, c. 365<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2014#000365#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2015 VA CH 412"><content><span normalizedCite="2015 Va. Ch. 412">2015, c. 412<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2015#000412#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2016 VA CH 671"><content><span normalizedCite="2016 Va. Ch. 671">2016, cc. 671<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2016#000671#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2016 VA CH 710"><content><span normalizedCite="2016 Va. Ch. 710">710<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2016#000710#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PTX0-004G-K01M-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 4.1.</desig><title>ALCOHOLIC BEVERAGE CONTROL ACT</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 2.</desig><title>ADMINISTRATION OF LICENSES</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="article"><heading><desig>ARTICLE 2.</desig><title>LICENSES GRANTED BY BOARD; LIMITATIONS; REVOCATION AND SUSPENSION</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Admiralty &amp; Maritime Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QzRDNDVDOTdGRUQ1NDE1M0I1RjRBRDFBRTI3ODFGMDk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Licensing &amp; Registration</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QkQ2NzAwOTIzNjIwNDJCQTkyRTYwQzM3RkY2NUJFNDk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NUNBQjc0Q0M5OTI5NEU1RUFCODY4OTgyODhCNkM0OTg</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Distribution, Processing &amp; Storage of Food &amp; Agricultural Products</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NENGNzZCMDU5RjcyNEM0NEFFOUU4ODFCQkZCOThBRkI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NkVDMzM4QkJENTg3NDQ0RDg3NTA5OEM3RkMyQTlENDI</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Licensing &amp; Registration</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6ODIzRDQwRTNBQUZBNDI2MTlFRjcxQTkyNEQzNzUyNzA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUJGMzIwOUU1NUY0NDU3MzhFRjhFRkMxQzgxOEI3MEY</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Vessel Licensing &amp; Registration</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QkQ2NzAwOTIzNjIwNDJCQTkyRTYwQzM3RkY2NUJFNDk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QzRDNDVDOTdGRUQ1NDE1M0I1RjRBRDFBRTI3ODFGMDk</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Governments</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjdEQjE4OUJDMzQxNDNEMEI0RTI1QUFCMzJENjEwRTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Administrative Boards</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QTYwRUFCMDc5MzQ5NDEyREFEQkU2NkE2MjRGQTlCNzY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Njg1MkM3RkYyNzIxNEVFRkJFMTI2NUM4NUU1ODdEM0Q</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Distribution, Processing &amp; Storage</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NENGNzZCMDU5RjcyNEM0NEFFOUU4ODFCQkZCOThBRkI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NkVDMzM4QkJENTg3NDQ0RDg3NTA5OEM3RkMyQTlENDI</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Duties &amp; Powers</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Njk1NTNGMzM0RTc3NDcyMUI4MENCQUQ1RDhEN0M1RUM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Njg1MkM3RkYyNzIxNEVFRkJFMTI2NUM4NUU1ODdEM0Q</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Licenses</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QUQzRDFDRDE0OTA0NDU2OEIwMUZCNDZEQTBBODdCODA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Njg1MkM3RkYyNzIxNEVFRkJFMTI2NUM4NUU1ODdEM0Q</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>International Trade Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RTRDNDkyQ0UwRkRGNEQ0MjgwNzM2NzI3NjlGODE0ODk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RkZGQjYyNTBDQTZBNDQzRjg5NkI1MDc5QzgyOTQwNDM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6REI1NUFFNkQ3REY5NEVDRUIzRTlEMjA5MUQwREI1QTE</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OTYyRUM0QjJCRTY0NDFGOUE1MjYxQjcxRkE2MDAyMkQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QUQwOThCQjVCQzk4NEU4NUIzQUQ1RUVBNTExRDhCQzM</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Real Property Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QUUyRTcxRURBNEY2NEE2MDk3QzBCNzRDOEY0NTZDQzk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Variances</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RkIxOThDMjUxN0JFNEEwNkI3MDNEMTA2NzdBMzU5REI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NjcyQTdEMEUxODYyNDY0OThFQTg1NUNGMjFBMTkxQ0M</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Transportation Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RTYzRTk5RDVBQkQ2NDcwQzk2NTU3ODQ5OEE3NDlBNzk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Licensing &amp; Registration</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6ODIzRDQwRTNBQUZBNDI2MTlFRjcxQTkyNEQzNzUyNzA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUJGMzIwOUU1NUY0NDU3MzhFRjhFRkMxQzgxOEI3MEY</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></metadata></legislativeDoc>