<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#349#000062#     1#        134.1#">Va. Code Ann. § 62.1-134.1</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_62.1-134.1"/><heading><desig>§ 62.1-134.1.</desig><title>Expediting shipment of coal</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a"/><heading><desig>A.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The Authority shall analyze the shipment of coal through the ports of the Commonwealth for the purpose of expediting such shipments. For this purpose, the Authority shall be authorized to collect, analyze, and require the furnishing of information, which is maintained in the ordinary course of business by the person, firm, or corporation providing such information, pertaining to the transportation of coal which has been moved to and from the ports of this Commonwealth, including:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> From a railway company or any subsidiary thereof involved in the shipment or storage of coal -- the inland origin; the identity of any transshipper, the rail destination; the route; the car movement record, whether such movement was pursuant to permit or agreement; the date of issuance of permits; the date and time of vessel registration; the position in vessel queue at the time of registration and at the time such vessel was ordered to berth for loading; and date such vessel was loaded;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> From any railway company, supplier, mining company, or transshipper -- the tonnage and classification of coal loaded aboard such vessel;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> From any transshipper -- the identity of any supplier, broker, transshipper, or purchaser of coal for shipment by railway;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_4"/><heading><desig>4.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> From any ship line, shipping company, ship agent, wholesaler, retailer, broker, transshipper, or operator of any coal storage facility -- the identity of any vessel loaded with coal, the date of such vessel's arrival at port, the date such vessel departed and the tonnage and classification of coal loaded aboard such vessel; and</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_5"/><heading><desig>5.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> From any of the parties mentioned in subdivisions 1, 2, 3, or 4 -- any other information which is relevant and necessary to such analysis of shipment of coal through the ports of the Commonwealth provided such information is maintained in the ordinary course of business of such person, firm, or corporation.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b"/><heading><desig>B.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Notwithstanding any provisions of law to the contrary, any person, firm, corporation or agent thereof engaged in the mining, consignment, sale, transportation, loading, unloading, storage, or handling of coal for shipment through any port of this Commonwealth, whether as a mining company, railway company, ship line, shipping company, ship agent, wholesaler, retailer, broker, transshipper, operator of any coal storage facility, or facility for the loading or unloading of railroad cars or ships, or any entity otherwise engaged in an activity which directly affects the transportation of coal to or from any port of this Commonwealth, within forty-five days after receiving a written request from the Authority, shall furnish the Authority with any such information as is described in subsection A of this section as is maintained in the ordinary course of business of the party requested to provide the information. In the event of willful noncompliance with the provisions of this section by any person, firm, or corporation, the Authority may petition an appropriate circuit court for injunctive relief or, in the alternative, for recovery of a civil penalty, payable to the Authority, in an amount no less than $ 100 per day and no more than $ 1,000 per day for each day noncompliance continues. Upon a finding that the defendant's noncompliance was willful, the court shall order compliance or payment of the civil penalty, as the case may be.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c"/><heading><desig>C.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The aforesaid information and data shall be supplied to the Executive Director of the Authority and shall be for the exclusive use of the Executive Director and the staff of the Authority. Neither the Executive Director nor any staff member of the Authority shall disclose this information and data to any member of the Board of Commissioners of the Authority; nor to any person, firm, corporation or agent thereof engaged in the mining, consignment, sale, transportation, loading, unloading, storage, or handling of coal, whether such person, firm, corporation or agent be public or private and whether or not such person, firm, corporation, or agent be a subsidiary or unit of the Authority; nor to anyone outside the Authority.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d"/><heading><desig>D.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> In carrying out the functions heretofore described the Authority shall be deemed to be performing essential governmental functions as an agent of the Commonwealth of Virginia.</p></bodyText></level><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p>1981, c. 464.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PTM0-004G-K11W-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 62.1.</desig><title>WATERS OF THE STATE, PORTS AND HARBORS</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 10.</desig><title>VIRGINIA PORT AUTHORITY</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Admiralty &amp; Maritime Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QzRDNDVDOTdGRUQ1NDE1M0I1RjRBRDFBRTI3ODFGMDk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Licensing &amp; Registration</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QkQ2NzAwOTIzNjIwNDJCQTkyRTYwQzM3RkY2NUJFNDk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NUNBQjc0Q0M5OTI5NEU1RUFCODY4OTgyODhCNkM0OTg</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Vessel Licensing &amp; Registration</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QkQ2NzAwOTIzNjIwNDJCQTkyRTYwQzM3RkY2NUJFNDk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QzRDNDVDOTdGRUQ1NDE1M0I1RjRBRDFBRTI3ODFGMDk</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Energy &amp; Utilities Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OUUzODAyRDk1QzVFNEZGMEJDM0RGMDYxOTlEMEEzRDA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QTU2OEY2MjlCMTQ4NEI1MTkwOEU5RUYyMTcxMDUzRUQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NkEyREE0NkU0MUQwNDhFQ0I0RTdBN0FCN0U2QzhDMTI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification><classificationGroup classificationScheme="indexing-terms"><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem score="90"><className>Admiralty &amp; Maritime</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QzRDNDVDOTdGRUQ1NDE1M0I1RjRBRDFBRTI3ODFGMDk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem score="90"><className>Transportation</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RTYzRTk5RDVBQkQ2NDcwQzk2NTU3ODQ5OEE3NDlBNzk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></classificationGroup></metadata></legislativeDoc>