<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#123#000055#     248.4#">Va. Code Ann. § 55-248.4</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_55-248.4"/><heading><desig>§ 55-248.4.</desig><title>Definitions</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><bodyText><p>When used in this chapter, unless expressly stated otherwise:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><bodyText><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Action"</emphasis> means recoupment, counterclaim, set off, or other civil suit and any other proceeding in which rights are determined, including without limitation actions for possession, rent, unlawful detainer, unlawful entry, and distress for rent.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Application deposit"</emphasis> means any refundable deposit of money, however denominated, including all money intended to be used as a security deposit under a rental agreement, or property, which is paid by a tenant to a landlord for the purpose of being considered as a tenant for a dwelling unit.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Application fee"</emphasis> means any nonrefundable fee, which is paid by a tenant to a landlord or managing agent for the purpose of being considered as a tenant for a dwelling unit. An application fee shall not exceed $ 50, exclusive of any actual out-of-pocket expenses paid by the landlord to a third party performing background, credit, or other pre-occupancy checks on the applicant. However, where an application is being made for a dwelling unit which is a public housing unit or other housing unit subject to regulation by the Department of Housing and Urban Development, an application fee shall not exceed $ 32, exclusive of any actual out-of-pocket expenses paid to a third party by the landlord performing background, credit, or other pre-occupancy checks on the applicant.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Assignment"</emphasis> means the transfer by any tenant of all interests created by a rental agreement.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Authorized occupant"</emphasis> means a person entitled to occupy a dwelling unit with the consent of the landlord, but who has not signed the rental agreement and therefore does not have the financial obligations as a tenant under the rental agreement.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Building or housing code"</emphasis> means any law, ordinance or governmental regulation concerning fitness for habitation, or the construction, maintenance, operation, occupancy, use or appearance of any structure or that part of a structure that is used as a home, residence or sleeping place by one person who maintains a household or by two or more persons who maintain a common household.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Commencement date of rental agreement"</emphasis> means the date upon which the tenant is entitled to occupy the dwelling unit as a tenant.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Dwelling unit"</emphasis> means a structure or part of a structure that is used as a home or residence by one or more persons who maintain a household, including, but not limited to, a manufactured home.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Effective date of rental agreement"</emphasis> means the date upon which the rental agreement is signed by the landlord and the tenant obligating each party to the terms and conditions of the rental agreement.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Facility"</emphasis> means something that is built, constructed, installed or established to perform some particular function.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Good faith"</emphasis> means honesty in fact in the conduct of the transaction concerned.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Guest or invitee"</emphasis> means a person, other than the tenant or person authorized by the landlord to occupy the premises, who has the permission of the tenant to visit but not to occupy the premises.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Interior of the dwelling unit"</emphasis> means the inside of the dwelling unit, consisting of interior walls, floor, and ceiling, that enclose the dwelling unit as conditioned space from the outside air.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Landlord"</emphasis> means the owner, lessor or sublessor of the dwelling unit or the building of which such dwelling unit is a part. "Landlord" also includes a managing agent of the premises who fails to disclose the name of such owner, lessor or sublessor. Such managing agent shall be subject to the provisions of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 16.1-88.03"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 16.1-88.03">§ 16.1-88.03.<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000016#     1#        88.03#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> Landlord shall not, however, include a community land trust as defined in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 55-221.1"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 55 -221.1">§ 55-221.1.<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#123#000055#     221.1#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation></p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Managing agent"</emphasis> means a person authorized by the landlord to act on behalf of the landlord under an agreement.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Mold remediation in accordance with professional standards"</emphasis> means mold remediation of that portion of the dwelling unit or premises affected by mold, or any personal property of the tenant affected by mold, performed consistent with guidance documents published by the United States Environmental Protection Agency, the U.S. Department of Housing and Urban Development, the American Conference of Governmental Industrial Hygienists (the Bioaerosols Manual), Standard Reference Guides of the Institute of Inspection, Cleaning and Restoration for Water Damage Restoration and Professional Mold Remediation, or any protocol for mold remediation prepared by an industrial hygienist consistent with said guidance documents.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Natural person,"</emphasis> wherever the chapter refers to an owner as a "natural person," includes co-owners who are natural persons, either as tenants in common, joint tenants, tenants in partnership, tenants by the entirety, trustees or beneficiaries of a trust, general partnerships, limited liability partnerships, registered limited liability partnerships or limited liability companies, or any lawful combination of natural persons permitted by law.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Notice"</emphasis> means notice given in writing by either regular mail or hand delivery, with the sender retaining sufficient proof of having given such notice, which may be either a United States postal certificate of mailing or a certificate of service confirming such mailing prepared by the sender. However, a person shall be deemed to have notice of a fact if he has actual knowledge of it, he has received a verbal notice of it, or from all of the facts and circumstances known to him at the time in question, he has reason to know it exists. A person "notifies" or "gives" a notice or notification to another by taking steps reasonably calculated to inform another person whether or not the other person actually comes to know of it. If notice is given that is not in writing, the person giving the notice has the burden of proof to show that the notice was given to the recipient of the notice.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Organization"</emphasis> means a corporation, government, governmental subdivision or agency, business trust, estate, trust, partnership or association, two or more persons having a joint or common interest, or any combination thereof, and any other legal or commercial entity.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><bodyText><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Owner"</emphasis> means one or more persons or entities, jointly or severally, in whom is vested:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> All or part of the legal title to the property, or</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> All or part of the beneficial ownership and a right to present use and enjoyment of the premises, and the term includes a mortgagee in possession.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><bodyText><p><pre/>"Person" means any individual, group of individuals, corporation, partnership, business trust, association or other legal entity, or any combination thereof.</p><p><pre/>"Premises" means a dwelling unit and the structure of which it is a part and facilities and appurtenances therein and grounds, areas and facilities held out for the use of tenants generally or whose use is promised to the tenant.</p><p><pre/><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Processing fee for payment of rent with bad check"</emphasis> means the processing fee specified in the rental agreement, not to exceed $ 50, assessed by a landlord against a tenant for payment of rent with a check drawn by the tenant on which payment has been refused by the payor bank because the drawer had no account or insufficient funds.</p><p><pre/><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Readily accessible"</emphasis> means areas within the interior of the dwelling unit available for observation at the time of the move-in inspection that do not require removal of materials, personal property, equipment or similar items.</p><p><pre/><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Rent"</emphasis> means all money, other than a security deposit, owed or paid to the landlord under the rental agreement, including prepaid rent paid more than one month in advance of the rent due date.</p><p><pre/><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Rental agreement"</emphasis> or <emphasis typeStyle="it">"lease agreement"</emphasis> means all agreements, written or oral, and valid rules and regulations adopted under <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 55-248.17"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 55 -248.17">§ 55-248.17<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#123#000055#    248.17#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> embodying the terms and conditions concerning the use and occupancy of a dwelling unit and premises.</p><p><pre/><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Rental application"</emphasis> means the written application or similar document used by a landlord to determine if a prospective tenant is qualified to become a tenant of a dwelling unit. A landlord may charge an application fee as provided in this chapter and may request a prospective tenant to provide information that will enable the landlord to make such determination. The landlord may photocopy each applicant's driver's license or other similar photo identification, containing either the applicant's social security number or control number issued by the Department of Motor Vehicles pursuant to <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 46.2-342"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 46.2-342">§ 46.2-342<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000046#     2#          342#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>. However, a landlord shall not photocopy a U.S. government-issued identification so long as to do so is a violation of Title 18 U.S.C. Part I, Chapter 33, § 701. The landlord may require that each applicant provide a social security number issued by the U.S. Social Security Administration or an individual taxpayer identification number issued by the U.S. Internal Revenue Service, for the purpose of determining whether each applicant is eligible to become a tenant in the landlord's dwelling unit.</p><p><pre/><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Roomer"</emphasis> means a person occupying a dwelling unit that lacks a major bathroom or kitchen facility, in a structure where one or more major facilities are used in common by occupants of the dwelling unit and other dwelling units. Major facility in the case of a bathroom means toilet, and either a bath or shower, and in the case of a kitchen means refrigerator, stove, or sink.</p><p><pre/><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Security deposit"</emphasis> means any refundable deposit of money that is furnished by a tenant to a landlord to secure the performance of the terms and conditions of a rental agreement, as a security for damages to the leased premises, or as a pet deposit. However, such money shall be deemed an application deposit until the commencement date of the rental agreement. Security deposit shall not include a damage insurance policy or renter's insurance policy as those terms are defined in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 55-248.7:2"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 55 -248.7:2">§ 55-248.7:2<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#142#        55#     248.7#         2#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> purchased by a landlord to provide coverage for a tenant.</p><p><pre/><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Single-family residence"</emphasis> means a structure, other than a multi-family residential structure, maintained and used as a single dwelling unit, condominium unit, or any other dwelling unit that has direct access to a street or thoroughfare and shares neither heating facilities, hot water equipment, nor any other essential facility or service with any other dwelling unit.</p><p><pre/><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Sublease"</emphasis> means the transfer by any tenant of any but not all interests created by a rental agreement.</p><p><pre/><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Tenant"</emphasis> means a person entitled only under the terms of a rental agreement to occupy a dwelling unit to the exclusion of others and shall include roomer. Tenant shall not include (i) an authorized occupant, (ii) a guest or invitee, or (iii) any person who guarantees or cosigns the payment of the financial obligations of a rental agreement but has no right to occupy a dwelling unit.</p><p><pre/><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Tenant records"</emphasis> means all information, including financial, maintenance, and other records about a tenant or prospective tenant, whether such information is in written or electronic form or other medium. A tenant may request copies of his tenant records pursuant to <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 55-248.9:1"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 55 -248.9:1">§ 55-248.9:1.<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#142#        55#     248.9#         1#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation></p><p><pre/><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Utility"</emphasis> means electricity, natural gas, water and sewer provided by a public service corporation or such other person providing utility services as permitted under <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 56-1.2"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 56 -1.2">§ 56-1.2.<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#123#000056#       1.2#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> If the rental agreement so provides, a landlord may use submetering equipment or energy allocation equipment as defined in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 56-245.2"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 56 -245.2">§ 56-245.2<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#123#000056#     245.2#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, or a ratio utility billing system as defined in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 55-226.2"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 55 -226.2">§ 55-226.2.<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#123#000055#     226.2#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation></p><p><pre/><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Visible evidence of mold"</emphasis> means the existence of mold in the dwelling unit that is visible to the naked eye by the landlord or tenant in areas within the interior of the dwelling unit readily accessible at the time of the move-in inspection.</p><p><pre/><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Written notice"</emphasis> means notice given in accordance with <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 55-248.6"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 55 -248.6">§ 55-248.6<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#123#000055#     248.6#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, including any representation of words, letters, symbols, numbers, or figures, whether (i) printed in or inscribed on a tangible medium or (ii) stored in an electronic form or other medium, retrievable in a perceivable form, and regardless of whether an electronic signature authorized by Chapter 42.1 (<citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 59.1-479"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 59.1-479">§ 59.1-479<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000059#     1#          479#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> et seq.) of Title 59.1 is affixed. The landlord may, in accordance with a written agreement, delegate to a managing agent or other third party the responsibility of providing any written notice required by this chapter.</p></bodyText></level><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p>1974, c. 680; 1977, c. 427; 1987, c. 428; <citation normalizedCite="1990 VA CH 55"><content><span normalizedCite="1990 Va. Ch. 55">1990, c. 55<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1990#000055#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1991 VA CH 205"><content><span normalizedCite="1991 Va. Ch. 205">1991, c. 205<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1991#000205#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1999 VA CH 77"><content><span normalizedCite="1999 Va. Ch. 77">1999, cc. 77<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1999#000077#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1999 VA CH 258"><content><span normalizedCite="1999 Va. Ch. 258">258<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1999#000258#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1999 VA CH 359"><content><span normalizedCite="1999 Va. Ch. 359">359<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1999#000359#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1999 VA CH 390"><content><span normalizedCite="1999 Va. Ch. 390">390<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1999#000390#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2000 VA CH 760"><content><span normalizedCite="2000 Va. Ch. 760">2000, cc. 760<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2000#000760#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2000 VA CH 816"><content><span normalizedCite="2000 Va. Ch. 816">816<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2000#000816#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2002 VA CH 531"><content><span normalizedCite="2002 Va. Ch. 531">2002, c. 531<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2002#000531#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2003 VA CH 355"><content><span normalizedCite="2003 Va. Ch. 355">2003, cc. 355<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2003#000355#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2003 VA CH 425"><content><span normalizedCite="2003 Va. Ch. 425">425<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2003#000425#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2003 VA CH 855"><content><span normalizedCite="2003 Va. Ch. 855">855<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2003#000855#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2004 VA CH 123"><content><span normalizedCite="2004 Va. Ch. 123">2004, c. 123<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2004#000123#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2007 VA CH 634"><content><span normalizedCite="2007 Va. Ch. 634">2007, c. 634<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2007#000634#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2008 VA CH 489"><content><span normalizedCite="2008 Va. Ch. 489">2008, cc. 489<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2008#000489#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2008 VA CH 640"><content><span normalizedCite="2008 Va. Ch. 640">640<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2008#000640#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2010 VA CH 180"><content><span normalizedCite="2010 Va. Ch. 180">2010, cc. 180<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2010#000180#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2010 VA CH 550"><content><span normalizedCite="2010 Va. Ch. 550">550<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2010#000550#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2012 VA CH 788"><content><span normalizedCite="2012 Va. Ch. 788">2012, c. 788<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2012#000788#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2013 VA CH 563"><content><span normalizedCite="2013 Va. Ch. 563">2013, c. 563<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2013#000563#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2014 VA CH 651"><content><span normalizedCite="2014 Va. Ch. 651">2014, c. 651<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2014#000651#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2015 VA CH 596"><content><span normalizedCite="2015 Va. Ch. 596">2015, c. 596<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2015#000596#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2016 VA CH 744"><content><span normalizedCite="2016 Va. Ch. 744">2016, c. 744<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2016#000744#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PTD0-004G-K350-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 55.</desig><title>PROPERTY AND CONVEYANCES</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 13.2.</desig><title>VIRGINIA RESIDENTIAL LANDLORD AND TENANT ACT</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="article"><heading><desig>ARTICLE 1.</desig><title>GENERAL PROVISIONS</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Limited Liability Partnerships</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Qzc3QkNFMUExQzM2NDJGRTg3REE0N0I1QzhCQUE3QjM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjA4OEVGODBENzY4NDcxM0IyQzA1OTEwQzVDODRBOUE</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjA4OEVGODBENzY4NDcxM0IyQzA1OTEwQzVDODRBOUE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MzZCNTdCQ0Q2OTRDNDYxOTg2MTY2NTREQUVGNjBBQzE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RTYwRjBDQTc2RUU5NDVGQkEwNjMwMTExRkI4QjQwNEQ</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NUUwRjE5Nzk1QUU0NEZGQTgxNjExMzg4QjMxQTYwMzI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NUFDMUUyMjFERDQ1NDg3NTg1NzVCNzQyMTU5QzlBODI</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RDVCRkUzRjg3NUFFNDMwNjhGMDc3MkNENDMxNzhFOEM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDFEQjUyNDAyMzQ0NDQyNUE5RjNGOEZEMzNBRDA1RUY</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Limited Liability Partnerships</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Qzc3QkNFMUExQzM2NDJGRTg3REE0N0I1QzhCQUE3QjM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjA4OEVGODBENzY4NDcxM0IyQzA1OTEwQzVDODRBOUE</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Commercial Law (UCC)</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QUI5QjdCNzBDNjY0NEY3QzlGRTNCQTMzQ0IwQ0MzRUQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RUQ5RTlBNDk5MTg2NDM5QTk3RTVFNkRGRTBBMTU4N0Y7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OUE1NDZGQjMwQTYyNDA1RkI2MTZBQjRFRjRGOEM1MjM</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Good Faith &amp; Fair Dealing</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NUZBQzJGMDUzQkZDNDk0RUI3RUQyQ0Y4MzdCODQ5NTY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NUY1N0M2MTVDREQwNEE4NTk1OUMzMUQ0RkZBQkVBODg</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Computer &amp; Internet Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Qzk0QUJBRENDQzhBNDc2MDk5OTAyQzI3QkRFMkU0OUU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Digital Signatures</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NTUxMzc0MDI4MjNBNDI5QkJBREYxQjk2OTg0ODZGMjA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QTkzQzdCODc0OERFNDNBQUJGMTMxQjg4RDExN0JDQUQ</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Contracts Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QzY0RTZFMzE0RjkwNDdFQUI5M0U5N0ZFMjYyREMyQzU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6REM4OThDMTQwNjI4NDVBRTg2OUJBRjlFNUY1MTk4MTQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MkUyQjY4NDMwRDBFNDVEQ0E4N0Y3M0Y0QkU2MzI3Rjc</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QTdGQUE3QkZDMDlBNDQ1MTkzRjEzMEQ1OEUwNzdDOTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NjZEOEU3MEJBRUQ2NDNFNzhFRjAxRTk1OEU1QjY2QTc</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Oral Leases</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NjVBQjBDQjM4MzUxNEZDM0EwMDJFNjFBRUE4ODZGODM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NjZEOEU3MEJBRUQ2NDNFNzhFRjAxRTk1OEU1QjY2QTc</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Energy &amp; Utilities Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OUUzODAyRDk1QzVFNEZGMEJDM0RGMDYxOTlEMEEzRDA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Qzk3MzQ5NjhDQjRGNEJBNzhBOEI5MkE3RjBEMTZDOUU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Rjk2NTk2ODk2RkMwNDZGQjgxNUI1RjE0MDk4MTNDQzY</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Estate, Gift &amp; Trust Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OENGNTY0MEQ2RTU2NDA2NTk4QjcyNzI2NTBERUU3NUI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Q0VEQ0U4QTFCMzc1NDkyQjgzMjNBQUJFREFDOEJCOTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NUQ4NThEMTk0MTQ4NDM3N0FGOEM5RkU2QUQ4RjA1MkQ</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RkM5NEM1RTczNTEzNDMwREIzODZFNkU3MDk1RTcxMjI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RUEwMTQ5RDk2OTM4NEIyNDgwNTY2RTNBOUYyOTk1REQ</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Single Beneficiaries</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NTU0NTUxOEFDMDBBNERGOTg5MkM5MTRGRTRDNDJFOUU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NzgwQzFGOTA0NDM5NDVGMEE5NkRCNjQ1NEM2NkZEN0Y</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Real Property Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QUUyRTcxRURBNEY2NEE2MDk3QzBCNzRDOEY0NTZDQzk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Building &amp; Housing Codes</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDZGNTdFRUIyNEQ2NDQ1QjlBMzEwRDQyOUZFRUFCRjM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NjcyQTdEMEUxODYyNDY0OThFQTg1NUNGMjFBMTkxQ0M</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Contractual Relationships</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDI4MDAwMkMzMTFGNDdDMTkyQ0ZGNUMwQzlBMkEzM0I7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NzE3OTZBQzE2NkRCNDA5MDlCNjRBRTVCMzk2NEU3MTE</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Forcible Entry &amp; Detainer</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RUU3RUYxRkNBQTk2NDMxMEIxREEwN0Q3MjlFM0FGOEY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUVBNzBGMzM3NUY1NEExQjg1QTUxRTZCRjA1QTU1NDk</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NTQwQjZGM0VDNUVENEQzMUE1QUNDNTM5ODY2NzlCMTc7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NTk0MkNDNEVCNEUyNDc5NTgxMDMyMzBEMUVFOTU1RTU</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NUExRkI0MTNBRjIwNDgwMkE0NEZGQzMxOEI2Q0MyQzc7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MzdEMEE5OUQ4RTAxNDBCRUJDOTA0N0ZDNTdFNDMwMDg</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RjBBQTVENjZENjJFNEEzNjlBRDE1QjZDRjQyM0FBNkM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NjcyQTdEMEUxODYyNDY0OThFQTg1NUNGMjFBMTkxQ0M</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Holding Trusts</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjAyRkY5RjIzM0Q0NDFBMEI4NEVFRjEwREY5MDE3QjQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDA0QjAwN0E3NDgwNDhBRjgxMDIzRUFDQkNERDc0ODQ</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Indoor Air &amp; Water Quality</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OUNEM0JGQjIzRDVFNDdEMjg2MjEyRTVFQ0Q1NkUyQzM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NkI1NUVDMDA0Nzk5NDJFM0EzQjMyRjQ4NUI1RjZFODc</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Leases</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QkNFM0ZCQzgzODg0NERCQzg5MkRBMDFGOEM0QUU4ODY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUMzQTI2Qzg3NkJDNDI5MEI1MTU1QkM0RDlGN0JENUU</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Mortgagee's Interests</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MzQwOUI5Qjk2Qzg5NEJDNUFBODI4M0NFNjE0MzYwNzI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDhDNTc4RkY3N0RDNDhDRkI1ODk3RjI2RkEyRTMwNEI</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Residential Leases</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NEIyMzc4RDNCMzc2NDA1NzhCOEY3MDhGMTMwQUM1RTc7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDU3NDIyNUI2MzczNEUwMzk0M0Y4MkZDQjk2OUUyRTQ</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Security Deposits</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDg3MDQyNUI0RkMxNDMwMzlBRDQyOUUxMkNFQjc5QTM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QUZDQTAzRTdEMTMzNDZEOTg4N0M3OUMyOUNEMjI0MTQ</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Tenancies in Common</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QzQ1NTNBRTU4OEVGNDY1REI1RjRFNDNFQTYxRDgwODk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RURDNEUyQzNBMTcwNDU4REJDQTM0NjRFQzI0QjNBQjY</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Unlawful Detainer</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6ODE1M0MwMTlBN0JBNEI2MjlDODYxNzJDMjQwQUYzQTE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RTdGQjZDMTAyQjUwNDg4NUFCRDQyMjVFMkFDQjAyMjQ</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Torts</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDAwOEM2NTEzQkVDNEI4NzlGMEZERUEyRjQwODM4Njg7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFBRjYxRjU2ODY3NDcwMUFERkE3MUMzRkMwMjlBOTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjkyMTA1NkNDNDlCNENFNDhGMDlDREREMzlBRkVGQkE</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OENGMEVCRTU5QzA2NDI3OEE0MTUyODI5ODNDRDQ5MDA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QTY5MTk2NDZERUFBNEJCMUE1MDc4NUMyOTA2NzAxQTA</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification><classificationGroup classificationScheme="indexing-terms"><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem score="90"><className>Real Property</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QUUyRTcxRURBNEY2NEE2MDk3QzBCNzRDOEY0NTZDQzk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></classificationGroup></metadata></legislativeDoc>