<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#123#000023#     276.1#">Va. Code Ann. § 23-276.1</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_23-276.1"/><heading><desig>§ 23-276.1.</desig><title>(Repealed effective October 1, 2016) Definitions</title></heading><bodyText><p>As used in this chapter:</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Academic-Vocational"</emphasis> refers to a noncollege degree school that offers degree and nondegree credit courses.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Agent"</emphasis> means a person who is employed by any institution of higher education or noncollege degree school, whether such institution or school is located within or outside the Commonwealth, to act as an agent, solicitor, procurer, broker or independent contractor to procure students or enrollees for any such institution or school by solicitation in any form at any place in the Commonwealth other than the office or principal location of such institution or school.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Certificate"</emphasis> or <emphasis typeStyle="it">"diploma"</emphasis> means an award that is given for successful completion of a curriculum comprised of courses that may also be taken for degree credit and shall apply only to those awards given for coursework offered by institutions of higher education and academic-vocational noncollege degree schools.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"College"</emphasis> means any institution of higher education that offers associate or baccalaureate level degree programs.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Continuing or professional education"</emphasis> means those classes, courses, and programs, designed specifically for individuals who have completed a degree in a professional field, that (i) are intended to fulfill the continuing education requirements for licensure or certification in said profession; (ii) have been approved by a legislatively or judicially established board or agency responsible for regulating the practice of the profession; and (iii) are offered exclusively to an individual practicing in the profession.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Council"</emphasis> means the State Council of Higher Education for Virginia.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Degree"</emphasis> means any earned award at the associate, baccalaureate, graduate, first professional or specialist levels that represents satisfactory completion of the requirements of a program or course of study or instruction beyond the secondary school level.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Degree credit course"</emphasis> means any earned credits awarded for successful completion of the requirements of a course of study or instruction beyond the secondary school level, which may be used toward completion of a certificate or diploma, or an associate, baccalaureate, graduate, first professional or specialist level degree.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Fraudulent academic credential"</emphasis> means a diploma, certification, academic transcript, or other document issued by a person or an entity that is not an institution of higher education that provides evidence of or demonstrates completion of course work or academic credit that results in the issuance of an associate or more advanced degree.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"In-state institution"</emphasis> means an institution of higher education that is formed, chartered, or established within Virginia. An out-of-state institution shall be deemed an in-state institution for the purposes of certification as a degree-granting institution if (i) it has no instructional campus in the jurisdiction in which it was formed, chartered, established, or incorporated and (ii) it produces clear and convincing evidence that its main or principal campus is located in Virginia.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Institution of higher education" </emphasis> or <emphasis typeStyle="it">"institution"</emphasis> means any person or entity, other than a Virginia state-supported institution of higher education named in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 23-9.5"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 23 -9.5">§ 23-9.5<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#123#000023#       9.5#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> or any public institution of higher education established in statute as an authority and declared a governmental instrumentality pursuant to <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 23-14"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 23 -14">§ 23-14<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#123#000023#        14#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, that has received approval from the Council to (i) use the term "college" or "university," or words of like meaning, in its name or in any manner in connection with its academic affairs or business; (ii) enroll students; or (iii) offer approved courses for degree credit or programs of study leading to a degree or to offer degrees either at a site in Virginia or via telecommunications equipment located within Virginia.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Multistate compact" </emphasis> means any agreement involving two or more states to offer jointly postsecondary educational opportunities, pursuant to policies and procedures set forth by such agreement and approved by the Council.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Noncollege degree school" </emphasis> means any postsecondary school that offers courses or programs of study that do not lead to an associate or higher level degree. Such schools may be academic-vocational or vocational.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Nondegree credit course" </emphasis> means any earned credits awarded for successful completion of the requirements of a course of study or instruction beyond the secondary school level, which may be used toward completion of a certificate or diploma, but may not be used to earn an associate or higher level degree.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Out-of-state institution" </emphasis> means an institution of higher education that is formed, chartered, established, or incorporated outside the Commonwealth.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Postsecondary school" </emphasis> or <emphasis typeStyle="it">"school"</emphasis> means any entity offering formal instructional programs with a curriculum designed primarily for students who have completed the requirements for a high school diploma or its equivalent. Such schools include programs of academic, vocational, and continuing professional education, and exclude avocational and adult basic education programs. For the purposes of this chapter, a "postsecondary school" shall be classified as either an institution of higher education as defined in this section or a noncollege degree school, as defined in this section.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Program" </emphasis> means a curriculum or course of study in a discipline or interdisciplinary area that leads to a degree, certificate, or diploma.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Program area" </emphasis> means a general group of disciplines in which one or more degree programs, certificates, or diplomas may be offered.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Proprietary" </emphasis> means a privately owned and managed, profit-making institution of higher education or noncollege degree school.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Site" </emphasis> means a location in Virginia where a postsecondary school (i) offers one or more courses on an established schedule and (ii) enrolls two or more persons who are not members of the same household. A site may be a branch of such postsecondary school, and shall not be required to possess administrative capability.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Teachout plan" </emphasis> means a written agreement between or among postsecondary schools that provides for the equitable treatment of students if one party to the agreement stops offering an educational program before all students enrolled in that program complete the program.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"University" </emphasis> means any institution offering programs leading to degrees or degree credit beyond the baccalaureate level.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Vocational"</emphasis> refers to a noncollege degree school that offers only nondegree credit courses, and shall not include instructional programs that are intended solely for recreation, enjoyment, personal interest, or as a hobby, or courses or programs of instruction that prepare individuals to teach such pursuits.</p></bodyText><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p>Code 1950, <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 23-265"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 23 -265">§ 23-265<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#123#000023#       265#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; 1980, c. 658; <citation normalizedCite="1996 VA CH 691"><content><span normalizedCite="1996 Va. Ch. 691">1996, cc. 691<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1996#000691#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1996 VA CH 832"><content><span normalizedCite="1996 Va. Ch. 832">832<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1996#000832#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1999 VA CH 458"><content><span normalizedCite="1999 Va. Ch. 458">1999, cc. 458<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1999#000458#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1999 VA CH 499"><content><span normalizedCite="1999 Va. Ch. 499">499<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1999#000499#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2002 VA CH 178"><content><span normalizedCite="2002 Va. Ch. 178">2002, c. 178<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2002#000178#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2004 VA CH 671"><content><span normalizedCite="2004 Va. Ch. 671">2004, cc. 671<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2004#000671#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2004 VA CH 991"><content><span normalizedCite="2004 Va. Ch. 991">991<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2004#000991#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2005 VA CH 447"><content><span normalizedCite="2005 Va. Ch. 447">2005, c. 447<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2005#000447#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2007 VA CH 82"><content><span normalizedCite="2007 Va. Ch. 82">2007, cc. 82<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2007#000082#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2007 VA CH 115"><content><span normalizedCite="2007 Va. Ch. 115">115<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2007#000115#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2008 VA CH 856"><content><span normalizedCite="2008 Va. Ch. 856">2008, c. 856<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2008#000856#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2010 VA CH 67"><content><span normalizedCite="2010 Va. Ch. 67">2010, cc. 67<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2010#000067#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2010 VA CH 263"><content><span normalizedCite="2010 Va. Ch. 263">263<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2010#000263#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2013 VA CH 229"><content><span normalizedCite="2013 Va. Ch. 229">2013, c. 229<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2013#000229#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PVB0-004G-K2CG-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 23.</desig><title>EDUCATIONAL INSTITUTIONS</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 21.1.</desig><title>REGULATION OF CERTAIN PRIVATE AND OUT-OF-STATE INSTITUTIONS OF HIGHER EDUCATION</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Education Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDkzNUEzQzFBNEZBNEFBREIxNDM5MTc1MUU5QjI4MTY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Certificates, Degrees &amp; Diplomas</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QTI2MURGN0ZBODNDNEU0ODg1QUNFQzc4MEI5REU2MTQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OTRGMkI4ODIzRjgxNEE2RkE2OEE5MTU0MDdFM0Y5RjI</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Governmental Authority</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NUIzM0FCQkI2OTkwNDlBNjlFOEE1Nzk2RUNDNkNFRjU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6M0EyN0YxOTc1NUQ2NDFEMTg1NkE3NjkwMkQxRDYwQzg</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification><classificationGroup classificationScheme="indexing-terms"><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem score="90"><className>Education</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDkzNUEzQzFBNEZBNEFBREIxNDM5MTc1MUU5QjI4MTY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></classificationGroup></metadata></legislativeDoc>