<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#349#000063#     2#          608#">Va. Code Ann. § 63.2-608</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_63.2-608"/><heading><desig>§ 63.2-608.</desig><title>Virginia Initiative for Employment Not Welfare (VIEW)</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a"/><heading><desig>A.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The Department shall establish and administer the Virginia Initiative for Employment Not Welfare (VIEW) to reduce long-term dependence on welfare, emphasize personal responsibility, and enhance opportunities for personal initiative and self-sufficiency by promoting the value of work. The Department shall endeavor to develop placements for VIEW participants that will enable participants to develop job skills that are likely to result in independent employment and that take into consideration the proficiency, experience, skills, and prior training of a participant.</p><p>VIEW shall recognize clearly defined responsibilities and obligations on the part of public assistance recipients and shall include a written agreement of personal responsibility requiring parents to participate in work activities while receiving TANF, earned-income disregards to reduce disincentives to work, and a limit on TANF financial assistance.</p><p>VIEW shall require all able-bodied recipients of TANF who do not meet an exemption to participate in a work activity. VIEW shall require eligible TANF recipients to participate in unsubsidized, partially subsidized or fully subsidized employment or other allowable TANF work activity as defined by federal law and enter into an agreement of personal responsibility.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b"/><heading><desig>B.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> To the maximum extent permitted by federal law, and notwithstanding other provisions of Virginia law, the Department and local departments may, through applicable procurement laws and regulations, engage the services of public and private organizations to operate VIEW and to provide services incident to such operation.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c"/><heading><desig>C.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> All VIEW participants shall be under the direction and supervision of a case manager.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d"/><heading><desig>D.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The Department shall ensure that participants are assigned to one of the following work activities within 90 days after the approval of TANF assistance:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Unsubsidized private-sector employment;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Subsidized employment, as follows:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d_2_a"/><heading><desig>a.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The Department shall conduct a program in accordance with this section that shall be known as the Full Employment Program (FEP). FEP replaces TANF with subsidized employment. Persons not able to find unsubsidized employment who are otherwise eligible for TANF may participate in FEP unless exempted by this chapter. FEP shall assign participants to subsidized wage-paying private-sector jobs designed to increase the participants' self-sufficiency and improve their competitive position in the workforce.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d_2_b"/><heading><desig>b.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Participants in FEP shall be placed in full-time employment when appropriate and shall be paid by the employer at an hourly rate not less than the federal or state minimum wage, whichever is higher. At no point shall a participant's spendable income received from wages and tax credits be less than the value of TANF received prior to the work placement.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d_2_c"/><heading><desig>c.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Every employer subject to the Virginia unemployment insurance tax shall be eligible for assignment of FEP participants, but no employer shall be required to utilize such participants. Employers shall ensure that jobs made available to FEP participants are in conformity with § 3304(a)(5) of the Federal Unemployment Tax Act. FEP participants cannot be used to displace regular workers.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d_2_d"/><heading><desig>d.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> FEP employers shall:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d_2_d_i"/><heading><desig>(i)</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Endeavor to make FEP placements positive learning and training experiences;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d_2_d_ii"/><heading><desig>(ii)</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Provide on-the-job training to the degree necessary for the participants to perform their duties;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d_2_d_iii"/><heading><desig>(iii)</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Pay wages to participants at the same rate that they are paid to other employees performing the same type of work and having similar experience and employment tenure;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d_2_d_iv"/><heading><desig>(iv)</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Provide sick leave, holiday and vacation benefits to participants to the same extent and on the same basis that they are provided to other employees performing the same type of work and having similar employment experience and tenure;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d_2_d_v"/><heading><desig>(v)</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Maintain health, safety and working conditions at or above levels generally acceptable in the industry and no less than those in which other employees perform the same type of work;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d_2_d_vi"/><heading><desig>(vi)</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Provide workers' compensation coverage for participants;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d_2_d_vii"/><heading><desig>(vii)</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Encourage volunteer mentors from among their other employees to assist participants in becoming oriented to work and the workplace; and</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d_2_d_viii"/><heading><desig>(viii)</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Sign an agreement with the local department outlining the employer requirements to participate in FEP. All agreements shall include notice of the employer's obligation to repay FEP reimbursements in the event the employer violates FEP rules.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d_2_e"/><heading><desig>e.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> As a condition of FEP participation, employers shall be prohibited from discriminating against any person, including program participants, on the basis of race, color, sex, national origin, religion, age, or disability;</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Part-time or temporary employment;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d_4"/><heading><desig>4.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Community work experience, as follows:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d_4_a"/><heading><desig>a.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The Department and local departments shall work with other state, regional and local agencies and governments in developing job placements that serve a useful public purpose as provided in § 482(f) of the Social Security Act, as amended. Placements shall be selected to provide skills and serve a public function. VIEW participants shall not displace regular workers.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d_4_b"/><heading><desig>b.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The number of hours per week for participants shall be determined by combining the total dollar amount of TANF and food stamps and dividing by the minimum wage with a maximum of a work week of 32 hours, of which up to 12 hours of employment-related education and training may substitute for work experience employment; or</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d_5"/><heading><desig>5.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Any other allowable TANF work activity as defined by federal law.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_e"/><heading><desig>E.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Notwithstanding the provisions of subsections A and D, if a local department determines that a VIEW participant is in need of job skills and would benefit from immediate job skills training, it may place the participant in a program preparing individuals for a high school equivalency examination approved by the Board of Education, a career and technical education program targeted at skills required for particular employment opportunities, or an apprenticeship program developed by the local department in accordance with requirements established by the Department. Eligible participants include those with problems related to obtaining and retaining employment, such as participants (i) with less than a high school education, (ii) whose reading or math skills are at or below the eighth grade level, (iii) who have not retained a job for a period of at least six months during the prior two years, or (iv) who are in a treatment program for a substance abuse problem or are receiving services through a family violence treatment program. The VIEW participant may continue in a high school equivalency examination preparation program, career and technical education program, or apprenticeship program for as long as the local department determines he is progressing satisfactorily and to the extent permitted by the Personal Responsibility and Work Opportunity Reconciliation Act of 1996 (P.L. 104-193), as amended.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_f"/><heading><desig>F.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Participants may be reevaluated after a period determined by the local department and reassigned to another work component. In addition, the number of hours worked may be reduced by the local department so that a participant may complete additional training or education to further his employability.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_g"/><heading><desig>G.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Local departments shall be authorized to sanction parents up to the full amount of the TANF grant for noncompliance, unless good cause exists.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_h"/><heading><desig>H.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> VIEW participants shall not be assigned to projects that require that they travel unreasonable distances from their homes or remain away from their homes overnight without their consent.</p><p>Any injury to a VIEW participant arising out of and in the course of community work experience shall be covered by the participant's existing Medicaid coverage. If a community work experience participant is unable to work due to such an accident, his status shall be reviewed to determine whether he is eligible for an exemption from the limitation on TANF financial assistance.</p><p>A community work experience participant who becomes incapacitated for 30 days or more shall be eligible for TANF financial assistance for the duration of the incapacity, if otherwise eligible.</p><p>The Board shall adopt regulations providing for the accrual of paid sick leave or other equivalent mechanism for community work experience participants.</p></bodyText></level><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p><citation normalizedCite="1994 VA CH 858"><content><span normalizedCite="1994 Va. Ch. 858">1994, cc. 858<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1994#000858#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1994 VA CH 951"><content><span normalizedCite="1994 Va. Ch. 951">951<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1994#000951#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, § 63.1-133.49; <citation normalizedCite="1995 VA CH 450"><content><span normalizedCite="1995 Va. Ch. 450">1995, c. 450<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1995#000450#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1996 VA CH 1023"><content><span normalizedCite="1996 Va. Ch. 1023">1996, c. 1023<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1996#001023#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1999 VA CH 759"><content><span normalizedCite="1999 Va. Ch. 759">1999, c. 759<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1999#000759#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2000 VA CH 483"><content><span normalizedCite="2000 Va. Ch. 483">2000, cc. 483<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2000#000483#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2000 VA CH 491"><content><span normalizedCite="2000 Va. Ch. 491">491<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2000#000491#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2001 VA CH 483"><content><span normalizedCite="2001 Va. Ch. 483">2001, c. 483<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2001#000483#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2002 VA CH 747"><content><span normalizedCite="2002 Va. Ch. 747">2002, c. 747<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2002#000747#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2003 VA CH 428"><content><span normalizedCite="2003 Va. Ch. 428">2003, cc. 428<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2003#000428#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2003 VA CH 467"><content><span normalizedCite="2003 Va. Ch. 467">467<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2003#000467#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2005 VA CH 472"><content><span normalizedCite="2005 Va. Ch. 472">2005, c. 472<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2005#000472#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2007 VA CH 568"><content><span normalizedCite="2007 Va. Ch. 568">2007, c. 568<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2007#000568#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2014 VA CH 84"><content><span normalizedCite="2014 Va. Ch. 84">2014, c. 84<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2014#000084#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2016 VA CH 101"><content><span normalizedCite="2016 Va. Ch. 101">2016, c. 101<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2016#000101#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PVB0-004G-K2K9-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 63.2.</desig><title>WELFARE (SOCIAL SERVICES)</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="subtitle"><heading><desig>SUBTITLE II.</desig><title>PUBLIC ASSISTANCE</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 6.</desig><title>TEMPORARY ASSISTANCE FOR NEEDY FAMILIES PROGRAM</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Court &amp; Government Imposed Plans</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NjA2NjczNzYzMDNGNEY0MDhEM0M4MkI0N0I4N0UxNkE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NkY3MjkxMTIwMDM3NEREOEEzMDkxMzNDQUFDRkM4OTc</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Family Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NEI4M0U5Qzg3RTk0NDdBRUJGNDRGNkZEQkU3RDdFNDU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Services</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NzcwRjRGMTkzNzU4NDQxNUI4NUE5NzBBNzVBMjhCNjY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QTIwNUFBN0IzQzc3NEE5QUE1MUFEMTFDQkIyNDAzN0U</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Labor &amp; Employment Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MTE3QUQwOTA0MUYzNDlCMEFFMjUwRUNDM0RDRkM5QzM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Court &amp; Government Imposed Plans</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NjA2NjczNzYzMDNGNEY0MDhEM0M4MkI0N0I4N0UxNkE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NkY3MjkxMTIwMDM3NEREOEEzMDkxMzNDQUFDRkM4OTc</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Discrimination</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUUxN0NBRDAyRDhFNDhEOTk2OTVCNEM0NEYzQUQ5Qzk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NkY3MjkxMTIwMDM3NEREOEEzMDkxMzNDQUFDRkM4OTc</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RUMxMEM5Mzk5NjdBNEQyMDg1NzYzNTNFMTc3QjExNkQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MEUyNDQ5RTc4RDI2NDc3Q0I3MUE0OEE2NTA3QjYzRkM</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MzE4REVFNzc1ODJCNEQyNTk4MThCNzdBNTU4NTExMDg7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDk1NzZDQzBDM0M1NENCOUE1ODc3ODI4QkI3MkYyMEY</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OUY1OTdBM0M0MzM2NDRERjkzNTZDQ0QyQ0RBQUVEQUM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NkM0MEYwMzFDQzhDNEY3NUIyMzBCRkNBNkI4Q0ZFN0M</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Suitable Employment</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NjZCQ0Q2NDA3OTdFNENBMkJFOEZCMjdGNDVERkYxQzU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDk1NzZDQzBDM0M1NENCOUE1ODc3ODI4QkI3MkYyMEY</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Public Health &amp; Welfare Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDYwRTY1MDg3MTk5NDUyNkFFRDI1RjJBRERGQ0UxNzI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Amount, Duration &amp; Scope of Benefits</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NzcwMzgxREMzMkNENDc1M0FEMTg0OEE4NDFERkQyNkM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NjQ0NkMzMERDQTk0NEJDRjkzN0ZGMDA0RDQ1RTc5NDU</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Eligibility</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QTk2QTMzQUQ3NEQ5NEYxN0E5QkY3NzUwMTY3MkQ2MTE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QThEREM1OTMyMDVFNEU2Nzk1Qjc4MDM1RkMzOTg1NkU</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QzJGMTAxNTEyNzRENDg2NEEyMkQxNEU1RTI0MEZFRTg7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QThEREM1OTMyMDVFNEU2Nzk1Qjc4MDM1RkMzOTg1NkU</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Workers' Compensation &amp; SSDI</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NTNGOEUzQTYwRUQ1NEFCN0FGMjg0Rjc5MjI3NjBDMEI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6M0MzNUQ3RjhGMjJGNDM0Qzk4MzVDNzc2REMzNDk3Qjk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MTFDQ0IzQ0NBNDczNDVGNDlBN0QyMkIzOUJEQzAzRDg</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification><classificationGroup classificationScheme="indexing-terms"><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem score="90"><className>Public Health &amp; Welfare</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDYwRTY1MDg3MTk5NDUyNkFFRDI1RjJBRERGQ0UxNzI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></classificationGroup></metadata></legislativeDoc>