<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#123#000023#        31#">Va. Code Ann. § 23-31</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_23-31"/><heading><desig>§ 23-31.</desig><title>(Repealed effective October 1, 2016) Unfunded scholarships</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a"/><heading><desig>A.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The corporate authorities of the University of Virginia, the University of Virginia's College at Wise, Virginia Military Institute, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University, The College of William and Mary, Christopher Newport University, George Mason University, Longwood University, the University of Mary Washington, James Madison University, Virginia Commonwealth University, Radford University, Old Dominion University, the Virginia Community College System, Virginia State University, Norfolk State University, and Richard Bland College may establish scholarships, hereafter to be designated as unfunded scholarships, in their respective institutions under such regulations and conditions as they may prescribe, but subject to the following limitations and restrictions:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> All such scholarships shall be applied exclusively to the remission, in whole or in part, of tuition and required fees.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The respective corporate authorities shall determine the number of such scholarships annually awarded to undergraduate Virginia and non-Virginia students.</p><p><pre/>The total value of all such scholarships annually awarded by an institution to undergraduate Virginia students shall not exceed in any year the amount arrived at by multiplying the applicable figure for undergraduate tuition and required fees by 20 percent of the enrollment of Virginia students in undergraduate studies in the institution during the preceding academic year. The total value of all such scholarships annually awarded by an institution to non-Virginia undergraduate students shall not exceed in any year the amount of the applicable, per capita out-of-state differential paid by non-Virginia undergraduate students for tuition and required fees multiplied by 20 percent of the enrollment of non-Virginia students in undergraduate studies in the institution during the preceding academic year.</p><p><pre/>All such scholarships awarded to undergraduate students shall be awarded only to undergraduate students in the first four years of undergraduate work and shall be awarded and renewed on a selective basis to students of character and ability who are in need of financial assistance. For purposes of determining need under this section, a nationally recognized needs-analysis system approved by the State Council of Higher Education shall be used.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The respective corporate authorities shall determine the number of such scholarships annually awarded to graduate students or teachers serving as clinical faculty pursuant to <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 22.1-290.1"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 22.1-290.1">§ 22.1-290.1.<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000022#     1#        290.1#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> The total value of all such scholarships annually awarded to such graduate students and clinical faculty shall not exceed in any year the amount arrived at by multiplying the applicable figure for graduate tuition and required fees by the number of graduate students who are employed as teaching assistants, graduate assistants, or research assistants with significant academic or academic support responsibilities and who are paid a stipend of at least $ 2,000 in the particular academic year and such clinical faculty. All graduate scholarships shall be awarded and renewed on a selective basis to such graduate students and clinical faculty of character and ability.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_4"/><heading><desig>4.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A scholarship awarded under this program shall entitle the holder to the following award, as appropriate:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_4_a"/><heading><desig>a.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A Virginia undergraduate student may receive an annual remission of an amount not to exceed the cost of tuition and fees required to be paid by the student;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_4_b"/><heading><desig>b.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A non-Virginia undergraduate student may receive an annual remission not to exceed the amount of the out-of-state differential required to be paid by the student for tuition and fees;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_4_c"/><heading><desig>c.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A qualified graduate student may receive an annual remission of an amount not to exceed the cost of tuition and fees required to be paid by the student;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_4_d"/><heading><desig>d.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A clinical faculty member may receive an award as determined by the governing body of the institution.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_5"/><heading><desig>5.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Notwithstanding the limitations on the awards of unfunded scholarships to undergraduate students pursuant to subdivision A 4 of this section, an institution may award additional unfunded scholarships to visiting foreign exchange students; however, the number of such awards in any fiscal year shall not exceed one quarter of one percent of the total institutional headcount enrollment.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b"/><heading><desig>B.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> No institution named herein shall remit any tuition or required fees or any special fees or charges to any student at such institution except as authorized in this section. Each institution named herein shall make a report to the State Council of Higher Education, upon request, showing the number and value of scholarships awarded under this section according to each student classification.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c"/><heading><desig>C.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Nothing in this section shall be construed to prevent or limit in any way the admission of certain students, known as state cadets, at the Virginia Military Institute or to affect the remission of tuition or required fees or other charges to such state cadets as permitted under existing law.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d"/><heading><desig>D.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Nothing in this section shall be construed to affect or limit in any way the control of the governing bodies of the respective institutions over any other scholarships; or over any gifts or donations made to such institutions for scholarships or other special purposes; or over any funds provided by the federal government or otherwise for the purpose of career and technical education or vocational rehabilitation in this Commonwealth; or over any funds derived from endowment or appropriations from the federal government for instruction in agriculture and mechanic arts in land grant colleges.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_e"/><heading><desig>E.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Nothing in this section shall be construed to prevent the governing bodies of the respective institutions from fixing a reasonably lower tuition charge for Virginia students than for non-Virginia students.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_f"/><heading><desig>F.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Nothing in this section or any other provision of law shall prohibit the awarding of 10 full tuition unfunded scholarships each year by Old Dominion University under the terms and conditions provided for in a deed conveying certain property in Norfolk known as the Old Larchmont School made July 5, 1930, between the City of Norfolk and The College of William and Mary.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_g"/><heading><desig>G.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Nothing in this section shall be construed to limit other financial aid programs provided pursuant to state law.</p></bodyText></level><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p>Code 1919, § 993; 1936, p. 447; 1952, c. 139; 1964, c. 440; 1966, c. 621; 1974, c. 317; 1975, c. 397; 1976, c. 189; 1977, cc. 296, 319; 1979, cc. 136, 145, 730; <citation normalizedCite="1990 VA CH 447"><content><span normalizedCite="1990 Va. Ch. 447">1990, c. 447<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1990#000447#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1992 VA CH 103"><content><span normalizedCite="1992 Va. Ch. 103">1992, c. 103<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1992#000103#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1996 VA CH 103"><content><span normalizedCite="1996 Va. Ch. 103">1996, c. 103<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1996#000103#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1999 VA CH 424"><content><span normalizedCite="1999 Va. Ch. 424">1999, cc. 424<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1999#000424#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1999 VA CH 437"><content><span normalizedCite="1999 Va. Ch. 437">437<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1999#000437#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2001 VA CH 483"><content><span normalizedCite="2001 Va. Ch. 483">2001, c. 483<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2001#000483#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2002 VA CH 158"><content><span normalizedCite="2002 Va. Ch. 158">2002, cc. 158<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2002#000158#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2002 VA CH 257"><content><span normalizedCite="2002 Va. Ch. 257">257<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2002#000257#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2004 VA CH 58"><content><span normalizedCite="2004 Va. Ch. 58">2004, cc. 58<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2004#000058#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2004 VA CH 176"><content><span normalizedCite="2004 Va. Ch. 176">176<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2004#000176#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2004 VA CH 195"><content><span normalizedCite="2004 Va. Ch. 195">195<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2004#000195#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2004 VA CH 739"><content><span normalizedCite="2004 Va. Ch. 739">739<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2004#000739#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2014 VA CH 594"><content><span normalizedCite="2014 Va. Ch. 594">2014, c. 594<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2014#000594#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PT00-004G-K1VH-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 23.</desig><title>EDUCATIONAL INSTITUTIONS</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 4.</desig><title>COLLEGE AND UNIVERSITY SCHOLARSHIPS</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Education Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDkzNUEzQzFBNEZBNEFBREIxNDM5MTc1MUU5QjI4MTY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Allocation of Funds</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RTk0MTc3MzdGQkU0NDI1OEFGOTA3NTkyRTJFM0VCQTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjZBQUM2RjM4QkI4NDlFMkFCNTBDMzJGNDg0MTgxOUU</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Instructional Staff</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OEYzNDIwNDU3MDYzNDVEMUIyMEU4OUM3MUVFOEZCRDc7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6REI2NEE4Nzk1Nzc3NEIzQkFFMzE2ODAyNUQzQkQ2Q0I</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Residency Classifications</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDkwNDFEQUZBRDFBNDA1M0FENUMxNjJFOTg4RDg2NTU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6N0QwQkFFRTFBMDIxNDU2QUFFOEMwRUQyMkVGNTQ2Rjc</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Governments</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjdEQjE4OUJDMzQxNDNEMEI0RTI1QUFCMzJENjEwRTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Land Grants</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NkQwQUIzQzVGRDBGNEZEMjg5Q0UyMTQzQjhFRDA5QTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6ODE4NDg4QUI2RDA3NDQ2RkI1QTRFNjA4OUM3QjA4MzA</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification><classificationGroup classificationScheme="indexing-terms"><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem score="90"><className>Education</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDkzNUEzQzFBNEZBNEFBREIxNDM5MTc1MUU5QjI4MTY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></classificationGroup></metadata></legislativeDoc>