<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#349#000054#     1#          500#">Va. Code Ann. § 54.1-500</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><note><bodyText><p>This section has more than one version with varying effective dates.  To view a complete list of the versions of this section see Table of Contents.</p></bodyText></note><anchor id="_54.1-500"/><heading><desig>§ 54.1-500.</desig><title>(Effective July 1, 2017) Definitions</title></heading><bodyText><p>As used in this chapter, unless the context requires a different meaning:</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Accredited asbestos training program"</emphasis> means a training program that has been approved by the Board to provide training for individuals to engage in asbestos abatement, conduct asbestos inspections, prepare management plans, prepare project designs or act as project monitors.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Accredited lead training program"</emphasis> means a training program that has been approved by the Board to provide training for individuals to engage in lead-based paint activities.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Accredited renovation training program"</emphasis> means a training program that has been approved by the Board to provide training for individuals to engage in renovation or dust clearance sampling.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Asbestos"</emphasis> means the asbestiform varieties of actinolite, amosite, anthophyllite, chrysotile, crocidolite, and tremolite.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Asbestos analytical laboratory license"</emphasis> means an authorization issued by the Board to perform phase contrast, polarized light, or transmission electron microscopy on material known or suspected to contain asbestos.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Asbestos contractor's license"</emphasis> means an authorization issued by the Board permitting a person to enter into contracts to perform an asbestos abatement project.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Asbestos-containing materials"</emphasis> or <emphasis typeStyle="it">"ACM"</emphasis> means any material or product which contains more than 1.0 percent asbestos or such other percentage as established by EPA final rule.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Asbestos inspector's license"</emphasis> means an authorization issued by the Board permitting a person to perform on-site investigations to identify, classify, record, sample, test and prioritize by exposure potential asbestos-containing materials.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Asbestos management plan"</emphasis> means a program designed to control or abate any potential risk to human health from asbestos.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Asbestos management planner's license"</emphasis> means an authorization issued by the Board permitting a person to develop or alter an asbestos management plan.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Asbestos project"</emphasis> or <emphasis typeStyle="it">"asbestos abatement project"</emphasis> means an activity involving job set-up for containment, removal, encapsulation, enclosure, encasement, renovation, repair, construction or alteration of an asbestos-containing material. An asbestos project or asbestos abatement project shall not include nonfriable asbestos-containing roofing, flooring and siding materials which when installed, encapsulated or removed do not become friable.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Asbestos project designer's license"</emphasis> means an authorization issued by the Board permitting a person to design an asbestos abatement project.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Asbestos project monitor's license"</emphasis> means an authorization issued by the Board permitting a person to monitor an asbestos project, subject to Department regulations.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Asbestos supervisor"</emphasis> means any person so designated by an asbestos contractor who provides on-site supervision and direction to the workers engaged in asbestos projects.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Asbestos worker's license"</emphasis> means an authorization issued by the Board permitting an individual to work on an asbestos project.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Board"</emphasis> means the Virginia Board for Asbestos, Lead, and Home Inspectors.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Dust clearance sampling"</emphasis> means an on-site collection of dust or other debris that is present after the completion of a renovation to determine the presence of lead-based paint hazards and the provisions of a report explaining the results.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Dust sampling technician"</emphasis> means an individual licensed by the Board to perform dust clearance sampling.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Friable"</emphasis> means that the material when dry may be crumbled, pulverized, or reduced to powder by hand pressure and includes previously nonfriable material after such previously nonfriable material becomes damaged to the extent that when dry it may be crumbled, pulverized, or reduced to powder by hand pressure.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Home inspection"</emphasis> means any inspection of a residential building for compensation conducted by a licensed home inspector. A home inspection shall include a written evaluation of the readily accessible components of a residential building, including heating, cooling, plumbing, and electrical systems; structural components; foundation; roof; masonry structure; exterior and interior components; and other related residential housing components. A home inspection may be limited in scope as provided in a home inspection contract, provided that such contract is not inconsistent with the provisions of this chapter or the regulations of the Board. For purposes of this chapter, residential building energy analysis alone, as defined in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 54.1-1144"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 54.1-1144">§ 54.1-1144<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000054#     1#         1144#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, shall not be considered a home inspection.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Home inspector"</emphasis> means a person who meets the criteria of education, experience, and testing required by this chapter and regulations of the Board and who has been licensed by the Board to perform home inspections.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Lead abatement"</emphasis> means any measure or set of measures designed to permanently eliminate lead-based paint hazards, including lead-contaminated dust or soil.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Lead-based paint"</emphasis> means paint or other surface coatings that contain lead equal to or in excess of 1.0 milligrams per square centimeter or more than 0.5 percent by weight.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Lead-based paint activity"</emphasis> means lead inspection, lead risk assessment, lead project design and abatement of lead-based paint and lead-based paint hazards, including lead-contaminated dust and lead-contaminated soil.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Lead-contaminated dust"</emphasis> means surface dust that contains an area or mass concentration of lead at or in excess of levels identified by the Environmental Protection Agency pursuant to § 403 of TSCA <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="15 USC 2683"><content><span normalizedCite="15 U.S.C. 2683">(15 U.S.C. § 2683).<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1828#123#000015#       2683#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation></p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Lead-contaminated soil"</emphasis> means bare soil that contains lead at or in excess of levels identified by the Environmental Protection Agency.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Lead contractor"</emphasis> means a person who has met the Board's requirements and has been issued a license by the Board to enter into contracts to perform lead abatements.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Lead inspection"</emphasis> means a surface-by-surface investigation to determine the presence of lead-based paint and the provisions of a report explaining the results of the investigation.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Lead inspector"</emphasis> means an individual who has been licensed by the Board to conduct lead inspections and abatement clearance testing.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Lead project design"</emphasis> means any descriptive form written as instructions or drafted as a plan describing the construction or setting up of a lead abatement project area and the work practices to be utilized during the lead abatement project.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Lead project designer"</emphasis> means an individual who has been licensed by the Board to prepare lead project designs.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Lead risk assessment"</emphasis> means (i) an on-site investigation to determine the existence, nature, severity and location of lead-based paint hazards and (ii) the provision of a report by the individual or the firm conducting the risk assessment, explaining the results of the investigation and options for reducing lead-based paint hazards.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Lead risk assessor"</emphasis> means an individual who has been licensed by the Board to conduct lead inspections, lead risk assessments and abatement clearance testing.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Lead supervisor"</emphasis> means an individual who has been licensed by the Board to supervise lead abatements.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Lead worker"</emphasis> or <emphasis typeStyle="it">"lead abatement worker"</emphasis> means an individual who has been licensed by the Board to perform lead abatement.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Person"</emphasis> means a corporation, partnership, sole proprietorship, firm, enterprise, franchise, association or any other individual or entity.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Principal instructor"</emphasis> means the individual who has the primary responsibility for organizing and teaching an accredited asbestos training program, an accredited lead training program, an accredited renovation training program, or any combination thereof.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Renovation"</emphasis> means the modification of any existing structure or portion thereof, for compensation, that results in the disturbance of painted surfaces, unless that activity is (i) performed as a part of a lead abatement or (ii) limited in scope to the site work or remediation as referenced in the definition of contractor in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 54.1-1100"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 54.1-1100">§ 54.1-1100<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000054#     1#         1100#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>. As used in this definition, "compensation" shall include the receipt of (a) pay for work performed, such as that paid to contractors and subcontractors; (b) wages, including but not limited to those paid to employees of contractors, building owners, property management companies, child-occupied facilities operators, state and local government agencies, and nonprofit organizations; and (c) rent for housing constructed before January 1, 1978, or child-occupied facilities in public or commercial building space.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Renovation contractor"</emphasis> means a person who has met the Board's requirements and has been issued a license by the Board to conduct renovations.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Renovator"</emphasis> means an individual who has been issued a license by the Board to perform renovations or to direct others who perform renovations.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Residential building"</emphasis> means, for the purposes of home inspection, a structure consisting of one to four dwelling units used or occupied, or intended to be used or occupied, for residential purposes.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Training manager"</emphasis> means the individual responsible for administering a training program and monitoring the performance of instructors for an accredited asbestos training, accredited lead training program or accredited renovation training program.</p></bodyText><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p>1987, c. 579, § 54-145.4; 1988, cc.  765, 802; <citation normalizedCite="1989 VA CH 397"><content><span normalizedCite="1989 Va. Ch. 397">1989, c. 397<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1989#000397#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1990 VA CH 49"><content><span normalizedCite="1990 Va. Ch. 49">1990, cc. 49<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1990#000049#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1990 VA CH 73"><content><span normalizedCite="1990 Va. Ch. 73">73<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1990#000073#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1990 VA CH 823"><content><span normalizedCite="1990 Va. Ch. 823">823<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1990#000823#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1992 VA CH 152"><content><span normalizedCite="1992 Va. Ch. 152">1992, c. 152<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1992#000152#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1993 VA CH 499"><content><span normalizedCite="1993 Va. Ch. 499">1993, cc. 499<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1993#000499#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1993 VA CH 660"><content><span normalizedCite="1993 Va. Ch. 660">660<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1993#000660#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1994 VA CH 185"><content><span normalizedCite="1994 Va. Ch. 185">1994, cc. 185<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1994#000185#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1994 VA CH 911"><content><span normalizedCite="1994 Va. Ch. 911">911<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1994#000911#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1996 VA CH 76"><content><span normalizedCite="1996 Va. Ch. 76">1996, cc. 76<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1996#000076#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1996 VA CH 176"><content><span normalizedCite="1996 Va. Ch. 176">176<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1996#000176#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1996 VA CH 180"><content><span normalizedCite="1996 Va. Ch. 180">180<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1996#000180#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1996 VA CH 846"><content><span normalizedCite="1996 Va. Ch. 846">846<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1996#000846#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1997 VA CH 885"><content><span normalizedCite="1997 Va. Ch. 885">1997, c. 885<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1997#000885#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1998 VA CH 739"><content><span normalizedCite="1998 Va. Ch. 739">1998, c. 739<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1998#000739#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2001 VA CH 723"><content><span normalizedCite="2001 Va. Ch. 723">2001, c. 723<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2001#000723#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2009 VA CH 358"><content><span normalizedCite="2009 Va. Ch. 358">2009, cc. 358<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2009#000358#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2009 VA CH 819"><content><span normalizedCite="2009 Va. Ch. 819">819<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2009#000819#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2012 VA CH 803"><content><span normalizedCite="2012 Va. Ch. 803">2012, cc. 803<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2012#000803#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2012 VA CH 835"><content><span normalizedCite="2012 Va. Ch. 835">835<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2012#000835#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2016 VA CH 161"><content><span normalizedCite="2016 Va. Ch. 161">2016, cc. 161<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2016#000161#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2016 VA CH 436"><content><span normalizedCite="2016 Va. Ch. 436">436<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2016#000436#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2016 VA CH 527"><content><span normalizedCite="2016 Va. Ch. 527">527<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2016#000527#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PWF0-004G-K48F-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 54.1.</desig><title>PROFESSIONS AND OCCUPATIONS</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="subtitle"><heading><desig>SUBTITLE II.</desig><title>PROFESSIONS AND OCCUPATIONS REGULATED BY THE DEPARTMENT OF PROFESSIONAL AND OCCUPATIONAL REGULATION AND BOARDS WITHIN THE DEPARTMENT</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 5.</desig><title>ASBESTOS, LEAD, AND HOME INSPECTION CONTRACTORS AND WORKERS</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="article"><heading><desig>ARTICLE 1.</desig><title>GENERAL PROVISIONS</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Work Practice Standards</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NUE3OUMzNUJGODYwNDkzRkI2Qjg4OEI1OTZGMDU3MzI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MTFEMUU1MDVBRTJGNDkzODlEQUM2OTJDNjY1MTNCREI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Environmental Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NzFDRDYyNkI2QjhBNDg3NTkyRjRDRkZEQjlCRkRBQzM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Audits &amp; Site Assessments</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MkFCNjI1NjZFRjJDNEE3NDg3MUMxM0ZDNEY1ODlGQkY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjI3QUU4NUZEQzZFNEYzRThENkZBRTA1MkUyQTAwQTA</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RTYwODA2QkYyNkQxNEQ3NUJCOUY2OEMxMUM3OTc2MDI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MTFEMUU1MDVBRTJGNDkzODlEQUM2OTJDNjY1MTNCREI</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Toxic Substances</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Nzc2Q0I3RkQ1N0ExNDM2NEI0MjAzMTg3ODU5NTE0NDI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUE3OUU5MDM1NjFGNDdBOEIxMDVCOUEyQTQ3QzcyOUQ</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Work Practice Standards</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NUE3OUMzNUJGODYwNDkzRkI2Qjg4OEI1OTZGMDU3MzI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MTFEMUU1MDVBRTJGNDkzODlEQUM2OTJDNjY1MTNCREI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Governments</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjdEQjE4OUJDMzQxNDNEMEI0RTI1QUFCMzJENjEwRTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Licenses</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6N0IyQjkyQkVENEM2NDczNzg5MDUwQ0U5RDMzRjlDNUM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QURCRDNBRjBGRTE0NEFBRUEzNUU1MzFGQjg3MTM4MDI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Real Property Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QUUyRTcxRURBNEY2NEE2MDk3QzBCNzRDOEY0NTZDQzk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Indoor Air &amp; Water Quality</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OUNEM0JGQjIzRDVFNDdEMjg2MjEyRTVFQ0Q1NkUyQzM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NkI1NUVDMDA0Nzk5NDJFM0EzQjMyRjQ4NUI1RjZFODc</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Torts</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDAwOEM2NTEzQkVDNEI4NzlGMEZERUEyRjQwODM4Njg7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Independent Contractors</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MTM0MzNFNjRCQzRGNDJEMjk0NTFCNzZGREU1OTRDMkY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MTEzNjUzREVEOURGNDE3MEEwQURENDBCMTBDOUVBNEI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification><classificationGroup classificationScheme="indexing-terms"><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem score="90"><className>Businesses &amp; Corporations</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjA4OEVGODBENzY4NDcxM0IyQzA1OTEwQzVDODRBOUE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></classificationGroup></metadata></legislativeDoc>