<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#349#000038#     2#         4920#">Va. Code Ann. § 38.2-4920</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_38.2-4920"/><heading><desig>§ 38.2-4920.</desig><title>Community-based continuing care disclosure statement; availability of disclosure statement to prospective participants</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a"/><heading><desig>A.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The initial disclosure statement of each community-based continuing care program shall contain the following information unless such information is contained in the CBCC contract and a copy of that contract is attached and made a part of the initial disclosure statement:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The name and business address of the CBCC provider and a statement of whether the provider is a partnership, foundation, association, corporation, or other type of business or legal entity;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Full information regarding ownership of the CCRC facility that the CBCC provider has operated for the minimum three-year period as required in the definition of CBCC provider in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 38.2-4918"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 38.2-4918">§ 38.2-4918<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000038#     2#         4918#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A complete listing of all CCRC facilities owned or operated, or both, by the CBCC provider and, for each, total liquid assets on the balance sheet and current occupancy percentages in independent living units;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_4"/><heading><desig>4.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The names and business addresses of the officers, directors, trustees, managing or general partners, and any person having a 10 percent or greater equity or beneficial interest in the CBCC provider, and a description of such person's interest in or occupation with the provider;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_5"/><heading><desig>5.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> For (i) the CBCC provider, (ii) any person named in response to subdivision 4, and (iii) the proposed management, if the CBCC program will be managed on a day-to-day basis by a person other than an individual directly employed by the provider:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_5_a"/><heading><desig>a.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A description of any business experience in the operation or management of community-based continuing care or long-term care programs;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_5_b"/><heading><desig>b.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The name and address of any professional service, firm, association, foundation, trust, partnership, or corporation or any other business or legal entity in which such person has, or which has in such person, a 10 percent or greater interest and which it is presently intended will or may provide goods, leases, or services to the CBCC provider of a value of $ 500 or more, within any year, including:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_5_b_1"/><heading><desig>(1)</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A description of the goods, leases, or services and the probable or anticipated cost thereof to the CBCC provider;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_5_b_2"/><heading><desig>(2)</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The process by which the contract was awarded;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_5_b_3"/><heading><desig>(3)</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Any additional offers that were received; and</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_5_b_4"/><heading><desig>(4)</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Any additional information requested by the Commission detailing how and why a contract was awarded; and</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_5_c"/><heading><desig>c.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A description of any matter in which such person:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_5_c_1"/><heading><desig>(1)</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Has been convicted of a felony or pleaded nolo contendere to a criminal charge or has been held liable or enjoined in a civil action by final judgment, if the crime or civil action involved fraud, embezzlement, fraudulent conversion, misappropriation of property, or moral turpitude;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_5_c_2"/><heading><desig>(2)</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Is subject to an injunctive or restrictive order of a court of record, or within the past five years had any state or federal license or permit suspended or revoked as a result of an action brought by a governmental agency or department, arising out of or relating to business activity or health care, including without limitation action affecting a license to operate a home care company, foster care facility, nursing home, retirement home, home for the aged, or facility registered under this article or similar laws in another state; or</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_5_c_3"/><heading><desig>(3)</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Is currently the subject of any state or federal prosecution or administrative investigation involving allegations of fraud, embezzlement, fraudulent conversion, or misappropriation of property;</p></bodyText></level></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_6"/><heading><desig>6.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A statement as to:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_6_a"/><heading><desig>a.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Whether the CBCC provider is or ever has been affiliated with a religious, charitable, or other nonprofit organization, the nature of any such affiliation, and the extent to which the affiliate organization is or will be responsible for the financial and contractual obligations of the CBCC provider; and</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_6_b"/><heading><desig>b.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Any provision of the federal Internal Revenue Code under which the CBCC provider is exempt from the payment of income tax;</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_7"/><heading><desig>7.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A description of the services provided or proposed to be provided under community-based continuing care contracts, including the extent to which medical care is furnished or is available pursuant to any arrangement. The disclosure statement shall clearly state which services are included in basic community-based continuing care contracts and which services are made available by the CBCC provider at extra charge. The disclosure statement shall also clearly state which services are offered by the CBCC provider and which services are offered through contractual arrangements. The name and address of the party providing such services shall be disclosed. A definition of the services shall also be provided;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_8"/><heading><desig>8.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A description of all fees required of participants, including any entrance fee and periodic charges. The description shall include (i) a description of all proposed uses of any funds or property required to be transferred to the CBCC provider or any other person prior to the participant's enrollment in the program and of any entrance fee; (ii) a description of provisions for the escrowing and return of any such funds, assets, or entrance fee, the manner and any conditions of return, and to whom earnings on escrowed funds are payable; and (iii) a description of the manner by which the CBCC provider may adjust periodic charges or other recurring fees and any limitations on such adjustments. If the program is already in operation, or if the CBCC provider operates one or more similar programs within the Commonwealth, there shall be included tables showing the frequency and average dollar amount of each increase in periodic rates at each program for the previous five years or such shorter period that the program has been operated by the CBCC provider;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_9"/><heading><desig>9.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A description of any provisions that have been made or will be made to provide reserve funding or security to enable the CBCC provider to fully perform its obligations under community-based continuing care contracts, including the establishment of escrow accounts, trusts, or reserve funds, together with the manner in which such funds will be invested and the names and experience of persons who will make the investment decisions. The disclosure statement shall clearly state whether or not reserve funds are maintained;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_10"/><heading><desig>10.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Certified financial statements of the CBCC provider, including (i) a balance sheet as of the end of the two most recent fiscal years and (ii) income statements of the CBCC provider for the two most recent fiscal years;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_11"/><heading><desig>11.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A pro forma income statement for the current fiscal year for the community-based continuing care program and for the provider of the CBCC;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_12"/><heading><desig>12.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A description of the CBCC provider's criteria for enrollment of participants;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_13"/><heading><desig>13.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A description of the CBCC provider's policies regarding community-based services to non-participants;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_14"/><heading><desig>14.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Any other material information concerning the program or the CBCC provider that may be required by the Commission or included by the CBCC provider; and</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_15"/><heading><desig>15.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The procedure by which a participant may file a complaint or disclose any concerns, to include the CBCC provider's process for resolving complaints and concerns.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b"/><heading><desig>B.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The disclosure statement shall state on its cover that the filing of the disclosure statement with the Commission does not constitute recommendation or endorsement of the CBCC program by the Commission.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c"/><heading><desig>C.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A copy of the standard form or forms for CBCC contracts used by the CBCC provider shall be attached as an exhibit to each disclosure statement.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d"/><heading><desig>D.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> If the Commission determines that the disclosure statement does not comply with the provisions of this article, it shall have the right to take action pursuant to <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 38.2-4931"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 38.2-4931">§ 38.2-4931<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000038#     2#         4931#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_e"/><heading><desig>E.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Three days prior to the execution of a community-based continuing care contract or the transfer of any money or other property to a provider by or on behalf of a prospective participant, whichever first occurs, the CBCC provider shall deliver to the person with whom the CBCC contract is to be entered into a copy of a disclosure statement with respect to the program in question meeting all requirements of this article as of the date of its delivery.</p></bodyText></level><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p><citation normalizedCite="2012 VA CH 208"><content><span normalizedCite="2012 Va. Ch. 208">2012, cc. 208<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2012#000208#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2012 VA CH 303"><content><span normalizedCite="2012 Va. Ch. 303">303<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2012#000303#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PVV0-004G-K53S-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 38.2.</desig><title>INSURANCE</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 49.</desig><title>CONTINUING CARE PROVIDERS AND COMMUNITY-BASED CONTINUING CARE PROVIDERS</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="article"><heading><desig>ARTICLE 2.</desig><title>COMMUNITY-BASED CONTINUING CARE PROVIDERS.</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Regulation of Nursing Facilities for Disabled &amp; Elderly Persons</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QkI5RTc4N0U1MjU1NDQwMEI1MzhDOThGRTIyNDU1NDU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MTlCM0Q3MTlFNUQ0NDA5OTgwQTEwQjE1M0ZGMTlFQjc</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjA4OEVGODBENzY4NDcxM0IyQzA1OTEwQzVDODRBOUE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NzQwNjJBMUVBRDAwNEVFNUIwNjE0M0JFQ0IwNjk5MDU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NTBBOERFMzlGNEE5NDI2OUEwMUFDNkNFOURENTQ5MDQ</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RkE2ODg4Mjk1MTE2NDgzOTk1NTVERDRBRUJFRUUxMjk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NjMzQjkyNzZDOUQ4NEQ2NEIyOEYxNkJCNzBGNTk1OEY</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Contracts Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QzY0RTZFMzE0RjkwNDdFQUI5M0U5N0ZFMjYyREMyQzU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QTdGQUE3QkZDMDlBNDQ1MTkzRjEzMEQ1OEUwNzdDOTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NjZEOEU3MEJBRUQ2NDNFNzhFRjAxRTk1OEU1QjY2QTc</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Criminal Law &amp; Procedure</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NEU0RkE1OUQwNUQwNDgxODhEODZCMjkzOTg3NThBNzk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjkyRDczRDVFODRCNDEwNDkxREY1OEVERTFBNzQ0Njg7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RjQ3RTU2M0FCNUE1NDIxMjlCQkQ5NEQ0NjZGMTk1RTY</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Healthcare Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NkUxMkVDQjJDOEY5NDVDQ0E5NTFEMTlDMjIwNzVERjc7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OUU3Q0QzQTAwQzNCNDdEQ0EwMTYyN0M2NEE4RDdFNEI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QkYxRTIwMkZDRTRCNEY0QzlGMDZDQjE5MkJERjYzNkQ</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Nonhospital Organizations</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6ODE2RkVCRjg3NjgwNEUyMTk5RjcwOTkyRTdCMUI3MjE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6REFBN0UwNDkwRjQ2NDRBQUEyNjBFMDQ1NzIwRjYwMTM</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Public Health &amp; Welfare Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDYwRTY1MDg3MTk5NDUyNkFFRDI1RjJBRERGQ0UxNzI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Nursing Facilities</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QkI5RTc4N0U1MjU1NDQwMEI1MzhDOThGRTIyNDU1NDU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NjVGRUIzQkI1QTg1NDUxNkJFM0UwN0IxRTVENDlBNTM</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Torts</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDAwOEM2NTEzQkVDNEI4NzlGMEZERUEyRjQwODM4Njg7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Remedies</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RjNBMkRDMUQ5RTc2NEZDMzgxRjQzQjdCQzYxNThEN0M7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RkJCRUQ3MDc0RkRGNEY0NUE2RTQ1RjEzNDc0REEzQjI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification><classificationGroup classificationScheme="indexing-terms"><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem score="90"><className>Insurance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDM4MzQ2QUYzMTY0NDQzQTkxRDQwRUUzRUM5RDg0OEM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></classificationGroup></metadata></legislativeDoc>