<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#349#000028#     2#          825#">Va. Code Ann. § 28.2-825</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_28.2-825"/><heading><desig>§ 28.2-825.</desig><title>Importing fish, shellfish or crustacea for introduction into waters of the Commonwealth; penalty</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a"/><heading><desig>A.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> It shall be unlawful for any person to import any fish, shellfish or crustacea into the Commonwealth with the intent of placing such fish, shellfish or crustacea into the waters of the Commonwealth unless one of the following conditions exists:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The fish, shellfish or crustacea are coming from within the continental United States from a state or waters which are on the Marine Resources Commission's list of approved states and waters, and are species which are on the Marine Resources Commission's list of approved species; or</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The person has notified the Commissioner of Marine Resources of such intent and has received written permission from the Commissioner of Marine Resources.</p><p>The list of approved states and waters shall be published by the Commissioner of Marine Resources, and a state or water shall be placed on or removed from such list only with the concurrence of the Director of the Virginia Institute of Marine Science. The Commissioner of Marine Resources, with the concurrence of the Director of the Virginia Institute of Marine Science, is authorized to change the list when he determines that it is necessary for the protection of the waters of the Commonwealth.</p><p>The list of approved species shall be published by the Commissioner of Marine Resources, and a species shall be placed on or removed from such list only with the concurrence of the Director of the Virginia Institute of Marine Science. The Commissioner of Marine Resources, with the concurrence of the Director of the Virginia Institute of Marine Science, is authorized to change the list when he determines that it is necessary for the protection of the waters of the Commonwealth.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b"/><heading><desig>B.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The notification of intent to import shall be in writing and submitted to the Commissioner of Marine Resources at least thirty days prior to the date of importation.  The notice shall state: (i) the specific fish, shellfish or crustacea to be imported, (ii) from what waters the fish, shellfish or crustacea are being taken, (iii) the period of time over which importation is to be accomplished, (iv) the quantities involved, and (v) into what waters the fish, shellfish or crustacea are to be placed.</p><p>A violation of this section is a Class 1 misdemeanor.</p></bodyText></level><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p>1974, c. 327, § 28.1-183.2; <citation normalizedCite="1992 VA CH 836"><content><span normalizedCite="1992 Va. Ch. 836">1992, c. 836<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1992#000836#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PV40-004G-K3R4-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 28.2.</desig><title>FISHERIES AND HABITAT OF THE TIDAL WATERS</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="subtitle"><heading><desig>SUBTITLE II.</desig><title>TIDAL FISHERIES</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 8.</desig><title>HEALTH AND SANITATION PROVISIONS</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="article"><heading><desig>ARTICLE 2.</desig><title>CONTROL OF CRUSTACEA, FINFISH AND SHELLFISH; VIOLATIONS AND PENALTIES</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>International Trade Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RTRDNDkyQ0UwRkRGNEQ0MjgwNzM2NzI3NjlGODE0ODk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MzQyOTdEMDcwRTU1NDFBMkJDNDVFNEQ4NDE2NTk0NDI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MTkwOUZBMTQxN0U2NEY0Qzg2NUQ1RDBFRjA4MDA0OUE</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></metadata></legislativeDoc>