<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#349#000013#     1#          718#">Va. Code Ann. § 13.1-718</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_13.1-718"/><heading><desig>§ 13.1-718.</desig><title>Action on a plan of merger or share exchange</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a"/><heading><desig>A.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> In the case of a domestic corporation that is a party to a merger or share exchange:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The plan of merger or share exchange shall be adopted by the board of directors.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Except as provided in subsections F and H and in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 13.1-719"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 13.1-719">§§ 13.1-719<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000013#     1#          719#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> and <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 13.1-719.1"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 13.1-719.1">13.1-719.1<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000013#     1#        719.1#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, after adopting the plan of merger or share exchange the board of directors shall submit the plan to the shareholders for their approval. The board of directors shall also transmit to the shareholders a recommendation that the shareholders approve the plan, unless the board of directors makes a determination that because of conflicts of interest or other special circumstances it should not make such a recommendation, in which case the board of directors shall transmit to the shareholders the basis for that determination.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b"/><heading><desig>B.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The board of directors may condition its submission of the plan of merger or share exchange to the shareholders on any basis.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c"/><heading><desig>C.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> If the plan of merger or share exchange is required to be approved by the shareholders, and if the approval is to be given at a meeting, the corporation shall notify each shareholder, whether or not entitled to vote, of the meeting of shareholders at which the plan is to be submitted for approval. The notice shall state that the purpose, or one of the purposes, of the meeting is to consider the plan and shall contain or be accompanied by a copy or summary of the plan. If the corporation is to be merged into an existing domestic or foreign corporation or eligible entity and its shareholders are to receive shares or other interests or the right to receive shares or other interests in the surviving corporation or eligible entity, the notice shall also include or be accompanied by a copy or summary of the articles of incorporation or organic document of that corporation or eligible entity. If the corporation is to be merged into a domestic or foreign corporation or eligible entity that is to be created pursuant to the merger and its shareholders are to receive shares or other interests or the right to receive shares or other interests in the surviving corporation or eligible entity, the notice shall include or be accompanied by a copy or a summary of the articles of incorporation or organic document of the new domestic or foreign corporation or eligible entity.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d"/><heading><desig>D.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Unless the articles of incorporation, or the board of directors acting pursuant to subsection B, require a greater vote, the plan of merger or share exchange to be authorized shall be approved by each voting group entitled to vote on the plan by more than two-thirds of all the votes entitled to be cast by that voting group. The articles of incorporation may provide for a greater or lesser vote than that provided for in this subsection or a vote by separate voting groups so long as the vote provided for is not less than a majority of all the votes cast on the plan by each voting group entitled to vote on the transaction at a meeting at which a quorum of the voting group exists.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_e"/><heading><desig>E.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Separate voting by voting groups is required:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_e_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Except as otherwise provided in the articles of incorporation, on a plan of merger by each class or series of shares that:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_e_1_a"/><heading><desig>a.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Is to be converted under the plan of merger into shares, other securities, eligible interests, obligations, rights to acquire shares, other securities or eligible interests, cash, other property, or any combination of the foregoing, or is proposed to be eliminated without being converted into any of the foregoing; or</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_e_1_b"/><heading><desig>b.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Would be entitled to vote as a separate group on a provision in the plan that, if contained in a proposed amendment to articles of incorporation, would require action by separate voting groups under <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 13.1-708"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 13.1-708">§ 13.1-708<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000013#     1#          708#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>;</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_e_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Except as otherwise provided in the articles of incorporation, on a plan of share exchange, by each class or series of shares included in the exchange, with each class or series constituting a separate voting group;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_e_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> On a plan of merger, if the voting group is entitled under the articles of incorporation to vote as a voting group to approve a plan of merger; and</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_e_4"/><heading><desig>4.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> On a plan of share exchange, if the voting group is entitled under the articles of incorporation to vote as a voting group to approve a plan of share exchange.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_f"/><heading><desig>F.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Unless the articles of incorporation otherwise provide, approval by the corporation's shareholders of a plan of merger or share exchange is not required if:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_f_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The corporation will survive the merger or is the acquiring corporation in a share exchange;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_f_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Except for amendments permitted by <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 13.1-706"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 13.1-706">§ 13.1-706<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000013#     1#          706#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, its articles of incorporation will not be changed;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_f_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Each shareholder of the corporation whose shares were outstanding immediately before the effective time of the merger or share exchange will hold the same number of shares, with identical preferences, limitations, and rights immediately after the effective time of the merger or share exchange; and</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_f_4"/><heading><desig>4.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> With respect to shares of the surviving corporation in a merger that are entitled to vote unconditionally in the election of directors, the number of shares outstanding immediately after the merger, plus the number of shares issuable as a result of the merger, either by the conversion of securities issued pursuant to the merger or the exercise of options, rights, and warrants issued pursuant to the merger, will not exceed by more than 20 percent the total number of shares of the surviving corporation outstanding immediately before the merger.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_g"/><heading><desig>G.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Unless the articles of incorporation otherwise provide, approval by the corporation's shareholders of a plan of merger or share exchange is not required if:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_g_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The corporation is a public corporation;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_g_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The plan of merger or share exchange expressly (i) permits or requires such a merger or share exchange to be effected under this subsection and (ii) provides that such merger or share exchange be effected as soon as practicable following the consummation of the offer referred to in subdivision 3 if such merger or share exchange is effected under this subsection;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_g_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A corporation or limited liability company irrevocably accepts for payment shares tendered pursuant to a tender or exchange offer for any and all of the outstanding shares of a constituent corporation, as defined in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 13.1-719.1"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 13.1-719.1">§ 13.1-719.1<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000013#     1#        719.1#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, on the terms provided in such plan of merger or share exchange that, absent this subsection, would be entitled to vote on the adoption of the plan of merger or share exchange; however, the offer may exclude shares of the constituent corporation that are owned at the commencement of the offer by:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_g_3_a"/><heading><desig>a.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The corporation or limited liability company making the offer;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_g_3_b"/><heading><desig>b.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Any person that owns, directly or indirectly, all of the outstanding shares or eligible interests of the corporation or limited liability company making the offer; or</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_g_3_c"/><heading><desig>c.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Any direct or indirect wholly-owned subsidiary of any corporation or limited liability company described in subdivision a or person described in subdivision b;</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_g_4"/><heading><desig>4.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Following the acceptance of shares referred to in this subsection, the shares irrevocably accepted for payment pursuant to the offer and received by the depository prior to expiration of the offer, plus the shares otherwise owned by the corporation or limited liability company consummating the offer, equals at least the percentage of the shares, and of each class or series thereof, that, absent this subsection, would be required to adopt a plan of merger or share exchange under this chapter and by the articles of incorporation of the constituent corporation;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_g_5"/><heading><desig>5.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The corporation or limited liability company accepting the shares referred to in subdivision 3 merges with or into the constituent corporation or acquires all of the outstanding shares of the constituent corporation pursuant to the plan; and</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_g_6"/><heading><desig>6.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Each outstanding share of each class or series of stock of the constituent corporation that is the subject of, and is not irrevocably accepted for payment in, the offer referred to in subdivision 3 is either:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_g_6_a"/><heading><desig>a.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> To be converted in such merger into, or into the right to receive, the same amount and kind of consideration to be paid for shares of such class or series of stock of such constituent corporation irrevocably accepted for payment in the offer; or</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_g_6_b"/><heading><desig>b.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Exchanged in such share exchange for, or for the right to receive, the same amount and kind of consideration to be paid for shares of such class or series of stock of such constituent corporation irrevocably accepted for payment in the offer.</p><p><pre/>As used in this subsection:</p><p><pre/><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Depository"</emphasis> means an agent appointed in connection with an offer referred to in subdivision 3 by the corporation or limited liability company consummating the offer.</p><p><pre/><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Person"</emphasis> means any individual, corporation, partnership, limited liability company, unincorporated association, or other entity.</p><p><pre/><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Received"</emphasis> means (i) with respect to certificated shares, the physical receipt of a stock certificate and (ii) with respect to uncertificated shares, (a) the transfer into the depository's account or (b) the receipt by the depository of an agent's message.</p></bodyText></level></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_h"/><heading><desig>H.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> If a corporation has not yet issued shares and its articles of incorporation do not otherwise provide, its board of directors may adopt and approve a plan of merger or share exchange on behalf of the corporation without shareholder action.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_i"/><heading><desig>I.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> If as a result of a merger or share exchange one or more shareholders of a domestic corporation would become subject to owner liability for the debts, obligations, or liabilities of any other person or entity, approval of the plan of merger or share exchange shall require the execution, by each shareholder, of a separate written consent to become subject to such owner liability.</p></bodyText></level><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p>Code 1950, § 13.1-70; 1956, c. 428; 1975, c. 500; 1985, c. 522; <citation normalizedCite="1991 VA CH 109"><content><span normalizedCite="1991 Va. Ch. 109">1991, c. 109<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1991#000109#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2005 VA CH 765"><content><span normalizedCite="2005 Va. Ch. 765">2005, c. 765<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2005#000765#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2006 VA CH 363"><content><span normalizedCite="2006 Va. Ch. 363">2006, cc. 363<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2006#000363#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2006 VA CH 663"><content><span normalizedCite="2006 Va. Ch. 663">663<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2006#000663#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2007 VA CH 165"><content><span normalizedCite="2007 Va. Ch. 165">2007, c. 165<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2007#000165#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2010 VA CH 782"><content><span normalizedCite="2010 Va. Ch. 782">2010, c. 782<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2010#000782#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2015 VA CH 611"><content><span normalizedCite="2015 Va. Ch. 611">2015, c. 611<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2015#000611#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PSK0-004G-K2CR-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 13.1.</desig><title>CORPORATIONS</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 9.</desig><title>VIRGINIA STOCK CORPORATION ACT</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="article"><heading><desig>ARTICLE 12.</desig><title>MERGERS AND SHARE EXCHANGES</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjA4OEVGODBENzY4NDcxM0IyQzA1OTEwQzVDODRBOUE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Amendments to Articles of Incorporation</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QkY4NEQ1REM5MTNGNDA0NDlFRUEyN0E2QTJDRjA5Mzk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QUQ2RDA4Mzc1QTE5NDk2MjgxOUZEM0RBOENDRTY3N0M</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Annual Meetings</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QUE1QTU0Njg5MDZENDYxQUFCM0VBNDZFMUYwNTAyRDU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NTQzNjBDNjkzMDg4NEIxOEFERDREN0Y3RDM1MkRGNTA</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Director Elections &amp; Removals</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RDUxMTEzOUMwM0RGNDc2Njg4M0U1OUVBOUYzNzM1NTc7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QUE1QTU0Njg5MDZENDYxQUFCM0VBNDZFMUYwNTAyRDU</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Fundamental Changes</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NEQ3OTg1NEZFMjkxNDYzNUFDQTRDRjMwRjBGMkE4Mzg7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RTdBMDVFQjdFRThCNDA0MkJBNDAzNkIyRUE0RjE5REM</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QzlCNzY2RTZEQzQ2NDRFRUEyQzdDMzI0NTFGQ0IyQ0U7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RTJGRkVBNjc4MzI3NDA5MTlEMDI1NjU2NzMyNkYzNTc</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RkFGNEU2QURBRkI2NEU2MjgzQ0RENUY5RDRDNzg4MkI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDY4MDk1M0I4ODA0NEFDMUEzMjgxOEYxRkIyQ0Y1Q0M</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RjFGRTI1RjU5QzhGNDY0ODg0MTdCRkJGNzZGN0U5QkU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MzAxMUZERUVDNEFDNDlBQUE3NkY0MDUyRDFBQjk2OTk</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QkQzRUUzNTMwQ0FENEQ3QjgwMEI1RkY3NTRGMENGRDE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QUMwNTJCQTlCODkzNEVENDkwNEExOTcwMjBDNTIwNUY</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OURBNTNBMkQxMTVENEY5RDkzMDkzRDIzQjBENTNFRjg7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDQ3M0RFODczN0I4NDg2RjlFRDNFMUNBODRDQTU0Q0E</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDk5NzZBNzE5Q0QyNENCNjk4QjcxMjUxQTY4MUUxRDU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QUQ2RDA4Mzc1QTE5NDk2MjgxOUZEM0RBOENDRTY3N0M</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MTI0RjgyMkRDQzE0NERBRjkyRTY4NTFERTFBQzUwMDA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NEI2QjYxNjkwMTkzNDhFRUExNjlFRjVFRUU3NDhBQkE</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6ODEyM0Y1MTE4RURFNDAzQjkwNTc5RkI2QTAyMzgxQTE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NTQzNjBDNjkzMDg4NEIxOEFERDREN0Y3RDM1MkRGNTA</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RDBEN0I2MEQxNkU5NEM2QUIwQTMwMTNGMUQwNEJEREI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6REE4MkJCN0Q4MUJCNEIyN0E3QTNDRTJFQURDNEJCODc</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDc1MERFNzE3ODExNDEyMDgwM0RDMTdBRjUxMDQwQUQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NkU1RUZCODkyMDJCNDgzODlDREYzQkNBQkZDNTNBMzc</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NUUwRjE5Nzk1QUU0NEZGQTgxNjExMzg4QjMxQTYwMzI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NUFDMUUyMjFERDQ1NDg3NTg1NzVCNzQyMTU5QzlBODI</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Procedural Matters</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDJFMjg3QURFOTcwNERBOTlBQTMxNzI2MzNBMTM4QjA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjQxOUM1MEFGMDNGNEYwMDg4MzJEQjkwRUMwODBFQjc</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Unincorporated Associations</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MEQyMkZCODQzMzhCNEQ1Nzg0NEY3MkZGNTk5NzFDMTY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjA4OEVGODBENzY4NDcxM0IyQzA1OTEwQzVDODRBOUE</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Mergers &amp; Acquisitions Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjRDRTUzQzBCMEIyNDU5QkE4QjFDMEE2Qjg2MUZDOTk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Duties &amp; Liabilities of Shareholders</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6M0M3RDcwOEJBRTU0NERBODg0Q0Q1Q0JCNkE3MDQxNTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MkZCODBEQTBEMjdDNDA1Njk5NDIxQjQ3MThGQ0MyMUM</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Transnational Mergers</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OEVGQTQzNkNBMTlCNDU4N0E2MDhENDlEQjFFMzhCOEI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NkE4OEIzNzhFMEUxNEMwRkFENkZBNzlCRDcyNUEyRkI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Torts</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDAwOEM2NTEzQkVDNEI4NzlGMEZERUEyRjQwODM4Njg7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QzJENTY2QjEzRThBNENCODk5MTI2RUMzNzNCQTdBNzc7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjUyM0Q1MkY3MUE0NEYyMzgwNjQxNjMzM0YyMEE1QzI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification><classificationGroup classificationScheme="indexing-terms"><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem score="90"><className>Businesses &amp; Corporations</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjA4OEVGODBENzY4NDcxM0IyQzA1OTEwQzVDODRBOUE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></classificationGroup></metadata></legislativeDoc>