<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#123#000055#    248.31#">Va. Code Ann. § 55-248.31</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_55-248.31"/><heading><desig>§ 55-248.31.</desig><title>Noncompliance with rental agreement; monetary penalty</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a"/><heading><desig>A.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Except as provided in this chapter, if there is a material noncompliance by the tenant with the rental agreement or a violation of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 55-248.16"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 55 -248.16">§ 55-248.16<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#123#000055#    248.16#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> materially affecting health and safety, the landlord may serve a written notice on the tenant specifying the acts and omissions constituting the breach and stating that the rental agreement will terminate upon a date not less than 30 days after receipt of the notice if the breach is not remedied in 21 days, and that the rental agreement shall terminate as provided in the notice.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b"/><heading><desig>B.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> If the breach is remediable by repairs or the payment of damages or otherwise and the tenant adequately remedies the breach prior to the date specified in the notice, the rental agreement shall not terminate.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c"/><heading><desig>C.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> If the tenant commits a breach which is not remediable, the landlord may serve a written notice on the tenant specifying the acts and omissions constituting the breach and stating that the rental agreement will terminate upon a date not less than 30 days after receipt of the notice. Notwithstanding anything to the contrary contained elsewhere in this chapter, when a breach of the tenant's obligations under this chapter or the rental agreement involves or constitutes a criminal or a willful act, which is not remediable and which poses a threat to health or safety, the landlord may terminate the rental agreement immediately and proceed to obtain possession of the premises. For purposes of this subsection, any illegal drug activity involving a controlled substance, as used or defined by the Drug Control Act (<citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 54.1-3400"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 54.1-3400">§ 54.1-3400<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000054#     1#         3400#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> et seq.), by the tenant, the tenant's authorized occupants, or the tenant's guests or invitees, shall constitute an immediate nonremediable violation for which the landlord may proceed to terminate the tenancy without the necessity of waiting for a conviction of any criminal offense that may arise out of the same actions. In order to obtain an order of possession from a court of competent jurisdiction terminating the tenancy for illegal drug activity or for any other action that involves or constitutes a criminal or willful act, the landlord shall prove any such violations by a preponderance of the evidence. However, where the illegal drug activity is engaged in by a tenant's authorized occupants, or guests or invitees, the tenant shall be presumed to have knowledge of such illegal drug activity unless the presumption is rebutted by a preponderance of the evidence. The initial hearing on the landlord's action for immediate possession of the premises shall be held within 15 calendar days from the date of service on the tenant; however, the court shall order an earlier hearing when emergency conditions are alleged to exist upon the premises which constitute an immediate threat to the health or safety of the other tenants. After the initial hearing, if the matter is scheduled for a subsequent hearing or for a contested trial, the court, to the extent practicable, shall order that the matter be given priority on the court's docket. Such subsequent hearing or contested trial shall be heard no later than 30 days from the date of service on the tenant. During the interim period between the date of the initial hearing and the date of any subsequent hearing or contested trial, the court may afford any further remedy or relief as is necessary to protect the interests of parties to the proceeding or the interests of any other tenant residing on the premises. Failure by the court to hold either of the hearings within the time limits set out herein shall not be a basis for dismissal of the case.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d"/><heading><desig>D.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> If the tenant is a victim of family abuse as defined in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 16.1-228"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 16.1-228">§ 16.1-228<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000016#     1#          228#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> that occurred in the dwelling unit or on the premises and the perpetrator is barred from the dwelling unit pursuant to <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 55-248.31:01"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 55 -248.31:01">§ 55-248.31:01<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#142#        55#    248.31#        01#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> based upon information provided by the tenant to the landlord, or by a protective order from a court of competent jurisdiction pursuant to <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 16.1-253.1"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 16.1-253.1">§ 16.1-253.1<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000016#     1#        253.1#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 16.1-279.1"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 16.1-279.1">16.1-279.1<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000016#     1#        279.1#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, or subsection B of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 20-103"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 20 -103">§ 20-103<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#123#000020#       103#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, the lease shall not terminate due solely to an act of family abuse against the tenant. However, these provisions shall not be applicable if (i) the tenant fails to provide written documentation corroborating the tenant's status as a victim of family abuse and the exclusion from the dwelling unit of the perpetrator no later than 21 days from the alleged offense or (ii) the perpetrator returns to the dwelling unit or the premises, in violation of a bar notice, and the tenant fails promptly to notify the landlord within 24 hours thereafter that the perpetrator has returned to the dwelling unit or the premises, unless the tenant proves by a preponderance of the evidence that the tenant had no actual knowledge that the perpetrator violated the bar notice, or it was not possible for the tenant to notify the landlord within 24 hours, in which case the tenant shall promptly notify the landlord, but in no event more than 7 days thereafter. If the provisions of this subsection are not applicable, the tenant shall remain responsible for the acts of the other co-tenants, authorized occupants or guests or invitees pursuant to <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 55-248.16"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 55 -248.16">§ 55-248.16<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#123#000055#    248.16#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, and is subject to termination of the tenancy pursuant to the lease and this chapter.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_e"/><heading><desig>E.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> If the tenant has been served with a prior written notice which required the tenant to remedy a breach, and the tenant remedied such breach, where the tenant intentionally commits a subsequent breach of a like nature as the prior breach, the landlord may serve a written notice on the tenant specifying the acts and omissions constituting the subsequent breach, make reference to the prior breach of a like nature, and state that the rental agreement will terminate upon a date not less than 30 days after receipt of the notice.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_f"/><heading><desig>F.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> If rent is unpaid when due, and the tenant fails to pay rent within five days after written notice is served on him notifying the tenant of his nonpayment, and of the landlord's intention to terminate the rental agreement if the rent is not paid within the five-day period, the landlord may terminate the rental agreement and proceed to obtain possession of the premises as provided in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 55-248.35"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 55 -248.35">§ 55-248.35.<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#123#000055#    248.35#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> If a check for rent is delivered to the landlord drawn on an account with insufficient funds, or if an electronic funds transfer has been rejected because of insufficient funds or a stop-payment order has been placed in bad faith by the authorizing party, and the tenant fails to pay rent within five days after written notice is served on him notifying the tenant of his nonpayment and of the landlord's intention to terminate the rental agreement if the rent is not paid by cash, cashier's check, certified check, or a completed electronic funds transfer within the five-day period, the landlord may terminate the rental agreement and proceed to obtain possession of the premises as provided in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 55-248.35"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 55 -248.35">§ 55-248.35.<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#123#000055#    248.35#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> Nothing shall be construed to prevent a landlord from seeking an award of costs or attorney fees under <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 8.01-27.1"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 8.01-27.1">§ 8.01-27.1<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000008#    01#         27.1#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> or civil recovery under <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 8.01-27.2"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 8.01-27.2">§ 8.01-27.2<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000008#    01#         27.2#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, as a part of other damages requested on the unlawful detainer filed pursuant to <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 8.01-126"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 8.01-126">§ 8.01-126<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000008#    01#          126#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, provided the landlord has given notice in accordance with <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 55-248.6"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 55 -248.6">§ 55-248.6<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#123#000055#     248.6#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, which notice may be included in the five-day termination notice provided in accordance with this section.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_g"/><heading><desig>G.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Except as provided in this chapter, the landlord may recover damages and obtain injunctive relief for any noncompliance by the tenant with the rental agreement or <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 55-248.16"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 55 -248.16">§ 55-248.16.<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#123#000055#    248.16#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> In the event of a breach of the rental agreement or noncompliance by the tenant, the landlord shall be entitled to recover from the tenant the following, regardless of whether or not a lawsuit is filed or an order obtained from a court: (i) rent due and owing as contracted for in the rental agreement, (ii) other charges and fees as contracted for in the rental agreement, (iii) late charges contracted for in the rental agreement, (iv) reasonable attorney fees as contracted for in the rental agreement or as provided by law, (v) costs of the proceeding as contracted for in the rental agreement or as provided by law only if court action has been filed, and (vi) damages to the dwelling unit or premises as contracted for in the rental agreement.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_h"/><heading><desig>H.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> In a case where a lawsuit is pending before the court upon a breach of the rental agreement or noncompliance by the tenant and the landlord prevails, the court shall award a money judgment to the landlord and against the tenant for the relief requested, which may include the following: (i) rent due and owing as of the court date as contracted for in the rental agreement, (ii) other charges and fees as contracted for in the rental agreement, (iii) late charges contracted for in the rental agreement, (iv) reasonable attorney fees as contracted for in the rental agreement or as provided by law, unless in any such action the tenant proves by a preponderance of the evidence that the tenant's failure to pay rent or vacate was reasonable, (v) costs of the proceeding as contracted for in the rental agreement or as provided by law, and (vi) damages to the dwelling unit or premises.</p></bodyText></level><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p>1974, c. 680; 1978, c. 378; 1980, c. 502; 1982, c. 260; 1984, c. 78; 1987, c. 387; 1988, c. 62; <citation normalizedCite="1989 VA CH 301"><content><span normalizedCite="1989 Va. Ch. 301">1989, c. 301<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1989#000301#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1995 VA CH 580"><content><span normalizedCite="1995 Va. Ch. 580">1995, c. 580<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1995#000580#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2000 VA CH 760"><content><span normalizedCite="2000 Va. Ch. 760">2000, c. 760<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2000#000760#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2003 VA CH 363"><content><span normalizedCite="2003 Va. Ch. 363">2003, c. 363<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2003#000363#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2004 VA CH 232"><content><span normalizedCite="2004 Va. Ch. 232">2004, c. 232<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2004#000232#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2005 VA CH 808"><content><span normalizedCite="2005 Va. Ch. 808">2005, cc. 808<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2005#000808#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2005 VA CH 883"><content><span normalizedCite="2005 Va. Ch. 883">883<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2005#000883#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2006 VA CH 628"><content><span normalizedCite="2006 Va. Ch. 628">2006, cc. 628<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2006#000628#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2006 VA CH 717"><content><span normalizedCite="2006 Va. Ch. 717">717<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2006#000717#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2007 VA CH 273"><content><span normalizedCite="2007 Va. Ch. 273">2007, c. 273<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2007#000273#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2008 VA CH 489"><content><span normalizedCite="2008 Va. Ch. 489">2008, c. 489<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2008#000489#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2013 VA CH 563"><content><span normalizedCite="2013 Va. Ch. 563">2013, c. 563<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2013#000563#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2014 VA CH 813"><content><span normalizedCite="2014 Va. Ch. 813">2014, c. 813<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2014#000813#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PTD0-004G-K361-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 55.</desig><title>PROPERTY AND CONVEYANCES</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 13.2.</desig><title>VIRGINIA RESIDENTIAL LANDLORD AND TENANT ACT</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="article"><heading><desig>ARTICLE 5.</desig><title>LANDLORD REMEDIES</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Banking Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjQyMUFCOUJBNURBNEFDREE3MTNCNDk5QkQ4NUM3RjI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDdDNUI3RDJCMEUyNDFGMTk3OUMwODYxQUJCQzU2QTc7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MzBDNzQyN0JENDRFNDYwMkEyNjVFRTgxNjNFRDExNUI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Civil Procedure</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MzUxNjJDMEQ5N0YwNDMzM0JDMjEzM0UzOTYzMzI3OTU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NUZGN0UyQTVGRDZGNDFFNEJDOUFFRTMxRTNDNkFCNjU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RTRDRkNFRjg3QkQ4NDdGRUJFQTQ3MzBFQjdCRDgzRkE</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Contracts Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QzY0RTZFMzE0RjkwNDdFQUI5M0U5N0ZFMjYyREMyQzU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6ODY5MDQzNkRBODFFNEY1REE5Q0UyNDQxRkVCNzY4NTE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDcyMDg3OEYyNEFFNEYxMDgxREM4MUY1QkU3NEM5QzY</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QTdGQUE3QkZDMDlBNDQ1MTkzRjEzMEQ1OEUwNzdDOTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NjZEOEU3MEJBRUQ2NDNFNzhFRjAxRTk1OEU1QjY2QTc</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Transfer of Negotiable Instruments</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6REM4MDY0REIxODc4NEI5NjlGRTVGQzA2NjA5QjhCNTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDMzOTAwOUFFMTFCNEE3Njg4QUEzQTJFOUE1NzE5MkM</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Criminal Law &amp; Procedure</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NEU0RkE1OUQwNUQwNDgxODhEODZCMjkzOTg3NThBNzk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Elements</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QTA3OEIwM0FCMDg3NEZCQ0JDMEU5MDRFMUM5ODE5ODY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NTYxMkNDNjUwRjk1NDZBQ0FFMTM5NEE0RUI0REYwNkI</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Elements</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OUE5RUZGRDFDOTdBNDE1RkEyRjc1Q0I1MUFERkM1RkY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MkRBRUE5MzYwRUJBNDA0MEExRjlDQUNGNjhFMjQwN0Y</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RkZFNENDRTlFNTI3NDg5MEJDMzJEQTQ0RkEzODFGQzY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6REE5OEU0MDg1QjVGNDNDMDk4NDQ1M0M3QzFDRTg4QjA</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MkE1NTE5MzkxN0M0NEVEOTk5NUNCMDZGOUI0NDE1OEM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NTYxMkNDNjUwRjk1NDZBQ0FFMTM5NEE0RUI0REYwNkI</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Willfulness</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NjJFOEQxMTg0QjM2NDQ3Qjk4MzlBM0FCNjEzMzI4NUM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RjUwMTBEODkxNTk4NENEM0E3MThCODlERDExMkEwNzM</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Labor &amp; Employment Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MTE3QUQwOTA0MUYzNDlCMEFFMjUwRUNDM0RDRkM5QzM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Rjg5MTlFRTc3MDNCNDlBRUI3MzA2MDM4NjE4NjI0NTY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjUzRkNDN0YxRUI4NDk1ODlCRTQyREU2MTMzMjYyQTQ</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Legal Ethics</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NUNFOUIxOEI1QzlBNDc2NkFFNTM0QjBGMEJGOTQ5OEI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Fee Agreements</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RjU3Q0U3N0FEOTVFNDYwQjk1QTQ4MzJEODU4RTgxRUQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QUFEODkwOTJBMzU5NDU3QTk1M0Q5MjcyNzRCOTk1QTk</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Real Property Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QUUyRTcxRURBNEY2NEE2MDk3QzBCNzRDOEY0NTZDQzk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Forcible Entry &amp; Detainer</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RUU3RUYxRkNBQTk2NDMxMEIxREEwN0Q3MjlFM0FGOEY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUVBNzBGMzM3NUY1NEExQjg1QTUxRTZCRjA1QTU1NDk</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NTQwQjZGM0VDNUVENEQzMUE1QUNDNTM5ODY2NzlCMTc7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NTk0MkNDNEVCNEUyNDc5NTgxMDMyMzBEMUVFOTU1RTU</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MzkwOEFCOUYzM0IxNEMwM0FGMzkwMjIyRjFFNUYxODI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDU3NDIyNUI2MzczNEUwMzk0M0Y4MkZDQjk2OUUyRTQ</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OTM3M0I4M0ZDQ0EyNEQ3NTgzQzU2MkMwODQxMUE2NTU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Q0RGNkYzMDg1MzhCNDcwOUJBN0NCMDcyNzM5NEFDMDI</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Q0E5OEMzQTI3N0NBNEQyQUJGNzNGQzdDODZDRDhFMUM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QkY0QjUyNzVCQUQ0NDRDRUFDNDk5QTZBQThGNTg1MzU</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Lease Provisions</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDkwNDU4NjdEMEJCNDdENkJCMUM2REVCNzBEQTE2Mzk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDU3NDIyNUI2MzczNEUwMzk0M0Y4MkZDQjk2OUUyRTQ</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Possession of Premises</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NjI5MTQ2MEU5NEZGNDkyOEI4MTYwOTY3NEY3MTRDQzc7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QkY0QjUyNzVCQUQ0NDRDRUFDNDk5QTZBQThGNTg1MzU</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Power to Reenter &amp; Terminate</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MkEwNzc0N0FCODk1NEQ0QjlEREY5QTIxODAwMEUxMzQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QUZDQTAzRTdEMTMzNDZEOTg4N0M3OUMyOUNEMjI0MTQ</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Rent Recovery</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6REFCQjM2RDAyODNBNEU3MTgzMjEyODBCQTFBM0U2RkM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QUZDQTAzRTdEMTMzNDZEOTg4N0M3OUMyOUNEMjI0MTQ</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Termination Notices</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Mzg4QjM3REE4Qzg0NDM4N0EyRENGMTBBMUJDREMzNkU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QUZDQTAzRTdEMTMzNDZEOTg4N0M3OUMyOUNEMjI0MTQ</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Torts</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDAwOEM2NTEzQkVDNEI4NzlGMEZERUEyRjQwODM4Njg7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFBRjYxRjU2ODY3NDcwMUFERkE3MUMzRkMwMjlBOTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjkyMTA1NkNDNDlCNENFNDhGMDlDREREMzlBRkVGQkE</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OENGMEVCRTU5QzA2NDI3OEE0MTUyODI5ODNDRDQ5MDA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QTY5MTk2NDZERUFBNEJCMUE1MDc4NUMyOTA2NzAxQTA</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Liability of Lessees</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MTAwRDI1QUJFRjVBNDE0M0FGOERCNkI0MDZFQkMwQzM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjkyMTA1NkNDNDlCNENFNDhGMDlDREREMzlBRkVGQkE</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification><classificationGroup classificationScheme="indexing-terms"><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem score="90"><className>Real Property</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QUUyRTcxRURBNEY2NEE2MDk3QzBCNzRDOEY0NTZDQzk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></classificationGroup></metadata></legislativeDoc>