<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#349#000054#     1#         3303#">Va. Code Ann. § 54.1-3303</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_54.1-3303"/><heading><desig>§ 54.1-3303.</desig><title>Prescriptions to be issued and drugs to be dispensed for medical or therapeutic purposes only</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a"/><heading><desig>A.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A prescription for a controlled substance may be issued only by a practitioner of medicine, osteopathy, podiatry, dentistry or veterinary medicine who is authorized to prescribe controlled substances, or by a licensed nurse practitioner pursuant to <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 54.1-2957.01"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 54.1-2957.01">§ 54.1-2957.01<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000054#     1#      2957.01#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, a licensed physician assistant pursuant to <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 54.1-2952.1"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 54.1-2952.1">§ 54.1-2952.1<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000054#     1#       2952.1#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, or a TPA-certified optometrist pursuant to Article 5 (<citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 54.1-3222"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 54.1-3222">§ 54.1-3222<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000054#     1#         3222#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> et seq.) of Chapter 32. The prescription shall be issued for a medicinal or therapeutic purpose and may be issued only to persons or animals with whom the practitioner has a bona fide practitioner-patient relationship.</p><p>For purposes of this section, a bona fide practitioner-patient-pharmacist relationship is one in which a practitioner prescribes, and a pharmacist dispenses, controlled substances in good faith to his patient for a medicinal or therapeutic purpose within the course of his professional practice. In addition, a bona fide practitioner-patient relationship means that the practitioner shall (i) ensure that a medical or drug history is obtained; (ii) provide information to the patient about the benefits and risks of the drug being prescribed; (iii) perform or have performed an appropriate examination of the patient, either physically or by the use of instrumentation and diagnostic equipment through which images and medical records may be transmitted electronically; except for medical emergencies, the examination of the patient shall have been performed by the practitioner himself, within the group in which he practices, or by a consulting practitioner prior to issuing a prescription; and (iv) initiate additional interventions and follow-up care, if necessary, especially if a prescribed drug may have serious side effects.</p><p>For the purpose of prescribing a Schedule VI controlled substance to a patient via telemedicine services as defined in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 38.2-3418.16"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 38.2-3418.16">§ 38.2-3418.16<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000038#     2#      3418.16#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, a prescriber may establish a bona fide practitioner-patient relationship by an examination through face-to-face interactive, two-way, real-time communications services or store-and-forward technologies when all of the following conditions are met: (a) the patient has provided a medical history that is available for review by the prescriber; (b) the prescriber obtains an updated medical history at the time of prescribing; (c) the prescriber makes a diagnosis at the time of prescribing; (d) the prescriber conforms to the standard of care expected of in-person care as appropriate to the patient's age and presenting condition, including when the standard of care requires the use of diagnostic testing and performance of a physical examination, which may be carried out through the use of peripheral devices appropriate to the patient's condition; (e) the prescriber is actively licensed in the Commonwealth and authorized to prescribe; (f) if the patient is a member or enrollee of a health plan or carrier, the prescriber has been credentialed by the health plan or carrier as a participating provider and the diagnosing and prescribing meets the qualifications for reimbursement by the health plan or carrier pursuant to <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 38.2-3418.16"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 38.2-3418.16">§ 38.2-3418.16<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000038#     2#      3418.16#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; and (g) upon request, the prescriber provides patient records in a timely manner in accordance with the provisions of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 32.1-127.1:03"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 32.1-127.1:03">§ 32.1-127.1:03<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#958#0000000032#0000000001#     127.1#0000000003#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> and all other state and federal laws and regulations. Nothing in this paragraph shall permit a prescriber to establish a bona fide practitioner-patient relationship for the purpose of prescribing a Schedule VI controlled substance when the standard of care dictates that an in-person physical examination is necessary for diagnosis. Nothing in this paragraph shall apply to: (1) a prescriber providing on-call coverage per an agreement with another prescriber or his prescriber's professional entity or employer; (2) a prescriber consulting with another prescriber regarding a patient's care; or (3) orders of prescribers for hospital out-patients or in-patients.</p><p>Any practitioner who prescribes any controlled substance with the knowledge that the controlled substance will be used otherwise than medicinally or for therapeutic purposes shall be subject to the criminal penalties provided in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 18.2-248"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 18.2-248">§ 18.2-248<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000018#     2#          248#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> for violations of the provisions of law relating to the distribution or possession of controlled substances.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b"/><heading><desig>B.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> In order to determine whether a prescription that appears questionable to the pharmacist results from a bona fide practitioner-patient relationship, the pharmacist shall contact the prescribing practitioner or his agent and verify the identity of the patient and name and quantity of the drug prescribed. The person knowingly filling an invalid prescription shall be subject to the criminal penalties provided in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 18.2-248"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 18.2-248">§ 18.2-248<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000018#     2#          248#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> for violations of the provisions of law relating to the sale, distribution or possession of controlled substances.</p><p>No prescription shall be filled unless there is a bona fide practitioner-patient-pharmacist relationship. A prescription not issued in the usual course of treatment or for authorized research is not a valid prescription.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c"/><heading><desig>C.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Notwithstanding any provision of law to the contrary and consistent with recommendations of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention or the Department of Health, a practitioner may prescribe Schedule VI antibiotics and antiviral agents to other persons in close contact with a diagnosed patient when (i) the practitioner meets all requirements of a bona fide practitioner-patient relationship, as defined in subsection A, with the diagnosed patient; (ii) in the practitioner's professional judgment, the practitioner deems there is urgency to begin treatment to prevent the transmission of a communicable disease; (iii) the practitioner has met all requirements of a bona fide practitioner-patient relationship, as defined in subsection A, for the close contact except for the physical examination required in clause (iii) of subsection A; and (iv) when such emergency treatment is necessary to prevent imminent risk of death, life-threatening illness, or serious disability.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d"/><heading><desig>D.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A pharmacist may dispense a controlled substance pursuant to a prescription of an out-of-state practitioner of medicine, osteopathy, podiatry, dentistry or veterinary medicine authorized to issue such prescription if the prescription complies with the requirements of this chapter and the Drug Control Act (<citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 54.1-3400"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 54.1-3400">§ 54.1-3400<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000054#     1#         3400#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> et seq.).</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_e"/><heading><desig>E.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A licensed nurse practitioner who is authorized to prescribe controlled substances pursuant to <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 54.1-2957.01"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 54.1-2957.01">§ 54.1-2957.01<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000054#     1#      2957.01#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> may issue prescriptions or provide manufacturers' professional samples for controlled substances and devices as set forth in the Drug Control Act (<citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 54.1-3400"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 54.1-3400">§ 54.1-3400<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000054#     1#         3400#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> et seq.) in good faith to his patient for a medicinal or therapeutic purpose within the scope of his professional practice.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_f"/><heading><desig>F.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A licensed physician assistant who is authorized to prescribe controlled substances pursuant to <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 54.1-2952.1"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 54.1-2952.1">§ 54.1-2952.1<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000054#     1#       2952.1#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> may issue prescriptions or provide manufacturers' professional samples for controlled substances and devices as set forth in the Drug Control Act (<citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 54.1-3400"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 54.1-3400">§ 54.1-3400<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000054#     1#         3400#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> et seq.) in good faith to his patient for a medicinal or therapeutic purpose within the scope of his professional practice.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_g"/><heading><desig>G.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A TPA-certified optometrist who is authorized to prescribe controlled substances pursuant to Article 5 (<citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 54.1-3222"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 54.1-3222">§ 54.1-3222<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000054#     1#         3222#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> et seq.) of Chapter 32 may issue prescriptions in good faith or provide manufacturers' professional samples to his patients for medicinal or therapeutic purposes within the scope of his professional practice for the drugs specified on the TPA-Formulary, established pursuant to <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 54.1-3223"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 54.1-3223">§ 54.1-3223<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000054#     1#         3223#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, which shall be limited to (i) analgesics included on Schedule II controlled substances as defined in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 54.1-3448"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 54.1-3448">§ 54.1-3448<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000054#     1#         3448#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> of the Drug Control Act (<citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 54.1-3400"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 54.1-3400">§ 54.1-3400<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000054#     1#         3400#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> et seq.) consisting of hydrocodone in combination with acetaminophen; (ii) oral analgesics included in Schedules III through VI, as defined in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 54.1-3450"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 54.1-3450">§§ 54.1-3450<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000054#     1#         3450#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> and <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 54.1-3455"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 54.1-3455">54.1-3455<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000054#     1#         3455#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> of the Drug Control Act (<citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 54.1-3400"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 54.1-3400">§ 54.1-3400<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000054#     1#         3400#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> et seq.), which are appropriate to relieve ocular pain; (iii) other oral Schedule VI controlled substances, as defined in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 54.1-3455"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 54.1-3455">§ 54.1-3455<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000054#     1#         3455#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> of the Drug Control Act, appropriate to treat diseases and abnormal conditions of the human eye and its adnexa; (iv) topically applied Schedule VI drugs, as defined in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 54.1-3455"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 54.1-3455">§ 54.1-3455<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000054#     1#         3455#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> of the Drug Control Act; and (v) intramuscular administration of epinephrine for treatment of emergency cases of anaphylactic shock.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_h"/><heading><desig>H.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The requirement for a bona fide practitioner-patient relationship shall be deemed to be satisfied by a member or committee of a hospital's medical staff when approving a standing order or protocol for the administration of influenza vaccinations and pneumococcal vaccinations in a hospital in compliance with <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 32.1-126.4"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 32.1-126.4">§ 32.1-126.4.<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000032#     1#        126.4#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation></p></bodyText></level><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p>1983, c. 528, § 54-524.50:1; 1985, c. 336; 1988, c. 765; <citation normalizedCite="1991 VA CH 519"><content><span normalizedCite="1991 Va. Ch. 519">1991, cc. 519<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1991#000519#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1991 VA CH 524"><content><span normalizedCite="1991 Va. Ch. 524">524<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1991#000524#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1992 VA CH 793"><content><span normalizedCite="1992 Va. Ch. 793">1992, c. 793<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1992#000793#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1996 VA CH 152"><content><span normalizedCite="1996 Va. Ch. 152">1996, cc. 152<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1996#000152#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1996 VA CH 158"><content><span normalizedCite="1996 Va. Ch. 158">158<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1996#000158#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1996 VA CH 408"><content><span normalizedCite="1996 Va. Ch. 408">408<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1996#000408#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1997 VA CH 806"><content><span normalizedCite="1997 Va. Ch. 806">1997, c. 806<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1997#000806#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1998 VA CH 101"><content><span normalizedCite="1998 Va. Ch. 101">1998, c. 101<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1998#000101#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1999 VA CH 745"><content><span normalizedCite="1999 Va. Ch. 745">1999, c. 745<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1999#000745#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2000 VA CH 882"><content><span normalizedCite="2000 Va. Ch. 882">2000, cc. 882<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2000#000882#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2000 VA CH 924"><content><span normalizedCite="2000 Va. Ch. 924">924<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2000#000924#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2001 VA CH 465"><content><span normalizedCite="2001 Va. Ch. 465">2001, c. 465<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2001#000465#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2003 VA CH 639"><content><span normalizedCite="2003 Va. Ch. 639">2003, c. 639<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2003#000639#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2004 VA CH 744"><content><span normalizedCite="2004 Va. Ch. 744">2004, c. 744<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2004#000744#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2006 VA CH 432"><content><span normalizedCite="2006 Va. Ch. 432">2006, c. 432<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2006#000432#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2010 VA CH 74"><content><span normalizedCite="2010 Va. Ch. 74">2010, c. 74<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2010#000074#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2015 VA CH 32"><content><span normalizedCite="2015 Va. Ch. 32">2015, cc. 32<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2015#000032#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2015 VA CH 115"><content><span normalizedCite="2015 Va. Ch. 115">115<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2015#000115#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2016 VA CH 86"><content><span normalizedCite="2016 Va. Ch. 86">2016, c. 86<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2016#000086#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PTB0-004G-K29B-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 54.1.</desig><title>PROFESSIONS AND OCCUPATIONS</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="subtitle"><heading><desig>SUBTITLE III.</desig><title>PROFESSIONS AND OCCUPATIONS REGULATED BY BOARDS WITHIN THE DEPARTMENT OF HEALTH PROFESSIONS</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 33.</desig><title>PHARMACY</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="article"><heading><desig>ARTICLE 1.</desig><title>GENERAL PROVISIONS</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Criminal Law &amp; Procedure</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NEU0RkE1OUQwNUQwNDgxODhEODZCMjkzOTg3NThBNzk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Definitions</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NjgxNTc0NUJENzUxNDFCOEI1NzU1RDE1Q0NBOTYzMEE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6REE5OEU0MDg1QjVGNDNDMDk4NDQ1M0M3QzFDRTg4QjA</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Elements</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QTA3OEIwM0FCMDg3NEZCQ0JDMEU5MDRFMUM5ODE5ODY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NTYxMkNDNjUwRjk1NDZBQ0FFMTM5NEE0RUI0REYwNkI</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RkI0NTU4NUZERDJCNEI0RTlDMkVGRkE3MjFGMDM0RkI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MzA5NDE4MjgyNDQwNEI1MTlEREVBN0Q4MjE3M0Q3REM</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MkE1NTE5MzkxN0M0NEVEOTk5NUNCMDZGOUI0NDE1OEM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NTYxMkNDNjUwRjk1NDZBQ0FFMTM5NEE0RUI0REYwNkI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Torts</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDAwOEM2NTEzQkVDNEI4NzlGMEZERUEyRjQwODM4Njg7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MkQwMTc0MUU5MzkxNEMwQzhEQkU0QjA2REQzQzNGMTc7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RjMzQjNFQ0U1MDdFNEQzMjg0MTA0MTY4MUZCQTZBM0U</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification><classificationGroup classificationScheme="indexing-terms"><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem score="90"><className>Businesses &amp; Corporations</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjA4OEVGODBENzY4NDcxM0IyQzA1OTEwQzVDODRBOUE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></classificationGroup></metadata></legislativeDoc>