<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#349#000016#     1#        278.9#">Va. Code Ann. § 16.1-278.9</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_16.1-278.9"/><heading><desig>§ 16.1-278.9.</desig><title>Delinquent children; loss of driving privileges for alcohol, firearm, and drug offenses; truancy</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a"/><heading><desig>A.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> If a court has found facts which would justify a finding that a child at least 13 years of age at the time of the offense is delinquent and such finding involves (i) a violation of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 18.2-266"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 18.2-266">§ 18.2-266<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000018#     2#          266#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> or of a similar ordinance of any county, city or town, (ii) a refusal to take a blood or breath test in violation of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 18.2-268.2"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 18.2-268.2">§ 18.2-268.2<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000018#     2#        268.2#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, (iii) a felony violation of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 18.2-248"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 18.2-248">§ 18.2-248<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000018#     2#          248#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 18.2-248.1"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 18.2-248.1">18.2-248.1<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000018#     2#        248.1#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> or <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 18.2-250"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 18.2-250">18.2-250<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000018#     2#          250#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, (iv) a misdemeanor violation of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 18.2-248"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 18.2-248">§ 18.2-248<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000018#     2#          248#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 18.2-248.1"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 18.2-248.1">18.2-248.1<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000018#     2#        248.1#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, or <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 18.2-250"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 18.2-250">18.2-250<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000018#     2#          250#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> or a violation of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 18.2-250.1"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 18.2-250.1">§ 18.2-250.1<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000018#     2#        250.1#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, (v) the unlawful purchase, possession or consumption of alcohol in violation of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 4.1-305"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 4.1-305">§ 4.1-305<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000004#     1#          305#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> or the unlawful drinking or possession of alcoholic beverages in or on public school grounds in violation of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 4.1-309"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 4.1-309">§ 4.1-309<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000004#     1#          309#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, (vi) public intoxication in violation of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 18.2-388"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 18.2-388">§ 18.2-388<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000018#     2#          388#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> or a similar ordinance of a county, city or town, (vii) the unlawful use or possession of a handgun or possession of a "streetsweeper" as defined below, or (viii) a violation of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 18.2-83"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 18.2-83">§ 18.2-83<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000018#     2#           83#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, the court shall order, in addition to any other penalty that it may impose as provided by law for the offense, that the child be denied a driver's license. In addition to any other penalty authorized by this section, if the offense involves a violation designated under clause (i) and the child was transporting a person 17 years of age or younger, the court shall impose the additional fine and order community service as provided in § 18.2-270. If the offense involves a violation designated under clause (i), (ii), (iii) or (viii), the denial of a driver's license shall be for a period of one year or until the juvenile reaches the age of 17, whichever is longer, for a first such offense or for a period of one year or until the juvenile reaches the age of 18, whichever is longer, for a second or subsequent such offense. If the offense involves a violation designated under clause (iv), (v) or (vi) the denial of driving privileges shall be for a period of six months unless the offense is committed by a child under the age of 16 years and three months, in which case the child's ability to apply for a driver's license shall be delayed for a period of six months following the date he reaches the age of 16 and three months. If the offense involves a first violation designated under clause (v) or (vi), the court shall impose the license sanction and may enter a judgment of guilt or, without entering a judgment of guilt, may defer disposition of the delinquency charge until such time as the court disposes of the case pursuant to subsection F of this section. If the offense involves a violation designated under clause (iii) or (iv), the court shall impose the license sanction and shall dispose of the delinquency charge pursuant to the provisions of this chapter or <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 18.2-251"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 18.2-251">§ 18.2-251<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000018#     2#          251#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>. If the offense involves a violation designated under clause (vii), the denial of driving privileges shall be for a period of not less than 30 days, except when the offense involves possession of a concealed handgun or a striker 12, commonly called a "streetsweeper," or any semi-automatic folding stock shotgun of like kind with a spring tension drum magazine capable of holding 12 shotgun shells, in which case the denial of driving privileges shall be for a period of two years unless the offense is committed by a child under the age of 16 years and three months, in which event the child's ability to apply for a driver's license shall be delayed for a period of two years following the date he reaches the age of 16 and three months.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a1"/><heading><desig>A1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> If a court finds that a child at least 13 years of age has failed to comply with school attendance and meeting requirements as provided in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 22.1-258"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 22.1-258">§ 22.1-258<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000022#     1#          258#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, the court shall order the denial of the child's driving privileges for a period of not less than 30 days. If such failure to comply involves a child under the age of 16 years and three months, the child's ability to apply for a driver's license shall be delayed for a period of not less than 30 days following the date he reaches the age of 16 and three months.</p><p>If the court finds a second or subsequent such offense, it may order the denial of a driver's license for a period of one year or until the juvenile reaches the age of 18, whichever is longer, or delay the child's ability to apply for a driver's license for a period of one year following the date he reaches the age of 16 and three months, as may be appropriate.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b"/><heading><desig>B.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Any child who has a driver's license at the time of the offense or at the time of the court's finding as provided in subsection A1 shall be ordered to surrender his driver's license, which shall be held in the physical custody of the court during any period of license denial.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c"/><heading><desig>C.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The court shall report any order issued under this section to the Department of Motor Vehicles, which shall preserve a record thereof. The report and the record shall include a statement as to whether the child was represented by or waived counsel or whether the order was issued pursuant to subsection A1 of this section. Notwithstanding the provisions of Article 12 (<citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 16.1-299"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 16.1-299">§ 16.1-299<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000016#     1#          299#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> et seq.) of this chapter or the provisions of Title 46.2, this record shall be available only to all law-enforcement officers, attorneys for the Commonwealth and courts. No other record of the proceeding shall be forwarded to the Department of Motor Vehicles unless the proceeding results in an adjudication of guilt pursuant to subsection F.</p><p>The Department of Motor Vehicles shall refuse to issue a driver's license to any child denied a driver's license until such time as is stipulated in the court order or until notification by the court of withdrawal of the order of denial under subsection E.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d"/><heading><desig>D.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> If the finding as to the child involves a violation designated under clause (i), (ii), (iii) or (vi) of subsection A, the child may be referred to a certified alcohol safety action program in accordance with <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 18.2-271.1"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 18.2-271.1">§ 18.2-271.1<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000018#     2#        271.1#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> upon such terms and conditions as the court may set forth. If the finding as to such child involves a violation designated under clause (iii), (iv), (v), (vii) or (viii) of subsection A, such child may be referred to appropriate rehabilitative or educational services upon such terms and conditions as the court may set forth.</p><p>The court, in its discretion and upon a demonstration of hardship, may authorize the use of a restricted permit to operate a motor vehicle by any child who has a driver's license at the time of the offense or at the time of the court's finding as provided in subsection A1 for any of the purposes set forth in subsection E of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 18.2-271.1"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 18.2-271.1">§ 18.2-271.1<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000018#     2#        271.1#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> or for travel to and from school, except that no restricted license shall be issued for travel to and from home and school when school-provided transportation is available and no restricted license shall be issued if the finding as to such child involves a violation designated under clause (iii) or (iv) of subsection A, or if it involves a second or subsequent violation of any offense designated in subsection A or a second finding by the court of failure to comply with school attendance and meeting requirements as provided in subsection A1. The issuance of the restricted permit shall be set forth within the court order, a copy of which shall be provided to the child, and shall specifically enumerate the restrictions imposed and contain such information regarding the child as is reasonably necessary to identify him. The child may operate a motor vehicle under the court order in accordance with its terms. Any child who operates a motor vehicle in violation of any restrictions imposed pursuant to this section shall be guilty of a violation of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 46.2-301"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 46.2-301">§ 46.2-301<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000046#     2#          301#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_e"/><heading><desig>E.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Upon petition made at least 90 days after issuance of the order, the court may review and withdraw any order of denial of a driver's license if for a first such offense or finding as provided in subsection A1. For a second or subsequent such offense or finding, the order may not be reviewed and withdrawn until one year after its issuance.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_f"/><heading><desig>F.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> If the finding as to such child involves a first violation designated under clause (vii) of subsection A, upon fulfillment of the terms and conditions prescribed by the court and after the child's driver's license has been restored, the court shall or, in the event the violation resulted in the injury or death of any person or if the finding involves a violation designated under clause (i), (ii), (v), or (vi) of subsection A, may discharge the child and dismiss the proceedings against him. Discharge and dismissal under these provisions shall be without an adjudication of guilt but a record of the proceeding shall be retained for the purpose of applying this section in subsequent proceedings. Failure of the child to fulfill such terms and conditions shall result in an adjudication of guilt. If the finding as to such child involves a violation designated under clause (iii) or (iv) of subsection A, the charge shall not be dismissed pursuant to this subsection but shall be disposed of pursuant to the provisions of this chapter or <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 18.2-251"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 18.2-251">§ 18.2-251<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000018#     2#          251#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>. If the finding as to such child involves a second violation under clause (v), (vi) or (vii) of subsection A, the charge shall not be dismissed pursuant to this subsection but shall be disposed of under <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 16.1-278.8"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 16.1-278.8">§ 16.1-278.8.<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000016#     1#        278.8#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation></p></bodyText></level><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p><citation normalizedCite="1991 VA CH 534"><content><span normalizedCite="1991 Va. Ch. 534">1991, cc. 534<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1991#000534#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1991 VA CH 696"><content><span normalizedCite="1991 Va. Ch. 696">696<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1991#000696#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1992 VA CH 701"><content><span normalizedCite="1992 Va. Ch. 701">1992, cc. 701<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1992#000701#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1992 VA CH 736"><content><span normalizedCite="1992 Va. Ch. 736">736<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1992#000736#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1992 VA CH 830"><content><span normalizedCite="1992 Va. Ch. 830">830<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1992#000830#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1993 VA CH 482"><content><span normalizedCite="1993 Va. Ch. 482">1993, cc. 482<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1993#000482#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1993 VA CH 866"><content><span normalizedCite="1993 Va. Ch. 866">866<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1993#000866#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1993 VA CH 972"><content><span normalizedCite="1993 Va. Ch. 972">972<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1993#000972#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1994 VA CH 338"><content><span normalizedCite="1994 Va. Ch. 338">1994, c. 338<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1994#000338#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2000 VA CH 835"><content><span normalizedCite="2000 Va. Ch. 835">2000, c. 835<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2000#000835#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2001 VA CH 248"><content><span normalizedCite="2001 Va. Ch. 248">2001, cc. 248<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2001#000248#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2001 VA CH 266"><content><span normalizedCite="2001 Va. Ch. 266">266<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2001#000266#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2002 VA CH 519"><content><span normalizedCite="2002 Va. Ch. 519">2002, cc. 519<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2002#000519#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2002 VA CH 755"><content><span normalizedCite="2002 Va. Ch. 755">755<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2002#000755#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2003 VA CH 118"><content><span normalizedCite="2003 Va. Ch. 118">2003, c. 118<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2003#000118#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2005 VA CH 895"><content><span normalizedCite="2005 Va. Ch. 895">2005, c. 895<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2005#000895#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2007 VA CH 731"><content><span normalizedCite="2007 Va. Ch. 731">2007, c. 731<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2007#000731#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2010 VA CH 522"><content><span normalizedCite="2010 Va. Ch. 522">2010, cc. 522<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2010#000522#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2010 VA CH 569"><content><span normalizedCite="2010 Va. Ch. 569">569<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2010#000569#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2010 VA CH 570"><content><span normalizedCite="2010 Va. Ch. 570">570<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2010#000570#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PTW0-004G-K541-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 16.1.</desig><title>COURTS NOT OF RECORD</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 11.</desig><title>JUVENILE AND DOMESTIC RELATIONS DISTRICT COURTS</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="article"><heading><desig>ARTICLE 9.</desig><title>DISPOSITION</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Criminal Law &amp; Procedure</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NEU0RkE1OUQwNUQwNDgxODhEODZCMjkzOTg3NThBNzk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Community Service</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MzQ1NENDRjI2N0VCNDBDQjlFREUzMEM2QjVBRDgyRTM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QUM4NjRENzc2NUY4NEQwMUEyQTdBNkM4MDhEQURCQjU</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Elements</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MTNGNEYwNTA4NTAyNENBMUEzNEUzMzNFRUJGRTYzN0Q7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjgxQTk4NTA5NDdDNDdENTkwRDcxRTM0NDI1QzhGOTg</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Elements</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MTMyNTFBNEYzNjI0NEEyQTg5N0I1MjFGQUQzRUZDOTM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OTQ0RTQ3NzYxOTUyNEQzMjgyREI4ODM2Mjc1MjgzNkE</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Elements</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MzU1Qjk1RTRGNDQzNDY2NTkyMTQ2MEZDMzM0ODMwNzA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Q0RDNjYyMTVEMkZFNEUxM0I4MTM2NDc3QjBEOEVDNEI</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Entry of Judgments</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUYzRjVDOUVEOTY2NDg5MzgwQkQxQjVFQzNGRDM5NTM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MEUzMkE2MTZCMThENDAwNDhCM0I4RDA2OURFRDAwNDI</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Nzk3NTlBMDhDNEZGNEZFQzk1QzI4QzVBRjIyRjU1Q0M7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RUUwRTU3NTU1NkRGNDlBQTkzQkRCM0RFQTZENTlBMUY</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Status Offenses</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QTE0NzM2MkMwNkRFNDIwQzgwQzc2NEE1QUQwRjQ1ODY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RkQ2MkRCMUMxMjAzNEMxMUI2MDE3RTQ4NzY2QUFCQjU</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Family Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NEI4M0U5Qzg3RTk0NDdBRUJGNDRGNkZEQkU3RDdFNDU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NkQzNDVBNDkwRkM2NDY2RkFEOUI2MzZENjREMkRCODg7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QUJCOTZBNkIyQjFFNDI2MDlGN0I2M0I4ODA5NzE5OTk</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Governments</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjdEQjE4OUJDMzQxNDNEMEI0RTI1QUFCMzJENjEwRTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Licenses</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QUQzRDFDRDE0OTA0NDU2OEIwMUZCNDZEQTBBODdCODA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Njg1MkM3RkYyNzIxNEVFRkJFMTI2NUM4NUU1ODdEM0Q</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Transportation Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RTYzRTk5RDVBQkQ2NDcwQzk2NTU3ODQ5OEE3NDlBNzk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6M0RGOEU0NUFFOTU3NDUxNjhEOEIxMDE2NUU1NzRDQUQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6ODY1RjFBNDEzNUFBNEYzMjhCMjhDRkU1NDlCQ0U3RkU</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Street Cleaning</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6M0M2RDFDNTUwREE5NDU2Q0FDNkE5MUVFNzM3QzcyOUE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjVCODE3RDNEMENDNDkxRjg5MzBBNTJFQkNCRDlFOEU</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification><classificationGroup classificationScheme="indexing-terms"><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem score="90"><className>Governments</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjdEQjE4OUJDMzQxNDNEMEI0RTI1QUFCMzJENjEwRTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></classificationGroup></metadata></legislativeDoc>