<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#349#000046#     2#          391#">Va. Code Ann. § 46.2-391</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_46.2-391"/><heading><desig>§ 46.2-391.</desig><title>Revocation of license for multiple convictions of driving while intoxicated; exception; petition for restoration of privilege</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a"/><heading><desig>A.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The Commissioner shall forthwith revoke and not thereafter reissue for three years the driver's license of any person on receiving a record of the conviction of any person who (i) is adjudged to be a second offender in violation of the provisions of subsection A of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 46.2-341.24"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 46.2-341.24">§ 46.2-341.24<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000046#     2#       341.24#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> (driving a commercial motor vehicle under the influence of drugs or intoxicants), or <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 18.2-266"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 18.2-266">§ 18.2-266<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000018#     2#          266#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> (driving under the influence of drugs or intoxicants), if the subsequent violation occurred within 10 years of the prior violation, or (ii) is convicted of any two or more offenses of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 18.2-272"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 18.2-272">§ 18.2-272<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000018#     2#          272#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> (driving while the driver's license has been forfeited for a conviction under <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 18.2-266"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 18.2-266">§ 18.2-266<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000018#     2#          266#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>) if the second or subsequent violation occurred within 10 years of the prior offense. However, if the Commissioner has received a copy of a court order authorizing issuance of a restricted license as provided in subsection E of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 18.2-271.1"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 18.2-271.1">§ 18.2-271.1<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000018#     2#        271.1#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, he shall proceed as provided in the order of the court. For the purposes of this subsection, an offense in violation of a valid local ordinance, or law of any other jurisdiction, which ordinance or law is substantially similar to any provision of Virginia law herein shall be considered an offense in violation of such provision of Virginia law. Additionally, in no event shall the Commissioner reinstate the driver's license of any person convicted of a violation of § 18.2-266, or of a substantially similar valid local ordinance or law of another jurisdiction, until receipt of notification that such person has successfully completed an alcohol safety action program if such person was required by court order to do so unless the requirement for completion of the program has been waived by the court for good cause shown. A conviction includes a finding of not innocent in the case of a juvenile.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b"/><heading><desig>B.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The Commissioner shall forthwith revoke and not thereafter reissue the driver's license of any person after receiving a record of the conviction of any person (i) convicted of a violation of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 18.2-36.1"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 18.2-36.1">§ 18.2-36.1<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000018#     2#         36.1#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> or <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 18.2-51.4"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 18.2-51.4">18.2-51.4<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000018#     2#         51.4#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> or a felony violation of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 18.2-266"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 18.2-266">§ 18.2-266<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000018#     2#          266#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> or (ii) convicted of three offenses arising out of separate incidents or occurrences within a period of 10 years in violation of the provisions of subsection A of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 46.2-341.24"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 46.2-341.24">§ 46.2-341.24<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000046#     2#       341.24#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> or <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 18.2-266"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 18.2-266">18.2-266<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000018#     2#          266#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, or a substantially similar ordinance or law of any other jurisdiction, or any combination of three such offenses. A conviction includes a finding of not innocent in the case of a juvenile.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c"/><heading><desig>C.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Any person who has had his driver's license revoked in accordance with subsection B of this section may petition the circuit court of his residence, or, if a nonresident of Virginia, any circuit court:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> For restoration of his privilege to drive a motor vehicle in the Commonwealth after the expiration of five years from the date of his last conviction. On such petition, and for good cause shown, the court may, in its discretion, restore to the person the privilege to drive a motor vehicle in the Commonwealth on condition that such person install an ignition interlock system in accordance with <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 18.2-270.1"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 18.2-270.1">§ 18.2-270.1<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000018#     2#        270.1#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> on all motor vehicles, as defined in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 46.2-100"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 46.2-100">§ 46.2-100<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000046#     2#          100#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, owned by or registered to him, in whole or in part, for a period of at least six months, and upon whatever other conditions the court may prescribe, subject to the provisions of law relating to issuance of driver's licenses, if the court is satisfied from the evidence presented that: (i) at the time of his previous convictions, the petitioner was addicted to or psychologically dependent on the use of alcohol or other drugs; (ii) at the time of the hearing on the petition, he is no longer addicted to or psychologically dependent on the use of alcohol or other drugs; and (iii) the defendant does not constitute a threat to the safety and welfare of himself or others with regard to the driving of a motor vehicle. However, prior to acting on the petition, the court shall order that an evaluation of the person, to include an assessment of his degree of alcohol abuse and the appropriate treatment therefor, if any, be conducted by a Virginia Alcohol Safety Action Program and recommendations therefrom be submitted to the court, and the court shall give the recommendations such weight as the court deems appropriate. The court may, in lieu of restoring the person's privilege to drive, authorize the issuance of a restricted license for a period not to exceed five years in accordance with the provisions of § 18.2-270.1 and subsection E of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 18.2-271.1"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 18.2-271.1">§ 18.2-271.1.<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000018#     2#        271.1#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> The court shall notify the Virginia Alcohol Safety Action Program which shall during the term of the restricted license monitor the person's compliance with the terms of the restrictions imposed by the court. Any violation of the restrictions shall be reported to the court, and the court may then modify the restrictions or revoke the license.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> For a restricted license to authorize such person to drive a motor vehicle in the Commonwealth in the course of his employment and to drive a motor vehicle to and from his home to the place of his employment after the expiration of three years from the date of his last conviction. The court may order that a restricted license for such purposes be issued in accordance with the procedures of subsection E of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 18.2-271.1"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 18.2-271.1">§ 18.2-271.1<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000018#     2#        271.1#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, if the court is satisfied from the evidence presented that (i) at the time of the previous convictions, the petitioner was addicted to or psychologically dependent on the use of alcohol or other drugs; (ii) at the time of the hearing on the petition, he is no longer addicted to or psychologically dependent on the use of alcohol or such other drugs; and (iii) the defendant does not constitute a threat to the safety and welfare of himself and others with regard to the driving of a motor vehicle. The court shall prohibit the person to whom a restricted license is issued from operating a motor vehicle that is not equipped with a functioning, certified ignition interlock system during all or any part of the term for which the restricted license is issued, in accordance with the provisions set forth in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 18.2-270.1"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 18.2-270.1">§ 18.2-270.1.<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000018#     2#        270.1#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> However, prior to acting on the petition, the court shall order that an evaluation of the person, to include an assessment of his degree of alcohol abuse and the appropriate treatment therefor, if any, be conducted by a Virginia Alcohol Safety Action Program and recommendations therefrom be submitted to the court, and the court shall give the recommendations such weight as the court deems appropriate. The Virginia Alcohol Safety Action Program shall during the term of the restricted license monitor the person's compliance with the terms of the restrictions imposed by the court. Any violation of the restrictions shall be reported to the court, and the court may then modify the restrictions or revoke the license.</p><p><pre/>The ignition interlock system installation requirement under subdivisions 1 and 2 of this subsection need only be satisfied once as to any single revocation under subsection B of this section for any person seeking restoration under subdivision 1 following the granting of a restricted license under subdivision 1 or 2.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d"/><heading><desig>D.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Any person convicted of driving a motor vehicle or any self-propelled machinery or equipment (i) while his license is revoked pursuant to subsection A or B or (ii) in violation of the terms of a restricted license issued pursuant to subsection C shall, provided such revocation was based on at least one conviction for an offense committed after July 1, 1999, be punished as follows:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> If such driving does not of itself endanger the life, limb, or property of another, such person shall be guilty of a Class 1 misdemeanor punishable by a mandatory minimum term of confinement in jail of 10 days except in cases wherein such operation is necessitated in situations of apparent extreme emergency that require such operation to save life or limb, the sentence, or any part thereof, may be suspended.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> a. If such driving (i) of itself endangers the life, limb, or property of another or (ii) takes place while such person is in violation of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 18.2-36.1"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 18.2-36.1">§§ 18.2-36.1<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000018#     2#         36.1#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 18.2-51.4"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 18.2-51.4">18.2-51.4<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000018#     2#         51.4#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 18.2-266"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 18.2-266">18.2-266<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000018#     2#          266#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, subsection A of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 46.2-341.24"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 46.2-341.24">§ 46.2-341.24<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000046#     2#       341.24#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, or a substantially similar law or ordinance of another jurisdiction, irrespective of whether the driving of itself endangers the life, limb or property of another and the person has been previously convicted of a violation of §§ 18.2-36.1, 18.2-51.4, 18.2-266, subsection A of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 46.2-341.24"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 46.2-341.24">§ 46.2-341.24<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000046#     2#       341.24#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, or a substantially similar local ordinance, or law of another jurisdiction, such person shall be guilty of a felony punishable by confinement in a state correctional facility for not less than one year nor more than five years, one year of which shall be a mandatory minimum term of confinement or, in the discretion of the jury or the court trying the case without a jury, by mandatory minimum confinement in jail for a period of 12 months and no portion of such sentence shall be suspended or run concurrently with any other sentence.</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d_2_b"/><heading><desig>b.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> However, in cases wherein such operation is necessitated in situations of apparent extreme emergency that require such operation to save life or limb, the sentence, or any part thereof, may be suspended.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> If any such offense of driving is a second or subsequent violation, such person shall be punished as provided in subdivision 2 of this subsection, irrespective of whether the offense, of itself, endangers the life, limb, or property of another.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_e"/><heading><desig>E.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Notwithstanding the provisions of subdivisions 2 and 3 of subsection D, following conviction and prior to imposition of sentence with the consent of the defendant, the court may order the defendant to be evaluated for and to participate in the Boot Camp Incarceration Program pursuant to <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 19.2-316.1"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 19.2-316.1">§ 19.2-316.1<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000019#     2#        316.1#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, or the Detention Center Incarceration Program pursuant to <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 19.2-316.2"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 19.2-316.2">§ 19.2-316.2<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000019#     2#        316.2#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, or the Diversion Center Incarceration Program pursuant to <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 19.2-316.3"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 19.2-316.3">§ 19.2-316.3.<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000019#     2#        316.3#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation></p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_f"/><heading><desig>F.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Any period of driver's license revocation imposed pursuant to this section shall not begin to expire until the person convicted has surrendered his license to the court or to the Department of Motor Vehicles.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_g"/><heading><desig>G.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Nothing in this section shall prohibit a person from operating any farm tractor on the highways when it is necessary to move the tractor from one tract of land used for agricultural purposes to another such tract of land when the distance between the tracts is no more than five miles.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_h"/><heading><desig>H.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Any person who operates a motor vehicle or any self-propelled machinery or equipment (i) while his license is revoked pursuant to subsection A or B, or (ii) in violation of the terms of a restricted license issued pursuant to subsection C, where the provisions of subsection D do not apply, shall be guilty of a violation of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 18.2-272"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 18.2-272">§ 18.2-272<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000018#     2#          272#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></level><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p>Code 1950, § 46-417; 1958, c. 541, § 46.1-421; 1960, c. 364; 1964, c. 194; 1968, c. 561; 1976, cc. 359, 612, 691; 1983, c. 504; 1984, cc. 658, 673, 780; 1987, c. 409; <citation normalizedCite="1989 VA CH 705"><content><span normalizedCite="1989 Va. Ch. 705">1989, cc. 705<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1989#000705#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1989 VA CH 727"><content><span normalizedCite="1989 Va. Ch. 727">727<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1989#000727#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1990 VA CH 949"><content><span normalizedCite="1990 Va. Ch. 949">1990, c. 949<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1990#000949#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1994 VA CH 573"><content><span normalizedCite="1994 Va. Ch. 573">1994, c. 573<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1994#000573#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1995 VA CH 486"><content><span normalizedCite="1995 Va. Ch. 486">1995, c. 486<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1995#000486#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1997 VA CH 691"><content><span normalizedCite="1997 Va. Ch. 691">1997, cc. 691<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1997#000691#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1997 VA CH 706"><content><span normalizedCite="1997 Va. Ch. 706">706<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1997#000706#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1999 VA CH 945"><content><span normalizedCite="1999 Va. Ch. 945">1999, cc. 945<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1999#000945#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1999 VA CH 987"><content><span normalizedCite="1999 Va. Ch. 987">987<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1999#000987#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2000 VA CH 243"><content><span normalizedCite="2000 Va. Ch. 243">2000, cc. 243<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2000#000243#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2000 VA CH 956"><content><span normalizedCite="2000 Va. Ch. 956">956<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2000#000956#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2000 VA CH 958"><content><span normalizedCite="2000 Va. Ch. 958">958<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2000#000958#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2000 VA CH 959"><content><span normalizedCite="2000 Va. Ch. 959">959<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2000#000959#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2000 VA CH 980"><content><span normalizedCite="2000 Va. Ch. 980">980<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2000#000980#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2000 VA CH 982"><content><span normalizedCite="2000 Va. Ch. 982">982<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2000#000982#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2000 VA CH 985"><content><span normalizedCite="2000 Va. Ch. 985">985<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2000#000985#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2001 VA CH 739"><content><span normalizedCite="2001 Va. Ch. 739">2001, c. 739<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2001#000739#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2004 VA CH 461"><content><span normalizedCite="2004 Va. Ch. 461">2004, cc. 461<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2004#000461#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2004 VA CH 937"><content><span normalizedCite="2004 Va. Ch. 937">937<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2004#000937#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2004 VA CH 951"><content><span normalizedCite="2004 Va. Ch. 951">951<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2004#000951#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2013 VA CH 415"><content><span normalizedCite="2013 Va. Ch. 415">2013, cc. 415<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2013#000415#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2013 VA CH 655"><content><span normalizedCite="2013 Va. Ch. 655">655<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2013#000655#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2016 VA CH 230"><content><span normalizedCite="2016 Va. Ch. 230">2016, c. 230<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2016#000230#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PV40-004G-K49B-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 46.2.</desig><title>MOTOR VEHICLES</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="subtitle"><heading><desig>SUBTITLE II.</desig><title>TITLING, REGISTRATION AND LICENSURE</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 3.</desig><title>LICENSURE OF DRIVERS</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="article"><heading><desig>ARTICLE 12.</desig><title>SUSPENSION AND REVOCATION OF LICENSES, GENERALLY; ADDITIONAL PENALTIES</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Maintenance &amp; Safety</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjdBNTEyMkZERDI4NDY4RTk3OTQ2N0FFMUNGRkIxNjE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OTU3NDRDNEM2QUYyNDdGQUE1NEU4NjRGMDRCMUEyNUU</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Criminal Law &amp; Procedure</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NEU0RkE1OUQwNUQwNDgxODhEODZCMjkzOTg3NThBNzk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Concurrent Sentences</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MEY2NDFGQTNBMEVGNDRGNzkwMDQwREZDMzBCNkVFMTQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUIzQ0NGRDZERUU3NERCODg2MEZFMDI2RTI0RTA3RTc</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Nzk3NTlBMDhDNEZGNEZFQzk1QzI4QzVBRjIyRjU1Q0M7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RUUwRTU3NTU1NkRGNDlBQTkzQkRCM0RFQTZENTlBMUY</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NTMxNkZFMzRCNDIwNEUxN0FERDIyNDZCRjkzMzU2RTE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QzY4Mzk5NDNDRjMzNEEwREE1RTU3NkM0QjAyQkEwNTA</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NTdDNkUxRDBFRUY4NDBFNjkyOEEyNTIwQTQ3MUE0NjM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NEE5MkQ0M0FBNzYyNEI4MzgwMjg5MTk5NzNDMzI3ODE</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Penalties</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RThBQ0I1NEVGNjFGNDc2RDhBQzgyOTk1QjdCODY1QTE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QzY4Mzk5NDNDRjMzNEEwREE1RTU3NkM0QjAyQkEwNTA</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Shock Incarceration</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6ODg2ODRGRjNDN0JENDQ5RDgyQTQ5QzQ2NkU2NUJDODM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QUM4NjRENzc2NUY4NEQwMUEyQTdBNkM4MDhEQURCQjU</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Suspension</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QUYzMDM5RjkwN0VBNDNGNzgzRkVCQjY4NUU2Nzg3Nzc7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUIzQ0NGRDZERUU3NERCODg2MEZFMDI2RTI0RTA3RTc</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Transportation Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RTYzRTk5RDVBQkQ2NDcwQzk2NTU3ODQ5OEE3NDlBNzk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Expiration</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDYwRkEzMTcyN0I3NDZBRDk1MkI5NTQzNDE2RUI5MTk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NUE5RTcxOUU3RDczNDlDNjgzMkJCMTQwQTkxQzdFNUU</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Farm Equipment</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6ODIzQjhERDhENDhBNEU3RUEwRUJCRkI5NjM4OERDMzA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RUI2RkNERjc3QTRCNEEyRkI5QkQwRTRFMzFBQkUxMjA</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6M0RGOEU0NUFFOTU3NDUxNjhEOEIxMDE2NUU1NzRDQUQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6ODY1RjFBNDEzNUFBNEYzMjhCMjhDRkU1NDlCQ0U3RkU</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Maintenance &amp; Safety</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjdBNTEyMkZERDI4NDY4RTk3OTQ2N0FFMUNGRkIxNjE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OTU3NDRDNEM2QUYyNDdGQUE1NEU4NjRGMDRCMUEyNUU</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Revocation &amp; Suspension</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QUNDMUM0MDYwNEE1NDZGQkIyNzQyNzQ0RTIzNkFBMzk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6ODY1RjFBNDEzNUFBNEYzMjhCMjhDRkU1NDlCQ0U3RkU</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification><classificationGroup classificationScheme="indexing-terms"><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem score="90"><className>Transportation</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RTYzRTk5RDVBQkQ2NDcwQzk2NTU3ODQ5OEE3NDlBNzk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></classificationGroup></metadata></legislativeDoc>