<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#123#000056#     237.1#">Va. Code Ann. § 56-237.1</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_56-237.1"/><heading><desig>§ 56-237.1.</desig><title>Notification of intent to seek rate change in schedules required to be filed under § 56-236</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a"/><heading><desig>A.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Every public utility, other than a public utility providing water or sewer service, that indicates upon existing required schedules, or upon new schedules required to be filed in lieu thereof, changes in rates, tolls, charges, rules and regulations, shall cause to have published, once a week for four successive weeks, in one or more newspapers in circulation in its franchise area and approved by the Commission, a notice of its intention to change its rates, tolls, charges, rules and regulations. Every public utility providing water or sewer service that indicates upon existing required schedules, or upon new schedules required to be filed in lieu thereof, changes in rates, tolls, charges, rules and regulations, shall cause to have published at least once in one or more newspapers in circulation in its franchise area and approved by the Commission, a notice of its intention to change its rates, tolls, charges, rules and regulations. The last such publication shall appear no less than 30 days prior to the time any changed rates, tolls, charges, rules and regulations shall take effect. This notice shall be in such form and contain such information as prescribed by the Commission.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b"/><heading><desig>B.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Every public utility that indicates upon existing required schedules, or upon new schedules required to be filed in lieu thereof, changes in rates, tolls, charges, rules, and regulations shall mail to each of its customers who receive periodic statements of charges by mail or send electronically to each of its customers who receive periodic statements of charges electronically, along with its periodic invoice, bill, or other statement advising the customer of its charges, a notice of its intention to change its rates, tolls, charges, rules, and regulations. This notice shall be mailed or sent electronically no less than 30 days prior to the time any such changed rate, toll, charge, rule, and regulation shall take effect. This notice shall be in such form and contain such information as prescribed by the Commission.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c"/><heading><desig>C.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Except for public utilities providing water or sewer service, the Commission may dispense with either or both of the requirements contained in subsections A and B if either or both such requirements are not necessary to provide adequate notice to all of the public utilities' customers. The Commission may prescribe additional requirements for notification to a public utility's customers of its intention to change its rates, tolls, charges, rules, and regulations.</p></bodyText></level><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p>1976, c. 763; <citation normalizedCite="2011 VA CH 738"><content><span normalizedCite="2011 Va. Ch. 738">2011, cc. 738<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2011#000738#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2011 VA CH 740"><content><span normalizedCite="2011 Va. Ch. 740">740<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2011#000740#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2016 VA CH 191"><content><span normalizedCite="2016 Va. Ch. 191">2016, cc. 191<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2016#000191#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2016 VA CH 283"><content><span normalizedCite="2016 Va. Ch. 283">283<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2016#000283#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PTD0-004G-K3NY-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 56.</desig><title>PUBLIC SERVICE COMPANIES</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 10.</desig><title>HEAT, LIGHT, POWER, WATER AND OTHER UTILITY COMPANIES GENERALLY</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="article"><heading><desig>ARTICLE 2.</desig><title>SERVICES, RATES, CHARGES, ETC</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Energy &amp; Utilities Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OUUzODAyRDk1QzVFNEZGMEJDM0RGMDYxOTlEMEEzRDA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RUM0NDIyNzUzRjNENDk1ODkzMkIxNjQzODNDQzkwQjA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NkU4REM5MTFCOTEzNDRDQ0IyNEEyRkNGRDQyQjM3REY</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OEFFRkJBRTg3MzUyNDJDMDk5MTA5MDc3NDFDMzlFMjU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDgxMjY0MUEwODJFNEQ4RkI3QjhCNUI3ODlFNERFRDY</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></metadata></legislativeDoc>