<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#142#        36#     55.33#         1#">Va. Code Ann. § 36-55.33:1</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_36-55.33_1"/><heading><desig>§ 36-55.33:1.</desig><title>Mortgage loan terms and conditions</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a"/><heading><desig>A.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> All mortgage loans made by HDA pursuant to <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 36-55.31"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 36 -55.31">§ 36-55.31<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#123#000036#     55.31#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> of this chapter shall be subject to the following terms and conditions:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The ratio of mortgage loan principal amount to total housing development costs and the amortization period of any mortgage loans made by HDA which are federally insured mortgages, in whole or in part, or which are otherwise assisted or aided, directly or indirectly, by the federal government, shall be governed by the rules and regulations provided in or pursuant to the federal government program under which the HDA mortgage loan or part thereof is insured, guaranteed, assisted or aided; but in no event shall such amortization period exceed 50 years.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A mortgage loan made by HDA may be prepaid to maturity after a period of years, and on such terms and conditions, as are determined by HDA in its rules and regulations or in the HDA resolution authorizing, or commitment for, such mortgage loan.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> HDA shall have authority to establish and modify from time to time the interest rates at which it shall make mortgage loans and commitments therefor. Such interest rates shall be established by HDA in its sole discretion at the lowest level consistent with HDA's cost of operation and its responsibilities to the holders of its bonds, bond anticipation notes and other obligations. In addition to such interest charges, HDA may make and collect such fees and charges, including but not limited to reimbursement of HDA's financing costs, service charges, insurance premiums and mortgage insurance premiums, as HDA determines to be reasonable. No person shall, by way of defense or otherwise, avail himself of any of the provisions of Chapter 3 (<citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 6.2-300"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 6.2-300">§ 6.2-300<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000006#     2#          300#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> et seq.) of Title 6.2 to avoid or defeat the payment of any interest or fee which he shall have contracted to pay on any loan or forbearance of money made, directly or indirectly, or assisted in any manner by HDA under or pursuant to this chapter.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b"/><heading><desig>B.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Mortgage loans made by HDA to housing sponsors to finance the ownership and operation of housing developments and multifamily residential housing intended for occupancy by persons and families of low and moderate income, pursuant to subdivision (10) of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 36-55.31"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 36 -55.31">§ 36-55.31<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#123#000036#     55.31#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, shall be subject to the following terms and conditions in addition to those contained in subsection A of this section:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The amount disbursed with respect to an HDA mortgage loan to a limited profit housing sponsor shall not exceed 95 percent of the total housing development costs and to a nonprofit housing sponsor shall not exceed 100 percent of the total housing development costs. Subsequent to the disbursement of such amount, additional amounts may be from time to time disbursed if the sum of the amount to be so disbursed and the then outstanding principal balance of the HDA mortgage loan does not exceed 95 percent of the market value of the housing development or residential housing as then determined by the Authority. The amortization period of such an HDA mortgage loan shall be as determined by HDA in its rules and regulations or in the HDA resolution authorizing, or commitment for, such mortgage loan; but in no event shall such amortization period exceed 50 years.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The instrument evidencing any such HDA mortgage loan and the mortgage securing any such HDA mortgage loan shall be in such form and contain such terms and conditions as shall be prescribed or approved by HDA. The aforesaid mortgage and instrument evidencing an HDA mortgage loan may contain exculpatory provisions relieving the housing sponsor or its principal or principals from personal liability if deemed desirable by HDA.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> With respect to any such HDA mortgage loan made to a limited profit housing sponsor, HDA may require that such limited profit housing sponsor not make distributions in any one year with respect to the housing development or multifamily residential housing financed by such HDA mortgage loan in excess of such percentage of such limited profit housing sponsor's equity in the housing development or multifamily residential housing as may be determined by HDA in its rules and regulations or in the HDA resolution authorizing, or commitment for such mortgage loan. None of the partners, principals, stockholders or holders of a beneficial interest in such limited profit housing sponsor shall earn, accept or receive a return in any one year with respect to the housing development or multifamily residential housing financed by such HDA mortgage loan greater than his applicable proportion of any such percentage of such limited profit housing sponsor's equity in the housing development or multifamily residential housing as may be determined by HDA in its rules and regulations or in the HDA resolution authorizing, or commitment for, such mortgage loan. The right to any such limited distribution or return may be cumulative to the extent provided by HDA in its rules and regulations or in the HDA resolution authorizing, or commitment for, such mortgage loan. For the purpose of this section, the terms "distribution" and "return" are intended to mean payments on account of the housing development or multifamily residential housing financed by such HDA mortgage loan resulting from the operation thereof. Any payment to a person or entity who is a partner, principal, stockholder or holder of a beneficial interest in such limited profit housing sponsor shall not be deemed a "distribution" or "return" to such person or entity if the funds with which such payment is made are funds paid or contributed to such limited profit housing sponsor by persons or entities purchasing a beneficial interest in such limited profit housing sponsor. At or after the completion of construction, rehabilitation or improvement of the housing development or multifamily residential housing financed by such HDA mortgage loan, such limited profit housing sponsor's equity in the housing development or multifamily residential housing shall be established in the manner provided by HDA in its rules and regulations or in the HDA resolution authorizing, or commitment for such mortgage loan. Such equity shall be determined by HDA, at its option, as either (i) the difference between the total housing development costs as to the housing development or multifamily residential housing and the final principal amount of such HDA mortgage loan, or (ii) the difference between the fair market value of such housing development and the final principal amount of such HDA mortgage loan. HDA may thereafter from time to time adjust such equity to be equal to the difference, as of the date of adjustment, between the fair market value of such housing development and the outstanding principal balance of such HDA mortgage loan. HDA may review and regulate a proposed retirement of any capital investment in, or redemption of any stock of, such limited profit housing sponsor in the manner provided by HDA in its rules and regulations or in the HDA resolution authorizing, or commitment for, such mortgage loan.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_4"/><heading><desig>4.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> With respect to any such HDA mortgage loan, HDA may require the housing sponsor and other parties related to the housing development or multifamily residential housing financed by such HDA mortgage loan to execute such agreements, assurances, guarantees and certifications as HDA shall determine to be necessary including, without limitation, agreements between HDA and such housing sponsor and its partners, principals or stockholders to limitations established by HDA as to rentals and other charges, profits, fees, the use and disposition of the real property constituting the site of or relating to the housing development or multifamily residential housing and other property of such housing sponsor, and the use and disposition of franchises of such housing sponsor to the extent more restrictive limitations are not provided by the law under which such housing sponsor is incorporated or organized.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_5"/><heading><desig>5.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> As a condition of any such HDA mortgage loan, HDA shall have the power to supervise the housing sponsor in accordance with the provisions of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 36-55.34:1"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 36 -55.34:1">§ 36-55.34:1<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#142#        36#     55.34#         1#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> at all times during which such HDA mortgage loan is outstanding and thereafter as necessary to preserve the federal tax exemption of the notes or bonds issued by HDA to finance such HDA mortgage loan.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c"/><heading><desig>C.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Mortgage loans made by HDA to persons and families of low and moderate income to finance the purchase or refinancing of single-family residential housing, pursuant to subdivision (11) of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 36-55.31"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 36 -55.31">§ 36-55.31<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#123#000036#     55.31#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, shall be subject to the following terms and conditions in addition to those contained in subsection A of this section:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The amount disbursed with respect to such HDA mortgage loan shall not exceed 100 percent of the sales price or market value of the single-family residential housing, as determined or approved by or on behalf of HDA. HDA may also disburse additional amounts to finance such closing costs and fees as it may deem necessary or appropriate, and all such disbursements and financings of closing costs and fees subsequent to the enactment of this chapter are hereby validated. The amortization period of such an HDA mortgage loan shall be as determined by HDA in its rules and regulations or in the HDA resolution authorizing, or commitment for, such mortgage loan; but in no event shall such amortization period exceed 50 years. If during the term of the HDA mortgage loan (i) the outstanding principal balance of the HDA mortgage loan is expected to increase to an amount in excess of the original principal balance or (ii) the amount of monthly payments on the HDA mortgage loan will or may be adjusted, HDA shall so notify the applicants prior to the execution of the HDA mortgage loan. Such notice shall describe the terms and conditions under which the outstanding principal balance or the amount of monthly payments, or both, may be so increased or adjusted, and such notice shall be signed by the applicants.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Such an HDA mortgage loan shall be made only after a determination that such a mortgage loan is not otherwise available from private lenders upon reasonably equivalent terms and conditions, and the HDA resolution authorizing, or commitment for, such mortgage loan shall contain such a determination.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The instrument evidencing any such HDA mortgage loan and the mortgage securing any such HDA mortgage loan shall be in such form and contain such terms and conditions as shall be prescribed or approved by HDA. With respect to any such HDA mortgage loan, HDA may require the person or family of low or moderate income to execute such agreements, assurances, guarantees and certifications as HDA shall determine to be necessary including, without limitation, agreements between HDA and such person or family of low or moderate income relating to the use, occupancy, maintenance and sale of the single-family residential housing financed by such HDA mortgage loan and the payment, prepayment and assignment of such HDA mortgage loan.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d"/><heading><desig>D.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Mortgage loans made by HDA to housing sponsors or persons or families of low or moderate income to finance the construction, rehabilitation, preservation or improvement of housing developments or residential housing intended, upon completion of such construction, rehabilitation, preservation or improvement, for ownership or occupancy by persons and families of low and moderate income, pursuant to subdivision (12) of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 36-55.31"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 36 -55.31">§ 36-55.31<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#123#000036#     55.31#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> of this chapter, shall be subject to the following terms and conditions in addition to those contained in subsection A of this section:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The amount disbursed with respect to such an HDA mortgage loan to a limited profit housing sponsor shall not exceed 95 percent of the total housing development costs and to a nonprofit housing sponsor or a person or family of low or moderate income shall not exceed 100 percent of the total housing development costs. Subsequent to the disbursement of such amount, additional amounts may be from time to time disbursed if the sum of the amount to be so disbursed and the then outstanding principal balance of the HDA mortgage loan does not exceed 95 percent of the market value of the housing development or residential housing as then determined by the Authority. Without regard as to whether HDA intends to remain the lender in respect to such mortgage loan throughout the amortization period thereof, the amortization period of such an HDA mortgage loan shall be as determined by HDA in its rules and regulations or in the HDA resolution authorizing, or commitment for, such mortgage loan.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> In considering any application for such an HDA mortgage loan, HDA shall give first priority to applications relating to housing developments or residential housing which are or will be well-planned and well-designed, and also shall give consideration to:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d_2_a"/><heading><desig>a.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The comparative need for housing for persons and families of low and moderate income in the area proposed to be served by the housing development or residential housing;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d_2_b"/><heading><desig>b.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The ability of the applicant to construct, rehabilitate or improve and market or operate, manage and maintain the housing development or residential housing;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d_2_c"/><heading><desig>c.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The existence of zoning or other regulations to protect adequately the housing development or residential housing against detrimental future uses which could cause undue depreciation in the value of the housing development or residential housing;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d_2_d"/><heading><desig>d.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The availability of adequate parks, recreational areas, utilities, schools, transportation and parking; and</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d_2_e"/><heading><desig>e.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The existence of statewide housing plans.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> With respect to any such HDA mortgage loan, HDA may require the housing sponsor, person or family of low or moderate income, contractors, architects, marketing agents, management agents and other parties related to the housing development or residential housing financed by such HDA mortgage loan to execute such agreements, assurances, guarantees and certifications as HDA shall determine to be necessary including, without limitation, agreements between HDA and such housing sponsor and its partners, principals or stockholders or such person or family of low or moderate income to limitations established by HDA as to rentals and other charges, profits, fees, the use and disposition of the real property constituting the site of or relating to the housing development or residential housing and other property of such housing sponsor, and the use and disposition of franchises of such housing sponsor to the extent more restrictive limitations are not provided by the law under which such housing sponsor is incorporated or organized. HDA shall require the housing sponsor or person or family of low or moderate income receiving such HDA mortgage loan, or the construction contractor, or both, to furnish such assurances of completion of the construction, rehabilitation or improvement as determined by HDA in its rules and regulations or in the HDA resolution authorizing, or commitment for, such mortgage loan.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d_4"/><heading><desig>4.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> As a condition of any such HDA mortgage loan to a housing sponsor, HDA shall have the power to supervise such housing sponsor in accordance with the provisions of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 36-55.34:1"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 36 -55.34:1">§ 36-55.34:1<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#142#        36#     55.34#         1#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> at all times during which such HDA mortgage loan is outstanding and thereafter as necessary to preserve the federal tax exemption of the notes or bonds issued by HDA to finance such HDA mortgage loan.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d_5"/><heading><desig>5.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> With respect to any such HDA mortgage loan, the provisions of subdivisions 2 and 3 of subsection B of this section shall be applicable.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_e"/><heading><desig>E.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Mortgage loans made by HDA pursuant to subdivision 13 of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 36-55.31"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 36 -55.31">§ 36-55.31<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#123#000036#     55.31#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> to finance the construction, rehabilitation, preservation or improvement, or ownership and operation, of economically mixed projects or portions thereof and, if any such project is within a revitalization area designated in or pursuant to <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 36-55.30:2"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 36 -55.30:2">§ 36-55.30:2<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#142#        36#     55.30#         2#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, any nonhousing buildings that are incidental to such project or are determined by such governing body of the city or county to be necessary or appropriate for the revitalization of such area or for the industrial, commercial or other economic development of such area shall be subject to the following terms and conditions in addition to those contained in subsection A of this section:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_e_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The principal amount of such an HDA mortgage loan shall not exceed 95 percent of the total housing development costs, and the amortization period of such an HDA mortgage loan shall be as determined by HDA in its rules and regulations or in the HDA resolution authorizing, or in the commitment for, such mortgage loan; but in no event shall such amortization period exceed 50 years.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_e_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Such an HDA mortgage loan shall be made only if the provisions of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 36-55.30:2"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 36 -55.30:2">§ 36-55.30:2<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#142#        36#     55.30#         2#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> are satisfied.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_e_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The instrument evidencing any such HDA mortgage loan and the mortgage securing any such HDA mortgage loan shall be in such form and contain such terms and conditions as shall be prescribed or approved by HDA. The aforesaid mortgage and instrument evidencing an HDA mortgage loan may contain exculpatory provisions relieving a housing sponsor, if any, or its principal or principals from personal liability if deemed desirable by HDA.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_e_4"/><heading><desig>4.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The nonhousing buildings shall be financed by such an HDA mortgage loan only if the HDA shall receive a certification from the housing sponsor that a mortgage loan for the financing of such nonhousing buildings is not otherwise available from private lenders upon reasonably equivalent terms and conditions.</p></bodyText></level></level><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p>1975, c. 536; 1979, c. 374; 1982, c. 176; 1987, c. 164; 1988, c. 556; <citation normalizedCite="1989 VA CH 161"><content><span normalizedCite="1989 Va. Ch. 161">1989, c. 161<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1989#000161#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1991 VA CH 447"><content><span normalizedCite="1991 Va. Ch. 447">1991, c. 447<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1991#000447#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2004 VA CH 187"><content><span normalizedCite="2004 Va. Ch. 187">2004, c. 187<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2004#000187#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2010 VA CH 794"><content><span normalizedCite="2010 Va. Ch. 794">2010, c. 794<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2010#000794#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PT30-004G-K3VN-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 36.</desig><title>HOUSING</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 1.2.</desig><title>VIRGINIA HOUSING DEVELOPMENT AUTHORITY ACT</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjA4OEVGODBENzY4NDcxM0IyQzA1OTEwQzVDODRBOUE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RkE2ODg4Mjk1MTE2NDgzOTk1NTVERDRBRUJFRUUxMjk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NjMzQjkyNzZDOUQ4NEQ2NEIyOEYxNkJCNzBGNTk1OEY</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Contracts Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QzY0RTZFMzE0RjkwNDdFQUI5M0U5N0ZFMjYyREMyQzU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Exculpatory Clauses</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NjJDRDFCOTMwRjVDNEZBMDk5Q0FGRTdFNTJBNUQwRkU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QUQwMUEyNUE3Nzg0NEJGNTg0MkJBNkRBNDUwNjRGRTI</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NTA0RUYzODAxQjFBNENCQUFDQ0JERDU0RTIxRTkxQTM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QUQwMUEyNUE3Nzg0NEJGNTg0MkJBNkRBNDUwNjRGRTI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Insurance Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDM4MzQ2QUYzMTY0NDQzQTkxRDQwRUUzRUM5RDg0OEM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OURFREJEQzQwMENCNDZGMkE2MzY3NTU5QzBDRTk2QkM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QzE0QTkzRDYwNjNCNDhFMEJDMTExNzcyNzgzMTAyQ0Q</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Real Property Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QUUyRTcxRURBNEY2NEE2MDk3QzBCNzRDOEY0NTZDQzk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Construction Loans</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RDNGMDlENjQ4NUYyNEM0MEIxRTAwMjAyRTdFRUNBRkY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MTY1MzRERDhBMDZCNDFBMDk0QUEwRjcyN0ZFNEY3REM</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QzNGRTg3NUQyRkMyNEZENEE5M0VDQ0RGMEFEQjc4MTQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MTY1MzRERDhBMDZCNDFBMDk0QUEwRjcyN0ZFNEY3REM</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUQ4QUQ1MjRFNkZENDJGNDgxN0JEQzcxNDc1Q0EyMjc7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDhDNTc4RkY3N0RDNDhDRkI1ODk3RjI2RkEyRTMwNEI</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Lien Priorities</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QUZFODEzOURCNDQ5NDMxM0E1NDA3QzZBNTdFM0FGNUQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDQzNzlERkQ2MUVDNDRENzlDQ0Q1Q0MyQzgxOEE3Q0M</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Mortgage Formalities</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MzE5QjU5QTAzQ0VCNEFFREJCOTY2RDEwQzI4OTg2REY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDhDNTc4RkY3N0RDNDhDRkI1ODk3RjI2RkEyRTMwNEI</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Mortgage Insurance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OEQ1MTZBMzJDQURBNDU5Njg3RkIzMkJEOEFEODBFNzY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDhDNTc4RkY3N0RDNDhDRkI1ODk3RjI2RkEyRTMwNEI</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Mortgagee's Interests</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MzQwOUI5Qjk2Qzg5NEJDNUFBODI4M0NFNjE0MzYwNzI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDhDNTc4RkY3N0RDNDhDRkI1ODk3RjI2RkEyRTMwNEI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Torts</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDAwOEM2NTEzQkVDNEI4NzlGMEZERUEyRjQwODM4Njg7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MzhCRTYwQUVCM0I3NEQ3QUJEMTNDODYyRjhGMDZBQUM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QkRBMERFNEJBN0UyNEQ5NUJDNkZBREYzRDREQzVFNTQ</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></metadata></legislativeDoc>