<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#349#000002#     2#         4519#">Va. Code Ann. § 2.2-4519</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_2.2-4519"/><heading><desig>§ 2.2-4519.</desig><title>Investment of funds by the Virginia Housing Development Authority and the Virginia Resources Authority</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a"/><heading><desig>A.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> For purposes of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 36-55.44"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 36 -55.44">§§ 36-55.44<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#123#000036#     55.44#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> and <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 62.1-221"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 62.1-221">62.1-221<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000062#     1#          221#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> only, the following investments shall be considered lawful investments and shall be conclusively presumed to have been prudent:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Obligations of the Commonwealth. Stocks, bonds, notes, and other evidences of indebtedness of the Commonwealth, and those unconditionally guaranteed as to the payment of principal and interest by the Commonwealth.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Obligations of the United States. Stocks, bonds, treasury notes, and other evidences of indebtedness of the United States, including the guaranteed portion of any loan guaranteed by the Small Business Administration, an agency of the United States government, and those unconditionally guaranteed as to the payment of principal and interest by the United States; bonds of the District of Columbia; bonds and notes of the Federal National Mortgage Association and the Federal Home Loan Banks; bonds, debentures, or other similar obligations of federal land banks, federal intermediate credit banks, or banks of cooperatives, issued pursuant to acts of Congress; and obligations issued by the United States Postal Service when the principal and interest thereon is guaranteed by the government of the United States. The evidences of indebtedness enumerated by this subdivision may be held directly, in the form of repurchase agreements collateralized by such debt securities, or in the form of securities of any open-end or closed-end management type investment company or investment trust registered under the federal Investment Company Act of 1940, provided that the portfolio of such investment company or investment trust is limited to such evidences of indebtedness or repurchase agreements collateralized by such debt securities, or securities of other such investment companies or investment trusts whose portfolios are so restricted.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Obligations of other states. Stocks, bonds, notes, and other evidences of indebtedness of any state of the United States upon which there is no default and upon which there has been no default for more than 90 days, provided that within the 20 fiscal years next preceding the making of such investment, such state has not been in default for more than 90 days in the payment of any part of principal or interest of any debt authorized by the legislature of such state to be contracted.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_4"/><heading><desig>4.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Obligations of Virginia counties, cities, or other public bodies. Stocks, bonds, notes, and other evidences of indebtedness of any county, city, town, district, authority, or other public body in the Commonwealth upon which there is no default, provided that if the principal and interest is payable from revenues or tolls and the project has not been completed, or if completed, has not established an operating record of net earnings available for payment of principal and interest equal to estimated requirements for that purpose according to the terms of the issue, the standards of judgment and care required in the Uniform Prudent Investor Act (<citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 64.2-780"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 64.2-780">§ 64.2-780<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000064#     2#          780#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> et seq.), without reference to this section, shall apply.</p><p><pre/>In any case in which an authority, having an established record of net earnings available for payment of principal and interest equal to estimated requirements for that purpose according to the terms of the issue, issues additional evidences of indebtedness for the purposes of acquiring or constructing additional facilities of the same general character that it is then operating, such additional evidences of indebtedness shall be governed fully by the provisions of this section without limitation.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_5"/><heading><desig>5.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Obligations of cities, counties, towns, or districts of other states. Legally authorized stocks, bonds, notes, and other evidences of indebtedness of any city, county, town, or district situated in any one of the states of the United States upon which there is no default and upon which there has been no default for more than 90 days, provided that (i) within the 20 fiscal years next preceding the making of such investment, the city, county, town, or district has not been in default for more than 90 days in the payment of any part of principal or interest of any stock, bond, note, or other evidence of indebtedness issued by it; (ii) the city, county, town, or district shall have been in continuous existence for at least 20 years; (iii) the city, county, town, or district has a population, as shown by the federal census next preceding the making of such investment, of not less than 25,000 inhabitants; (iv) the stocks, bonds, notes, or other evidences of indebtedness in which such investment is made are the direct legal obligations of the city, county, town, or district issuing the same; (v) the city, county, town, or district has power to levy taxes on the taxable real property therein for the payment of such obligations without limitation of rate or amount; and (vi) the net indebtedness of the city, county, town, or district, including the issue in which such investment is made, after deducting the amount of its bonds issued for self-sustaining public utilities, does not exceed 10 percent of the value of the taxable property in the city, county, town, or district, to be ascertained by the valuation of such property therein for the assessment of taxes next preceding the making of such investment.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_6"/><heading><desig>6.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Obligations subject to repurchase. Investments set forth in subdivisions 1 through 5 may also be made subject to the obligation or right of the seller to repurchase these on a specific date.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_7"/><heading><desig>7.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Bonds secured on real estate. Bonds and negotiable notes directly secured by a first lien on improved real estate or farm property in the Commonwealth, or in any state contiguous to the Commonwealth within a 50-mile area from the borders of the Commonwealth, not to exceed 80 percent of the fair market value of such real estate, including any improvements thereon at the time of making such investment, as ascertained by an appraisal thereof made by two reputable persons who are not interested in whether or not such investment is made.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_8"/><heading><desig>8.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Bonds secured on city property in Fifth Federal Reserve District. Bonds and negotiable notes directly secured by a first lien on improved real estate situated in any incorporated city in any of the states of the United States which lie wholly or in part within the Fifth Federal Reserve District of the United States as constituted on June 18, 1928, pursuant to the act of Congress of December 23, 1913, known as the Federal Reserve Act, as amended, not to exceed 60 percent of the fair market value of such real estate, with the improvements thereon, at the time of making such investment, as ascertained by an appraisal thereof made by two reputable persons who are not interested in whether or not such investment is made, provided that such city has a population, as shown by the federal census next preceding the making of such investments, of not less than 5,000 inhabitants.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_9"/><heading><desig>9.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Bonds of Virginia educational institutions. Bonds of any of the educational institutions of the Commonwealth that have been or may be authorized to be issued by the General Assembly.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_10"/><heading><desig>10.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Securities of the Richmond, Fredericksburg and Potomac Railroad Company. Stocks, bonds, and other securities of the Richmond, Fredericksburg and Potomac Railroad Company, including bonds or other securities guaranteed by the Richmond, Fredericksburg and Potomac Railroad Company.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_11"/><heading><desig>11.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Obligations of railroads. Bonds, notes, and other evidences of indebtedness, including equipment trust obligations, which are direct legal obligations of or which have been unconditionally assumed or guaranteed as to the payment of principal and interest by, any railroad corporation operating within the United States that meets the following conditions and requirements:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_11_a"/><heading><desig>a.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The gross operating revenue of such corporation for the fiscal year preceding the making of such investment, or the average of the gross operating revenue for the five fiscal years next preceding the making of such investment, whichever of these two is the larger, shall have not been less than $ 10 million;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_11_b"/><heading><desig>b.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The total fixed charges of such corporation, as reported for the fiscal year next preceding the making of the investment, shall have been earned an average of at least two times annually during the seven fiscal years preceding the making of the investment and at least one and one-half times during the fiscal year immediately preceding the making of the investment. The term "total fixed charges" as used in this subdivision and subdivision c shall be deemed to refer to the term used in the accounting reports of common carriers as prescribed by the regulations of the Interstate Commerce Commission; and</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_11_c"/><heading><desig>c.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The aggregate of the average market prices of the total amounts of each of the individual securities of such corporation junior to its bonded debt and outstanding at the time of the making of such investment shall be equal to at least two-thirds of the total fixed charges for such railroad corporation for the fiscal year next preceding the making of such investment capitalized at an annual interest rate of five percent. Such average market price of any one of such individual securities shall be determined by the average of the highest quotation and the lowest quotation of the individual security for a period immediately preceding the making of such investment, which period shall be the full preceding calendar year plus the then-expired portion of the calendar year in which such investment is made, provided that if more than six months of the calendar year in which such investment is made shall have expired, then such period shall be only the then-expired portion of the calendar year in which such investment is made, and provided further that if such individual security shall not have been outstanding during the full extent of such period, such period shall be deemed to be the length of time such individual security shall have been outstanding.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_12"/><heading><desig>12.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Obligations of leased railroads. Stocks, bonds, notes, other evidences of indebtedness, and any other securities of any railroad corporation operating within the United States, the railroad lines of which have been leased by a railroad corporation, either alone or jointly with other railroad corporations, whose bonds, notes, and other evidences of indebtedness shall, at the time of the making of such investment, qualify as lawful investments for fiduciaries under the terms of subdivision 11, provided that the terms of such lease shall provide for the payment by such lessee railroad corporation individually, irrespective of the liability of other joint lessee railroad corporations, if any, in this respect, of an annual rental of an amount sufficient to defray the total operating expenses and maintenance charges of the lessor railroad corporation plus its total fixed charges, plus, in the event of the purchase of such a stock, a fixed dividend upon any issue of such stock in which such investment is made, and provided that if such investment so purchased shall consist of an obligation of definite maturity, such lease shall be one which shall, according to its terms, provide for the payment of the obligation at maturity or extend for a period of not less than 20 years beyond the maturity of such obligations so purchased, or if such investment so purchased shall be a stock or other form of investment having no definite date of maturity, such lease shall be one which shall, according to its terms, extend for a period of at least 50 years beyond the date of the making of such investment.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_13"/><heading><desig>13.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Equipment trust obligations. Equipment trust obligations issued under the "Philadelphia Plan" in connection with the purchase for use on railroads of new standard gauge rolling stock, provided that the owner, purchaser, or lessee of such equipment, or one or more of such owners, purchasers, or lessees, shall be a railroad corporation whose bonds, notes, and other evidences of indebtedness shall, at the time of the making of such investment, qualify as lawful investments for fiduciaries under the terms of subdivision 11, and provided that all of such owners, purchasers, or lessees shall be both jointly and severally liable under the terms of such contract of purchase or lease, or both, for the fulfillment thereof.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_14"/><heading><desig>14.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Preferred stock of railroads. Any preference stock of any railroad corporation operating within the United States, provided such stock and such railroad corporation meet the following conditions and requirements:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_14_a"/><heading><desig>a.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Such stock shall be preferred as to dividends, such dividends shall be cumulative, and such stock shall be preferred as to assets in the event of liquidation or dissolution;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_14_b"/><heading><desig>b.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The gross operating revenue of such corporation for the fiscal year preceding the making of such investment, or the average of the gross operating revenue for the five fiscal years next preceding the making of such investment, whichever of these two is the larger, shall have been not less than $ 10 million;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_14_c"/><heading><desig>c.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The total fixed charges, as defined in subdivision 11 b, of such corporation, as reported for the fiscal year next preceding the making of such investment, plus the amount, at the time of making such investment, of the annual dividend requirements on such preference stock and any preference stock having the same or senior rank, such fixed charges and dividend requirements being considered the same for every year, shall have been earned an average of at least two and one-half times annually for the seven fiscal years preceding the making of such investment and at least two times for the fiscal year immediately preceding the making of such investment; and</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_14_d"/><heading><desig>d.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The aggregate of the average market prices of the total amount of each of the individual securities of such corporation, junior to such preference stock and outstanding at the time of the making of such investment, shall be at least equal to the par value of the total issue of the preference stock in question plus the total par value of all other issues of its preference stock having either the same rank as, or a senior rank to, the issue of such preference stock plus total fixed charges, as defined in subdivision 11 b, for such railroad corporation for the fiscal year next preceding the making of such investment capitalized at an annual interest rate of five percent. Such average market price of any one of such individual securities shall be determined in the same manner as prescribed in subdivision 11 c.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_15"/><heading><desig>15.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Obligations of public utilities. Bonds, notes, and other evidences of indebtedness of any public utility operating company operating within the United States, provided such company meets the following conditions and requirements:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_15_a"/><heading><desig>a.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The gross operating revenue of such public utility operating company for the fiscal year preceding the making of such investment, or the average of the gross operating revenue for the five fiscal years next preceding the making of such investment, whichever of these two is the larger, shall have been not less than $ 5 million;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_15_b"/><heading><desig>b.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The total fixed charges of such corporation, as reported for the fiscal year next preceding the making of the investment, shall have been earned, after deducting operating expenses, depreciation, and taxes, other than income taxes, an average of at least one and three-quarters times annually during the seven fiscal years preceding the making of the investment and at least one and one-half times during the fiscal year immediately preceding the making of the investment;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_15_c"/><heading><desig>c.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> In the fiscal year next preceding the making of such investment, the ratio of the total par value of the bonded debt of such public utility operating company, including the total bonded indebtedness of all its subsidiary companies, whether assumed by the public utility operating company in question or not, to its gross operating revenue shall not be greater than four to one; and</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_15_d"/><heading><desig>d.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Such public utility operating company shall be subject to permanent regulation by a state commission or other duly authorized and recognized regulatory body.</p><p><pre/>The term "public utility operating company" as used in this subdivision and subdivision 16 means a public utility or public service corporation (i) of whose total income available for fixed charges for the fiscal year next preceding the making of such investment at least 55 percent thereof shall have been derived from direct payments by customers for service rendered them; (ii) of whose total operating revenue for the fiscal year next preceding the making of such investment at least 60 percent thereof shall have been derived from the sale of electric power, gas, water, or telephone service and not more than 10 percent thereof shall have been derived from traction operations; and (iii) whose gas properties are all within the limits of one state, if more than 20 percent of its total operating revenues are derived from gas.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_16"/><heading><desig>16.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Preferred stock of public utilities. Any preference stock of any public utility operating company operating within the United States, provided such stock and such company meet the following conditions and requirements:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_16_a"/><heading><desig>a.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Such stock shall be preferred as to dividends, such dividends shall be cumulative, and such stock shall be preferred as to assets in the event of liquidation or dissolution;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_16_b"/><heading><desig>b.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The gross operating revenue of such public utility operating company for the fiscal year preceding the making of such investment, or the average of the gross operating revenue for the five fiscal years next preceding the making of such investment, whichever of these two is the larger, shall have been not less than $ 5 million;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_16_c"/><heading><desig>c.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The total fixed charges of such public utility operating company, as reported for the fiscal year next preceding the making of such investment, plus the amount, at the time of making such investment, of the annual dividend requirements on such preference stock and any preference stock having the same or senior rank, such fixed charges and dividend requirements being considered the same for every year, shall have been earned, after deducting operating expenses, depreciation, and taxes, including income taxes, an average of at least two times annually for the seven fiscal years preceding the making of such investment and at least two times for the fiscal year immediately preceding the making of such investment;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_16_d"/><heading><desig>d.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> In the fiscal year next preceding the making of such investment, the ratio of the sum of the total par value of the bonded debt of such public utility operating company, the total par value of the issue of such preference stock, and the total par value of all other issues of its preference stock having the same or senior rank to its gross operating revenue shall not be greater than four to one; and</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_16_e"/><heading><desig>e.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Such public utility operating company shall be subject to permanent regulation by a state commission or other duly authorized and recognized regulatory body.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_17"/><heading><desig>17.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Obligations of the following telephone companies. Bonds, notes, and other evidences of indebtedness of American Telephone and Telegraph, Bell Atlantic, Bell South, Southwestern Bell, Pacific Telesis, Nynex, American Information Technologies, or U.S. West, and bonds, notes, and other evidences of indebtedness unconditionally assumed or guaranteed as to the payment of principal and interest by any such company, provided that the total fixed charges, as reported for the fiscal year next preceding the making of the investment, of such company and all of its subsidiary corporations on a consolidated basis shall have been earned, after deducting operating expenses, depreciation, and taxes, other than income taxes, an average of at least one and three-fourths times annually during the seven fiscal years preceding the making of the investment and at least one and one-half times during the fiscal year immediately preceding the making of the investment.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_18"/><heading><desig>18.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Obligations of municipally owned utilities. The stocks, bonds, notes, and other evidences of indebtedness of any electric, gas, or water department of any state, county, city, town, or district whose obligations would qualify as legal for purchase under subdivision 3, 4, or 5, the interest and principal of which are payable solely out of the revenues from the operations of the facility for which the obligations were issued, provided that the department issuing such obligations meets the requirements applying to public utility operating companies as set out in subdivisions 15 a through c.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_19"/><heading><desig>19.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Obligations of industrial corporations. Bonds, notes, and other evidences of indebtedness of any industrial corporation incorporated under the laws of the United States or of any state thereof, provided such corporation meets the following conditions and requirements:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_19_a"/><heading><desig>a.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The gross operating revenue of such corporation for the fiscal year preceding the making of such investment, or the average of the gross operating revenue for the five fiscal years next preceding the making of such investment, whichever of these two is the larger, shall have been not less than $ 10 million;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_19_b"/><heading><desig>b.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The total fixed charges of such corporation, as reported for the fiscal year next preceding the making of the investment, shall have been earned, after deducting operating expenses, depreciation, and taxes, other than income taxes, and depletion in the case of companies commonly considered as depleting their natural resources in the course of business, an average of at least three times annually during the seven fiscal years preceding the making of the investment and at least two and one-half times during the fiscal year immediately preceding the making of the investment;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_19_c"/><heading><desig>c.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The net working capital of such industrial corporation, as shown by its last published fiscal year-end statement prior to the making of such investment, or in the case of a new issue, as shown by the financial statement of such corporation giving effect to the issuance of any new security, shall be at least equal to the total par value of its bonded debt as shown by such statement; and</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_19_d"/><heading><desig>d.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The aggregate of the average market prices of the total amounts of each of the individual securities of such industrial corporation, junior to its bonded debt and outstanding at the time of the making of such investment, shall be at least equal to the total par value of the bonded debt of such industrial corporation at the time of the making of such investment, such average market price of any one of such individual securities being determined in the same manner as prescribed in subdivision 11 c.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_20"/><heading><desig>20.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Preferred stock of industrial corporations. Any preference stock of any industrial corporation incorporated under the laws of the United States or of any state thereof, provided such stock and such industrial corporation meet the following conditions and requirements:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_20_a"/><heading><desig>a.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Such stock shall be preferred as to dividends, such dividends shall be cumulative, and such stock shall be preferred as to assets in the event of liquidation or dissolution;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_20_b"/><heading><desig>b.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The gross operating revenue of such corporation for the fiscal year preceding the making of such investment, or the average of the gross operating revenue for the five fiscal years next preceding the making of such investment, whichever of these two is the larger, shall have been not less than $ 10 million;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_20_c"/><heading><desig>c.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The total fixed charges of such corporation, as reported for the fiscal year next preceding the making of such investment, plus the amount, at the time of making such investment, of the annual dividend requirements on such preference stock and any preference stock having the same or senior rank, such fixed charges and dividend requirements being considered the same for every year, shall have been earned, after deducting operating expenses, depreciation, and taxes, including income taxes, and depletion in the case of companies commonly considered as depleting their natural resources in the course of business, an average of at least four times annually for the seven fiscal years preceding the making of such investment and at least three times for the fiscal year immediately preceding the making of such investment;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_20_d"/><heading><desig>d.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The net working capital of such industrial corporation, as shown by its last published fiscal year-end statement prior to the making of such investment, or, in the case of a new issue, as shown by the financial statement of such corporation giving effect to the issuance of any new security, shall be at least equal to the total par value of its bonded debt plus the total par value of the issue of such preference stock plus the total par value of all other issues of its preference stock having the same or senior rank; and</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_20_e"/><heading><desig>e.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The aggregate of the lowest market prices of the total amounts of each of the individual securities of such industrial corporation junior to such preference stock and outstanding at the time of the making of such investment shall be at least two and one-half times the par value of the total issue of such preference stock plus the total par value of all other issues of its preference stock having the same or senior rank plus the par value of the total bonded debt of such industrial corporation. Such lowest market price of any one of such individual securities shall be determined by the lowest single quotation of the individual security for a period immediately preceding the making of such investment, which period shall be the full preceding calendar year plus the then-expired portion of the calendar year in which such investment is made, and if such individual security shall not have been outstanding during the full extent of such period, such period shall be deemed to be the length of time such individual security shall have been outstanding.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_21"/><heading><desig>21.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Obligations of finance corporations. Bonds, notes, and other evidences of indebtedness of any finance corporation incorporated under the laws of the United States or of any state thereof, provided such corporation meets the following conditions and requirements:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_21_a"/><heading><desig>a.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The gross operating income of such corporation for the fiscal year preceding the making of such investment, or the average of the gross operating income for the five fiscal years next preceding the making of such investment, whichever of these two is the larger, shall have been not less than $ 5 million;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_21_b"/><heading><desig>b.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The total fixed charges of such corporation, as reported for the fiscal year next preceding the making of the investment, shall have been earned, after deducting operating expenses, depreciation, and taxes, other than income taxes, an average of at least two and one-half times annually during the seven fiscal years preceding the making of the investment and at least two times during the fiscal year immediately preceding the making of the investment;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_21_c"/><heading><desig>c.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The aggregate indebtedness of such finance corporation as shown by its last fiscal year-end statement, or, in the case of a new issue, as shown by the financial statement giving effect to the issuance of any new securities, shall be no greater than three times the aggregate net worth, as represented by preferred and common stocks and surplus of such corporation; and</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_21_d"/><heading><desig>d.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The aggregate of the average market prices of the total amounts of each of the individual securities of such finance corporation, junior to its bonded debt and outstanding at the time of the making of such investment, shall be at least equal to one-third of the sum of the par value of the bonded debt plus all other indebtedness of such finance corporation as shown by the last published fiscal year-end statement, such average market price of any one of such individual securities being determined in the same manner as prescribed in subdivision 11 c.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_22"/><heading><desig>22.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Preferred stock of finance corporations. Any preference stock of any finance corporation incorporated under the laws of the United States or of any state thereof, provided such stock and such corporation meet the following conditions and requirements:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_22_a"/><heading><desig>a.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Such stock shall be preferred as to dividends, such dividends shall be cumulative, and such stock shall be preferred as to assets in the event of liquidation or dissolution;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_22_b"/><heading><desig>b.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The gross operating income of such corporation for the fiscal year preceding the making of such investment, or the average of the gross operating income for the five fiscal years next preceding the making of such investment, whichever of these two is the larger, shall have been not less than $ 5 million;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_22_c"/><heading><desig>c.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The total fixed charges of such finance corporation, as reported for the fiscal year next preceding the making of such investment, plus the amount, at the time of making such investment, of the annual dividend requirements on such preference stock and any preference stock having the same or senior rank, such fixed charges and dividend requirements being considered the same for every year, shall have been earned, after deducting operating expenses, depreciation, and taxes, including income taxes, an average of at least three and one-half times annually for the seven fiscal years preceding the making of such investment and at least three times for the fiscal year immediately preceding the making of such investment;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_22_d"/><heading><desig>d.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The aggregate indebtedness and par value of the purchased stock, both the issue in question and any issues equal or senior thereto, of such finance corporation as shown by its last published fiscal year-end statement, or, in the case of a new issue, as shown by the financial statement giving effect to the issuance of any new securities, shall be no greater than three times the aggregate par value of the junior securities and surplus of such corporation; and</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_22_e"/><heading><desig>e.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The aggregate of the lowest market prices of the total amounts of each of the individual securities of such finance corporation junior to such preference stock and outstanding at the time of the making of such investment shall be at least equal to one-third of the sum of the par value of such preference stock plus the total par value of all other issues of preference stock having the same or senior rank plus the par value of the total bonded debt plus all other indebtedness of such finance corporation as shown by the last published fiscal year-end statement, such lowest market price of any one of such individual securities being determined in the same manner as prescribed in subdivision 20 e.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_23"/><heading><desig>23.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Federal housing loans. First mortgage real estate loans insured by the Federal Housing Administrator under Title II of the National Housing Act.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_24"/><heading><desig>24.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Certificates of deposit and savings accounts. Certificates of deposit of, and savings accounts in, any bank, banking institution, or trust company, whose deposits are insured by the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation at the prevailing rate of interest on such certificates or savings accounts; however, no such fiduciary shall invest in such certificates of, or deposits in, any one bank, banking institution, or trust company an amount from any one fund in his or its care which shall be in excess of such amount as shall be fully insured as a deposit in such bank, banking institution, or trust company by the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation. A corporate fiduciary shall not, however, be prohibited by the terms of this subdivision from depositing in its own banking department, in the form of demand deposits, savings accounts, time deposits, or certificates of deposit, funds in any amount awaiting investments or distribution, provided that it shall have complied with the provisions of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 6.2-1005"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 6.2-1005">§§ 6.2-1005<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000006#     2#         1005#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> and <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 6.2-1007"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 6.2-1007">6.2-1007<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000006#     2#         1007#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, with reference to the securing of such deposits.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_25"/><heading><desig>25.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Obligations of International Bank, Asian Development Bank, and African Development Bank. Bonds and other obligations issued, guaranteed, or assumed by the International Bank for Reconstruction and Development, the Asian Development Bank, or the African Development Bank.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_26"/><heading><desig>26.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Deposits in savings institutions. Certificates of deposit of, and savings accounts in, any state or federal savings institution or savings bank lawfully authorized to do business in the Commonwealth whose accounts are insured by the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation or other federal insurance agency; however, no such fiduciary shall invest in such shares of any one such association an amount from any one fund in his or its care which shall be in excess of such amount as shall be fully insured as an account in such association by the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation or other federal insurance agency.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_27"/><heading><desig>27.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Certificates evidencing ownership of undivided interests in pools of mortgages. Certificates evidencing ownership of undivided interests in pools of bonds or negotiable notes directly secured by first lien deeds of trust or mortgages on real property located in the Commonwealth improved by single-family residential housing units or multi-family dwelling units, provided that (i) such certificates are rated AA or better by a nationally recognized independent rating agency; (ii) the loans evidenced by such bonds or negotiable notes do not exceed 80 percent of the fair market value, as determined by an independent appraisal thereof, of the real property and the improvements thereon securing such loans; and (iii) such bonds or negotiable notes are assigned to a corporate trustee for the benefit of the holders of such certificates.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_28"/><heading><desig>28.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Shares in credit unions. Shares and share certificates in any credit union lawfully authorized to do business in the Commonwealth whose accounts are insured by the National Credit Union Share Insurance Fund or the Virginia Credit Union Share Insurance Corporation, provided no such fiduciary shall invest in such shares an amount from any one fund in his or its care which shall be in excess of such amount as shall be fully insured as an account in such credit union by the National Credit Union Share Insurance Fund or the Virginia Credit Union Share Insurance Corporation.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b"/><heading><desig>B.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Whenever under the terms of this section the par value of a preference stock is required to be used in a computation, there shall be used instead of such par value the liquidating value of such preference stock in the case of involuntary liquidation, as prescribed by the terms of its issue, in the event that such liquidating value shall be greater than the par value of such preference stock; or in the event that the preference stock in question has no par value, then such liquidating value shall be used instead; or when such preference stock shall be one of no par value and one for which no such liquidating value shall have been so prescribed, then for the purposes of such computation the preference stock in question shall be deemed to have a value of $ 100 per share.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c"/><heading><desig>C.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> When any security provided for in this section is purchased by a fiduciary and at the time of such purchase the statement for the preceding fiscal year of the corporation issuing the security so being purchased has not been published and is therefore not available, the statement of such corporation for the fiscal year immediately prior to such preceding fiscal year shall be considered the statement for such preceding fiscal year and shall have the same force and effect as the statement for the fiscal year preceding such purchase, provided the date of such purchase is not more than four months after the end of the last fiscal year of the corporation.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d"/><heading><desig>D.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> In testing a new issue of securities under the provisions of this section, it shall be permissible, in determining the number of times that fixed charges or preferred dividend requirements have been earned, to use pro forma fixed charges or dividend requirements, provided the corporation or its corporate predecessor has been in existence for a period of not less than seven years.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_e"/><heading><desig>E.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Investments made under the provisions of this section, if in conformity with the requirements of this section at the time such investments were made, may be retained even though they cease to be eligible for purchase under the provisions of this section, but shall be subject to the provisions of the Uniform Prudent Investor Act (<citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 64.2-780"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 64.2-780">§ 64.2-780<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000064#     2#          780#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> et seq.).</p></bodyText></level><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p><citation normalizedCite="2012 VA CH 614"><content><span normalizedCite="2012 Va. Ch. 614">2012, c. 614<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2012#000614#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PVV0-004G-K559-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 2.2.</desig><title>ADMINISTRATION OF GOVERNMENT</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="subtitle"><heading><desig>SUBTITLE II.</desig><title>ADMINISTRATION OF STATE GOVERNMENT</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="part"><heading><desig>PART B.</desig><title>TRANSACTION OF PUBLIC BUSINESS</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 45.</desig><title>INVESTMENT OF PUBLIC FUNDS ACT</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Banking Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjQyMUFCOUJBNURBNEFDREE3MTNCNDk5QkQ4NUM3RjI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Federal Reserve Act</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6N0E1MTA3QzNGM0IwNEJGQkI5OEY0RjdDQzQ2RDZEQzE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RUMwQTBCNEI1REYxNDExMDgzQzVBNTc4NzgwN0YzQzg</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Real Estate Loans</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjhBQjg5RThFOUI0NDYwRUIwOEYzQzFBNEQ2OUQ3QjE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QUZCMDY0MTYzMTAwNEIzNUIyMEM5QkYwQkM5QjVEMDg</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjA4OEVGODBENzY4NDcxM0IyQzA1OTEwQzVDODRBOUE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Cancellation &amp; Redemption</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NUI1RkE1QTk0MjdGNDU3MDkxRjY1OUZGMUJBNTlBQUM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDlEODVGNzI3M0MyNEEzM0EzMThGNTNDMTQ0NjFBNDU</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Consideration</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NzY5MDFBREJDRTkxNDg4Qjg5RDI5QjM3OTIwRTc0ODk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QUMwNTJCQTlCODkzNEVENDkwNEExOTcwMjBDNTIwNUY</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Contracts Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QzY0RTZFMzE0RjkwNDdFQUI5M0U5N0ZFMjYyREMyQzU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QUNCM0E5RTA5QUFBNDNDNzgxMjQ1RTZFQzYzQkMyMDk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MTg5OTE0NDQzNTJCNERDRkI3NDZEMzdBMjREMERGRDM</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QTdGQUE3QkZDMDlBNDQ1MTkzRjEzMEQ1OEUwNzdDOTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NjZEOEU3MEJBRUQ2NDNFNzhFRjAxRTk1OEU1QjY2QTc</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Joint &amp; Several Instruments</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NjkyQjAwMzA1QjBDNDFBRTkxQjVFRTgyMkNDRkU4OEI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDE0RTBDNTU5RUI0NDM1RTk0NjI0NjAzMjkwQTkyMkQ</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Energy &amp; Utilities Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OUUzODAyRDk1QzVFNEZGMEJDM0RGMDYxOTlEMEEzRDA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NEFGODVDQ0YxOEU1NEU5OThGMDAzNzk5RDlENjc0MTY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RjFGM0IxMEExQzRGNEM3OEI0Mjg2QzVGMDlENDk3QUQ</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RkM1QzU3MDk5NDNFNEM3OUIxMzAwQUIwMjY3OUE5Qjk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RDM5MTFCRDA1Rjg2NEM4QzhDQzhBNkE4MjQzNUQxQzA</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MzdCQkJDOTQxQzQyNEE5REIzRDQxMjFERTkyODlCN0U7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NkYzN0Y3MzM3MTFCNDM2Qzk3QzI5NzNCRTRDM0ZCNkY</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Municipal &amp; State Ownership</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RTIxOTVEQ0RGRjI1NDEzQTk2QTg1QzMwMzJGMEZFNEI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjNBOTc1MjdCNkU5NENCRDg1OTk1QjQyRjNBNDMwOUU</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Raising Capital</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RTY0QTJCQjRERjYxNDU2ODk2QjExQURBMTdCMjI0NTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RjFGM0IxMEExQzRGNEM3OEI0Mjg2QzVGMDlENDk3QUQ</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Governments</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjdEQjE4OUJDMzQxNDNEMEI0RTI1QUFCMzJENjEwRTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Fiduciaries</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RDRDQjYwNDkxREQ4NDE4Nzk4QzY0QTIyMzYzOTM0REQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjdEQjE4OUJDMzQxNDNEMEI0RTI1QUFCMzJENjEwRTA</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Finance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjMzOTBBRTg2MUVDNDdDNUE1M0QxNDk1RERCNjNCN0I7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Njg1MkM3RkYyNzIxNEVFRkJFMTI2NUM4NUU1ODdEM0Q</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Property</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDhDNkM0Q0Y5QTIwNDlCODhEMkJFMUY4QzQxQTA2QkI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MkM1MTYwRDE0NkJBNEVFMEIxQjM3RUE2NDRFQUFEODY</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Real Property Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QUUyRTcxRURBNEY2NEE2MDk3QzBCNzRDOEY0NTZDQzk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Federal National Mortgage Association</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjI2QzQwRTFCRTdCNDI0Njg4QzFERTI3MTY5MjY5NTE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6ODdGMkREOEEwRERENDA4RkJGRDVDMzBCNEVCNzg3QzQ</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6ODBCMkIzQTJENDhFNEIzM0FBMzhGNDE4OTUxMDFFNDE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MEY3MDVBRjkxN0UzNENDRDlGQjg1NjYyQzY0QkI5Mjk</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Property Valuations</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NkI0ODJENjlDNkNCNEE3MkI1RkNCMjVBODkzNUI3MTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QUUyRTcxRURBNEY2NEE2MDk3QzBCNzRDOEY0NTZDQzk</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>State Regulations</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QkFCQ0M4RUMwQTYxNDdEOTg3OThDOEVGMDQxMEU2RDM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Nzg5NTlBMjdCREU3NDE1OTg1QjFCODExQkZENkM1Nzk</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Securities Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RkFFMTQ3ODhCRDYyNDkyN0IwQkEyQzRCRDlFMEM5ODc7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Distributions, Redemptions &amp; Repurchases</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MEUwNDVCQTlEMDQ4NEUzRDg0NDA2RjQzRTg5MDRDMTM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NEZBNjUwRkEwQjJGNDgzQzlEMzMyNEE1RDAyOTY4RkE</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NTBGQTg1QUM3RDIwNDI2NjhCNjFBNjZDNkYwMzE5QkQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NEZBNjUwRkEwQjJGNDgzQzlEMzMyNEE1RDAyOTY4RkE</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Unregistered Company Transactions</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6M0VGM0UyRDEzRTZFNDYwMEE0RDQwNkREOTI2MDkxNDg7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NEZBNjUwRkEwQjJGNDgzQzlEMzMyNEE1RDAyOTY4RkE</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Tax Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OTNEM0E2OEE0RkQyNEY1MDhBQzdGMkQ4ODI4QTJDODE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QkFDMkYzNjc0NDQ4NDVGNkE4OTRBODgzOUM3RDdFREY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RDMzMjY1RUM1NjRGNEUxRUIxMUMyRDk4NjBFQUEyRjk</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RjlFQUVFMDQ0OURFNDYzOUEwRkUxRjM4RkVCMTA4NjU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Q0MyNTYzNDdFMDc4NDJCQUE2QkM0NDkzMEIyOTcwMUU</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Torts</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDAwOEM2NTEzQkVDNEI4NzlGMEZERUEyRjQwODM4Njg7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NkU0OTJFRkU2RTY3NENGMUI1OEZEQUY5MkFFRDE3RTU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDcwN0QzMzM1MDJGNDRFNjhDMjg0MTk0OTkxQzQ5RTg</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification><classificationGroup classificationScheme="indexing-terms"><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem score="90"><className>Governments</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjdEQjE4OUJDMzQxNDNEMEI0RTI1QUFCMzJENjEwRTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></classificationGroup></metadata></legislativeDoc>