<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#349#000015#     2#         6632#">Va. Code Ann. § 15.2-6632</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_15.2-6632"/><heading><desig>§ 15.2-6632.</desig><title>Powers</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><bodyText><p>The Authority is hereby granted all powers necessary or appropriate to carry out the purposes of this act, including the following, to:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Adopt bylaws for the regulation of its affairs and the conduct of its business;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Sue and be sued in its own name;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Have perpetual succession;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_4"/><heading><desig>4.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Adopt a corporate seal and alter the same at its pleasure;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_5"/><heading><desig>5.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Maintain offices at such places as it may designate;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_6"/><heading><desig>6.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Acquire, establish, construct, enlarge, improve, maintain, equip, operate, and regulate public access sites that are owned or managed by the authority within the territorial limits of the participating political subdivisions;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_7"/><heading><desig>7.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Construct, install, maintain, and operate facilities for managing access sites;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_8"/><heading><desig>8.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Determine fees, rates, and charges for the use of its facilities;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_9"/><heading><desig>9.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Apply for and accept gifts, or grants of money or gifts, grants or loans of other property, or other financial assistance from the United States of America and agencies and instrumentalities thereof, the Commonwealth of Virginia, or any other person or entity, for or in aid of the construction, acquisition, ownership, operation, maintenance, or repair of the public access sites or for the payment of principal of any indebtedness of the Authority, interest thereon or other cost incident thereto, and to this end the Authority shall have the power to render such services, comply with such conditions, and execute such agreements, and legal instruments, as may be necessary, convenient, or desirable or imposed as a condition to such financial aid;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_10"/><heading><desig>10.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Appoint, employ, or engage such officers, employees, architects, engineers, attorneys, accountants, financial advisors, investment bankers, and other advisors, consultants, and agents as may be necessary or appropriate, and to fix their duties and compensation;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_11"/><heading><desig>11.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Contract with any participating political subdivision for such subdivision to provide legal services, engineering services, and depository and investment services contemplated by <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 15.2-6638"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 15.2-6638">§ 15.2-6638<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000015#     2#         6638#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> hereof, accounting services, including the annual independent audit required by <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 15.2-6635"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 15.2-6635">§ 15.2-6635<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000015#     2#         6635#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> hereof, procurement of goods and services, and to act as fiscal agent for the Authority;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_12"/><heading><desig>12.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Establish personnel rules;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_13"/><heading><desig>13.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Own, purchase, lease, obtain options upon, acquire by gift, grant, or bequest or otherwise acquire any property, real or personal, or any interest therein, and in connection therewith to assume or take subject to any indebtedness secured by such property;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_14"/><heading><desig>14.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Make, assume, and enter into all contracts, leases, and arrangements necessary or incidental to the exercise of its powers, including contracts for the management or operation of all or any part of its facilities;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_15"/><heading><desig>15.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Borrow money, as hereinafter provided, and to borrow money for the purpose of meeting casual deficits in its revenues;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_16"/><heading><desig>16.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Adopt, amend, and repeal rules and regulations for the use, maintenance, and operation of its facilities and governing the conduct of persons and organizations using its facilities and to enforce such rules and regulations and all other rules, regulations, ordinances, and statutes relating to its facilities, all as hereinafter provided;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_17"/><heading><desig>17.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Purchase and maintain insurance or provide indemnification on behalf of any person who is or was a director, officer, employee or agent of the Authority against any liability asserted against him or incurred by him in any such capacity or arising out of his status as such;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_18"/><heading><desig>18.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Do all things necessary or convenient to the purposes of this act. To that end, the Authority may acquire, own, or convey property; enter into contracts; seek financial assistance and incur debt; and adopt rules and regulations; and</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_19"/><heading><desig>19.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Whenever it shall appear to the Authority, or to a simple majority of participating political subdivisions, that the need for the Authority no longer exists, the Authority, or in the proper case, any such subdivision, may petition the circuit court of a participating political subdivision for the dissolution of the Authority. If the court shall determine that the need for the Authority as set forth in this act no longer exists and that all debts and pecuniary obligations of the Authority have been fully paid or provided for, it may enter an order dissolving the Authority.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><bodyText><p>Upon dissolution, the court shall order any real or tangible personal property contributed to the Authority by a participating political subdivision, together with any improvements thereon, returned to such participating political subdivisions. The remaining assets of the Authority shall be distributed to the participating political subdivisions in proportion to their respective contributions theretofore made to the Authority.</p><p>Each participating political subdivision and all holders of the Authority's bonds shall be made parties to any such proceeding and shall be given notice as provided by law. Any party defendant may reply to such petition at any time within six months after the filing of the petition. From the final judgment of the court, an appeal shall lie to the Supreme Court of Virginia.</p></bodyText></level><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p><citation normalizedCite="2005 VA CH 842"><content><span normalizedCite="2005 Va. Ch. 842">2005, c. 842<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2005#000842#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PVF0-004G-K4D3-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 15.2.</desig><title>COUNTIES, CITIES AND TOWNS</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="subtitle"><heading><desig>SUBTITLE IV.</desig><title>OTHER GOVERNMENTAL ENTITIES</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 66.1.</desig><title>NORTHERN NECK CHESAPEAKE BAY PUBLIC ACCESS AUTHORITY ACT</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Estate, Gift &amp; Trust Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OENGNTY0MEQ2RTU2NDA2NTk4QjcyNzI2NTBERUU3NUI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NTM0MTFFRkQ3M0E2NEQwREFFMzc3QjBDQjhEQjZEOTM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RkJCNEFGNEQyOEM1NEZBQ0ExREJFNUQyMDM5N0U2Rjg</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Governments</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjdEQjE4OUJDMzQxNDNEMEI0RTI1QUFCMzJENjEwRTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Finance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjMzOTBBRTg2MUVDNDdDNUE1M0QxNDk1RERCNjNCN0I7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Njg1MkM3RkYyNzIxNEVFRkJFMTI2NUM4NUU1ODdEM0Q</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Securities Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RkFFMTQ3ODhCRDYyNDkyN0IwQkEyQzRCRDlFMEM5ODc7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Compensation</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6ODlDOEU5OEE1Rjk2NDJCRThCNkREMUFBN0RFOTVENUE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6ODQ2M0Q5NUExRUZENEY2NDkzMzlDMDVFNjFCNTY3MTQ</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Fiduciary Responsibilities</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NkVFRjQxNkFGODkzNEE0NEJDRDEyQ0Q4QkIxRTg2QzM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6ODQ2M0Q5NUExRUZENEY2NDkzMzlDMDVFNjFCNTY3MTQ</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification><classificationGroup classificationScheme="indexing-terms"><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem score="90"><className>Governments</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjdEQjE4OUJDMzQxNDNEMEI0RTI1QUFCMzJENjEwRTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></classificationGroup></metadata></legislativeDoc>