<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#349#000029#     1#          529#">Va. Code Ann. § 29.1-529</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_29.1-529"/><heading><desig>§ 29.1-529.</desig><title>Killing of deer, elk or bear damaging fruit trees, crops, livestock, or personal property; wildlife creating a hazard to aircraft or motor vehicles</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a"/><heading><desig>A.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Whenever deer, elk or bear are damaging fruit trees, crops, livestock or personal property utilized for commercial agricultural production in the Commonwealth, the owner or lessee of the lands on which such damage is done shall immediately report the damage to the Director or his designee for investigation. If after investigation the Director or his designee finds that deer or bear are responsible for the damage, he shall authorize in writing the owner, lessee or any other person designated by the Director or his designee to kill such deer or bear when they are found upon the land upon which the damages occurred. However, the Director or his designee shall have the option of authorizing nonlethal control measures rather than authorizing the killing of elk or bear, provided that such measures occur within a reasonable period of time; and whenever deer cause damage on parcels of land of five acres or less, except when such acreage is used for commercial agricultural production, the Director or his designee shall have discretion as to whether to issue a written authorization to kill the deer. The Director or his designee may limit such authorization by specifying in writing the number of animals to be killed and duration for which the authorization is effective and may in proximity to residential areas and under other appropriate circumstances limit or prohibit the authorization between 11:00 p.m. and one-half hour before sunrise of the following day. The Director or his designees issuing these authorizations shall specify in writing that only antlerless deer shall be killed, unless the Director or his designee determines that there is clear and convincing evidence that the damage was done by deer with antlers. Any owner or lessee of land who has been issued a written authorization shall not be issued an authorization in subsequent years unless he can demonstrate to the satisfaction of the Director or his designee that during the period following the prior authorization, the owner or his designee has hunted bear or deer on the land for which he received a previous authorization.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b"/><heading><desig>B.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Subject to the provisions of subsection A, the Director or his designee may issue a written authorization to kill deer causing damage to residential plants, whether ornamental, noncommercial agricultural, or other types of residential plants. The Director may charge a fee not to exceed actual costs. The holder of this written authorization shall be subject to local ordinances, including those regulating the discharge of firearms.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c"/><heading><desig>C.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Whenever wildlife is creating a hazard to the operation of any aircraft or to the facilities connected with the operation of aircraft, the person or persons responsible for the safe operation of the aircraft or facilities shall report such fact to the Director or his designee for investigation. If after investigation the Director or his designee finds that wildlife is creating a hazard, he shall authorize such person or persons or their representatives to kill wildlife when the wildlife is found to be creating such a hazard. As used in this subsection, the term "wildlife" shall not include any federally protected species.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d"/><heading><desig>D.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Whenever deer are creating a hazard to the operation of motor vehicle traffic within the corporate limits of any city or town, the operator of a motor vehicle or chief law-enforcement officer of the city or town may report such fact to the Director or his designee for investigation. If after investigation the Director or his designee finds that deer are creating a hazard within such city or town, he may authorize responsible persons, or their representatives, to kill the deer when they are found to be creating such a hazard.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_e"/><heading><desig>E.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Whenever deer are damaging property in a locality in which deer herd population reduction has been recommended in the current Deer Management Plan adopted by the Board, the owner or lessee of the lands on which such damage is being done may report such damage to the Director or his designee for investigation. If after investigation the Director or his designee finds that deer are responsible for the damage, he may authorize in writing the owner, lessee or any other person designated by the Director or his designee to kill such deer when they are found upon the land upon which the damages occurred. The Director or his designee also may limit such authorization by specifying in writing the number of animals to be killed and the period of time for which the authorization is effective. The requirement in subsection A of this section, that an owner or lessee of land demonstrate that during the period following the prior authorization deer or bear have been hunted on his land, shall not apply to any locality that conducts a deer population control program authorized by the Department.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_f"/><heading><desig>F.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The Director or his designee may revoke or refuse to reissue any authorization granted under this section when it has been shown by a preponderance of the evidence that an abuse of the authorization has occurred. Such evidence may include a complaint filed by any person with the Department alleging that an abuse of the written authorization has occurred. Any person aggrieved by the issuance, denial or revocation of a written authorization can appeal the decision to the Department of Game and Inland Fisheries. Any person convicted of violating any provision of the hunting and trapping laws and regulations shall be entitled to receive written authorization to kill deer or bear. However, such person shall not (i) be designated as a shooter nor (ii) carry out the authorized activity for a person who has received such written authorization for a period of at least two years and up to five years following his most recent conviction for violating any provision of the hunting and trapping laws and regulations. In determining the appropriate length of this restriction, the Director shall take into account the nature and severity of the most recent violation and of any past violations of the hunting and trapping laws and regulations by the applicant. No person shall be designated as a shooter under this section during a period when such person's hunting license or privileges to hunt have been suspended or revoked.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_g"/><heading><desig>G.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The Director or his designee may authorize, subject to the provisions of this section, the killing of deer over bait within the political boundaries of any city or town, or any county with a special late antlerless season, in the Commonwealth when requested by a certified letter from the governing body of such locality.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_h"/><heading><desig>H.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The parts of any deer or bear killed pursuant to this section or wildlife killed pursuant to subsection C shall not be used for the purposes of taxidermy, mounts, or any public display unless authorized by the Director or his designee. However, the meat of any such animal may be used for human consumption. The carcass and any unused meat of any such animal shall be disposed of within 24 hours of being killed. Any person who violates any provision of this subsection is guilty of a Class 3 misdemeanor.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_i"/><heading><desig>I.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> It is unlawful to willfully and intentionally impede any person who is engaged in the lawful killing of a bear or deer pursuant to written authorization issued under this section. Any person convicted of a violation of this subsection is guilty of a Class 3 misdemeanor.</p></bodyText></level><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p>Code 1950, § 29-145.1; 1954, c. 686; 1956, c. 684; 1958, cc. 315, 609; 1960, c. 129; 1962, c. 229; 1970, c. 79; 1980, c. 271; 1987, cc. 48, 488; <citation normalizedCite="1991 VA CH 99"><content><span normalizedCite="1991 Va. Ch. 99">1991, c. 99<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1991#000099#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1993 VA CH 204"><content><span normalizedCite="1993 Va. Ch. 204">1993, cc. 204<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1993#000204#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1993 VA CH 273"><content><span normalizedCite="1993 Va. Ch. 273">273<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1993#000273#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1994 VA CH 571"><content><span normalizedCite="1994 Va. Ch. 571">1994, c. 571<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1994#000571#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1996 VA CH 314"><content><span normalizedCite="1996 Va. Ch. 314">1996, c. 314<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1996#000314#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1998 VA CH 179"><content><span normalizedCite="1998 Va. Ch. 179">1998, c. 179<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1998#000179#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1999 VA CH 563"><content><span normalizedCite="1999 Va. Ch. 563">1999, c. 563<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1999#000563#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2000 VA CH 6"><content><span normalizedCite="2000 Va. Ch. 6">2000, c. 6<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2000#000006#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2002 VA CH 174"><content><span normalizedCite="2002 Va. Ch. 174">2002, c. 174<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2002#000174#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2003 VA CH 123"><content><span normalizedCite="2003 Va. Ch. 123">2003, cc. 123<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2003#000123#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2003 VA CH 135"><content><span normalizedCite="2003 Va. Ch. 135">135<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2003#000135#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2004 VA CH 447"><content><span normalizedCite="2004 Va. Ch. 447">2004, c. 447<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2004#000447#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2008 VA CH 17"><content><span normalizedCite="2008 Va. Ch. 17">2008, cc. 17<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2008#000017#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2008 VA CH 260"><content><span normalizedCite="2008 Va. Ch. 260">260<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2008#000260#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2009 VA CH 8"><content><span normalizedCite="2009 Va. Ch. 8">2009, cc. 8<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2009#000008#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2009 VA CH 305"><content><span normalizedCite="2009 Va. Ch. 305">305<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2009#000305#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2010 VA CH 5"><content><span normalizedCite="2010 Va. Ch. 5">2010, c. 5<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2010#000005#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2012 VA CH 247"><content><span normalizedCite="2012 Va. Ch. 247">2012, c. 247<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2012#000247#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2013 VA CH 346"><content><span normalizedCite="2013 Va. Ch. 346">2013, c. 346<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2013#000346#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PT20-004G-K309-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 29.1.</desig><title>GAME, INLAND FISHERIES AND BOATING</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 5.</desig><title>WILDLIFE AND FISH LAWS</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="article"><heading><desig>ARTICLE 2.</desig><title>HUNTING AND TRAPPING</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Food Product Quality</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NTY2RjcwMUNENUZDNEYxRDg0NDg1QTI5NzAyMEUwRkE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NkVDMzM4QkJENTg3NDQ0RDg3NTA5OEM3RkMyQTlENDI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Governments</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjdEQjE4OUJDMzQxNDNEMEI0RTI1QUFCMzJENjEwRTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Animal Protection</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6N0EyNzFDRkFDRjdCNDdDM0I0QjBFNjZDMENCNDJDRDQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NkVDMzM4QkJENTg3NDQ0RDg3NTA5OEM3RkMyQTlENDI</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Licenses</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QUQzRDFDRDE0OTA0NDU2OEIwMUZCNDZEQTBBODdCODA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Njg1MkM3RkYyNzIxNEVFRkJFMTI2NUM4NUU1ODdEM0Q</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Product Quality</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NTY2RjcwMUNENUZDNEYxRDg0NDg1QTI5NzAyMEUwRkE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NkVDMzM4QkJENTg3NDQ0RDg3NTA5OEM3RkMyQTlENDI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Torts</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDAwOEM2NTEzQkVDNEI4NzlGMEZERUEyRjQwODM4Njg7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MkQwMTc0MUU5MzkxNEMwQzhEQkU0QjA2REQzQzNGMTc7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RjMzQjNFQ0U1MDdFNEQzMjg0MTA0MTY4MUZCQTZBM0U</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Transportation Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RTYzRTk5RDVBQkQ2NDcwQzk2NTU3ODQ5OEE3NDlBNzk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Traffic Regulation</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QTFBOTRGRDZDRTJENEYyOTg0MUI3NzlFODQ4RTY3Mzc7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OTU3NDRDNEM2QUYyNDdGQUE1NEU4NjRGMDRCMUEyNUU</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></metadata></legislativeDoc>