<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#349#000006#     2#         1199#">Va. Code Ann. § 6.2-1199</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_6.2-1199"/><heading><desig>§ 6.2-1199.</desig><title>Powers of Commission in case of nonobservance of law, noncompliance with orders, insufficient reserves or insolvency; appointment of Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation as receiver</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a"/><heading><desig>A.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> If the Commission finds that: (i) the laws of the Commonwealth are not being fully observed by a savings institution doing business in the Commonwealth; (ii) a savings institution is being operated in an unsafe or unsound manner; (iii) the institution has failed to comply with the lawful orders of the Commission; (iv) the reserve of the institution is insufficient for the protection of account holders; or (v) a savings institution is, or is about to become, insolvent, it shall give immediate notice thereof to the officers and directors of the institution. If necessary to conserve the assets of the institution or to protect the interests of its account holders or the public interest, the Commission may, after reasonable notice to the institution and opportunity for it to be heard:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Close the institution for a period not exceeding 60 days, which period may be further extended for a like period or periods as the Commission deems necessary;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Require the officers and directors of the institution to liquidate, insofar as is required, its outstanding loans;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Require that all lawful orders of the Commission be complied with;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_4"/><heading><desig>4.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Require the institution to make reports daily or at such other times as it may require as to the results achieved in carrying out its orders;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_5"/><heading><desig>5.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Temporarily suspend the right of such institution to receive any further deposits;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_6"/><heading><desig>6.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Without examination, close, for such period or periods as the Commission may deem necessary, any savings institution facing an emergency due to withdrawal of deposits or otherwise, or, without closing such savings institution, grant to it the right to suspend or limit the withdrawal of deposits, for such period as the Commission may determine; or</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_7"/><heading><desig>7.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Require that the savings institution desist from those activities that have resulted in the unsafe or unsound operation of the institution.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b"/><heading><desig>B.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> If the Commission determines that a receiver should be appointed for a savings institution, the Commission may close the doors of the institution, take charge of the books, assets and affairs of the institution, and apply to any court in the Commonwealth having jurisdiction to appoint receivers for the appointment of a receiver to take charge of the institution's business and assets. Proceedings for the appointment of a receiver of a savings institution shall not be entertained by any court except on the application of the Commission.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c"/><heading><desig>C.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> In any case where the Commission finds that an insured savings institution is insolvent or about to become insolvent, the Commission may seek the appointment of the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation as receiver for the savings institution. The court may appoint the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation as receiver for the savings institution if it finds that to do so would be in the public interest. Upon its being appointed, the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation shall not be required to post bond, and it shall have as receiver all those powers afforded under federal law.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d"/><heading><desig>D.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The Commissioner may issue and serve upon an association an order to cease and desist from an unsafe or unsound practice or a violation if, in the opinion of the Commissioner, an association (i) is engaging or has engaged, or there is reasonable cause to believe is about to engage, in an unsafe or unsound practice in conducting the business of the association; or (ii) is violating or has violated, or there is reasonable cause to believe is about to violate, this chapter or any other applicable law, regulation, or order. An order to cease and desist shall contain a statement of the facts constituting the alleged violation or unsafe or unsound practice, and it may require, in terms that may be mandatory or otherwise, an association, its directors, officers, employees, or agents to cease and desist from such violation or practice. The order shall specify the effective date thereof and shall contain a notice to the association of its right to request a hearing on the order in accordance with the Commission's Rules.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_e"/><heading><desig>E.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> When the unsafe or unsound practice or the violation specified in an order to cease and desist, or any continuation thereof, is likely to prejudice the interests of the account holders or the stockholders of an association, the Commissioner may issue his order effective immediately. An order to cease and desist shall remain in effect until it is withdrawn by the Commissioner or is terminated by the Commission after a hearing on the matter. A request for hearing under this section shall be given expeditious treatment on the docket of the Commission, and the Commission need not allow for 10 days' notice to the parties.</p></bodyText></level><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p>Code 1950, § 6-201.60; 1960, c. 402; 1966, c. 584, § 6.1-190; 1972, c. 796, § 6.1-195.70; 1983, c. 506; 1985, c. 425, § 6.1-194.83; <citation normalizedCite="1990 VA CH 3"><content><span normalizedCite="1990 Va. Ch. 3">1990, c. 3<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1990#000003#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2010 VA CH 794"><content><span normalizedCite="2010 Va. Ch. 794">2010, c. 794<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2010#000794#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PVS0-004G-K3WV-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 6.2.</desig><title>FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS AND SERVICES</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="subtitle"><heading><desig>SUBTITLE II.</desig><title>DEPOSITORY INSTITUTIONS AND TRUST ORGANIZATIONS</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 11.</desig><title>SAVINGS INSTITUTIONS</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="article"><heading><desig>ARTICLE 9.</desig><title>SUPERVISION.</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Banking Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjQyMUFCOUJBNURBNEFDREE3MTNCNDk5QkQ4NUM3RjI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Supervisory Powers</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RjNFOEVBOTgzOUY2NDYxOTkzODc2REY4NTcxOUQ0NDE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NTlEOTlBRENDOEEzNDYxMEI5NUUwOTFERDE3QjhGRDY</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Civil Procedure</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MzUxNjJDMEQ5N0YwNDMzM0JDMjEzM0UzOTYzMzI3OTU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Appointment of Receivers</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RTBFM0VDMEU5RjRBNDRCM0I1OTEyNUE1RDZCRTU1RTk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NjhGMDdBOTgwNEU1NEU4Mzk0NTRGRkZEMUI5OTI1OEE</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Appointments</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NEI4N0I5M0M5RTg3NDAwRTk5QUE2QkNGRjlENzkyMUI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6ODE4OUM5ODZGMzVBNDZCMDkzNDQ5RkQ1MEMyNEZCOEQ</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Deposits in Court</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RkM4Njg2MDM3RkZFNEY2NUFGNDRFM0ZCRTFBQTVFQTQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OUE4ODNBQkNCRDczNEQ1QzhCOEU1REIxNjhEN0Q0Qjk</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OEUzMEY1NDc0QUFBNDdFRkE3NjQ3MkRENTg4Nzg2OTE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NjhGMDdBOTgwNEU1NEU4Mzk0NTRGRkZEMUI5OTI1OEE</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification><classificationGroup classificationScheme="indexing-terms"><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem score="90"><className>Banking &amp; Finance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjQyMUFCOUJBNURBNEFDREE3MTNCNDk5QkQ4NUM3RjI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></classificationGroup></metadata></legislativeDoc>