<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#349#000019#     2#        169.6#">Va. Code Ann. § 19.2-169.6</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_19.2-169.6"/><heading><desig>§ 19.2-169.6.</desig><title>Inpatient psychiatric hospital admission from local correctional facility</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a"/><heading><desig>A.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Any inmate of a local correctional facility who is not subject to the provisions of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 19.2-169.2"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 19.2-169.2">§ 19.2-169.2<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000019#     2#        169.2#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> may be hospitalized for psychiatric treatment at a hospital designated by the Commissioner of Behavioral Health and Developmental Services as appropriate for treatment of persons under criminal charge if:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The court with jurisdiction over the inmate's case, if it is still pending, on the petition of the person having custody over an inmate or on its own motion, holds a hearing at which the inmate is represented by counsel and finds by clear and convincing evidence that (i) the inmate has a mental illness; (ii) there exists a substantial likelihood that, as a result of a mental illness, the inmate will, in the near future, (a) cause serious physical harm to himself or others as evidenced by recent behavior causing, attempting, or threatening harm and any other relevant information or (b) suffer serious harm due to his lack of capacity to protect himself from harm as evidenced by recent behavior and any other relevant information; and (iii) the inmate requires treatment in a hospital rather than the local correctional facility. Prior to making this determination, the court shall consider the examination conducted in accordance with <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 37.2-815"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 37.2-815">§ 37.2-815<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000037#     2#          815#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> and the preadmission screening report prepared in accordance with <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 37.2-816"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 37.2-816">§ 37.2-816<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000037#     2#          816#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> and conducted in-person or by means of a two-way electronic video and audio communication system as authorized in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 37.2-804.1"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 37.2-804.1">§ 37.2-804.1<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000037#     2#        804.1#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> by an employee or designee of the local community services board or behavioral health authority who is skilled in the assessment and treatment of mental illness, who is not providing treatment to the inmate, and who has completed a certification program approved by the Department of Behavioral Health and Developmental Services as provided in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 37.2-809"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 37.2-809">§ 37.2-809<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000037#     2#          809#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>. The examiner appointed pursuant to <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 37.2-815"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 37.2-815">§ 37.2-815<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000037#     2#          815#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, if not physically present at the hearing, shall be available whenever possible for questioning during the hearing through a two-way electronic video and audio or telephonic communication system as authorized in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 37.2-804.1"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 37.2-804.1">§ 37.2-804.1.<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000037#     2#        804.1#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> Any employee or designee of the local community services board or behavioral health authority, as defined in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 37.2-809"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 37.2-809">§ 37.2-809<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000037#     2#          809#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, representing the board or authority that prepared the preadmission screening report shall attend the hearing in person or, if physical attendance is not practicable, shall participate in the hearing through a two-way electronic video and audio communication system as authorized in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 37.2-804.1"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 37.2-804.1">§ 37.2-804.1.<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000037#     2#        804.1#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> When the hearing is held outside the service area of the community services board or behavioral health authority that prepared the preadmission screening report, and it is not practicable for a representative of the board or authority to attend or participate in the hearing, arrangements shall be made by the board or authority for an employee or designee of the board or authority serving the area in which the hearing is held to attend or participate on behalf of the board or authority that prepared the preadmission screening report; or</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Upon petition by the person having custody over an inmate, a magistrate finds probable cause to believe that (i) the inmate has a mental illness; (ii) there exists a substantial likelihood that, as a result of a mental illness, the inmate will, in the near future, (a) cause serious physical harm to himself or others as evidenced by recent behavior causing, attempting, or threatening harm and any other relevant information or (b) suffer serious harm due to his lack of capacity to protect himself from harm as evidenced by recent behavior and any other relevant information; and (iii) the inmate requires treatment in a hospital rather than a local correctional facility, and the magistrate issues a temporary detention order for the inmate. Prior to the filing of the petition, the person having custody shall arrange for an evaluation of the inmate conducted in-person or by means of a two-way electronic video and audio communication system as authorized in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 37.2-804.1"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 37.2-804.1">§ 37.2-804.1<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000037#     2#        804.1#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> by an employee or designee of the local community services board or behavioral health authority who is skilled in the assessment and treatment of mental illness and who has completed a certification program approved by the Department as provided in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 37.2-809"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 37.2-809">§ 37.2-809<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000037#     2#          809#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>. After considering the evaluation of the employee or designee of the local community services board or behavioral health authority, and any other information presented, and finding that probable cause exists to meet the criteria, the magistrate may issue a temporary detention order in accordance with the applicable procedures specified in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 37.2-809"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 37.2-809">§§ 37.2-809<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000037#     2#          809#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> through <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 37.2-813"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 37.2-813">37.2-813<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000037#     2#          813#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>. The person having custody over the inmate shall notify the court having jurisdiction over the inmate's case, if it is still pending, and the inmate's attorney prior to the detention pursuant to a temporary detention order or as soon thereafter as is reasonable.</p><p><pre/>Upon detention pursuant to this subdivision, a hearing shall be held either before the court having jurisdiction over the inmate's case or before a district court judge or a special justice, as defined in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 37.2-100"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 37.2-100">§ 37.2-100<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000037#     2#          100#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, in accordance with the provisions of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 37.2-815"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 37.2-815">§§ 37.2-815<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000037#     2#          815#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> through <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 37.2-821"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 37.2-821">37.2-821<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000037#     2#          821#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, in which case the inmate shall be represented by counsel as specified in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 37.2-814"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 37.2-814">§ 37.2-814<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000037#     2#          814#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>. The hearing shall be held within 72 hours of execution of the temporary detention order issued pursuant to this subdivision. If the 72-hour period terminates on a Saturday, Sunday, legal holiday, or day on which the court is lawfully closed, the inmate may be detained until the close of business on the next day that is not a Saturday, Sunday, legal holiday, or day on which the court is lawfully closed. Any employee or designee of the local community services board or behavioral health authority, as defined in § 37.2-809, representing the board or authority that prepared the preadmission screening report shall attend the hearing in person or, if physical attendance is not practicable, shall participate in the hearing through a two-way electronic video and audio communication system as authorized in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 37.2-804.1"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 37.2-804.1">§ 37.2-804.1.<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000037#     2#        804.1#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> When the hearing is held outside the service area of the community services board or behavioral health authority that prepared the preadmission screening report, and it is not practicable for a representative of the board or authority to attend or participate in the hearing, arrangements shall be made by the board or authority for an employee or designee of the board or authority serving the area in which the hearing is held to attend or participate on behalf of the board or authority that prepared the preadmission screening report. The judge or special justice conducting the hearing may order the inmate hospitalized if, after considering the examination conducted in accordance with <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 37.2-815"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 37.2-815">§ 37.2-815<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000037#     2#          815#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, the preadmission screening report prepared in accordance with <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 37.2-816"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 37.2-816">§ 37.2-816<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000037#     2#          816#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, and any other available information as specified in subsection C of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 37.2-817"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 37.2-817">§ 37.2-817<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000037#     2#          817#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, he finds by clear and convincing evidence that (1) the inmate has a mental illness; (2) there exists a substantial likelihood that, as a result of a mental illness, the inmate will, in the near future, (a) cause serious physical harm to himself or others as evidenced by recent behavior causing, attempting, or threatening harm and any other relevant information or (b) suffer serious harm due to his lack of capacity to protect himself from harm as evidenced by recent behavior and any other relevant information; and (3) the inmate requires treatment in a hospital rather than a local correctional facility. The examiner appointed pursuant to <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 37.2-815"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 37.2-815">§ 37.2-815<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000037#     2#          815#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, if not physically present at the hearing, shall be available whenever possible for questioning during the hearing through a two-way electronic video and audio or telephonic communication system as authorized in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 37.2-804.1"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 37.2-804.1">§ 37.2-804.1.<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000037#     2#        804.1#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> The examination and the preadmission screening report shall be admitted into evidence at the hearing.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b"/><heading><desig>B.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> In no event shall an inmate have the right to make application for voluntary admission as may be otherwise provided in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 37.2-805"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 37.2-805">§ 37.2-805<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000037#     2#          805#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> or <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 37.2-814"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 37.2-814">37.2-814<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000037#     2#          814#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> or be subject to an order for mandatory outpatient treatment as provided in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 37.2-817"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 37.2-817">§ 37.2-817<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000037#     2#          817#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c"/><heading><desig>C.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> If an inmate is hospitalized pursuant to this section and his criminal case is still pending, the court having jurisdiction over the inmate's case may order that the admitting hospital evaluate the inmate's competency to stand trial and his mental state at the time of the offense pursuant to <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 19.2-169.1"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 19.2-169.1">§§ 19.2-169.1<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000019#     2#        169.1#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> and <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 19.2-169.5"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 19.2-169.5">19.2-169.5.<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000019#     2#        169.5#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation></p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d"/><heading><desig>D.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> An inmate may not be hospitalized longer than 30 days under subsection A unless the court which has criminal jurisdiction over him or a district court judge or a special justice, as defined in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 37.2-100"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 37.2-100">§ 37.2-100<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000037#     2#          100#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, holds a hearing and orders the inmate's continued hospitalization in accordance with the provisions of subdivision A 2. If the inmate's hospitalization is continued under this subsection by a court other than the court which has jurisdiction over his criminal case, the facility at which the inmate is hospitalized shall notify the court with jurisdiction over his criminal case and the inmate's attorney in the criminal case, if the case is still pending.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_e"/><heading><desig>E.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Hospitalization may be extended in accordance with subsection D for periods of 60 days for inmates awaiting trial, but in no event may such hospitalization be continued beyond trial, nor shall such hospitalization act to delay trial, as long as the inmate remains competent to stand trial. Hospitalization may be extended in accordance with subsection D for periods of 180 days for an inmate who has been convicted and not yet sentenced, or for an inmate who has been convicted of a crime and is in the custody of a local correctional facility after sentencing, but in no event may such hospitalization be continued beyond the date upon which his sentence would have expired had he received the maximum sentence for the crime charged. Any inmate who has not completed service of his sentence upon discharge from the hospital shall serve the remainder of his sentence.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_f"/><heading><desig>F.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> For any inmate who has been convicted and not yet sentenced, or who has been convicted of a crime and is in the custody of a local correctional facility after sentencing, the time the inmate is confined in a hospital for psychiatric treatment shall be deducted from any term for which he may be sentenced to any penal institution, reformatory or elsewhere.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_g"/><heading><desig>G.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Any health care provider, as defined in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 32.1-127.1:03"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 32.1-127.1:03">§ 32.1-127.1:03<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#958#0000000032#0000000001#     127.1#0000000003#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, or other provider rendering services to an inmate who is the subject of a proceeding under this section, upon request, shall disclose to a magistrate, the court, the inmate's attorney, the inmate's guardian ad litem, the examiner appointed pursuant to <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 37.2-815"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 37.2-815">§ 37.2-815<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000037#     2#          815#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, the community service board or behavioral health authority preparing the preadmission screening pursuant to <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 37.2-816"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 37.2-816">§ 37.2-816<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000037#     2#          816#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, or the sheriff or administrator of the local correctional facility any and all information that is necessary and appropriate to enable each of them to perform his duties under this section. These health care providers and other service providers shall disclose to one another health records and information where necessary to provide care and treatment to the inmate and to monitor that care and treatment. Health records disclosed to a sheriff or administrator of the local correctional facility shall be limited to information necessary to protect the sheriff or administrator of the local correctional facility and his employees, the inmate, or the public from physical injury or to address the health care needs of the inmate. Information disclosed to a law-enforcement officer shall not be used for any other purpose, disclosed to others, or retained.</p><p>Any health care provider disclosing records pursuant to this section shall be immune from civil liability for any harm resulting from the disclosure, including any liability under the federal Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="42 USC 1320D"><content><span normalizedCite="42 U.S.C. 1320D">(42 U.S.C. § 1320d<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1828#123#000042#      1320d#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> et seq.), as amended, unless the person or provider disclosing such records intended the harm or acted in bad faith.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_h"/><heading><desig>H.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Any order entered where an inmate is the subject of proceedings under this section shall provide for the disclosure of medical records pursuant to subsection G. This subsection shall not preclude any other disclosures as required or permitted by law.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_i"/><heading><desig>I.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> As used in this section, "person having custody over an inmate" means the sheriff or other person in charge of the local correctional facility where the inmate is incarcerated at the time of the filing of a petition for the psychiatric treatment of the inmate.</p></bodyText></level><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p>1982, c. 653; 1986, c. 629; 1987, c. 96; <citation normalizedCite="1990 VA CH 76"><content><span normalizedCite="1990 Va. Ch. 76">1990, c. 76<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1990#000076#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1995 VA CH 844"><content><span normalizedCite="1995 Va. Ch. 844">1995, c. 844<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1995#000844#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2005 VA CH 716"><content><span normalizedCite="2005 Va. Ch. 716">2005, c. 716<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2005#000716#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2008 VA CH 779"><content><span normalizedCite="2008 Va. Ch. 779">2008, cc. 779<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2008#000779#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2008 VA CH 782"><content><span normalizedCite="2008 Va. Ch. 782">782<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2008#000782#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2008 VA CH 850"><content><span normalizedCite="2008 Va. Ch. 850">850<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2008#000850#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2008 VA CH 870"><content><span normalizedCite="2008 Va. Ch. 870">870<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2008#000870#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2010 VA CH 340"><content><span normalizedCite="2010 Va. Ch. 340">2010, cc. 340<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2010#000340#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2010 VA CH 406"><content><span normalizedCite="2010 Va. Ch. 406">406<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2010#000406#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2012 VA CH 801"><content><span normalizedCite="2012 Va. Ch. 801">2012, c. 801<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2012#000801#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2014 VA CH 499"><content><span normalizedCite="2014 Va. Ch. 499">2014, cc. 499<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2014#000499#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2014 VA CH 538"><content><span normalizedCite="2014 Va. Ch. 538">538<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2014#000538#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2014 VA CH 691"><content><span normalizedCite="2014 Va. Ch. 691">691<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2014#000691#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2016 VA CH 357"><content><span normalizedCite="2016 Va. Ch. 357">2016, cc. 357<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2016#000357#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2016 VA CH 599"><content><span normalizedCite="2016 Va. Ch. 599">599<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2016#000599#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PVF0-004G-K4BW-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 19.2.</desig><title>CRIMINAL PROCEDURE</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 11.</desig><title>PROCEEDINGS ON QUESTION OF INSANITY</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Health Insurance Portability &amp; Accountability Act</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NjVFNjYwOEVBNEUyNEMwQjk3NzlCRjI5NzBDNDlBOTM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QzNEOEE3NjhDNTJBNDhCOTgxRkQzNzc1Q0JCMkU4Q0I</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Civil Rights Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NURDOUM5MEJFQUZGNEFBMDgzMkM0RTgwODdDNTMxREM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Medical Treatment</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NERCMDdCODIyRUI1NDQyQUFFQjNEMEIzMDQxRTlEQzY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OTM3NjVDMkYzMzkwNDJFNDg3M0EyRTZERDBDRkFCNDY</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Criminal Law &amp; Procedure</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NEU0RkE1OUQwNUQwNDgxODhEODZCMjkzOTg3NThBNzk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Imprisonment</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NURCMTExOEEzNDJBNDk4RjhFQTQ0NzEwMzc0OTg3RTE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QTFGRjg4NjA3RTg1NDA2RkIzMDk4QzdGREIyQzVGMDk</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Mental Incapacity</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MTM2NTM1NjkwMkFCNDYxNkI0NUMwNkIwNjkwMzRGNTQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUIzQ0NGRDZERUU3NERCODg2MEZFMDI2RTI0RTA3RTc</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Governments</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjdEQjE4OUJDMzQxNDNEMEI0RTI1QUFCMzJENjEwRTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Administrative Boards</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QTYwRUFCMDc5MzQ5NDEyREFEQkU2NkE2MjRGQTlCNzY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Njg1MkM3RkYyNzIxNEVFRkJFMTI2NUM4NUU1ODdEM0Q</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Sunday Closing Laws</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NjE1QTMyMzg5RjAyNDA1QUE4RkFFREQ1MjgzRUFGMzM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6ODM0MTQxODNGMEIyNDI0QkE5NTYzMEJBM0E4NTJBM0U</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Pensions &amp; Benefits Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QzNEOEE3NjhDNTJBNDhCOTgxRkQzNzc1Q0JCMkU4Q0I7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Health Insurance Portability &amp; Accountability Act</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NjVFNjYwOEVBNEUyNEMwQjk3NzlCRjI5NzBDNDlBOTM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QzNEOEE3NjhDNTJBNDhCOTgxRkQzNzc1Q0JCMkU4Q0I</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Public Health &amp; Welfare Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDYwRTY1MDg3MTk5NDUyNkFFRDI1RjJBRERGQ0UxNzI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Discharge &amp; Release of Adults</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QkYyOEQ5NDlGQUNFNDdFMjlBNDA4MkJFMThERkQ3NjM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QkQzMjQzQzhBQUQ2NDRBQTg4MjYwMzQ0QTI0N0E3RTQ</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification><classificationGroup classificationScheme="indexing-terms"><classification classificationScheme="legal"/></classificationGroup></metadata></legislativeDoc>