<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#349#000059#     1#           96#">Va. Code Ann. § 59.1-96</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_59.1-96"/><heading><desig>§ 59.1-96.</desig><title>Offenses and punishments</title></heading><bodyText><p>It shall be unlawful for any person to fill with soda waters, mineral or aerated waters, cider, ginger ale, milk, or soft drinks, or other beverages or with medicine, medical preparations, perfumery, oils, compounds or mixtures, any bottle, box, crate, tin or keg so marked or distinguished as provided in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 59.1-94"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 59.1-94">§ 59.1-94<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000059#     1#           94#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> with or by any name, mark or device, of which a description shall have been filed and published, as provided in such section, or to deface, erase, obliterate, cover up or otherwise remove, or conceal, any such name, mark or device thereon, or to sell, buy, give, take, receive, or otherwise dispose of or traffic in the same without the written consent of, or unless the same shall have been purchased by an agreement in writing from, the person whose mark or device shall be or shall have been in or upon the bottle, siphon, siphon head, crate, tin or keg so filled, trafficked in, used or handled as aforesaid. It shall also be unlawful for any person to sell, buy, rent, or otherwise traffic in any clean laundered or soiled articles mentioned in this chapter so marked or designated as provided in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 59.1-94"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 59.1-94">§ 59.1-94<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000059#     1#           94#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> with or by any name, mark or device, of which a description shall have been filed and published, as provided in such section, or to deface, erase, obliterate, cover up or otherwise remove or conceal, any such name, mark or device thereon, or to sell, buy, give, take, receive or otherwise dispose of or traffic in the same without the written consent of, or unless the same shall have been purchased by an agreement in writing from, the person whose mark or device shall be or shall have been in or upon any such clean laundered or soiled article. Any person offending against the provisions of this section shall be deemed guilty of a misdemeanor, and shall be punished for the first offense by imprisonment for not less than ten days, nor more than one year, or by a fine of $ 5, and in addition thereto fifty cents for each and every such bottle, box, siphon, siphon head, crate, tin, or keg, sold, disposed of, received, bought or trafficked in, or by both such fine and imprisonment, and for each subsequent offense by imprisonment for not less than twenty days nor more than one year, or by a fine of not less than $ 50, and in addition thereto $ 1 for each and every bottle, box, siphon, crate, tin or keg filled, sold, used, disposed of, received, bought or trafficked in, or by both such fine and imprisonment, in the discretion of the judge or jury before whom the offense shall be tried; provided that in the case of any person offending against the provisions of this section relating to clean laundered or soiled articles such fine for the first offense shall be not less than $ 25 nor more than $ 200 and for each subsequent offense, the fine shall be not less than $ 50 nor more than $ 400.</p></bodyText><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p>Code 1950, § 59-193; 1958, c. 579; 1968, c. 439.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PTM0-004G-K086-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 59.1.</desig><title>TRADE AND COMMERCE</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 7.</desig><title>NAMES, MARKS AND DEVICES ON CERTAIN CONTAINERS AND OTHER ARTICLES</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classificationGroup classificationScheme="indexing-terms"><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Banking Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjQyMUFCOUJBNURBNEFDREE3MTNCNDk5QkQ4NUM3RjI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem score="61"><className>Money Laundering</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDRGN0EyOTJBOEM4NDkzOUIyNkNBQkYyMDI3RDM4OTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NkUzNTQ1QUZBM0Y5NDcyQjk4N0I5Mjg0QzU3NDk0MDI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem score="90"><className>Antitrust</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6REEyRTNDM0JGQzYyNEMyOEFGNTAwNUJEOUU1MDg4NjU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></classificationGroup></metadata></legislativeDoc>