<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#123#000027#        97#">Va. Code Ann. § 27-97</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_27-97"/><heading><desig>§ 27-97.</desig><title>Adoption of Fire Prevention Code</title></heading><bodyText><p>The Board of Housing and Community Development is hereby empowered to adopt and promulgate a Statewide Fire Prevention Code which shall be cooperatively developed with the Fire Services Board pursuant to procedures agreed to by the two Boards. The Fire Prevention Code shall prescribe regulations to be complied with for the protection of life and property from the hazards of fire or explosion and for the handling, storage, sale and use of fireworks, explosives or blasting agents, and shall provide for the administration and enforcement of such regulations. The Fire Prevention Code shall require manufacturers of fireworks or explosives, as defined in the Code, to register and report information concerning their manufacturing facilities and methods of operation within the Commonwealth in accordance with regulations adopted by the Board. In addition to conducting criminal background checks pursuant to <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 27-97.2"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 27 -97.2">§ 27-97.2<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#123#000027#      97.2#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, the Board shall also establish regulations for obtaining permits for the manufacturing, storage, handling, use, or sales of fireworks or explosives. In the enforcement of such regulations, the enforcing agency may issue annual permits for such activities to any state regulated public utility. Such permits shall not apply to the storage, handling, or use of explosives or blasting agents pursuant to the provisions of Title 45.1.</p><p>The Fire Prevention Code shall prohibit any person, firm, or corporation from transporting, manufacturing, storing, selling, offering for sale, exposing for sale, or buying, using, igniting, or exploding any fireworks except for those persons, firms, or corporations that manufacture, store, market and distribute fireworks for the sole purpose of fireworks displays permitted by an enforcement agency or by any locality.</p><p>The Fire Prevention Code shall supersede fire prevention regulations heretofore adopted by local governments or other political subdivisions. Local governments are hereby empowered to adopt fire prevention regulations that are more restrictive or more extensive in scope than the Fire Prevention Code provided such regulations do not affect the manner of construction, or materials to be used in the erection, alteration, repair, or use of a building or structure, including the voluntary installation of smoke alarms and regulation and inspections thereof in commercial buildings where such smoke alarms are not required under the provisions of the Code. The Fire Prevention Code shall prohibit any person not certified by the State Fire Marshal's Office as a fireworks operator or pyrotechnician to design, set up, or conduct or supervise the design, setup, or conducting of any fireworks display, either inside a building or structure or outdoors and shall require that at least one person holding a valid certification is present at the site where the fireworks display is being conducted. Certification shall not be required for the design, storage, sale, use, conduct, transportation, and set up of permissible fireworks or the supervision thereof or in connection with any fireworks display conducted by a volunteer fire department provided one member of the volunteer fire department holds a valid certification.</p><p>In formulating the Fire Prevention Code, the Board shall have due regard for generally accepted standards as recommended by nationally recognized organizations including, but not limited to, standards of the International Code Council, the National Fire Protection Association, and recognized organizations issuing standards for the protection of the public from the hazards of explosives and blasting agents. Such standards shall be based on the companion document to the model building code referenced by the Uniform Statewide Building Code.</p><p>The Fire Prevention Code shall require that buildings constructed prior to 1973 be maintained in accordance with state fire and public building regulations in effect prior to March 31, 1986, and that any building which is (i) more than 75 feet or more than six stories high and (ii) used, in whole or in part, as a dormitory to house students by any public or private institution of higher education shall be required to comply with the provisions of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 36-99.3"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 36 -99.3">§ 36-99.3.<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#123#000036#      99.3#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> The Fire Prevention Code shall also require annual fire drills in all buildings having floors used for human occupancy located more than 75 feet above the lowest level of fire department vehicle access. The drills shall be conducted by building staff personnel or the owner of the building in accordance with a plan approved by the appropriate fire official and shall not affect other current occupants. The Board may modify, amend or repeal any Code provisions as the public interest requires. Any such Code changes shall be developed in cooperation with the Fire Services Board pursuant to procedures agreed to by the two Boards.</p></bodyText><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p>1986, c. 429; 1988, cc. 199, 340; <citation normalizedCite="1989 VA CH 90"><content><span normalizedCite="1989 Va. Ch. 90">1989, cc. 90<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1989#000090#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1989 VA CH 420"><content><span normalizedCite="1989 Va. Ch. 420">420<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1989#000420#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1990 VA CH 69"><content><span normalizedCite="1990 Va. Ch. 69">1990, c. 69<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1990#000069#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1991 VA CH 53"><content><span normalizedCite="1991 Va. Ch. 53">1991, c. 53<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1991#000053#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1994 VA CH 275"><content><span normalizedCite="1994 Va. Ch. 275">1994, c. 275<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1994#000275#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1997 VA CH 584"><content><span normalizedCite="1997 Va. Ch. 584">1997, c. 584<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1997#000584#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2000 VA CH 951"><content><span normalizedCite="2000 Va. Ch. 951">2000, cc. 951<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2000#000951#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2000 VA CH 1065"><content><span normalizedCite="2000 Va. Ch. 1065">1065<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2000#001065#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2002 VA CH 856"><content><span normalizedCite="2002 Va. Ch. 856">2002, c. 856<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2002#000856#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2007 VA CH 647"><content><span normalizedCite="2007 Va. Ch. 647">2007, cc. 647<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2007#000647#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2007 VA CH 741"><content><span normalizedCite="2007 Va. Ch. 741">741<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2007#000741#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2010 VA CH 587"><content><span normalizedCite="2010 Va. Ch. 587">2010, cc. 587<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2010#000587#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2010 VA CH 643"><content><span normalizedCite="2010 Va. Ch. 643">643<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2010#000643#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PVJ0-004G-K0XK-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 27.</desig><title>FIRE PROTECTION</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 9.</desig><title>STATEWIDE FIRE PREVENTION CODE ACT</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Governments</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjdEQjE4OUJDMzQxNDNEMEI0RTI1QUFCMzJENjEwRTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Administrative Boards</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QTYwRUFCMDc5MzQ5NDEyREFEQkU2NkE2MjRGQTlCNzY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Njg1MkM3RkYyNzIxNEVFRkJFMTI2NUM4NUU1ODdEM0Q</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Fire Departments</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MEU4MjlBNENBOEQxNDU5NTkyM0Y5M0YzMEEyODU3NEY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Njg1MkM3RkYyNzIxNEVFRkJFMTI2NUM4NUU1ODdEM0Q</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Ordinances &amp; Regulations</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NjQ1MzRDRUY1OTZBNDRDNTlDODQzRDRCMUFCNDc2RTU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Njg1MkM3RkYyNzIxNEVFRkJFMTI2NUM4NUU1ODdEM0Q</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Real Property Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QUUyRTcxRURBNEY2NEE2MDk3QzBCNzRDOEY0NTZDQzk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Building &amp; Housing Codes</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDZGNTdFRUIyNEQ2NDQ1QjlBMzEwRDQyOUZFRUFCRjM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NjcyQTdEMEUxODYyNDY0OThFQTg1NUNGMjFBMTkxQ0M</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RjBBQTVENjZENjJFNEEzNjlBRDE1QjZDRjQyM0FBNkM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NjcyQTdEMEUxODYyNDY0OThFQTg1NUNGMjFBMTkxQ0M</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></metadata></legislativeDoc>