<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#349#000051#     1#       505.01#">Va. Code Ann. § 51.1-505.01</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><note><bodyText><p>This section has more than one version with varying effective dates.  To view a complete list of the versions of this section see Table of Contents.</p></bodyText></note><anchor id="_51.1-505.01"/><heading><desig>§ 51.1-505.01.</desig><title>(Effective October 1, 2016) Additional accidental death and dismemberment benefits</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><bodyText><p>The group life, accidental death, and dismemberment insurance coverage purchased by the Board shall include, but not be limited to, the following benefits:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a"/><heading><desig>A.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> If, as a result of an accident, an insured employee dies at least seventy-five miles from his principal residence, an additional accidental death benefit shall be paid for the preparation and transportation of the employee to a mortuary. The additional benefit shall be the lesser of the actual cost for such preparation and transportation or $ 5,000;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b"/><heading><desig>B.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> If an insured employee dies or suffers a dismemberment as a result of an accident that occurs while the employee is driving or riding in a private passenger vehicle, an additional accidental death or dismemberment benefit shall be paid, provided that (i) the private passenger vehicle is equipped with a safety restraint system; (ii) such safety restraint system was being used properly by the insured employee at the time of the accident, as certified in the official accident report or by the official investigating officer; and (iii) at the time of the accident, the driver of the private passenger vehicle held a current license to operate a private passenger vehicle and was not intoxicated, driving while impaired or under the influence of alcohol or drugs, as is defined or determined under applicable law.</p><p><pre/>The additional benefit shall be the lesser of ten percent of the amount otherwise payable due to such accidental death or dismemberment or $ 50,000.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c"/><heading><desig>C.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Death or dismemberment from a felonious assault.</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> If an insured employee dies or suffers a dismemberment as a result of an accident caused by a felonious assault committed by other than an immediate family member, there shall be paid an additional accidental death or dismemberment benefit equal to the lesser of twenty-five percent of the amount otherwise payable due to such accidental death or dismemberment or $ 50,000.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> In addition, if (i) an insured employee dies as a result of an accident caused by a felonious assault committed by other than an immediate family member, and (ii) such insured employee has a qualifying child at the time of such accident, a savings trust account shall be opened for each qualifying child pursuant to the Virginia College Savings Plan (§ 23.1-700 et seq.). The Retirement System shall contribute into the account of each such qualifying child an amount approximately equal to the current cost of purchasing in full a prepaid tuition contract for tuition and mandatory fees at a four-year public institution of higher education in the Commonwealth, as determined under § 23.1-700 et seq. The qualified beneficiary, as defined in § 23.1-700, shall be the qualifying child on whose behalf such account was opened. Specific benefits of the savings trust account shall be as defined by the Virginia College Savings Plan.</p></bodyText></level></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><bodyText><p><pre/>Funds in a savings trust account opened on behalf of a qualifying child shall be used for qualified higher education expenses at eligible institutions, both as defined in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="26 USC 529"><content><span normalizedCite="26 U.S.C. 529">§ 529 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#29854#1127#00000000529#1#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, as amended, or other applicable federal law, as determined by the Board of the Virginia College Savings Plan. Savings trust account funds shall not be disbursed prior to a qualifying child being admitted and enrolled at an eligible institution. Any funds in a savings trust account that are not used by a qualifying child before the expiration of the time period for the use of such funds, as determined by the Virginia College Savings Plan, shall be paid to the Retirement System promptly after the expiration of such period.</p></bodyText></level><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p><citation normalizedCite="2001 VA CH 685"><content><span normalizedCite="2001 Va. Ch. 685">2001, cc. 685<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2001#000685#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2001 VA CH 690"><content><span normalizedCite="2001 Va. Ch. 690">690<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2001#000690#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2002 VA CH 313"><content><span normalizedCite="2002 Va. Ch. 313">2002, c. 313<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2002#000313#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PWF0-004G-K47R-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 51.1.</desig><title>PENSIONS, BENEFITS, AND RETIREMENT</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 5.</desig><title>GROUP INSURANCE PROGRAM</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Criminal Law &amp; Procedure</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NEU0RkE1OUQwNUQwNDgxODhEODZCMjkzOTg3NThBNzk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6ODYxNTIxRjQyOUI3NDlGQUFERUQxM0I1Rjk4MkQ5NDY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QTQxQUQ5OThEM0I3NDg3OUJGNDlDQTE5MDMzM0M3RDc</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Nzk3NTlBMDhDNEZGNEZFQzk1QzI4QzVBRjIyRjU1Q0M7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RUUwRTU3NTU1NkRGNDlBQTkzQkRCM0RFQTZENTlBMUY</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification><classificationGroup classificationScheme="indexing-terms"><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem score="90"><className>Pensions &amp; Benefits</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QzNEOEE3NjhDNTJBNDhCOTgxRkQzNzc1Q0JCMkU4Q0I7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></classificationGroup></metadata></legislativeDoc>