<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#349#000016#     1#        285.2#">Va. Code Ann. § 16.1-285.2</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_16.1-285.2"/><heading><desig>§ 16.1-285.2.</desig><title>Release and review hearing for serious offender</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a"/><heading><desig>A.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Upon receipt of a petition of the Department of Juvenile Justice for a hearing concerning a juvenile committed under <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 16.1-285.1"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 16.1-285.1">§ 16.1-285.1<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000016#     1#        285.1#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, the court shall schedule a hearing within thirty days and shall appoint counsel for the juvenile pursuant to <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 16.1-266"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 16.1-266">§ 16.1-266<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000016#     1#          266#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>. The court shall provide a copy of the petition, the progress report required by this section, and notice of the time and place of the hearing to (i) the juvenile, (ii) the juvenile's parent, legal guardian, or person standing in loco parentis, (iii) the juvenile's guardian ad litem, if any, (iv) the juvenile's legal counsel, and (v) the attorney for the Commonwealth who prosecuted the juvenile during the delinquency proceeding. The attorney for the Commonwealth shall provide notice of the time and place of the hearing by first-class mail to the last known address of any victim of the offense for which the juvenile was committed if such victim has submitted a written request for notification to the attorney for the Commonwealth.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b"/><heading><desig>B.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The petition shall be filed in the committing court and shall be accompanied by a progress report from the Department. This report shall describe (i) the facility and living arrangement provided for the juvenile by the Department, (ii) the services and treatment programs afforded the juvenile, (iii) the juvenile's progress toward treatment goals and objectives, which shall include a summary of his educational progress, (iv) the juvenile's potential for danger to either himself or the community, and (v) a comprehensive aftercare plan for the juvenile.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b1"/><heading><desig>B1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The appearance of the juvenile before the court may be by (i) personal appearance before the judge, or (ii) use of two-way electronic video and audio communication. If two-way electronic video and audio communication is used, a judge may exercise all powers conferred by law and all communications and proceedings shall be conducted in the same manner as if the appearance were in person, and any documents filed may be transmitted by facsimile process. A facsimile may be served or executed by the officer or person to whom sent, and returned in the same manner, and with the same force, effect, authority, and liability as an original document. All signatures thereon shall be treated as original signatures. Any two-way electronic video and audio communication system used for an appearance shall meet the standards as set forth in subsection B of § 19.2-3.1.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c"/><heading><desig>C.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> At the hearing the court shall consider the progress report. The court may also consider additional evidence from (i) probation officers, the juvenile correctional center, treatment professionals, and the court service unit; (ii) the juvenile, his legal counsel, parent, guardian or family member; or (iii) other sources the court deems relevant. The hearing and all records relating thereto shall be governed by the confidentiality provisions of Article 12 (<citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 16.1-299"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 16.1-299">§ 16.1-299<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000016#     1#          299#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> et seq.) of this chapter.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d"/><heading><desig>D.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> At the conclusion of the hearing, the court shall order (i) continued commitment of the juvenile to the Department for completion of the original determinate period of commitment or such lesser time as the court may order or (ii) release of the juvenile under such terms and conditions as the court may prescribe. In making a determination under this section, the court shall consider (i) the experiences and character of the juvenile before and after commitment, (ii) the nature of the offenses that the juvenile was found to have committed, (iii) the manner in which the offenses were committed, (iv) the protection of the community, (v) the recommendations of the Department, and (vi) any other factors the court deems relevant. The order of the court shall be final and not subject to appeal.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_e"/><heading><desig>E.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> In the case of a juvenile convicted as an adult and committed as a serious offender under subdivision A 1 of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 16.1-272"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 16.1-272">§ 16.1-272<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000016#     1#          272#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, at the conclusion of the review hearing, the circuit court shall order (i) the juvenile to begin serving any adult sentence in whole or in part that may include any remaining part of the original determinate period of commitment, or (ii) the suspension of the unserved portion of the adult sentence in whole or in part based upon the juvenile's successful completion of the commitment as a serious offender, or (iii) the continued commitment of the juvenile to the Department for completion of the original determinate period of commitment or such lesser time as the court may order, or (iv) the release of the juvenile under such terms and conditions as the court may prescribe.</p></bodyText></level><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p><citation normalizedCite="1994 VA CH 859"><content><span normalizedCite="1994 Va. Ch. 859">1994, cc. 859<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1994#000859#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1994 VA CH 949"><content><span normalizedCite="1994 Va. Ch. 949">949<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1994#000949#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1995 VA CH 536"><content><span normalizedCite="1995 Va. Ch. 536">1995, c. 536<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1995#000536#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1996 VA CH 755"><content><span normalizedCite="1996 Va. Ch. 755">1996, cc. 755<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1996#000755#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1996 VA CH 914"><content><span normalizedCite="1996 Va. Ch. 914">914<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1996#000914#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2002 VA CH 511"><content><span normalizedCite="2002 Va. Ch. 511">2002, c. 511<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2002#000511#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PV00-004G-K0XJ-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 16.1.</desig><title>COURTS NOT OF RECORD</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 11.</desig><title>JUVENILE AND DOMESTIC RELATIONS DISTRICT COURTS</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="article"><heading><desig>ARTICLE 9.</desig><title>DISPOSITION</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Family Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NEI4M0U5Qzg3RTk0NDdBRUJGNDRGNkZEQkU3RDdFNDU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>In Loco Parentis</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QUQyQjNGQUI2QjE1NEVCN0FDQUNERjlFQkEzQ0Y0MDQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RDEyNDI5NzYyODkyNDcxNzgwQkRBNjA0NzAxMEVCOTQ</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification><classificationGroup classificationScheme="indexing-terms"><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem score="90"><className>Governments</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjdEQjE4OUJDMzQxNDNEMEI0RTI1QUFCMzJENjEwRTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></classificationGroup></metadata></legislativeDoc>