<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#142#        23#     50.16#         4#">Va. Code Ann. § 23-50.16:4</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_23-50.16_4"/><heading><desig>§ 23-50.16:4.</desig><title>(Repealed effective October 1, 2016) Definitions</title></heading><bodyText><p>As used in this chapter, the following terms have the following meanings, unless the context requires otherwise:</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Authority"</emphasis> means the Virginia Commonwealth University Health System Authority.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Board"</emphasis> means the Board of Directors of the Authority.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Bonds"</emphasis> means bonds, notes, revenue certificates, lease participation certificates or other evidences of indebtedness or deferred purchase financing arrangements.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Costs"</emphasis> means costs of construction, reconstruction, renovation, site work and acquisition of lands, structures, rights-of-way, franchises, easements and other property rights and interests; costs of demolition, removal or relocation of buildings or structures; costs of labor, materials, machinery and all other kinds of equipment; financing charges; costs of engineering and inspections; costs of financial, legal and accounting services; costs of plans, specifications, studies, and surveys; estimates of costs and of revenues; feasibility studies and administrative expenses, including administrative expenses during the start-up of any project; costs of issuance of bonds, including printing, engraving, advertising, legal and other similar expenses; credit enhancement and liquidity facility fees; fees for interest rate caps, collars, swaps or other financial derivative products; interest on bonds in connection with a project prior to and during construction or acquisition thereof and for a period not exceeding one year thereafter; provisions for working capital to be used in connection with any project; redemption premiums, obligations purchased to provide for the payment of bonds being refunded and other costs necessary or incident to refunding of bonds; operating and maintenance reserve funds, debt reserve funds and other reserves for the payment of principal and interest on bonds; and all other expenses necessary, desirable or incidental to the operation of the Authority's facilities or the construction, reconstruction, renovation, acquisition or financing of projects or other facilities or equipment appropriate for carrying out the purposes of this chapter and the placing of the same in operation; or the refunding of bonds.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Chief executive officer"</emphasis> means the chief executive officer of the Virginia Commonwealth University Health System Authority.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Hospital facilities"</emphasis> means all property or rights in property, real and personal, tangible and intangible, including all facilities suitable for providing hospital and health care services and including any and all structures, buildings, improvements, additions, extensions, replacements, appurtenances, lands, rights in land, furnishings, landscaping, approaches, roadways and other related and supporting facilities, now or hereafter owned, leased, operated or used, in whole or in part, by Virginia Commonwealth University as part of, or in connection with, the Medical College of Virginia Hospitals in the normal course of its operations as a teaching, research and medical treatment facility.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Hospital obligations"</emphasis> means all debts or other obligations, contingent or certain, owing to any person or other entity on the transfer date, arising out of the operation of the Medical College of Virginia Hospitals as a medical treatment facility or arising out of the financing or refinancing of hospital facilities, and including all bonds and other debts for the purchase of goods and services, whether or not delivered, and obligations for the delivery of services, whether or not performed.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Project"</emphasis> means any health care, research or educational facility or equipment necessary or convenient to or consistent with the purposes of the Authority, whether or not owned by the Authority, including, without limitation, hospitals; nursing homes; continuing care facilities; self-care facilities; wellness and health maintenance centers; medical office facilities; clinics; out-patient clinics; surgical centers; alcohol, substance abuse, and drug treatment centers; laboratories; sanitariums; hospices; facilities for the residence or care of the elderly, the handicapped, or the chronically ill; residential facilities for nurses, interns, and physicians; other kinds of facilities for the treatment of sick, disturbed, or infirm persons or the prevention of disease or maintenance of health; colleges, schools or divisions offering undergraduate or graduate programs for the health professions and sciences and such other branches of learning as may be appropriate, together with research, training, and teaching facilities; all related and supporting facilities and equipment necessary or desirable in connection therewith or incidental thereto; or equipment alone, including, without limitation, parking, kitchen, laundry, laboratory, wellness, pharmaceutical, administrative, communications, computer, and recreational facilities; power plants and equipment; storage space; mobile medical facilities; vehicles; air transport equipment and other equipment necessary or desirable for the transportation of medical equipment, medical personnel or patients; and all lands, buildings, improvements, approaches and appurtenances necessary or desirable in connection with or incidental to any project.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Transfer date"</emphasis> means a date or dates agreed to by the Board of Visitors of Virginia Commonwealth University and the Authority for the transfer of employees to the Authority and for the transfer of hospital facilities, or any parts thereof, to and the assumption, directly or indirectly, of hospital obligations by the Authority, which dates for the various transfers and the various assumptions may be different, but in no event shall any date be later than June 30, 1997.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"University"</emphasis> means Virginia Commonwealth University.</p></bodyText><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p><citation normalizedCite="1996 VA CH 905"><content><span normalizedCite="1996 Va. Ch. 905">1996, cc. 905<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1996#000905#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1996 VA CH 1046"><content><span normalizedCite="1996 Va. Ch. 1046">1046<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1996#001046#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2000 VA CH 720"><content><span normalizedCite="2000 Va. Ch. 720">2000, c. 720<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2000#000720#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PV10-004G-K1RR-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 23.</desig><title>EDUCATIONAL INSTITUTIONS</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 6.2.</desig><title>VIRGINIA COMMONWEALTH UNIVERSITY HEALTH SYSTEM AUTHORITY</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Education Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDkzNUEzQzFBNEZBNEFBREIxNDM5MTc1MUU5QjI4MTY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NjA2NDg3NzhDRjYxNDNFMTk0NkY5OTdFRjhGMjBGMUY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QTU5MTJDNDBCQkU0NEY2MEIyREVGRkM0Qzg1NjY5RTQ</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Real Property Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QUUyRTcxRURBNEY2NEE2MDk3QzBCNzRDOEY0NTZDQzk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Construction Loans</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RDNGMDlENjQ4NUYyNEM0MEIxRTAwMjAyRTdFRUNBRkY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MTY1MzRERDhBMDZCNDFBMDk0QUEwRjcyN0ZFNEY3REM</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification><classificationGroup classificationScheme="indexing-terms"><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem score="90"><className>Education</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDkzNUEzQzFBNEZBNEFBREIxNDM5MTc1MUU5QjI4MTY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></classificationGroup></metadata></legislativeDoc>