<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#349#000063#     2#         1808#">Va. Code Ann. § 63.2-1808</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_63.2-1808"/><heading><desig>§ 63.2-1808.</desig><title>Rights and responsibilities of residents of assisted living facilities; certification of licensure</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a"/><heading><desig>A.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Any resident of an assisted living facility has the rights and responsibilities enumerated in this section. The operator or administrator of an assisted living facility shall establish written policies and procedures to ensure that, at the minimum, each person who becomes a resident of the assisted living facility:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Is fully informed, prior to or at the time of admission and during the resident's stay, of his rights and of all rules and expectations governing the resident's conduct, responsibilities, and the terms of the admission agreement; evidence of this shall be the resident's written acknowledgment of having been so informed, which shall be filed in his record;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Is fully informed, prior to or at the time of admission and during the resident's stay, of services available in the facility and of any related charges; this shall be reflected by the resident's signature on a current resident's agreement retained in the resident's file;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Unless a committee or conservator has been appointed, is free to manage his personal finances and funds regardless of source; is entitled to access to personal account statements reflecting financial transactions made on his behalf by the facility; and is given at least a quarterly accounting of financial transactions made on his behalf when a written delegation of responsibility to manage his financial affairs is made to the facility for any period of time in conformance with state law;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_4"/><heading><desig>4.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Is afforded confidential treatment of his personal affairs and records and may approve or refuse their release to any individual outside the facility except as otherwise provided in law and except in case of his transfer to another care-giving facility;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_5"/><heading><desig>5.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Is transferred or discharged only when provided with a statement of reasons, or for nonpayment for his stay, and is given reasonable advance notice; upon notice of discharge or upon giving reasonable advance notice of his desire to move, shall be afforded reasonable assistance to ensure an orderly transfer or discharge; such actions shall be documented in his record;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_6"/><heading><desig>6.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> In the event a medical condition should arise while he is residing in the facility, is afforded the opportunity to participate in the planning of his program of care and medical treatment at the facility and the right to refuse treatment;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_7"/><heading><desig>7.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Is not required to perform services for the facility except as voluntarily contracted pursuant to a voluntary agreement for services that states the terms of consideration or remuneration and is documented in writing and retained in his record;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_8"/><heading><desig>8.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Is free to select health care services from reasonably available resources;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_9"/><heading><desig>9.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Is free to refuse to participate in human subject experimentation or to be party to research in which his identity may be ascertained;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_10"/><heading><desig>10.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Is free from mental, emotional, physical, sexual, and economic abuse or exploitation; is free from forced isolation, threats or other degrading or demeaning acts against him; and his known needs are not neglected or ignored by personnel of the facility;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_11"/><heading><desig>11.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Is treated with courtesy, respect, and consideration as a person of worth, sensitivity, and dignity;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_12"/><heading><desig>12.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Is encouraged, and informed of appropriate means as necessary, throughout the period of stay to exercise his rights as a resident and as a citizen; to this end, he is free to voice grievances and recommend changes in policies and services, free of coercion, discrimination, threats or reprisal;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_13"/><heading><desig>13.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Is permitted to retain and use his personal clothing and possessions as space permits unless to do so would infringe upon rights of other residents;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_14"/><heading><desig>14.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Is encouraged to function at his highest mental, emotional, physical and social potential;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_15"/><heading><desig>15.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Is free of physical or mechanical restraint except in the following situations and with appropriate safeguards:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_15_a"/><heading><desig>a.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> As necessary for the facility to respond to unmanageable behavior in an emergency situation, which threatens the immediate safety of the resident or others;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_15_b"/><heading><desig>b.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> As medically necessary, as authorized in writing by a physician, to provide physical support to a weakened resident;</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_16"/><heading><desig>16.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Is free of prescription drugs except where medically necessary, specifically prescribed, and supervised by the attending physician, physician assistant, or nurse practitioner;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_17"/><heading><desig>17.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Is accorded respect for ordinary privacy in every aspect of daily living, including but not limited to the following:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_17_a"/><heading><desig>a.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> In the care of his personal needs except as assistance may be needed;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_17_b"/><heading><desig>b.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> In any medical examination or health-related consultations the resident may have at the facility;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_17_c"/><heading><desig>c.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> In communications, in writing or by telephone;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_17_d"/><heading><desig>d.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> During visitations with other persons;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_17_e"/><heading><desig>e.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> In the resident's room or portion thereof; residents shall be permitted to have guests or other residents in their rooms unless to do so would infringe upon the rights of other residents; staff may not enter a resident's room without making their presence known except in an emergency or in accordance with safety oversight requirements included in regulations of the Board;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_17_f"/><heading><desig>f.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> In visits with his spouse; if both are residents of the facility they are permitted but not required to share a room unless otherwise provided in the residents' agreements;</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_18"/><heading><desig>18.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Is permitted to meet with and participate in activities of social, religious, and community groups at his discretion unless medically contraindicated as documented by his physician, physician assistant, or nurse practitioner in his medical record;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_19"/><heading><desig>19.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Is fully informed, as evidenced by the written acknowledgment of the resident or his legal representative, prior to or at the time of admission and during his stay, that he should exercise whatever due diligence he deems necessary with respect to information on any sex offenders registered pursuant to Chapter 9 (<citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 9.1-900"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 9.1-900">§ 9.1-900<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000009#     1#          900#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> et seq.) of Title 9.1, including how to obtain such information. Upon request, the assisted living facility shall assist the resident, prospective resident, or the legal representative of the resident or prospective resident in accessing this information and provide the resident, prospective resident, or the legal representative of the resident or prospective resident with printed copies of the requested information; and</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_20"/><heading><desig>20.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Is informed, in writing and upon request, of whether the assisted living facility maintains the minimum liability coverage, as established by the Board pursuant to subdivision A 10 of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 63.2-1805"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 63.2-1805">§ 63.2-1805<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000063#     2#         1805#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b"/><heading><desig>B.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> If the resident is unable to fully understand and exercise the rights and responsibilities contained in this section, the facility shall require that a responsible individual, of the resident's choice when possible, designated in writing in the resident's record, be made aware of each item in this section and the decisions that affect the resident or relate to specific items in this section; a resident shall be assumed capable of understanding and exercising these rights unless a physician determines otherwise and documents the reasons for such determination in the resident's record.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c"/><heading><desig>C.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The rights and responsibilities of residents shall be printed in at least 12-point type and posted conspicuously in a public place in all assisted living facilities. The facility shall also post the name and telephone number of the regional licensing supervisor of the Department, the Adult Protective Services' toll-free telephone number, as well as the toll-free telephone number for the Virginia Long-Term Care Ombudsman Program, any sub-state ombudsman program serving the area, and the toll-free number of the Commonwealth's designated protection and advocacy system.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d"/><heading><desig>D.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The facility shall make its policies and procedures for implementing this section available and accessible to residents, relatives, agencies, and the general public.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_e"/><heading><desig>E.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The provisions of this section shall not be construed to restrict or abridge any right that any resident has under law.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_f"/><heading><desig>F.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Each facility shall provide appropriate staff training to implement each resident's rights included in this section.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_g"/><heading><desig>G.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The Board shall adopt regulations as necessary to carry out the full intent of this section.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_h"/><heading><desig>H.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> It shall be the responsibility of the Commissioner to ensure that the provisions of this section are observed and implemented by assisted living facilities as a condition to the issuance, renewal, or continuation of the license required by this article.</p></bodyText></level><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p>1984, c. 677, § 63.1-182.1; <citation normalizedCite="1989 VA CH 271"><content><span normalizedCite="1989 Va. Ch. 271">1989, c. 271<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1989#000271#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1990 VA CH 458"><content><span normalizedCite="1990 Va. Ch. 458">1990, c. 458<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1990#000458#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1992 VA CH 356"><content><span normalizedCite="1992 Va. Ch. 356">1992, c. 356<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1992#000356#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1993 VA CH 957"><content><span normalizedCite="1993 Va. Ch. 957">1993, cc. 957<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1993#000957#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1993 VA CH 993"><content><span normalizedCite="1993 Va. Ch. 993">993<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1993#000993#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1997 VA CH 801"><content><span normalizedCite="1997 Va. Ch. 801">1997, c. 801<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1997#000801#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2000 VA CH 177"><content><span normalizedCite="2000 Va. Ch. 177">2000, c. 177<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2000#000177#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2002 VA CH 45"><content><span normalizedCite="2002 Va. Ch. 45">2002, cc. 45<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2002#000045#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2002 VA CH 572"><content><span normalizedCite="2002 Va. Ch. 572">572<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2002#000572#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2002 VA CH 747"><content><span normalizedCite="2002 Va. Ch. 747">747<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2002#000747#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2004 VA CH 855"><content><span normalizedCite="2004 Va. Ch. 855">2004, c. 855<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2004#000855#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2006 VA CH 396"><content><span normalizedCite="2006 Va. Ch. 396">2006, c. 396<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2006#000396#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2007 VA CH 120"><content><span normalizedCite="2007 Va. Ch. 120">2007, cc. 120<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2007#000120#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2007 VA CH 163"><content><span normalizedCite="2007 Va. Ch. 163">163<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2007#000163#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2013 VA CH 320"><content><span normalizedCite="2013 Va. Ch. 320">2013, cc. 320<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2013#000320#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2013 VA CH 571"><content><span normalizedCite="2013 Va. Ch. 571">571<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2013#000571#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PVD0-004G-K430-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 63.2.</desig><title>WELFARE (SOCIAL SERVICES)</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="subtitle"><heading><desig>SUBTITLE IV.</desig><title>LICENSURE</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 18.</desig><title>FACILITIES AND PROGRAMS</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="article"><heading><desig>ARTICLE 1.</desig><title>ASSISTED LIVING FACILITIES</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Governments</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjdEQjE4OUJDMzQxNDNEMEI0RTI1QUFCMzJENjEwRTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RkE2M0MyMkU1MDJENDc5NjhFRDc0QTREMjRFMDA1Njc7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MTkwNDc4Q0NCRDkxNDdCMUI4MjFBQzg4NjlDMUZCMjI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Healthcare Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NkUxMkVDQjJDOEY5NDVDQ0E5NTFEMTlDMjIwNzVERjc7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Right to Refuse Treatment</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OTY1QTdGOENFQTkwNDVGNUE1OTE2Mjk3M0M3MzY3Qzg7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OEQ4NDdDRTY1QTdDNEZFODhDREYxQTRGMDhGQURDMzU</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification><classificationGroup classificationScheme="indexing-terms"><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem score="90"><className>Public Health &amp; Welfare</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDYwRTY1MDg3MTk5NDUyNkFFRDI1RjJBRERGQ0UxNzI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></classificationGroup></metadata></legislativeDoc>