<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#123#000021#     117.1#">Va. Code Ann. § 21-117.1</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_21-117.1"/><heading><desig>§ 21-117.1.</desig><title>Abolishing sanitary districts</title></heading><bodyText><p>Any sanitary district heretofore or hereafter created in any county under the provisions of the preceding sections of this article, may be abolished by an order entered by the circuit court of such county, or the judge thereof in vacation, upon the petition of the governing body of the county and of no less than 50 qualified voters residing within the boundaries of the district desired to be abolished, or if the district contains less than 100 qualified voters upon petition of the governing body of the county and fifty percent of the qualified voters residing within the boundaries of such district.</p><p>Upon filing of the petition, the court shall fix a day for a hearing on the question of abolishing the sanitary district which hearing shall embrace a consideration of whether the property in the sanitary district will or will not be benefited by the abolition thereof and the court shall be fully informed as to the obligations and functions of the sanitary district. Notice of such hearing shall be given by publication once a week for three consecutive weeks in some newspaper of general circulation within the county to be designated by the court or the judge thereof in vacation. At least ten days shall intervene between the completion of the publication and the date set for hearing, and such publication shall be considered complete on the twenty-first day after the first publication and no such district shall be abolished until the notice has been given and the hearing had.</p><p>Any interested parties may appear and be heard on any matters pertaining to the subject of the hearing.</p><p>Upon the hearing, such order shall be made and entered as to the court or judge may seem equitable and proper, concerning the abolition of the district and as to the funds on hand to the credit of the district. Provided, however, that no such order shall be made abolishing the sanitary district unless any bonds of the sanitary district which have theretofore been issued have been redeemed and the purposes for which the sanitary district was created have been completed, or, unless all obligations and functions of the sanitary district have been taken over by the county as a whole, or, unless the purposes for which the sanitary district was created are impractical or impossible of accomplishment and no obligations have been incurred by said sanitary district.</p></bodyText><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p>1954, c. 135.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PSY0-004G-K0VD-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 21.</desig><title>DRAINAGE, SOIL CONSERVATION, SANITATION AND PUBLIC FACILITIES DISTRICTS</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 2.</desig><title>SANITARY DISTRICTS</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="article"><heading><desig>ARTICLE 1.</desig><title>GENERAL PROVISIONS</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Governments</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjdEQjE4OUJDMzQxNDNEMEI0RTI1QUFCMzJENjEwRTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Finance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjMzOTBBRTg2MUVDNDdDNUE1M0QxNDk1RERCNjNCN0I7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Njg1MkM3RkYyNzIxNEVFRkJFMTI2NUM4NUU1ODdEM0Q</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></metadata></legislativeDoc>