<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#349#000005#     1#          152#">Va. Code Ann. § 5.1-152</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_5.1-152"/><heading><desig>§ 5.1-152.</desig><title>Definitions</title></heading><bodyText><p>For the purposes of this act, the following terms and phrases shall mean:</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Authority"</emphasis> shall mean the Metropolitan Washington Airports Authority created by this act and by similar enactment by the District of Columbia or, if the Authority shall be abolished, the board, body, or commission or agency succeeding to the principal functions thereof or upon whom the powers given by this act to the Authority shall be conferred by law;</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Authority Facilities"</emphasis> shall mean any or all airport facilities now existing or hereafter acquired or constructed or caused to be constructed by the Authority under this act, and together with any or all buildings, improvements, additions, extensions, replacements, appurtenances, lands, rights in land, water rights, air rights, franchises, machinery, equipment, furnishings, landscaping, easements, utilities, approaches, roadways and other facilities necessary or desirable in connection therewith or incidental thereto, including the existing Dulles Airport Access Road and its right-of-way, acquired or constructed by the Authority;</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Bonds"</emphasis> or <emphasis typeStyle="it">"revenue bonds"</emphasis> shall mean bonds and notes or refunding bonds and notes or bond anticipation notes or other obligations of the Authority issued under the provisions of this act.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Cost"</emphasis> shall mean, as applied to Authority Facilities, the cost of acquisition of all lands, structures, rights-of-way, franchises, easements and other property rights and interests, the cost of lease payments, the cost of construction, the cost of demolishing, removing or relocating any buildings or structures on lands acquired, including the cost of acquiring any lands to which such buildings or structures may be moved or relocated, the cost of any extensions, enlargements, additions and improvements, the cost of all labor, materials, machinery and equipment, financing charges, interest on all bonds prior to and during construction and, if deemed advisable by the Authority, for a period not exceeding one year after completion of such construction, the cost of engineering, financial and legal services, plans, specifications, studies, surveys, estimates of cost and of revenues, other expenses necessary or incident to determining the feasibility or practicability of constructing the Authority Facilities, administrative expenses, provisions for working capital, reserves for interest and for extensions, enlargements, additions and improvements, the cost of bond issuance and other devices designed to enhance the creditworthiness of the bonds, and such other expenses as may be necessary or incidental to the construction of the Authority Facilities, the financing of such construction and the placing of the Authority Facilities in operation. Any obligation or expenses incurred by the Commonwealth or any agency thereof, with the approval of the Authority, for studies, surveys, borings, preparation of plans and specifications or other work or materials in connection with the construction of the Authority Facilities may be regarded as part of the cost of the Authority Facilities and may be reimbursed to the Commonwealth or such agency out of any funds available therefor or the proceeds of the revenue bonds issued for such Authority Facilities as hereinafter authorized.</p></bodyText><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p><citation normalizedCite="2001 VA CH 342"><content><span normalizedCite="2001 Va. Ch. 342">2001, c. 342<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2001#000342#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PV60-004G-K553-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 5.1.</desig><title>AVIATION</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 10.</desig><title>METROPOLITAN WASHINGTON AIRPORTS AUTHORITY</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classificationGroup classificationScheme="indexing-terms"><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem score="58"><className>State &amp; Local Regulation</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6N0I4MUNDQTM5NEVBNEJGNDlEODNERjUxRkE4REFDMjI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NkEyRTREQTdBRjkzNDE5OTk4ODAzMEY5MDkzRjlGRTE</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem score="90"><className>Transportation</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RTYzRTk5RDVBQkQ2NDcwQzk2NTU3ODQ5OEE3NDlBNzk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Transportation Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RTYzRTk5RDVBQkQ2NDcwQzk2NTU3ODQ5OEE3NDlBNzk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem score="58"><className>State &amp; Local Regulation</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6N0I4MUNDQTM5NEVBNEJGNDlEODNERjUxRkE4REFDMjI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NkEyRTREQTdBRjkzNDE5OTk4ODAzMEY5MDkzRjlGRTE</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></classificationGroup></metadata></legislativeDoc>