<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#349#000022#     1#          254#">Va. Code Ann. § 22.1-254</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_22.1-254"/><heading><desig>§ 22.1-254.</desig><title>Compulsory attendance required; excuses and waivers; alternative education program attendance; exemptions from article</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a"/><heading><desig>A.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Except as otherwise provided in this article, every parent, guardian, or other person in the Commonwealth having control or charge of any child who will have reached the fifth birthday on or before September 30 of any school year and who has not passed the eighteenth birthday shall, during the period of each year the public schools are in session and for the same number of days and hours per day as the public schools, send such child to a public school or to a private, denominational, or parochial school or have such child taught by a tutor or teacher of qualifications prescribed by the Board of Education and approved by the division superintendent, or provide for home instruction of such child as described in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 22.1-254.1"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 22.1-254.1">§ 22.1-254.1.<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000022#     1#        254.1#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation></p><p>As prescribed in the regulations of the Board of Education, the requirements of this section may also be satisfied by sending a child to an alternative program of study or work/study offered by a public, private, denominational, or parochial school or by a public or private degree-granting institution of higher education. Further, in the case of any five-year-old child who is subject to the provisions of this subsection, the requirements of this section may be alternatively satisfied by sending the child to any public educational pre-kindergarten program, including a Head Start program, or in a private, denominational, or parochial educational pre-kindergarten program.</p><p>Instruction in the home of a child or children by the parent, guardian, or other person having control or charge of such child or children shall not be classified or defined as a private, denominational or parochial school.</p><p>The requirements of this section shall apply to (i) any child in the custody of the Department of Juvenile Justice or the Department of Corrections who has not passed his eighteenth birthday and (ii) any child whom the division superintendent has required to take a special program of prevention, intervention, or remediation as provided in subsection C of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 22.1-253.13:1"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 22.1-253.13:1">§ 22.1-253.13:1<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#958#0000000022#0000000001#    253.13#0000000001#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> and in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 22.1-254.01"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 22.1-254.01">§ 22.1-254.01.<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000022#     1#       254.01#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> The requirements of this section shall not apply to (a) any person 16 through 18 years of age who is housed in an adult correctional facility when such person is actively pursuing the achievement of a passing score on a high school equivalency examination approved by the Board of Education but is not enrolled in an individual student alternative education plan pursuant to subsection E, and (b) any child who has obtained a high school diploma or its equivalent, a certificate of completion, or has achieved a passing score on a high school equivalency examination approved by the Board of Education, or who has otherwise complied with compulsory school attendance requirements as set forth in this article.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b"/><heading><desig>B.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A school board shall excuse from attendance at school:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Any pupil who, together with his parents, by reason of bona fide religious training or belief is conscientiously opposed to attendance at school. For purposes of this subdivision, "bona fide religious training or belief" does not include essentially political, sociological or philosophical views or a merely personal moral code; and</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> On the recommendation of the juvenile and domestic relations district court of the county or city in which the pupil resides and for such period of time as the court deems appropriate, any pupil who, together with his parents, is opposed to attendance at a school by reason of concern for such pupil's health, as verified by competent medical evidence, or by reason of such pupil's reasonable apprehension for personal safety when such concern or apprehension in that pupil's specific case is determined by the court, upon consideration of the recommendation of the principal and division superintendent, to be justified.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c"/><heading><desig>C.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Each local school board shall develop policies for excusing students who are absent by reason of observance of a religious holiday. Such policies shall ensure that a student shall not be deprived of any award or of eligibility or opportunity to compete for any award, or of the right to take an alternate test or examination, for any which he missed by reason of such absence, if the absence is verified in a manner acceptable to the school board.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d"/><heading><desig>D.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A school board may excuse from attendance at school:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> On recommendation of the principal and the division superintendent and with the written consent of the parent or guardian, any pupil who the school board determines, in accordance with regulations of the Board of Education, cannot benefit from education at such school; or</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> On recommendation of the juvenile and domestic relations district court of the county or city in which the pupil resides, any pupil who, in the judgment of such court, cannot benefit from education at such school.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_e"/><heading><desig>E.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Local school boards may allow the requirements of subsection A to be met under the following conditions:</p><p>For a student who is at least 16 years of age, there shall be a meeting of the student, the student's parents, and the principal or his designee of the school in which the student is enrolled in which an individual student alternative education plan shall be developed in conformity with guidelines prescribed by the Board, which plan must include:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_e_a"/><heading><desig>a.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Career guidance counseling;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_e_b"/><heading><desig>b.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Mandatory enrollment and attendance in a preparatory program for passing a high school equivalency examination approved by the Board of Education or other alternative education program approved by the local school board with attendance requirements that provide for reporting of student attendance by the chief administrator of such preparatory program or approved alternative education program to such principal or his designee;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_e_c"/><heading><desig>c.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Mandatory enrollment in a program to earn a Board of Education-approved career and technical education credential, such as the successful completion of an industry certification, a state licensure examination, a national occupational competency assessment, or the Virginia workplace readiness skills assessment;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_e_d"/><heading><desig>d.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Successful completion of the course in economics and personal finance required to earn a Board of Education-approved high school diploma;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_e_e"/><heading><desig>e.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Counseling on the economic impact of failing to complete high school; and</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_e_f"/><heading><desig>f.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Procedures for reenrollment to comply with the requirements of subsection A.</p><p><pre/>A student for whom an individual student alternative education plan has been granted pursuant to this subsection and who fails to comply with the conditions of such plan shall be in violation of the compulsory school attendance law, and the division superintendent or attendance officer of the school division in which such student was last enrolled shall seek immediate compliance with the compulsory school attendance law as set forth in this article.</p><p><pre/>Students enrolled with an individual student alternative education plan shall be counted in the average daily membership of the school division.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_f"/><heading><desig>F.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A school board may, in accordance with the procedures set forth in Article 3 (<citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 22.1-276.01"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 22.1-276.01">§ 22.1-276.01<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000022#     1#       276.01#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> et seq.) of Chapter 14 and upon a finding that a school-age child has been (i) charged with an offense relating to the Commonwealth's laws, or with a violation of school board policies, on weapons, alcohol or drugs, or intentional injury to another person; (ii) found guilty or not innocent of a crime that resulted in or could have resulted in injury to others, or of an offense that is required to be disclosed to the superintendent of the school division pursuant to subsection G of § 16.1-260; (iii) suspended pursuant to <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 22.1-277.05"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 22.1-277.05">§ 22.1-277.05<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000022#     1#       277.05#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; or (iv) expelled from school attendance pursuant to <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 22.1-277.06"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 22.1-277.06">§ 22.1-277.06<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000022#     1#       277.06#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> or <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 22.1-277.07"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 22.1-277.07">22.1-277.07<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000022#     1#       277.07#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> or subsection B of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 22.1-277"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 22.1-277">§ 22.1-277<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000022#     1#          277#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, require the child to attend an alternative education program as provided in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 22.1-209.1:2"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 22.1-209.1:2">§ 22.1-209.1:2<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#958#0000000022#0000000001#     209.1#0000000002#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> or <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 22.1-277.2:1"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 22.1-277.2:1">22.1-277.2:1.<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#958#0000000022#0000000001#     277.2#0000000001#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation></p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_g"/><heading><desig>G.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Whenever a court orders any pupil into an alternative education program, including a program preparing students for a high school equivalency examination approved by the Board of Education, offered in the public schools, the local school board of the school division in which the program is offered shall determine the appropriate alternative education placement of the pupil, regardless of whether the pupil attends the public schools it supervises or resides within its school division.</p><p>The juvenile and domestic relations district court of the county or city in which a pupil resides or in which charges are pending against a pupil, or any court in which charges are pending against a pupil, may require the pupil who has been charged with (i) a crime that resulted in or could have resulted in injury to others, (ii) a violation of Article 1 (<citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 18.2-77"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 18.2-77">§ 18.2-77<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000018#     2#           77#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> et seq.) of Chapter 5 of Title 18.2, or (iii) any offense related to possession or distribution of any Schedule I, II, or III controlled substances to attend an alternative education program, including, but not limited to, night school, adult education, or any other education program designed to offer instruction to students for whom the regular program of instruction may be inappropriate.</p><p>This subsection shall not be construed to limit the authority of school boards to expel, suspend, or exclude students, as provided in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 22.1-277.04"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 22.1-277.04">§§ 22.1-277.04<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000022#     1#       277.04#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 22.1-277.05"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 22.1-277.05">22.1-277.05<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000022#     1#       277.05#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 22.1-277.06"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 22.1-277.06">22.1-277.06<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000022#     1#       277.06#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 22.1-277.07"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 22.1-277.07">22.1-277.07<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000022#     1#       277.07#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, and <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 22.1-277.2"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 22.1-277.2">22.1-277.2.<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000022#     1#        277.2#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> As used in this subsection, the term "charged" means that a petition or warrant has been filed or is pending against a pupil.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_h"/><heading><desig>H.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Within one calendar month of the opening of school, each school board shall send to the parents or guardian of each student enrolled in the division a copy of the compulsory school attendance law and the enforcement procedures and policies established by the school board.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_i"/><heading><desig>I.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The provisions of this article shall not apply to:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_i_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Children suffering from contagious or infectious diseases while suffering from such diseases;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_i_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Children whose immunizations against communicable diseases have not been completed as provided in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 22.1-271.2"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 22.1-271.2">§ 22.1-271.2<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000022#     1#        271.2#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_i_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Children under 10 years of age who live more than two miles from a public school unless public transportation is provided within one mile of the place where such children live;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_i_4"/><heading><desig>4.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Children between the ages of 10 and 17, inclusive, who live more than 2.5 miles from a public school unless public transportation is provided within 1.5 miles of the place where such children live; and</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_i_5"/><heading><desig>5.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Children excused pursuant to subsections B and D.</p><p><pre/>Further, any child who will not have reached his sixth birthday on or before September 30 of each school year whose parent or guardian notifies the appropriate school board that he does not wish the child to attend school until the following year because the child, in the opinion of the parent or guardian, is not mentally, physically, or emotionally prepared to attend school, may delay the child's attendance for one year.</p><p><pre/>The distances specified in subdivisions 3 and 4 of this subsection shall be measured or determined from the child's residence to the entrance to the school grounds or to the school bus stop nearest the entrance to the residence of such children by the nearest practical routes which are usable for walking or riding. Disease shall be established by the certificate of a reputable practicing physician in accordance with regulations adopted by the Board of Education.</p></bodyText></level></level><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p>Code 1950, § 22-275.1; 1952, c. 279; 1959, Ex. Sess., c. 72; 1968, c. 178; 1974, c. 199; 1976, cc. 681, 713; 1978, c. 518; 1980, c. 559; 1984, c. 436; <citation normalizedCite="1989 VA CH 515"><content><span normalizedCite="1989 Va. Ch. 515">1989, c. 515<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1989#000515#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1990 VA CH 797"><content><span normalizedCite="1990 Va. Ch. 797">1990, c. 797<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1990#000797#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1991 VA CH 295"><content><span normalizedCite="1991 Va. Ch. 295">1991, c. 295<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1991#000295#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1993 VA CH 903"><content><span normalizedCite="1993 Va. Ch. 903">1993, c. 903<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1993#000903#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1996 VA CH 163"><content><span normalizedCite="1996 Va. Ch. 163">1996, cc. 163<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1996#000163#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1996 VA CH 916"><content><span normalizedCite="1996 Va. Ch. 916">916<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1996#000916#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1996 VA CH 964"><content><span normalizedCite="1996 Va. Ch. 964">964<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1996#000964#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1997 VA CH 828"><content><span normalizedCite="1997 Va. Ch. 828">1997, c. 828<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1997#000828#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1999 VA CH 488"><content><span normalizedCite="1999 Va. Ch. 488">1999, cc. 488<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1999#000488#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1999 VA CH 552"><content><span normalizedCite="1999 Va. Ch. 552">552<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1999#000552#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2000 VA CH 184"><content><span normalizedCite="2000 Va. Ch. 184">2000, c. 184<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2000#000184#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2001 VA CH 688"><content><span normalizedCite="2001 Va. Ch. 688">2001, cc. 688<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2001#000688#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2001 VA CH 820"><content><span normalizedCite="2001 Va. Ch. 820">820<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2001#000820#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2003 VA CH 119"><content><span normalizedCite="2003 Va. Ch. 119">2003, c. 119<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2003#000119#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2004 VA CH 251"><content><span normalizedCite="2004 Va. Ch. 251">2004, c. 251<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2004#000251#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2006 VA CH 335"><content><span normalizedCite="2006 Va. Ch. 335">2006, c. 335<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2006#000335#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2010 VA CH 605"><content><span normalizedCite="2010 Va. Ch. 605">2010, c. 605<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2010#000605#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2012 VA CH 454"><content><span normalizedCite="2012 Va. Ch. 454">2012, cc. 454<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2012#000454#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2012 VA CH 642"><content><span normalizedCite="2012 Va. Ch. 642">642<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2012#000642#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2014 VA CH 84"><content><span normalizedCite="2014 Va. Ch. 84">2014, c. 84<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2014#000084#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PTW0-004G-K54J-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 22.1.</desig><title>EDUCATION</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 14.</desig><title>PUPILS</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="article"><heading><desig>ARTICLE 1.</desig><title>COMPULSORY SCHOOL ATTENDANCE</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Criminal Law &amp; Procedure</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NEU0RkE1OUQwNUQwNDgxODhEODZCMjkzOTg3NThBNzk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MEU1MzkwRjgyRjdENEMyREJEMDZFNDQxNjYzODdBMjk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUI3NjYzN0UxRTI4NEE2MEE2NzlCQTkxRkM1NUEwRDc</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Education Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDkzNUEzQzFBNEZBNEFBREIxNDM5MTc1MUU5QjI4MTY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Adult Education</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RjVCNkRBREVGQTJGNEJGNDg3OURFMzlCQTdCNDAwRUU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QzMyRkUwN0EzNzQ2NENEMUJEMDY4MEYxRjJCNzUxODE</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Alternative Placements</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MTMyMDc5M0RERTE0NDcwMEFGOTk5NERFMTIyMEE1Mjg7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QzBCRkVBRDQ2MUYxNDlGMUFGQzc3N0ZCMDYyMzc5NTA</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Certificates, Degrees &amp; Diplomas</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QTI2MURGN0ZBODNDNEU0ODg1QUNFQzc4MEI5REU2MTQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OTRGMkI4ODIzRjgxNEE2RkE2OEE5MTU0MDdFM0Y5RjI</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Exemptions From Compulsory Education</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QTlDRkRBNDUwNTFFNDA2REIyRDAxNEQxRjEyQjUxNUI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RkY0QjA5RkIyNkQwNDM2OTk2MzJCMEJBNjMxQjQwNjM</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Expulsions</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MTA3NzVDMUY1OERENEQyNzlERDY1RjZFRjc0MDkyMTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QzBCRkVBRDQ2MUYxNDlGMUFGQzc3N0ZCMDYyMzc5NTA</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MTU3QUQyNzg4MkQ5NDU5NkE4OUVCQTZBNUM5Q0EwQkI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RkY0QjA5RkIyNkQwNDM2OTk2MzJCMEJBNjMxQjQwNjM</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OUU0NDI1MjI5N0RGNERFOTkwN0U5RkMyODE0RDAzMkM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6REM1MkZFRUQwMzBBNDk5QjgwQkI0RDBDQzc2MTI0ODc</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Mandatory Attendance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RUJFRjlDQzI1NzNDNEU4NEEwMTNFNDE5NjY3NUIyNDE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RkY0QjA5RkIyNkQwNDM2OTk2MzJCMEJBNjMxQjQwNjM</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Regulation of Homeschooling</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QTZCMzVBQzUyOTgxNDVDMUIxNjRBRTRBODY0Qjg2OUM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QTE0REU4REYxN0I5NDc3OEJDQzkzQjcxODYyRUE0Nzg</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Student Transportation</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6REZEMjUxMkJBNUI0NDExM0FFRkI5RkYwRUUyM0ZGMzM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6ODhDOTBDNkNGQUQwNDUxRTk0M0ZDQ0RBRUNFNjM3ODg</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Suspensions of Students</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NjQ5NzZCQzFDODM0NDJEQThEOEQzNjQyRDJBREUwMTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QzBCRkVBRDQ2MUYxNDlGMUFGQzc3N0ZCMDYyMzc5NTA</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Family Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NEI4M0U5Qzg3RTk0NDdBRUJGNDRGNkZEQkU3RDdFNDU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Education</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RkVBNDQ5QTI0RUE4NDYzOTk3RUYzOERDMTU1Mzg2QjE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RjI4OUQ3QTU3RTRENDdDMTk4MEMyMzlENDFEQzM0MTI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Public Health &amp; Welfare Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDYwRTY1MDg3MTk5NDUyNkFFRDI1RjJBRERGQ0UxNzI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Communicable Diseases</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MEZGMDkyRUNCQzQzNDQ0OEE1N0ExOTE1NUYzRUZFMkQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RDEwNjlEODdCNEMyNEY1MjlCRDNEMDkyMTI3QjlBOUI</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Maternity &amp; Children</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QzM4NjUxNjZFQ0M3NDc2Qzg5NzNCRDA0ODgxNjc2Mzg7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MTlCM0Q3MTlFNUQ0NDA5OTgwQTEwQjE1M0ZGMTlFQjc</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification><classificationGroup classificationScheme="indexing-terms"><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem score="90"><className>Education</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDkzNUEzQzFBNEZBNEFBREIxNDM5MTc1MUU5QjI4MTY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></classificationGroup></metadata></legislativeDoc>