<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#349#000016#     1#        106.1#">Va. Code Ann. § 16.1-106.1</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_16.1-106.1"/><heading><desig>§ 16.1-106.1.</desig><title>Withdrawal of appeal in civil cases</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a"/><heading><desig>A.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A party who has appealed a final judgment or order rendered by a general district court or a juvenile and domestic relations district court in a civil case may seek to withdraw that appeal at any time.</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> If the appeal has not been perfected by posting a required appeal bond or paying required costs, or within 10 days after entry of the judgment or order when no appeal bond or costs are required to perfect the appeal, the appeal may be withdrawn by filing in the district court that entered the judgment or order and serving, in person or by first-class mail, on all parties or their counsel a written notice of intent to withdraw the appeal. When the appeal is withdrawn in the district court, the judgment or order of the district court shall have the same effect as if no appeal had been noted.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> After the appeal is perfected by posting a required appeal bond or paying required costs, or after 10 days have elapsed since the entry of the judgment or order when no appeal bond or costs are required to perfect the appeal, an appealing party may request that the appeal be withdrawn by filing in the circuit court and serving, in person or by first-class mail, on all parties or their counsel a written notice of intent to withdraw the appeal.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b"/><heading><desig>B.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Upon receipt of a notice of intent to withdraw an appeal filed in the circuit court, any party to the appeal, or the circuit court on its own motion, may give notice of a hearing, which shall be scheduled no later than the date set by the circuit court for trial of the appeal. Unless the hearing is scheduled at the time previously set for trial of the appeal, notice of the hearing shall be given, in person or by first-class mail, to all parties or their counsel, any non-party who has posted an appeal bond, and, when appropriate, the Department of Social Services, Division of Child Support Enforcement.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c"/><heading><desig>C.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> At the hearing, the circuit court shall determine whether any party objects to the proposed withdrawal. A party may object to the withdrawal of an appeal by filing in the circuit court and serving, in person or by first-class mail, on all parties or their counsel a written notice of objection to withdrawal of the appeal. If such a written objection is filed and served within a reasonable period after service of the notice of intent to withdraw the appeal, upon a showing of good cause by the party objecting to the withdrawal of the appeal, the circuit court may decline to permit the withdrawal of the appeal. If no such written objection is timely filed, the appeal shall be deemed to be withdrawn and, subject to subsections E and F, the circuit court shall enter an order disposing of the case in accordance with the judgment or order entered in the district court.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d"/><heading><desig>D.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> If a party who has appealed a judgment or order of a district court fails to appear in circuit court either at the time for setting the appeal for trial or on the trial date, the circuit court may, upon the motion of any party, enter an order treating the appeal as withdrawn and disposing of the case in accordance with this section. If no party appears for trial, the court may deem the appeal to be withdrawn without a motion and enter an order disposing of the case in accordance with this section.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_e"/><heading><desig>E.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Upon the withdrawal of an appeal from a general district court, the circuit court shall, upon request of a party who did not appeal the judgment or order, determine whether, as a result of the appeal, a party has a right to additional relief in the circuit court which has accrued since the appeal was noted, including but not limited to attorneys' fees provided for by contract or statute. Subject to any rights of a surety pursuant to <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 16.1-110"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 16.1-110">§ 16.1-110<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000016#     1#          110#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, the circuit court shall also order its clerk to disburse any cash bond posted to perfect the appeal as follows:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_e_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> First, to the clerk of the court to cover taxable costs in the circuit court as provided by statute;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_e_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Second, to the prevailing party in an amount sufficient to satisfy any judgment or order entered in the general district court and any additional relief granted by the circuit court; and</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_e_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Third, the balance, if any, to the person who posted the bond in the general district court.</p><p><pre/>In addition, the circuit court shall enter such order as may be appropriate to conclude all matters arising out of the appeal from the general district court.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_f"/><heading><desig>F.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Upon the withdrawal of an appeal from a juvenile and domestic relations district court, the circuit court shall, upon request of a party who did not appeal the judgment or order, determine whether, as a result of the appeal, a party has a right to additional relief in the circuit court which has accrued since the appeal was noted, including but not limited to attorneys' fees provided for by contract or statute. Subject to any rights of a surety pursuant to <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 16.1-110"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 16.1-110">§ 16.1-110<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000016#     1#          110#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, the circuit court shall also order its clerk to disburse any cash bond posted to perfect the appeal as follows:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_f_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> First, to the clerk of the court to cover taxable costs in the circuit court as provided by statute;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_f_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Second, to the prevailing party in an amount sufficient to satisfy any judgment or order entered in the juvenile and domestic relations district court and any additional relief granted by the circuit court; and</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_f_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Third, the balance, if any, to the person who posted the bond in the juvenile and domestic relations district court.</p><p><pre/>In addition, the circuit court shall enter such order as may be appropriate to conclude all matters arising out of the petition or motion filed in the juvenile and domestic relations district court and the appeal in circuit court, consistent with the judgment or order entered in the juvenile and domestic relations district court, as modified by the grant of any additional relief by the circuit court pursuant to this subsection. Unless the circuit court orders that the case remain in the circuit court, the case shall be remanded to the juvenile and domestic relations district court for purposes of enforcement and future modification and shall be subject to all the requirements of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 16.1-297"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 16.1-297">§ 16.1-297<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000016#     1#          297#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></level></level><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p><citation normalizedCite="2008 VA CH 706"><content><span normalizedCite="2008 Va. Ch. 706">2008, c. 706<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2008#000706#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PVJ0-004G-K14T-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 16.1.</desig><title>COURTS NOT OF RECORD</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 6.</desig><title>VENUE, JURISDICTION AND PROCEDURE IN CIVIL MATTERS</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="article"><heading><desig>ARTICLE 3.</desig><title>PROCEDURE IN CIVIL CASES</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Civil Procedure</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MzUxNjJDMEQ5N0YwNDMzM0JDMjEzM0UzOTYzMzI3OTU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Altering &amp; Amending Judgments</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QUJCQzQzRDVFQjQ1NDhBNEFBQ0FDMDI1MUQwNTYwMzk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RUFDMkE0QkZBRDY0NDU4MEJBN0IzQTFGMjcyOTFFQkI</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NUNCNTk2MkFDQTFGNDE5REJGNTBCRTk5MEFGMDZDNDE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Mjk4NzRCMDI4Q0IyNDc4MEE5ODA0RDc1MDU4RkQ2RjI</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MzU3MTQwOUJCRDEwNEM3RUFGRjYyNDEwNTJEQjVDRTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NkJCNTZBN0Y5OTZFNDI2QzgxMUQ3NzY4MzdBQTgzMkQ</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NjdCQjZCM0M1QzI3NDI2MzhEMzlDQTE4MTI4MERCNkU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NUE4NUFGMzRCNjZFNEI1ODlBRkI1MUFBNUFBNkI4QzY</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Governments</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjdEQjE4OUJDMzQxNDNEMEI0RTI1QUFCMzJENjEwRTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Clerks of Court</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6REVFMjkzRDI1MkU2NERDNjk3OEUxODY0REYwMUI1NjE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NURENzJGNTEyQzM0NEREQUI2RkVCRTM4RTc1RTZBREU</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Time Limitations</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDU5MENDQ0RCNEUyNEZBQjk1MkZGNTZGMzg1RTgyQjI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OUMyNDcyQTZEN0MxNDEzMEI0RDFFOTYwOTFFQjRDNzE</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification><classificationGroup classificationScheme="indexing-terms"><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem score="90"><className>Governments</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjdEQjE4OUJDMzQxNDNEMEI0RTI1QUFCMzJENjEwRTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></classificationGroup></metadata></legislativeDoc>