<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#349#000016#     1#          323#">Va. Code Ann. ยง 16.1-323</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_16.1-323"/><heading><desig>ยง 16.1-323.</desig><title>Governor to execute; form of compact</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><bodyText><p>The Governor of Virginia is hereby authorized and requested to execute, on behalf of the Commonwealth of Virginia, with any other state or states legally joining therein, a compact which shall be in form substantially as follows:</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="article"><anchor id="_i"/><heading><desig>Article I.</desig></heading><bodyText><p>Purpose. </p><p>The compacting states to this Interstate Compact recognize that each state is responsible for the proper supervision or return of juveniles, delinquents, and status offenders who are on probation or parole and who have absconded, escaped or run away from supervision and control and in so doing have endangered their own safety and the safety of others. The compacting states also recognize that each state is responsible for the safe return of juveniles who have run away from home and in doing so have left their state of residence. The compacting states also recognize that Congress by enacting the Crime Control Act, <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="4 USC 112"><content><span normalizedCite="4 U.S.C. 112">4 U.S.C. ยง 112<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1828#123#000004#        112#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> (1965), has authorized and encouraged compacts for cooperative efforts and mutual assistance in the prevention of crime.</p><p>It is the purpose of this compact, through means of joint and cooperative action among the compacting states, to (i) ensure that the adjudicated juveniles and status offenders subject to this compact are provided adequate supervision and services in the receiving state as ordered by the adjudicating judge or parole authority in the sending state; (ii) ensure that the public safety interests of the citizens, including the victims of juvenile offenders, in both the sending and receiving states are adequately protected; (iii) return juveniles who have run away, absconded or escaped from supervision or control or have been accused of an offense to the state requesting their return; (iv) make contracts for the cooperative institutionalization in public facilities in member states for delinquent youth needing special services; (v) provide for the effective tracking and supervision of juveniles; (vi) equitably allocate the costs, benefits and obligations of the compacting states; (vii) establish procedures to manage the movement between states of juvenile offenders released to the community under the jurisdiction of courts, juvenile departments, or any other criminal or juvenile justice agency that has jurisdiction over juvenile offenders; (viii) ensure immediate notice to jurisdictions where defined offenders are authorized to travel or to relocate across state lines; (ix) establish procedures to resolve pending charges (detainers) against juvenile offenders prior to transfer or release to the community under the terms of this compact; (x) establish a system of uniform data collection on information pertaining to juveniles subject to this compact that allows access by authorized juvenile justice and criminal justice officials, and regular reporting of compact activities to heads of state executive, judicial, and legislative branches and juvenile and criminal justice administrators; (xi) monitor compliance with rules governing interstate movement of juveniles and initiate interventions to address and correct noncompliance; (xii) coordinate training and education regarding the regulation of interstate movement of juveniles for officials involved in such activity; and (xiii) coordinate the implementation and operation of the compact with the Interstate Compact on the Placement of Children, the Interstate Compact for Adult Offender Supervision, and other compacts affecting juveniles particularly in those cases where concurrent or overlapping supervision issues arise. It is the policy of the compacting states that the activities conducted by the Interstate Commission created herein are the formation of public policies and therefore are public business. Furthermore, the compacting states shall cooperate and observe their individual and collective duties and responsibilities for the prompt return and acceptance of juveniles subject to the provisions of this compact. The provisions of this compact shall be reasonably and liberally construed to accomplish the purposes and policies of the compact.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="article"><anchor id="_ii"/><heading><desig>Article II.</desig></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><bodyText><p>Definitions. </p><p>As used in this compact, unless the context clearly requires a different construction:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><bodyText><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Bylaws"</emphasis> means those bylaws established by the Interstate Commission for its governance or for directing or controlling its actions or conduct.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Commissioner"</emphasis> means the voting representative of each compacting state appointed pursuant to Article III of this compact.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Compact administrator"</emphasis> means the individual in each compacting state appointed pursuant to the terms of this compact responsible for the administration and management of the state's supervision and transfer of juveniles subject to the terms of this compact, the rules adopted by the Interstate Commission, and policies adopted by the state council under this compact.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Compacting state"</emphasis> means any state that has enacted the enabling legislation for this compact.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Court"</emphasis> means any court having jurisdiction over delinquent, neglected, or dependent children.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Deputy compact administrator"</emphasis> means the individual, if any, in each compacting state appointed to act on behalf of a compact administrator pursuant to the terms of this compact responsible for the administration and management of the state's supervision and transfer of juveniles subject to the terms of this compact, the rules adopted by the Interstate Commission and policies adopted by the state council under this compact.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Interstate Commission"</emphasis> means the Interstate Commission for Juveniles created by Article III of this compact.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><bodyText><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Juvenile"</emphasis> means any person defined as a juvenile in any member state or by the rules of the Interstate Commission, including:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_ii_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Accused delinquent: a person charged with an offense that, if committed by an adult, would be a criminal offense;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_ii_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Accused status offender: a person charged with an offense that would not be a criminal offense if committed by an adult;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_ii_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Adjudicated delinquent: a person found to have committed an offense that, if committed by an adult, would be a criminal offense;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_ii_4"/><heading><desig>4.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Adjudicated status offender: a person found to have committed an offense that would not be a criminal offense if committed by an adult; and</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_ii_5"/><heading><desig>5.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Nonoffender: a person in need of supervision who has not been accused of being or adjudicated a status offender or delinquent.</p><p><pre/><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Noncompacting state"</emphasis> means any state that has not enacted the enabling legislation for this compact.</p><p><pre/><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Probation or parole"</emphasis> means any kind of supervision or conditional release of juveniles authorized under the laws of the compacting states.</p><p><pre/><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Rule"</emphasis> means a written statement by the Interstate Commission promulgated pursuant to Article VI of this compact that is of general applicability, implements, interprets or prescribes a policy or provision of the compact, or an organizational, procedural, or practice requirement of the commission, that has the force and effect of statutory law in a compacting state, and includes the amendment, repeal, or suspension of an existing rule.</p><p><pre/><emphasis typeStyle="it">"State"</emphasis> means a state of the United States, the District of Columbia or its designee, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the U.S.Virgin Islands, Guam, American Samoa, or the Northern Marianas Islands.</p></bodyText></level></level></level><level levelType="article"><anchor id="_iii"/><heading><desig>Article III.</desig></heading><bodyText><p>Interstate Commission for Juveniles. </p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_iii_a"/><heading><desig>A.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The compacting states hereby create the "Interstate Commission for Juveniles." The commission shall be a body corporate and joint agency of the compacting states. The commission shall have all the responsibilities, powers and duties set forth herein and additional powers as may be conferred upon it by subsequent action of the respective legislatures of the compacting states in accordance with the terms of this compact.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_iii_b"/><heading><desig>B.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The Interstate Commission shall consist of commissioners appointed by the appropriate appointing authority in each state pursuant to the rules and requirements of each compacting state and in consultation with the State Council for Interstate Juvenile Supervision created in Article IX. The commissioner shall be the compact administrator, deputy compact administrator, or designee from that state who shall serve on the Interstate Commission in such capacity under or pursuant to the applicable law of the compacting state.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_iii_c"/><heading><desig>C.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> In addition to the commissioners who are the voting representatives of each state, the Interstate Commission shall include individuals who are not commissioners but who are members of interested organizations. Such noncommissioner members shall include a member of the national organizations of governors, legislators, state chief justices, attorneys general, Interstate Compact for Adult Offender Supervision, Interstate Compact on the Placement of Children, juvenile justice and juvenile corrections officials, and crime victims. All noncommissioner members of the Interstate Commission shall be ex officio (nonvoting) members. The Interstate Commission may provide in its bylaws for such additional ex officio (nonvoting) members, including members of other national organizations, in such numbers as shall be determined by the commission.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_iii_d"/><heading><desig>D.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Each compacting state represented at any meeting of the commission is entitled to one vote. A majority of the compacting states shall constitute a quorum for the transaction of business, unless a larger quorum is required by the bylaws of the Interstate Commission.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_iii_e"/><heading><desig>E.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The commission shall meet at least once each calendar year. The chairperson may call additional meetings and, upon the request of a simple majority of the compacting states, shall call additional meetings. Public notice shall be given of all meetings and meetings shall be open to the public.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_iii_f"/><heading><desig>F.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The Interstate Commission shall establish an executive committee, which shall include commission officers, members, and others as determined by the bylaws. The executive committee shall have the power to act on behalf of the Interstate Commission during periods when the Interstate Commission is not in session, with the exception of rulemaking or amendment to the compact. The executive committee shall oversee the day-to-day activities of the administration of the compact managed by an executive director and Interstate Commission staff; administer enforcement and compliance with the provisions of the compact, its bylaws, and rules; and perform other duties as directed by the Interstate Commission or set forth in the bylaws.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_iii_g"/><heading><desig>G.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Each member of the Interstate Commission shall have the right and power to cast a vote to which that compacting state is entitled and to participate in the business and affairs of the Interstate Commission. A member shall vote in person and shall not delegate a vote to another compacting state. However, a commissioner, in consultation with the state council, shall appoint another authorized representative, in the absence of the commissioner from that state, to cast a vote on behalf of the compacting state at a specific meeting. The bylaws may provide for members' participation in meetings by telephone or other means of telecommunication or electronic communication.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_iii_h"/><heading><desig>H.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The Interstate Commission's bylaws shall establish conditions and procedures under which the Interstate Commission shall make its information and official records available to the public for inspection or copying. The Interstate Commission may exempt from disclosure any information or official records to the extent that they would adversely affect personal privacy rights or proprietary interests.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_iii_i"/><heading><desig>I.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Public notice shall be given of all meetings, and all meetings shall be open to the public except as set forth in the rules or as otherwise provided in the compact. The Interstate Commission and any of its committees may close a meeting to the public where it determines by two-thirds vote that an open meeting would be likely to:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_iii_i_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Relate solely to the Interstate Commission's internal personnel practices and procedures;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_iii_i_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Disclose matters specifically exempted from disclosure by statute;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_iii_i_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Disclose trade secrets or commercial or financial information that is privileged or confidential;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_iii_i_4"/><heading><desig>4.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Involve accusing any person of a crime or formally censuring any person;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_iii_i_5"/><heading><desig>5.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Disclose information of a personal nature where disclosure would constitute a clearly unwarranted invasion of personal privacy;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_iii_i_6"/><heading><desig>6.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Disclose investigative records compiled for law-enforcement purposes;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_iii_i_7"/><heading><desig>7.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Disclose information contained in or related to examination, operating, or condition reports prepared by, on behalf of, or for the use of the Interstate Commission with respect to a regulated person or entity for the purpose of regulation or supervision of such person or entity;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_iii_i_8"/><heading><desig>8.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Disclose information the premature disclosure of which would significantly endanger the stability of a regulated person or entity; or</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_iii_i_9"/><heading><desig>9.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Specifically relate to the Interstate Commission's issuance of a subpoena or its participation in a civil action or other legal proceeding.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_iii_j"/><heading><desig>J.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> For every meeting closed pursuant to this provision, the Interstate Commission's legal counsel shall publicly certify that, in the legal counsel's opinion, the meeting may be closed to the public and shall reference each relevant exemptive provision. The Interstate Commission shall keep minutes that shall fully and clearly describe all matters discussed in any meeting and shall provide a full and accurate summary of any actions taken and the reasons therefor, including a description of each of the views expressed on any item and the record of any roll call vote (reflected in the vote of each member on the question). All documents considered in connection with any action shall be identified in the minutes.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_iii_k"/><heading><desig>K.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The Interstate Commission shall collect standardized data concerning the interstate movement of juveniles as directed through its rules that shall specify the data to be collected, the means of collection and data exchange, and reporting requirements. Such methods of data collection, exchange, and reporting shall insofar as is reasonably possible conform to up-to-date technology and coordinate its information functions with the appropriate repository of records.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="article"><anchor id="_iv"/><heading><desig>Article IV.</desig></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><bodyText><p>Powers and Duties of the Interstate Commission. </p><p>The commission shall have the following powers and duties:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_iv_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> To provide for dispute resolution among compacting states;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_iv_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> To promulgate rules to effect the purposes and obligations as enumerated in this compact, which shall have the force and effect of statutory law and shall be binding in the compacting states to the extent and in the manner provided in this compact;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_iv_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> To oversee, supervise, and coordinate the interstate movement of juveniles subject to the terms of this compact and any bylaws adopted and rules promulgated by the Interstate Commission;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_iv_4"/><heading><desig>4.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> To enforce compliance with the compact provisions, the rules promulgated by the Interstate Commission, and the bylaws, using all necessary and proper means, including but not limited to the use of judicial process;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_iv_5"/><heading><desig>5.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> To establish and maintain offices that shall be located within one or more of the compacting states;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_iv_6"/><heading><desig>6.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> To purchase and maintain insurance and bonds;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_iv_7"/><heading><desig>7.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> To borrow, accept, hire, or contract for services of personnel;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_iv_8"/><heading><desig>8.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> To establish and appoint committees and hire staff that it deems necessary for carrying out its functions including but not limited to an executive committee as required by Article III that shall have the power to act on behalf of the Interstate Commission in carrying out its powers and duties hereunder;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_iv_9"/><heading><desig>9.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> To elect or appoint such officers, attorneys, employees, agents, or consultants and to fix their compensation, define their duties and determine their qualifications and to establish the Interstate Commission's personnel policies and programs relating to, inter alia, conflicts of interest, rates of compensation, and qualifications of personnel;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_iv_10"/><heading><desig>10.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> To accept any and all donations and grants of money, equipment, supplies, materials, and services, and to receive, utilize, and dispose of it;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_iv_11"/><heading><desig>11.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> To lease, purchase, accept contributions or donations of, or otherwise to own, hold, improve or use, any property, real, personal, or mixed;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_iv_12"/><heading><desig>12.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> To sell, convey, mortgage, pledge, lease, exchange, abandon, or otherwise dispose of any property, real, personal, or mixed;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_iv_13"/><heading><desig>13.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> To establish a budget and make expenditures and levy dues as provided in Article VIII of this compact;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_iv_14"/><heading><desig>14.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> To sue and be sued;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_iv_15"/><heading><desig>15.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> To adopt a seal and bylaws governing the management and operation of the Interstate Commission;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_iv_16"/><heading><desig>16.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> To perform such functions as may be necessary or appropriate to achieve the purposes of this compact;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_iv_17"/><heading><desig>17.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> To report annually to the legislatures, governors, judiciary, and state councils of the compacting states concerning the activities of the Interstate Commission during the preceding year. Such reports shall also include any recommendations that may have been adopted by the Interstate Commission;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_iv_18"/><heading><desig>18.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> To coordinate education, training, and public awareness regarding the interstate movement of juveniles for officials involved in such activity;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_iv_19"/><heading><desig>19.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> To establish uniform standards of the reporting, collecting, and exchanging of data; and</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_iv_20"/><heading><desig>20.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> To maintain its corporate books and records in accordance with the bylaws.</p></bodyText></level></level></level><level levelType="article"><anchor id="_v"/><heading><desig>Article V.</desig></heading><bodyText><p>Organization and Operation of the Interstate Commission. </p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_v_a"/><heading><desig>A.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Bylaws.</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_v_a_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The Interstate Commission shall, by a majority of the members present and voting, within 12 months after the first Interstate Commission meeting, adopt bylaws to govern its conduct as may be necessary or appropriate to carry out the purposes of the compact, including but not limited to:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_v_a_1_a"/><heading><desig>a.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Establishing the fiscal year of the Interstate Commission;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_v_a_1_b"/><heading><desig>b.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Establishing an executive committee and such other committees as may be necessary;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_v_a_1_c"/><heading><desig>c.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Providing for the establishment of committees governing any general or specific delegation of any authority or function of the Interstate Commission;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_v_a_1_d"/><heading><desig>d.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Providing reasonable procedures for calling and conducting meetings of the Interstate Commission and ensuring reasonable notice of each such meeting;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_v_a_1_e"/><heading><desig>e.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Establishing the titles and responsibilities of the officers of the Interstate Commission;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_v_a_1_f"/><heading><desig>f.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Providing a mechanism for concluding the operations of the Interstate Commission and the return of any surplus funds that may exist upon the termination of the compact after the payment or reserving of all its debts and obligations;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_v_a_1_g"/><heading><desig>g.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Providing start-up rules for initial administration of the compact; and</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_v_a_1_h"/><heading><desig>h.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Establishing standards and procedures for compliance and technical assistance in carrying out the compact.</p></bodyText></level></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_v_b"/><heading><desig>B.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Officers and staff.</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_v_b_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The Interstate Commission shall, by a majority of the members, elect annually from among its members a chairman and a vice-chairman, each of whom shall have such authority and duties as may be specified in the bylaws. The chairman or, in the chairman's absence or disability, the vice-chairman shall preside at all meetings of the Interstate Commission. The officers so elected shall serve without compensation or remuneration from the Interstate Commission; provided that, subject to the availability of budgeted funds, the officers shall be reimbursed for any ordinary and necessary costs and expenses incurred by them in the performance of their duties and responsibilities as officers of the Interstate Commission.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_v_b_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The Interstate Commission shall, through its executive committee, appoint or retain an executive director for such period, upon such terms and conditions, and for such compensation as the Interstate Commission may deem appropriate. The executive director shall serve as secretary to the Interstate Commission but shall not be a member and shall hire and supervise such other staff as may be authorized by the Interstate Commission.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_v_c"/><heading><desig>C.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Qualified immunity, defense and indemnification.</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_v_c_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The commission's executive director and employees shall be immune from suit and liability, either personally or in their official capacity, for any claim for damage to or loss of property or personal injury or other civil liability caused by, arising out of, or relating to any actual or alleged act, error, or omission that occurred or that such person had a reasonable basis for believing occurred within the scope of commission employment, duties, or responsibilities; however, any such person shall not be protected from suit or liability for any damage, loss, injury, or liability caused by the intentional or willful and wanton misconduct of any such person.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_v_c_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The liability of any commissioner or the employee or agent of a commissioner, acting within the scope of such person's employment or duties, for acts, errors, or omissions occurring within such person's state may not exceed the limits of liability set forth under the constitution and laws of that state for state officials, employees, and agents. Nothing in this subdivision shall be construed to protect any such person from suit or liability for any damage, loss, injury, or liability caused by the intentional or willful and wanton misconduct of any such person.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_v_c_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The Interstate Commission shall defend the executive director or the employees or representatives of the Interstate Commission and, subject to the approval of the attorney general of the state represented by any commissioner of a compacting state, shall defend such commissioner or the commissioner's representatives or employees in any civil action seeking to impose liability arising out of any actual or alleged act, error, or omission that occurred within the scope of Interstate Commission employment, duties, or responsibilities or that the defendant had a reasonable basis for believing occurred within the scope of Interstate Commission employment, duties, or responsibilities, provided that the actual or alleged act, error, or omission did not result from intentional or willful and wanton misconduct on the part of such person.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_v_c_4"/><heading><desig>4.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The Interstate Commission shall indemnify and hold the commissioner of a compacting state, the commissioner's representatives or employees, or the Interstate Commission's representatives or employees harmless in the amount of any settlement or judgment obtained against such persons arising out of any actual or alleged act, error, or omission that occurred within the scope of Interstate Commission employment, duties, or responsibilities or that such persons had a reasonable basis for believing occurred within the scope of Interstate Commission employment, duties, or responsibilities, provided that the actual or alleged act, error, or omission did not result from intentional or willful and wanton misconduct on the part of such persons.</p></bodyText></level></level></level><level levelType="article"><anchor id="_vi"/><heading><desig>Article VI.</desig></heading><bodyText><p>Rulemaking Functions of the Interstate Commission. </p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_vi_a"/><heading><desig>A.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The Interstate Commission shall promulgate and publish rules in order to effectively and efficiently achieve the purposes of the compact.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_vi_b"/><heading><desig>B.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Rulemaking shall occur pursuant to the criteria set forth in this article and the bylaws and rules adopted pursuant thereto. Such rulemaking shall substantially conform to the principles of the Model State Administrative Procedure Act, 1981 Act, Uniform Laws Annotated, vol. 15, p. 1 (2000), or such other administrative procedures act, as the Interstate Commission deems appropriate consistent with due process requirements under the U.S. Constitution as now or hereafter interpreted by the U.S. Supreme Court. All rules and amendments shall become binding as of the date specified, as published with the final version of the rule as approved by the commission.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_vi_c"/><heading><desig>C.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> When promulgating a rule, the Interstate Commission shall, at a minimum:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_vi_c_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Publish the proposed rule's entire text, stating the reasons for that proposed rule;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_vi_c_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Allow and invite any and all persons to submit written data, facts, opinions and arguments, which information shall be added to the record and be made publicly available;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_vi_c_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Provide an opportunity for an informal hearing if petitioned by 10 or more persons; and</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_vi_c_4"/><heading><desig>4.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Promulgate a final rule and its effective date, if appropriate, based on input from state or local officials or interested parties.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_vi_d"/><heading><desig>D.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Allow, not later than 60 days after a rule is promulgated, any interested person to file a petition in the United States District Court for the District of Columbia or in the federal district court where the Interstate Commission's principal office is located for judicial review of such rule. If the court finds that the Interstate Commission's action is not supported by substantial evidence in the rulemaking record, the court shall hold the rule unlawful and set it aside. For purposes of this subsection, evidence is substantial if it would be considered substantial evidence under the Model State Administrative Procedure Act.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_vi_e"/><heading><desig>E.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> If a majority of the legislatures of the compacting states rejects a rule, those states may, by enactment of a statute or resolution in the same manner used to adopt the compact, cause that such rule shall have no further force and effect in any compacting state.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_vi_f"/><heading><desig>F.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The existing rules governing the operation of the Interstate Compact on Juveniles superseded by this act shall be null and void 12 months after the first meeting of the Interstate Commission created hereunder.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_vi_g"/><heading><desig>G.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Upon determination by the Interstate Commission that a state of emergency exists, it may promulgate an emergency rule that shall become effective immediately upon adoption, provided that the usual rulemaking procedures provided hereunder shall be retroactively applied to the rule as soon as reasonably possible, but no later than 90 days after the effective date of the emergency rule.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="article"><anchor id="_vii"/><heading><desig>Article VII.</desig></heading><bodyText><p>Oversight, Enforcement and Dispute Resolution by the Interstate Commission. </p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_vii_a"/><heading><desig>A.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Oversight.</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_vii_a_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The Interstate Commission shall oversee the administration and operations of the interstate movement of juveniles subject to this compact in the compacting states and shall monitor such activities being administered in noncompacting states that might significantly affect compacting states.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_vii_a_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The courts and executive agencies in each compacting state shall enforce this compact and shall take all actions necessary and appropriate to effectuate the compact's purposes and intent. The provisions of this compact and the rules promulgated hereunder shall be received by all the judges, public officers, commissions, and departments of the state government as evidence of the authorized statute and administrative rules. All courts shall take judicial notice of the compact and the rules. In any judicial or administrative proceeding in a compacting state pertaining to the subject matter of this compact that may affect the powers, responsibilities or actions of the Interstate Commission, it shall be entitled to receive all service of process in any such proceeding and shall have standing to intervene in the proceeding for all purposes.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_vii_b"/><heading><desig>B.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Dispute resolution.</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_vii_b_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The compacting states shall report to the Interstate Commission on all issues and activities necessary for the administration of the compact as well as issues and activities pertaining to compliance with the provisions of the compact and its bylaws and rules.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_vii_b_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The Interstate Commission shall attempt, upon the request of a compacting state, to resolve any disputes or other issues that are subject to the compact and that may arise among compacting states and between compacting and noncompacting states. The commission shall promulgate a rule providing for both mediation and binding dispute resolution for disputes among the compacting states.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_vii_b_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The Interstate Commission, in the reasonable exercise of its discretion, shall enforce the provisions and rules of this compact using any means set forth in Article XI of this compact.</p></bodyText></level></level></level><level levelType="article"><anchor id="_viii"/><heading><desig>Article VIII.</desig></heading><bodyText><p>Finance. </p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_viii_a"/><heading><desig>A.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The Interstate Commission shall pay or provide for the payment of the reasonable expenses of its establishment, organization, and ongoing activities.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_viii_b"/><heading><desig>B.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The Interstate Commission shall levy on and collect an annual assessment from each compacting state to cover the cost of the internal operations and activities of the Interstate Commission and its staff that shall be in a total amount sufficient to cover the Interstate Commission's annual budget as approved each year. The aggregate annual assessment amount shall be allocated based upon a formula to be determined by the Interstate Commission, taking into consideration the population of each compacting state and the volume of interstate movement of juveniles in each compacting state and shall promulgate a rule binding upon all compacting states that governs said assessment.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_viii_c"/><heading><desig>C.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The Interstate Commission shall not incur any obligations of any kind prior to securing the funds adequate to meet them; nor shall the Interstate Commission pledge the credit of any of the compacting states, except by and with the authority of the compacting state.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_viii_d"/><heading><desig>D.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The Interstate Commission shall keep accurate accounts of all receipts and disbursements. The receipts and disbursements of the Interstate Commission shall be subject to the audit and accounting procedures established under its bylaws. However, all receipts and disbursements of funds handled by the Interstate Commission shall be audited yearly by a certified or licensed public accountant, and the report of the audit shall be included in and become part of the annual report of the Interstate Commission.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="article"><anchor id="_ix"/><heading><desig>Article IX.</desig></heading><bodyText><p>The State Council. </p><p>Each member state shall create a State Council for Interstate Juvenile Supervision. While each state may determine the membership of its own state council, its membership shall include at least one representative from the legislative, judicial, and executive branches of government, victims groups, and the compact administrator, deputy compact administrator, or designee. Each compacting state retains the right to determine the qualifications of the compact administrator or deputy compact administrator. Each state council will advise and may exercise oversight and advocacy concerning that state's participation in Interstate Commission activities and other duties as may be determined by that state, including but not limited to development of policy concerning operations and procedures of the compact within that state.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="article"><anchor id="_x"/><heading><desig>Article X.</desig></heading><bodyText><p>Compacting States, Effective Date and Amendment. </p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_x_a"/><heading><desig>A.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Any state, the District of Columbia or its designee, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the U.S.Virgin Islands, Guam, American Samoa, and the Northern Marianas Islands are eligible to become a compacting state.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_x_b"/><heading><desig>B.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The compact shall become effective and binding upon legislative enactment of the compact into law by no less than 35 of the states. The initial effective date shall be the later of July 1, 2004, or upon enactment of the compact into law by the 35th jurisdiction. Thereafter it shall become effective and binding as to any other compacting state upon enactment of the compact into law by that state. The governors of nonmember states or their designees shall be invited to participate in the activities of the Interstate Commission on a nonvoting basis prior to adoption of the compact by all states and territories of the United States.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_x_c"/><heading><desig>C.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The Interstate Commission may propose amendments to the compact for enactment by the compacting states. No amendment shall become effective and binding upon the Interstate Commission and the compacting states unless and until it is enacted into law by unanimous consent of the compacting states.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="article"><anchor id="_xi"/><heading><desig>Article XI.</desig></heading><bodyText><p>Withdrawal, Default, Termination, and Judicial Enforcement. </p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_xi_a"/><heading><desig>A.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Withdrawal.</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_xi_a_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Once effective, the compact shall continue in force and remain binding upon each compacting state; provided that a compacting state may withdraw from the compact by specifically repealing the statute that enacted the compact into law.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_xi_a_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The effective date of withdrawal is the effective date of the repeal.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_xi_a_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The withdrawing state shall immediately notify the chairman of the Interstate Commission in writing upon the introduction of legislation repealing this compact in the withdrawing state. The Interstate Commission shall notify the other compacting states of the withdrawing state's intent to withdraw within 60 days of its receipt thereof.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_xi_a_4"/><heading><desig>4.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The withdrawing state is responsible for all assessments, obligations, and liabilities incurred through the effective date of withdrawal, including any obligations the performance of which extends beyond the effective date of withdrawal.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_xi_a_5"/><heading><desig>5.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Reinstatement following withdrawal of any compacting state shall occur upon the withdrawing state's reenacting the compact or upon such later date as determined by the Interstate Commission.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_xi_b"/><heading><desig>B.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Technical assistance, fines, suspension, termination, and default.</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_xi_b_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> If the Interstate Commission determines that any compacting state has at any time defaulted in the performance of any of its obligations or responsibilities under this compact, the bylaws, or duly promulgated rules, the Interstate Commission may impose any or all of the following penalties:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_xi_b_1_a"/><heading><desig>a.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Remedial training and technical assistance as directed by the Interstate Commission;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_xi_b_1_b"/><heading><desig>b.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Alternative dispute resolution;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_xi_b_1_c"/><heading><desig>c.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Fines, fees, and costs in such amounts as are deemed to be reasonable as fixed by the Interstate Commission; and</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_xi_b_1_d"/><heading><desig>d.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Suspension or termination of membership in the compact, which shall be imposed only after all other reasonable means of securing compliance under the bylaws and rules have been exhausted and the Interstate Commission has therefore determined that the offending state is in default. Immediate notice of suspension shall be given by the Interstate Commission to the governor, the chief justice or the chief judicial officer of the state, the majority and minority leaders of the defaulting state's legislature, and the state council. The grounds for default include but are not limited to failure of a compacting state to perform such obligations or responsibilities imposed upon it by this compact, the bylaws, or duly promulgated rules and any other grounds designated in commission bylaws and rules. The Interstate Commission shall immediately notify the defaulting state in writing of the penalty imposed by the Interstate Commission and of the default pending a cure of the default. The commission shall stipulate the conditions and the time period within which the defaulting state shall cure its default. If the defaulting state fails to cure the default within the time period specified by the commission, the defaulting state shall be terminated from the compact upon an affirmative vote of a majority of the compacting states and all rights, privileges, and benefits conferred by this compact shall be terminated from the effective date of termination.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_xi_b_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Within 60 days of the effective date of the termination of a defaulting state, the commission shall notify the governor, the chief justice or chief judicial officer, the majority and minority leaders of the defaulting state's legislature, and the state council.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_xi_b_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The defaulting state is responsible for all assessments, obligations, and liabilities incurred through the effective date of termination, including any obligations the performance of which extends beyond the effective date of termination.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_xi_b_4"/><heading><desig>4.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The Interstate Commission shall not bear any costs relating to the defaulting state unless otherwise mutually agreed upon in writing between the Interstate Commission and the defaulting state.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_xi_b_5"/><heading><desig>5.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Reinstatement following termination of any compacting state requires both a reenactment of the compact by the defaulting state and the approval of the Interstate Commission pursuant to the rules.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_xi_c"/><heading><desig>C.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Judicial enforcement.</p><p>The Interstate Commission may, by majority vote of the members, initiate legal action in the United States District Court for the District of Columbia or, at the discretion of the Interstate Commission, in the federal district where the Interstate Commission has its offices, to enforce compliance with the provisions of the compact, its duly promulgated rules, and bylaws, against any compacting state in default. In the event that judicial enforcement is necessary, the prevailing party shall be awarded all costs of such litigation, including reasonable attorney fees.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_xi_d"/><heading><desig>D.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Dissolution of compact.</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_xi_d_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The compact dissolves effective upon the date of the withdrawal or default of the compacting state that reduces membership in the compact to one compacting state.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_xi_d_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Upon the dissolution of this compact, the compact becomes null and void and shall be of no further force or effect, and the business and affairs of the Interstate Commission shall be concluded and any surplus funds shall be distributed in accordance with the bylaws.</p></bodyText></level></level></level><level levelType="article"><anchor id="_xii"/><heading><desig>Article XII.</desig></heading><bodyText><p>Severability and Construction. </p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_xii_a"/><heading><desig>A.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The provisions of this compact shall be severable, and if any phrase, clause, sentence, or provision is deemed unenforceable, the remaining provisions of the compact shall be enforceable.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_xii_b"/><heading><desig>B.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The provisions of this compact shall be liberally construed to effectuate its purposes.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="article"><anchor id="_xiii"/><heading><desig>Article XIII.</desig></heading><bodyText><p>Binding Effect of Compact and Other Laws. </p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_xiii_a"/><heading><desig>A.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Other laws.</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_xiii_a_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Nothing herein prevents the enforcement of any other law of a compacting state that is not inconsistent with this compact.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_xiii_a_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> All compacting states' laws other than state constitutions and other interstate compacts conflicting with this compact are superseded to the extent of the conflict.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_xiii_b"/><heading><desig>B.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Binding effect of the compact.</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_xiii_b_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> All lawful actions of the Interstate Commission, including all rules and bylaws promulgated by the Interstate Commission, are binding upon the compacting states.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_xiii_b_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> All agreements between the Interstate Commission and the compacting states are binding in accordance with their terms.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_xiii_b_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> When there is a conflict over meaning or interpretation of Interstate Commission, the Interstate Commission may issue advisory opinions regarding such meaning or interpretation upon the request of a party to the conflict and upon a majority vote of the compacting states.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_xiii_b_4"/><heading><desig>4.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> In the event that any provision of this compact exceeds the constitutional limits imposed on the legislature of any compacting state, the obligations, duties, powers, or jurisdiction sought to be conferred by such provision upon the Interstate Commission shall be ineffective, and such obligations, duties, powers, or jurisdiction shall remain in the compacting state and shall be exercised by the agency thereof to which such obligations, duties, powers, or jurisdiction are delegated by law in effect at the time this compact becomes effective.</p></bodyText></level></level></level><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p>Code 1950, ยง 16.1-213.1; 1977, c. 559; <citation normalizedCite="2007 VA CH 277"><content><span normalizedCite="2007 Va. Ch. 277">2007, cc. 277<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2007#000277#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2007 VA CH 387"><content><span normalizedCite="2007 Va. Ch. 387">387<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2007#000387#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PVJ0-004G-K0S0-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright ยฉ 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 16.1.</desig><title>COURTS NOT OF RECORD</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 11.</desig><title>JUVENILE AND DOMESTIC RELATIONS DISTRICT COURTS</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="article"><heading><desig>ARTICLE 14.</desig><title>INTERSTATE COMPACT RELATING TO JUVENILES</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Administrative Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NjMxMjc0MUIzQjkzNEM4MEI4NkZGQjVCREJCRDk4OUM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Binding Effect</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MzBBRTY4MDFBOTk2NEFFNDkwNzhEMkJGQjYxNEFGRTU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RDk0RkJCOUQ5NEFCNDE2N0EzRUE0QzU2RUFBOEEzRTI</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NEU2MUI0N0NCM0RDNDNDM0JBRDFFQzRDRDhGNkQwRjE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QkRFNDkwODkxNDVGNDI1NDg0RUU3RjREMTgwNEJEQzA</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Formation</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RTUxRjA3MUFGOUFFNEE3MUE5NENGNTc2MjhEMDBGNjM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QTNCQUY4MUFBQzI2NEY1QzhENjQzNDZDRjRERTcwNDQ</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjA4OEVGODBENzY4NDcxM0IyQzA1OTEwQzVDODRBOUE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Compensatory Damages</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OUVBNkFCODVBRjM2NDk3QTlFQkVEMzBGMzEyRkJFOTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDc2NDFDODAyNkI4NEM5NEFDOUM1MEYzNzdCMkM3ODE</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Formation</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RTUxRjA3MUFGOUFFNEE3MUE5NENGNTc2MjhEMDBGNjM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QTNCQUY4MUFBQzI2NEY1QzhENjQzNDZDRjRERTcwNDQ</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Member Duties &amp; Liabilities</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RjNFRjI0NzlCRkM0NDI3ODk2RUNCQkE0M0E3RUQzMkY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QTNCQUY4MUFBQzI2NEY1QzhENjQzNDZDRjRERTcwNDQ</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Constitutional Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QkI5QzFFRjAxMEFFNDMxOThENUE1RjVCQUYzQkQ2RjQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Personal Information</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NkE0QzE1MzlFODJCNDkwQzlDNDVENEQ2NjM3MzQ0RDg7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6REEwQTU4Q0U1MEUzNENFMDkwMDY3QjIwMjgzODEwNTQ</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Contracts Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QzY0RTZFMzE0RjkwNDdFQUI5M0U5N0ZFMjYyREMyQzU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QTdGQUE3QkZDMDlBNDQ1MTkzRjEzMEQ1OEUwNzdDOTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NjZEOEU3MEJBRUQ2NDNFNzhFRjAxRTk1OEU1QjY2QTc</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Criminal Law &amp; Procedure</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NEU0RkE1OUQwNUQwNDgxODhEODZCMjkzOTg3NThBNzk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Delinquency</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6M0Q3Qzc3MkE2OTRGNDdDMTgyNjI5OUNCNzMwMjBCRjI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RkQ2MkRCMUMxMjAzNEMxMUI2MDE3RTQ4NzY2QUFCQjU</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Mjk5MEU5MDg5QjBFNEFBMjg2QkE5RjMyMERFQzVDNkE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RkQ2MkRCMUMxMjAzNEMxMUI2MDE3RTQ4NzY2QUFCQjU</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Parole</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MzU2NUJBMjkzQjE0NEE0OTg3MDQ1QzFDRTI2NUJCRTU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QTFGRjg4NjA3RTg1NDA2RkIzMDk4QzdGREIyQzVGMDk</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Status Offenses</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QTE0NzM2MkMwNkRFNDIwQzgwQzc2NEE1QUQwRjQ1ODY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RkQ2MkRCMUMxMjAzNEMxMUI2MDE3RTQ4NzY2QUFCQjU</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Evidence</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUVGQkU0QjJFMTIzNDNBM0FCNTVEQjAxQTM3RDcwOTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Elements</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjlFNDE5QTgzMzYzNDIwQkE5MEYxNDcyNjgwRUI0ODE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QUFBMEM5OUVCQTVENDYxRTk4RTFFQTcxMzBGOTlBQTQ</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Exceptions</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDIyNEZFREI5NDY1NDYzNkIyMkFFNzhDQTk0QjE2MkQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QUFBMEM5OUVCQTVENDYxRTk4RTFFQTcxMzBGOTlBQTQ</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6M0MzNjE5MkM3MjczNEM2RDlCMURBNTZGMENCQjMzNkY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QUFBMEM5OUVCQTVENDYxRTk4RTFFQTcxMzBGOTlBQTQ</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Scope</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6N0IzMzUxNEM0QzlFNDhFNkEwOEMxODk5QTRCNEQ1MDI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QUFBMEM5OUVCQTVENDYxRTk4RTFFQTcxMzBGOTlBQTQ</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Family Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NEI4M0U5Qzg3RTk0NDdBRUJGNDRGNkZEQkU3RDdFNDU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Delinquency Proceedings</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RTE4NjRFQzE4QTRGNEQzQzk1MTE0MTY4NzU5N0Q5RDM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QUJCOTZBNkIyQjFFNDI2MDlGN0I2M0I4ODA5NzE5OTk</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NkQzNDVBNDkwRkM2NDY2RkFEOUI2MzZENjREMkRCODg7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QUJCOTZBNkIyQjFFNDI2MDlGN0I2M0I4ODA5NzE5OTk</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Interstate Adoptions</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RjY4QThGQTA1MDQxNENFM0E0NEM5NERCMUQyMEVCNjg7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NkQzREUxNDFCODczNDBENEEyREQwN0Y2OTM3OTU2REM</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Governments</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjdEQjE4OUJDMzQxNDNEMEI0RTI1QUFCMzJENjEwRTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Boundaries</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Qzg0MTI1ODBDMUY1NDUzN0JGRUQwMTYwQTlCMzAzRkE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QURCRDNBRjBGRTE0NEFBRUEzNUU1MzFGQjg3MTM4MDI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Labor &amp; Employment Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MTE3QUQwOTA0MUYzNDlCMEFFMjUwRUNDM0RDRkM5QzM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Public Employees</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NjgzOEU4NTUwMTZFNDgzODkyNTQyOTA4QzlGQjI3Mjc7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RTVEMkI2QkRBRDIwNDRGMkIyNDI4QUYzQUQyNTFFOTI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Torts</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDAwOEM2NTEzQkVDNEI4NzlGMEZERUEyRjQwODM4Njg7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Qualified Immunity</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6N0MyNEU3RTY5MURGNDNEQzhCNUU5NzlEMDIyOTkyMDY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OEE2Njc0MkM4NDAwNDg5QjgwOEVFNUIwNjQ4MjIwRUE</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification><classificationGroup classificationScheme="indexing-terms"><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem score="90"><className>Governments</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjdEQjE4OUJDMzQxNDNEMEI0RTI1QUFCMzJENjEwRTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></classificationGroup></metadata></legislativeDoc>