<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#349#000054#     1#         3937#">Va. Code Ann. § 54.1-3937</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_54.1-3937"/><heading><desig>§ 54.1-3937.</desig><title>Procedure for revocation of certificate of registration of professional law corporations or professional limited liability companies</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a"/><heading><desig>A.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> If the Supreme Court, the Court of Appeals or any circuit court of this Commonwealth observes, or if a complaint, verified by affidavit, is made by any person to a circuit court having jurisdiction where the alleged violation occurred, that any law corporation or professional limited liability company has willfully failed to comply with the applicable ethical standards of the Virginia Code of Professional Responsibility or the applicable statutes governing professional corporations or professional limited liability companies, such court may issue a rule against such law corporation or law professional limited liability company to show cause why its certificate of registration should not be revoked. If the complaint, verified by affidavit, is made by the Bar Counsel or a district committee of the Virginia State Bar, the court shall issue a rule against the law corporation or law professional limited liability company to show cause why its certificate of registration should not be revoked.  However, such rule shall not issue if the violation is (i) that of one or several persons only and the interest of justice and the protection of the public can be fairly served by appropriate disciplinary proceedings against the individuals involved, or (ii) that the law corporation does not have a valid certificate of registration.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b"/><heading><desig>B.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> If the rule is issued by the Supreme Court, the rule shall be returnable to the Circuit Court of the City of Richmond. At the time the rule is issued, the Chief Justice of the Supreme Court shall designate three circuit court judges to hear and decide the case.</p><p>If the rule is issued by a circuit court or the Court of Appeals, it shall thereupon certify the fact of such issuance to the Chief Justice of the Supreme Court. The Chief Justice shall designate three circuit court judges of circuits other than the circuit in which the case is pending to hear and decide the case.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c"/><heading><desig>C.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Bar Counsel of the Virginia State Bar shall prosecute the case. Special counsel may be appointed to prosecute the case pursuant to <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 2.2-510"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 2.2-510">§ 2.2-510<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000002#     2#          510#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d"/><heading><desig>D.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> If, after notice and opportunity to be heard, the law corporation or law professional limited liability company is found guilty by the court of a willful failure to comply with the applicable ethical standards in the Virginia Code of Professional Responsibility or the applicable statutes governing professional corporations or professional limited liability companies, the court may (i) reprimand the professional corporation or professional limited liability company, (ii) put it on terms to comply with the applicable law or ethical standards within a reasonable time upon condition that failure to comply shall constitute grounds for suspension or revocation of the certificate of registration or for other disciplinary action, or (iii) suspend or revoke the certificate of registration. If the violation is such that it can be corrected upon notice to the law corporation or law professional limited liability company and it is corrected to the satisfaction of the court, or if the violation is that of one or several persons only, the certificate of registration shall not be suspended or revoked if the interest of justice and the protection of the public can be fairly served by applicable disciplinary proceedings against the individuals involved.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_e"/><heading><desig>E.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The law corporation or professional limited liability company may, as of right, appeal from the judgment of the court to the Supreme Court by petition based upon a true transcript of the record, which shall be made up and certified as in actions at law. In all cases where a professional corporation's or professional limited liability company's certificate of registration has been revoked or suspended by the court, such revocation or suspension shall be suspended pending appeal.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_f"/><heading><desig>F.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> In any proceedings under this section the defendant shall be entitled to a full and fair hearing and representation by counsel.</p></bodyText></level><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p>1974, c. 674, § 54-74.1; 1980, c. 289; 1984, c. 703; 1988, c. 765; <citation normalizedCite="1992 VA CH 574"><content><span normalizedCite="1992 Va. Ch. 574">1992, c. 574<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1992#000574#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PTB0-004G-K2H5-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 54.1.</desig><title>PROFESSIONS AND OCCUPATIONS</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="subtitle"><heading><desig>SUBTITLE IV.</desig><title>PROFESSIONS REGULATED BY THE SUPREME COURT</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 39.</desig><title>ATTORNEYS</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="article"><heading><desig>ARTICLE 6.</desig><title>REVOCATION OR SUSPENSION OF LICENSES; DISBARMENT PROCEEDINGS</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Professional Associations &amp; Corporations</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDNFNEY0MDRGOEI1NEQ0M0FENEFERDEzOEM0N0E2QjE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjA4OEVGODBENzY4NDcxM0IyQzA1OTEwQzVDODRBOUE</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjA4OEVGODBENzY4NDcxM0IyQzA1OTEwQzVDODRBOUE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NUUwRjE5Nzk1QUU0NEZGQTgxNjExMzg4QjMxQTYwMzI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NUFDMUUyMjFERDQ1NDg3NTg1NzVCNzQyMTU5QzlBODI</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Professional Associations &amp; Corporations</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDNFNEY0MDRGOEI1NEQ0M0FENEFERDEzOEM0N0E2QjE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjA4OEVGODBENzY4NDcxM0IyQzA1OTEwQzVDODRBOUE</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Legal Ethics</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NUNFOUIxOEI1QzlBNDc2NkFFNTM0QjBGMEJGOTQ5OEI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Disbarments</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDFFQTQ3OTBDNTFENEQ0OThERjRCNkNCRTMzODk2OEU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6ODU0RjVEOEZGQTAxNDBBN0EwQ0JGQkJBOUEzNkYxOTc</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Suspensions</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MTFGQjc3RURBOUVFNDFBMzgyQjMxMUQ3OTA1RDUyNEM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6ODU0RjVEOEZGQTAxNDBBN0EwQ0JGQkJBOUEzNkYxOTc</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification><classificationGroup classificationScheme="indexing-terms"><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem score="90"><className>Businesses &amp; Corporations</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjA4OEVGODBENzY4NDcxM0IyQzA1OTEwQzVDODRBOUE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem score="90"><className>Legal Ethics</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NUNFOUIxOEI1QzlBNDc2NkFFNTM0QjBGMEJGOTQ5OEI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></classificationGroup></metadata></legislativeDoc>