<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#349#000015#     2#      1636.14#">Va. Code Ann. § 15.2-1636.14</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_15.2-1636.14"/><heading><desig>§ 15.2-1636.14.</desig><title>Proportion borne by Commonwealth and by localities</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a"/><heading><desig>A.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The salaries, expenses and other allowances of attorneys for the Commonwealth in counties and cities as fixed and determined by the Compensation Board shall be paid by the Commonwealth after July 1, 1980.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b"/><heading><desig>B.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The salaries, expenses and other allowances of treasurers and commissioners, or any officers, whether elected or appointed, who hold the combined office of county or city treasurer and commissioner of the revenue in the counties and cities shall be paid in the proportion of one-half by the respective counties and cities and one-half by the Commonwealth, except as hereafter in this section provided.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c"/><heading><desig>C.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The salary, expenses and other allowances of any city treasurer who neither collects nor disburses local taxes or revenues shall be paid entirely by the Commonwealth and the salary, expenses and other allowances of any city treasurer who disburses local revenues but does not collect the same shall be paid in the proportion of one-third by the city and two-thirds by the Commonwealth.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d"/><heading><desig>D.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> In no event shall the amount paid by each city and county as its share of the salary of its respective treasurer and commissioner in any fiscal year exceed the actual dollar amount paid by such city and county for such salaries during the fiscal year ending June 30, 1980.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_e"/><heading><desig>E.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> In the case of each county and city treasurer except a city treasurer who neither collects nor disburses local taxes or revenues, and in the case of each county and city commissioner of the revenue, the cost of such office furniture, office equipment and office appliances as may be specifically authorized by and included in the then current expense allowance made to such officer under the provisions of this article, shall be paid in the proportion of two-thirds by the county or city and one-third by the Commonwealth. The prices paid for such office furniture, office equipment and office appliances shall not be in excess of the prices available to the Commonwealth if such purchases were made through the Department of General Services' Division of Purchases and Supply. The words "office furniture, office equipment and office appliances," as used in this subsection, mean such items of this character as have a useful life of more than one year; and the word "cost," as used in this subsection, may include a rental cost, in the discretion of the Compensation Board, in any case in which, in the opinion of the Board, such rental cost, in whole or in part, is properly includible in the expense allowance.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_f"/><heading><desig>F.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> If any county or city commissioner of the revenue or county or city treasurer uses any forms, sheets or books of any kind for the assessment or collection of state or local taxes or levies, or in connection with the assessment or collection of such taxes or levies, in lieu of the standard forms, sheets or books furnished by the Commonwealth, no part of the cost of such forms, sheets or books shall be paid by the Commonwealth, but their entire cost shall be paid out of the treasury of the county or city whose governing body required, authorized or consented to their use. This subsection shall not be construed as enlarging the existing powers of local governing bodies to require, authorize or consent to the use of such forms, sheets or books.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_g"/><heading><desig>G.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The cost of all forms, sheets and books of all kinds used for the assessment or collection of local license and local excise taxes or used in connection with the assessment or collection of local license and local excise taxes, shall be paid entirely out of the local treasury, including the cost of any tags, stamps, stickers, or other devices intended to evidence the payment of any such local license or local excise taxes.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_h"/><heading><desig>H.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The cost of all forms, sheets and books of all kinds used in the ascertainment, billing or collection of charges for utility or other special services rendered by a county or city, or by any district or agency thereof shall be paid entirely by the locality, although it may be the duty of the treasurer or the commissioner of the revenue to ascertain or collect such charges under applicable provisions of law.</p><p>The governing body of each county and city shall provide suitable office space for the treasurer and commissioner of the revenue, together with the necessary heat, light, water and janitorial service. The entire cost of providing such office space, heat, light, water and janitorial service shall be paid out of the local treasury.</p><p>The provisions of this section, as amended, shall not affect any county operating under an optional form of organization and government as provided by Chapter 3 (<citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 15.2-300"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 15.2-300">§ 15.2-300<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000015#     2#          300#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> et seq.) of this title.</p></bodyText></level><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p>Code 1950, § 14-77; 1954, c. 652; 1964, c. 386, § 14.1-64; 1972, c. 731; 1977, c. 623; 1979, c. 83; 1980, c. 588; <citation normalizedCite="1998 VA CH 872"><content><span normalizedCite="1998 Va. Ch. 872">1998, c. 872<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1998#000872#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PV30-004G-K2YM-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 15.2.</desig><title>COUNTIES, CITIES AND TOWNS</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="subtitle"><heading><desig>SUBTITLE II.</desig><title>POWERS OF LOCAL GOVERNMENT</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 16.</desig><title>LOCAL CONSTITUTIONAL OFFICERS, COURTHOUSES AND SUPPLIES</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="article"><heading><desig>ARTICLE 6.1.</desig><title>COMPENSATION BOARD GENERALLY.</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Governments</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjdEQjE4OUJDMzQxNDNEMEI0RTI1QUFCMzJENjEwRTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Administrative Boards</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QTYwRUFCMDc5MzQ5NDEyREFEQkU2NkE2MjRGQTlCNzY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Njg1MkM3RkYyNzIxNEVFRkJFMTI2NUM4NUU1ODdEM0Q</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Duties &amp; Powers</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Njk1NTNGMzM0RTc3NDcyMUI4MENCQUQ1RDhEN0M1RUM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Njg1MkM3RkYyNzIxNEVFRkJFMTI2NUM4NUU1ODdEM0Q</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Finance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjMzOTBBRTg2MUVDNDdDNUE1M0QxNDk1RERCNjNCN0I7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Njg1MkM3RkYyNzIxNEVFRkJFMTI2NUM4NUU1ODdEM0Q</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6ODVDMjQ1RDhGQjAzNDBBMUFFQ0E2Mzk5MTg3REQ0NTM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Njg1MkM3RkYyNzIxNEVFRkJFMTI2NUM4NUU1ODdEM0Q</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Licenses</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QUQzRDFDRDE0OTA0NDU2OEIwMUZCNDZEQTBBODdCODA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Njg1MkM3RkYyNzIxNEVFRkJFMTI2NUM4NUU1ODdEM0Q</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Tax Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OTNEM0E2OEE0RkQyNEY1MDhBQzdGMkQ4ODI4QTJDODE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Collection of Taxes</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RTg5OTkxQ0U0RjIwNEY4Qjg2MkQ1OTZCRTM2RDY4MTM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjkxRkVDMkNDMjBGNDdFMkI1RDQ3Nzk4QjgwOTBGQjU</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDQyRUI1MjgzQThENEZGRThFQzlCMjFBRkJGM0RDNzE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDE4M0NFRUE4OEM2NEI0NEExOTUzMTRFQUU5NzA4MDU</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QzQzNERBRTAxRDI0NDg4OUI1NzY1RjU4Q0IzRDVDODc7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjkxRkVDMkNDMjBGNDdFMkI1RDQ3Nzk4QjgwOTBGQjU</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification><classificationGroup classificationScheme="indexing-terms"><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem score="90"><className>Governments</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjdEQjE4OUJDMzQxNDNEMEI0RTI1QUFCMzJENjEwRTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></classificationGroup></metadata></legislativeDoc>