<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#123#000056#        61#">Va. Code Ann. § 56-61</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_56-61"/><heading><desig>§ 56-61.</desig><title>Action of Commission on such application</title></heading><bodyText><p>When an application is filed with the Commission under <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 56-60"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 56 -60">§ 56-60<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#123#000056#        60#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> it shall consider and pass upon the same within twenty-five days, and when the application sets forth that such securities are to be issued or such obligations or liabilities are to be assumed for any purpose set forth in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 56-58"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 56 -58">§ 56-58<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#123#000056#        58#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, and the Commission so finds, it shall approve the application and issue the order applied for, unless the Commission shall find, for reasons stated by it, that the issuance of such securities or the assumption of such obligations or liabilities is not reasonably necessary to carry out one or more of the purposes set forth in the application. The Commission may by its order grant permission for any such issuance or assumption in the amount or on the terms applied for, or in a less amount, or on different terms, or not at all, and may include in its order such terms and conditions fairly relating to the matter of such issuance or assumption as it may deem reasonable or necessary. Whenever the Commission refuses, in whole or in part, an application to issue securities or assume obligations or liabilities, or grants such an application with modifications, it shall state specifically its reasons so that such refusal or modifications may be reviewed judicially on appeal. If at the end of twenty-five days after the filing of such an application, or at the end of any extension or extensions of that time, which may have been ordered by the Commission, no order of disapproval is entered, the application shall be deemed in fact and law to have been approved, and an order shall be issued by the Commission authorizing the issuance of the securities or the assumption of the obligations or liabilities as applied for and such securities may be issued or such obligations or liabilities assumed accordingly. But the Commission may extend the original twenty-five-day period not to exceed an additional thirty days unless the Commission shall conclude that fifty-five days is not a sufficient time in which fully to investigate and determine whether such certificate shall be issued, in which event it shall by written order extend the time for a specified reasonable period, and in such order set forth the reasons for such extension, which order shall be viewed in law as a final order for purposes of appeal, and upon appeal the court shall approve or decrease the period specified in the order.</p><p>To enable it to determine whether it will issue such order, the Commission may hold a hearing and may make such additional inquiry or investigation, and examine such witnesses, books, papers, documents and contracts, and require the filing of such data as it may deem of assistance.</p></bodyText><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p>1934, p. 222; Michie Code 1942, § 4073(5); 1980, c. 246.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PTD0-004G-K3K2-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 56.</desig><title>PUBLIC SERVICE COMPANIES</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 3.</desig><title>ISSUANCE OF STOCKS, BONDS, ETC.</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Administrative Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NjMxMjc0MUIzQjkzNEM4MEI4NkZGQjVCREJCRDk4OUM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Contents</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NkJBRTQ2MTg5OTJDNDFCNjkwNEIwMkY4MDZGRUI2MDM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Mjk5NzNDQUI3MEI1NDc2N0FFNEQzNTYyNTYwRDk1NjQ</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Civil Procedure</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MzUxNjJDMEQ5N0YwNDMzM0JDMjEzM0UzOTYzMzI3OTU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Extension of Time</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RjYwQjREMDgwNjIzNDU2MjkxRTc5ODRGNzkzRjI5REE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QzE1REJEMzY3RTI1NDMxNUE1NUM3M0M2MEUxQTVDQTM</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Mjk0NkYzNTA3MUNGNEFGMzhDMTQwNjQ5RkQzODI5Q0Q7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QzE1REJEMzY3RTI1NDMxNUE1NUM3M0M2MEUxQTVDQTM</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></metadata></legislativeDoc>