<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#123#000056#     249.6#">Va. Code Ann. § 56-249.6</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_56-249.6"/><heading><desig>§ 56-249.6.</desig><title>Recovery of fuel and purchased power costs</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a"/><heading><desig>A.</desig></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Each electric utility that purchases fuel for the generation of electricity or purchases power and that was not, as of July 1, 1999, bound by a rate case settlement adopted by the Commission that extended in its application beyond January 1, 2002, shall submit to the Commission its estimate of fuel costs, including the cost of purchased power, for the 12-month period beginning on the date prescribed by the Commission. Upon investigation of such estimates and hearings in accordance with law, the Commission shall direct each company to place in effect tariff provisions designed to recover the fuel costs determined by the Commission to be appropriate for that period, adjusted for any over-recovery or under-recovery of fuel costs previously incurred.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The Commission shall continuously review fuel costs and if it finds that any utility described in subdivision A 1 is in an over-recovery position by more than five percent, or likely to be so, it may reduce the fuel cost tariffs to correct the over-recovery.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Beginning July 1, 2009, for all utilities described in subdivision A 1 and subsection B, if the Commission approves any increase in fuel factor charges pursuant to this section that would increase the total rates of the residential class of customers of any such utility by more than 20 percent, the Commission, within six months following the effective date of such increase, shall review fuel costs, and if the Commission finds that the utility is, or is likely to be, in an over-recovery position with respect to fuel costs for the 12-month period for which the increase in fuel factor charges was approved by more than five percent, it may reduce the utility's fuel cost tariffs to correct the over-recovery.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b"/><heading><desig>B.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> All fuel costs recovery tariff provisions in effect on January 1, 2004, for any electric utility that purchases fuel for the generation of electricity and that was, as of July 1, 1999, bound by a rate case settlement adopted by the Commission that extended in its application beyond January 1, 2002, shall remain in effect until the later of (i) July 1, 2007 or (ii) the establishment of tariff provisions under subsection C. Any such utility shall continue to report to the Commission annually its actual fuel costs, including the cost of purchased power.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c"/><heading><desig>C.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Each electric utility described in subsection B shall submit annually to the Commission its estimate of fuel costs, including the cost of purchased power, for successive 12-month periods beginning on July 1, 2007, and each July 1 thereafter. Upon investigation of such estimates and hearings in accordance with law, the Commission shall direct each such utility to place in effect tariff provisions designed to recover the fuel costs determined by the Commission to be appropriate for such periods, adjusted for any over-recovery or under-recovery of fuel costs previously incurred; however, (i) no such adjustment for any over-recovery or under-recovery of fuel costs previously incurred shall be made for any period prior to July 1, 2007, and (ii) the Commission shall order that the deferral portion, if any, of the total increase in fuel tariffs for all classes as determined by the Commission to be appropriate for the 12-month period beginning July 1, 2007, above the fuel tariffs previously existing, shall be deferred without interest and recovered from all classes of customers as follows: (i) in the 12-month period beginning July 1, 2008, that part of the deferral portion of the increase in fuel tariffs that the Commission determines would increase the total rates of the residential class of customers of the utility by four percent over the level of such total rates in existence on June 30, 2008, shall be recovered; (ii) in the 12-month period beginning July 1, 2009, that part of the balance of the deferral portion of the increase in fuel tariffs, if any, that the Commission determines would increase the total rates of the residential class of customers of the utility by four percent over the level of such total rates in existence on June 30, 2009, shall be recovered; and (iii) in the 12-month period beginning July 1, 2010, the entire balance of the deferral portion of the increase in fuel tariffs, if any, shall be recovered. The "deferral portion of the increase in fuel tariffs" means the portion of such increase in fuel tariffs that exceeds the amount of such increase in fuel tariffs that the Commission determines would increase the total rates of the residential class of customers of the utility by more than four percent over the level of such total rates in existence on June 30, 2007.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d"/><heading><desig>D.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> In proceedings under subsections A and C:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Energy revenues associated with off-system sales of power shall be credited against fuel factor expenses in an amount equal to the total incremental fuel factor costs incurred in the production and delivery of such sales. In addition, 75 percent of the total annual margins from off-system sales shall be credited against fuel factor expenses; however, the Commission, upon application and after notice and opportunity for hearing, may require that a smaller percentage of such margins be so credited if it finds by clear and convincing evidence that such requirement is in the public interest. The remaining margins from off-system sales shall not be considered in the biennial reviews of electric utilities conducted pursuant to <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 56-585.1"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 56 -585.1">§ 56-585.1.<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#123#000056#     585.1#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> In the event such margins result in a net loss to the electric utility, (i) no charges shall be applied to fuel factor expenses and (ii) any such net losses shall not be considered in the biennial reviews of electric utilities conducted pursuant to <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 56-585.1"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 56 -585.1">§ 56-585.1.<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#123#000056#     585.1#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> For purposes of this subsection, "margins from off-system sales" shall mean the total revenues received from off-system sales transactions less the total incremental costs incurred; and</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The Commission shall disallow recovery of any fuel costs that it finds without just cause to be the result of failure of the utility to make every reasonable effort to minimize fuel costs or any decision of the utility resulting in unreasonable fuel costs, giving due regard to reliability of service and the need to maintain reliable sources of supply, economical generation mix, generating experience of comparable facilities, and minimization of the total cost of providing service.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_e"/><heading><desig>E.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The Commission is authorized to promulgate, in accordance with the provisions of this section, all rules and regulations necessary to allow the recovery by electric utilities of all of their prudently incurred fuel costs under subsections A and C, including the cost of purchased power, as precisely and promptly as possible, with no over-recovery or under-recovery, except as provided in subsection C, in a manner that will tend to assure public confidence and minimize abrupt changes in charges to consumers.</p></bodyText></level><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p>1978, c. 636; 1979, c. 492; 1980, c. 384; 1982, c. 584; 1984, cc. 716, 725; <citation normalizedCite="1989 VA CH 666"><content><span normalizedCite="1989 Va. Ch. 666">1989, c. 666<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1989#000666#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2004 VA CH 827"><content><span normalizedCite="2004 Va. Ch. 827">2004, c. 827<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2004#000827#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2006 VA CH 939"><content><span normalizedCite="2006 Va. Ch. 939">2006, c. 939<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2006#000939#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2007 VA CH 888"><content><span normalizedCite="2007 Va. Ch. 888">2007, cc. 888<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2007#000888#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2007 VA CH 933"><content><span normalizedCite="2007 Va. Ch. 933">933<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2007#000933#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2009 VA CH 244"><content><span normalizedCite="2009 Va. Ch. 244">2009, c. 244<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2009#000244#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PTF0-004G-K3PW-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 56.</desig><title>PUBLIC SERVICE COMPANIES</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 10.</desig><title>HEAT, LIGHT, POWER, WATER AND OTHER UTILITY COMPANIES GENERALLY</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="article"><heading><desig>ARTICLE 3.</desig><title>POWERS OF COMMISSION IN RELATION TO SERVICE</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Energy &amp; Utilities Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OUUzODAyRDk1QzVFNEZGMEJDM0RGMDYxOTlEMEEzRDA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OEFFRkJBRTg3MzUyNDJDMDk5MTA5MDc3NDFDMzlFMjU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDgxMjY0MUEwODJFNEQ4RkI3QjhCNUI3ODlFNERFRDY</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDYwNDUwQTk3Mzc5NDFFQTkxQTdFMjI3MTE5OTM3MjU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NjBBNzlERUQ4N0I1NDUwMEE1MDYyOEExQTM3NEU1NEU</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Price Terms</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QUU1NjhDMTFBMURBNDcxOEIzRTZDQzA2RDA4RjMzODg7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NkYzN0Y3MzM3MTFCNDM2Qzk3QzI5NzNCRTRDM0ZCNkY</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Ratemaking Procedures</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NURFMjYyMkQzNTQ2NDNBQjlFMzI4NzlCNzVDMkNGNDI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NjY3Q0UyNTVFNkQ2NDI1QkEyQkIxRDRGMzQzRjAxOEE</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></metadata></legislativeDoc>