<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#349#000038#     2#         6101#">Va. Code Ann. § 38.2-6101</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_38.2-6101"/><heading><desig>§ 38.2-6101.</desig><title>Definitions</title></heading><bodyText><p>As used in this chapter:</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Contract holder"</emphasis> means (i) with respect to group contracts, the organization or entity to which the dental benefit contract is issued, and (ii) with respect to individual contracts, the individual who enters into a dental benefit contract covering the individual or the individual and dependents of the individual.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Copayment"</emphasis> means the amount payable for a particular service by an enrollee in accordance with the patient charge schedule or for which the enrollee is responsible as a condition for receiving benefits under a dental benefit contract. A copayment may be expressed as a specific dollar amount or as a percentage of the allowable charge for a service.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Dental benefit contract"</emphasis> means a contract that provides benefits for dental services entered into between the dental plan organization and a contract holder.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Dental plan"</emphasis> means a contractual arrangement for dental services provided or arranged for, that pays benefits or is administered on an individual or group basis. A dental plan includes, but is not limited to, an arrangement where fixed indemnity benefits are paid to an individual or provider for dental services.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Dental plan organization"</emphasis> means a company that provides directly or arranges for a dental plan.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Dental service"</emphasis> means a service included in the current Dental Terminology Manual issued by the American Dental Association.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Dependent"</emphasis> means an individual who is the spouse or child of a subscriber.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Enrollee"</emphasis> means an individual or a dependent of an individual who is enrolled in a dental plan.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Evidence of coverage"</emphasis> means any certificate, agreement, or contract issued to a subscriber of a group that sets out the dental services to which the enrollees are entitled.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Fixed indemnity benefits"</emphasis> means the payment amount or amounts stated in the reimbursement schedule of a dental plan organization that will be paid to a subscriber, or to the subscriber's dentist, for dental services.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Plan dentist"</emphasis> means any dentist, licensed by the Virginia Board of Dentistry, who has contracted with the dental plan organization or with an entity acting on behalf of the dental plan organization to provide dental services to the enrollees. A dental plan organization may, but is not required to, utilize plan dentists.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Plan dentist contract"</emphasis> means a contract between the dental plan organization or an entity acting on behalf of the dental plan organization and a plan dentist.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Subscriber"</emphasis> means (i) with respect to group dental benefit contracts, the person who is covered by the contract, other than as a dependent, by satisfying the eligibility requirements of the group, and (ii) with respect to individual dental benefit contracts, the individual who obtains coverage of the individual only or the individual and dependents of the individual.</p></bodyText><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p><citation normalizedCite="2004 VA CH 668"><content><span normalizedCite="2004 Va. Ch. 668">2004, c. 668<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2004#000668#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PVD0-004G-K3VS-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 38.2.</desig><title>INSURANCE</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 61.</desig><title>DENTAL PLAN ORGANIZATIONS</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Healthcare Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NkUxMkVDQjJDOEY5NDVDQ0E5NTFEMTlDMjIwNzVERjc7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Patient Obligations</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NkQ5M0JGOTcxQTIzNEE4N0FBODZENTNCQTJGREU3RkM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NzYzODNGRDdGNkNDNDE4MTlDNTU4REQ1MEE3MUNFOEI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification><classificationGroup classificationScheme="indexing-terms"><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem score="90"><className>Insurance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDM4MzQ2QUYzMTY0NDQzQTkxRDQwRUUzRUM5RDg0OEM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></classificationGroup></metadata></legislativeDoc>