<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#123#000055#     374.2#">Va. Code Ann. § 55-374.2</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_55-374.2"/><heading><desig>§ 55-374.2.</desig><title>Exchange programs</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a"/><heading><desig>A.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Any exchange company which offers an exchange program in the Commonwealth shall prepare and register with the Board a disclosure document including, but not limited to, the following:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The name and address of the exchange company;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The names and addresses of the top three officers, all directors, and, if the exchange company is privately held, all shareholders owning five percent or more interest in the exchange company;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Whether the exchange company or any of its officers or directors has any legal or beneficial interest in any developer or managing agent for any time-share program participating in the exchange program and, if so, the name and location of the time-share project and the nature of the interest;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_4"/><heading><desig>4.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Unless the exchange company is also the developer or an affiliate, a statement that the purchaser's contract with the exchange company is a contract separate and distinct from the sales contract;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_5"/><heading><desig>5.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Whether the purchaser's participation in the exchange program is dependent upon the continued affiliation of the time-share project with the exchange program;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_6"/><heading><desig>6.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Whether the purchaser's membership or participation, or both, in the exchange program is voluntary or mandatory;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_7"/><heading><desig>7.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A complete and accurate description of the terms and conditions of the purchaser's contractual relationship with the exchange company and the procedure by which changes in the terms and conditions of the exchange contract may be made;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_8"/><heading><desig>8.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A complete and accurate description of the procedure to qualify for and effectuate exchanges;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_9"/><heading><desig>9.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A complete and accurate description of all limitations, restrictions, or priorities employed in the operation of the exchange program including, but not limited to, limitations on exchanges based on seasonality, unit size, or levels of occupancy, expressed in boldfaced type, and, in the event that such limitations, restrictions, or priorities are not uniformly applied by the exchange program, a clear description of the manner in which they are applied;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_10"/><heading><desig>10.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Whether exchanges are arranged on a space available basis and whether any guarantees of fulfillment of specific requests for exchanges are made by the exchange program;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_11"/><heading><desig>11.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Whether and under what circumstances an owner, in dealing with the exchange company, may lose the use of occupancy of his time-share in any properly applied for exchange, without being provided with substitute accommodations by the exchange company;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_12"/><heading><desig>12.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The fees or range of fees for participation by owners in the exchange program, a statement of whether any such fees may be altered by the exchange company, and the circumstances under which alterations may be made;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_13"/><heading><desig>13.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The name and address of the site of each time-share property, accommodation or facility participating in the exchange program;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_14"/><heading><desig>14.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The number of units in each property participating in the exchange program which are available for occupancy and which qualify for participation in the exchange program, expressed within the following numerical groupings: 1-5, 6-10, 11-20, 21-50, and 51 and over;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_15"/><heading><desig>15.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The number of owners with respect to each time-share program or other property who are eligible to participate in the exchange program, expressed within the following numerical groupings: 1-100, 101-249, 250-499, 500-999, and 1,000 and over, and a statement of the criteria used to determine those owners currently eligible to participate in the exchange program;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_16"/><heading><desig>16.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The disposition made by the exchange company of time-shares deposited with the exchange program by owners eligible to participate in the exchange program and not used by the exchange company in effecting exchanges;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_17"/><heading><desig>17.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The following information, which, except as provided in subsection B of this section, shall be independently audited by a certified public accountant or accounting firm in accordance with the standards of the Accounting Standards Board of the American Institute of Certified Public Accountants and reported for each year no later than July 1 of the succeeding year, beginning no later than July 1, 1985:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_17_a"/><heading><desig>a.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The number of owners enrolled in the exchange program. Such numbers shall disclose the relationship between the exchange company and owners as being either fee paying or gratuitous in nature;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_17_b"/><heading><desig>b.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The number of time-share properties, accommodations or facilities eligible to participate in the exchange program;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_17_c"/><heading><desig>c.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The percentage of confirmed exchanges, which shall be the number of exchanges confirmed by the exchange company divided by the number of exchanges properly applied for, together with a complete and accurate statement of the criteria used to determine whether an exchange request was properly applied for;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_17_d"/><heading><desig>d.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The number of time-shares for which the exchange company has an outstanding obligation to provide an exchange to an owner who relinquished a time-share during the year in exchange for a time-share in any future year;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_17_e"/><heading><desig>e.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The number of exchanges confirmed by the exchange company during the year.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_18"/><heading><desig>18.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A statement in boldfaced type to the effect that the percentage described in subdivision 17 c of this subsection is a summary of the exchange requests entered with the exchange company in the period reported and that the percentage does not indicate a purchaser's or owner's probabilities of being confirmed to any specific choice or range of choices, since availability at individual locations may vary.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b"/><heading><desig>B.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The information required by subsection A shall be accurate as of a date which is no more than 30 days prior to the date on which the information is delivered to the purchaser, except that the information required by subsection A, subdivisions 2, 12, 13, 14, 15, and 16 shall be accurate as of December 31 of the preceding year if the information is delivered between July 1 and December 31 of any year; information delivered between January 1 and June 30 of any year shall be accurate as of December 31 of the year prior to the preceding year. At no time shall such information be accurate as of a date which is more than eighteen months prior to the date of delivery. All references in this section to the word "year" shall mean calendar year.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c"/><heading><desig>C.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> In the event an exchange company offers an exchange program directly to the purchaser, the exchange company shall deliver to such purchaser, simultaneously with such offering and prior to the execution of any contract between the purchaser and the exchange company, the information set forth in subsection A, above. The requirements of this subsection shall not apply to any renewal of a contract between a purchaser and an exchange company.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d"/><heading><desig>D.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Each exchange company must include the statement set forth in subdivision 18 of subsection A on all promotional brochures, pamphlets, advertisements, or other materials disseminated by the exchange company which also contain the percentage of confirmed exchanges described in subdivision 17 c of subsection A.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_e"/><heading><desig>E.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> An exchange company shall, on or before July 1 of each year, file with the Board and the association for the time-share program in which the time-shares are offered or disposed, the information required by this section with respect to the preceding year. If the Board determines that any of the information supplied fails to meet the requirements of this section, the Board may undertake enforcement action against the exchange company in accordance with the provisions of Article 6 (<citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 55-396"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 55 -396">§ 55-396<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#123#000055#       396#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> et seq.) of this chapter. No developer shall have any liability arising out of the use, delivery or publication by the developer of written information provided to it by the exchange company pursuant to this section. Except for written information provided to the developer by the exchange company, no exchange company shall have any liability with respect to (i) any representation made by the developer relating to the exchange program or exchange company, or (ii) the use, delivery or publication by the developer of any information relating to the exchange program or exchange company. The failure of the exchange company to observe the requirements of this section, or the use by it of any unfair or deceptive act or practice in connection with the operation of the exchange program, shall be a violation of this section.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_f"/><heading><desig>F.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The Board may establish by regulation reasonable fees for registration of the exchange company disclosure document. All fees shall be remitted by the Board to the Treasurer of the Commonwealth, and shall be placed to the credit of the Common Interest Community Management Information Fund established pursuant to <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 55-529"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 55 -529">§ 55-529<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#123#000055#       529#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></level><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p>1985, c. 517; <citation normalizedCite="1998 VA CH 460"><content><span normalizedCite="1998 Va. Ch. 460">1998, c. 460<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1998#000460#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2008 VA CH 851"><content><span normalizedCite="2008 Va. Ch. 851">2008, cc. 851<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2008#000851#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2008 VA CH 871"><content><span normalizedCite="2008 Va. Ch. 871">871<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2008#000871#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PTD0-004G-K3BN-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 55.</desig><title>PROPERTY AND CONVEYANCES</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 21.</desig><title>THE VIRGINIA REAL ESTATE TIME-SHARE ACT</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="article"><heading><desig>ARTICLE 3.</desig><title>PROTECTION OF PURCHASERS</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Real Property Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QUUyRTcxRURBNEY2NEE2MDk3QzBCNzRDOEY0NTZDQzk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjJCOTVGQkMzRkQzNEQ2RjkzOEFGNzY4QUVBNEUzRTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjQxMkNBNkE1ODE5NDg0NUJDMTkzNzA1NTMwQzRFQ0M</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Timeshares</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OTQ2MTA5RjlGODA0NDhFMEIzMEE2NDI4ODRBM0Y3MDU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjQxMkNBNkE1ODE5NDg0NUJDMTkzNzA1NTMwQzRFQ0M</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification><classificationGroup classificationScheme="indexing-terms"><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem score="90"><className>Real Property</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QUUyRTcxRURBNEY2NEE2MDk3QzBCNzRDOEY0NTZDQzk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></classificationGroup></metadata></legislativeDoc>