<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#349#000054#     1#         4400#">Va. Code Ann. § 54.1-4400</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_54.1-4400"/><heading><desig>§ 54.1-4400.</desig><title>Definitions</title></heading><bodyText><p>As used in this chapter, unless the context clearly indicates otherwise:</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Accredited institution"</emphasis> means a degree-granting college or university accredited either by (i) one of the six major regional accrediting organizations-Middle States Association of Colleges and Schools, New England Association of Schools and Colleges, North Central Association of Colleges and Schools, Northwest Commission on Colleges and Universities, Southern Association of Colleges and Schools, and Western Association of Schools and Colleges-or their successors; or (ii) an accrediting organization demonstrating to the Board periodically, as prescribed by the Board, that its accreditation process and standards are substantially equivalent to the accreditation process and standards of the six major regional accrediting organizations.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Assurance"</emphasis> means any form of expressed or implied opinion or conclusion about the conformity of a financial statement with any recognition, measurement, presentation, or disclosure principles for financial statements.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Attest services"</emphasis> means audit, review, or other attest services for which standards have been established by the Public Company Accounting Oversight Board, by the Auditing Standards Board or the Accounting and Review Services Committee of the American Institute of Certified Public Accountants, or by any successor standard-setting authorities.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Board"</emphasis> means the Virginia Board of Accountancy.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Compilation services"</emphasis> means compiling financial statements in accordance with standards established by the American Institute of Certified Public Accountants or by any successor standard-setting authorities.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Continuing professional education"</emphasis> means the education that a person obtains after passing the CPA examination and that relates to services provided to an employer in academia, government, or industry using the CPA title or to services provided to the public using the CPA title.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"CPA"</emphasis> means certified public accountant.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"CPA examination"</emphasis> means the national uniform CPA examination approved and administered by the board of accountancy of a state or by the board's designee.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"CPA wall certificate"</emphasis> means the symbolic document suitable for wall display that is issued by the board of accountancy of a state to a person meeting the requirements to use the CPA title in that state.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Executive Director"</emphasis> means the Executive Director of the Board.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Experience"</emphasis> means employment in academia, a firm, government, or industry in any capacity involving the substantial use of accounting, financial, tax, or other skills that are relevant, as determined by the Board, to provide services to an employer using the CPA title or to the public using the CPA title.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Facilitated State Board Access"</emphasis> or <emphasis typeStyle="it">"FSBA"</emphasis> means the sponsoring organization's process whereby it provides the Board access to peer review results via a secure website.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Financial statement"</emphasis> means a presentation of historical or prospective financial information about one or more persons or entities.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Financial statement preparation services"</emphasis> means financial statement preparation services for which standards have been established by the American Institute of Certified Public Accountants or by any successor standard-setting authorities.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Firm"</emphasis> means an entity formed by one or more licensees as a sole proprietorship, a partnership, a corporation, a limited liability company, or any other type of entity permitted by law.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"License of another state"</emphasis> means the license that is issued by the board of accountancy of a state other than Virginia that gives a person the privilege of using the CPA title in that state or that gives a firm the privilege of providing attest services, compilation services, and financial statement preparation services to persons and entities located in that state.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Licensed"</emphasis> means holding a Virginia license or the license of another state.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Licensee"</emphasis> means a person or firm holding a Virginia license or the license of another state.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Peer review"</emphasis> means a review of a firm's attest services, compilation services, and financial statements preparation services that is conducted in accordance with the applicable monitoring program of the American Institute of Certified Public Accountants or its successor, or with another monitoring program approved by the Board.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Practice of public accounting"</emphasis> means the giving of an assurance other than (i) by the person or persons about whom the financial information is presented or (ii) by one or more owners, officers, employees, or members of the governing body of the entity or entities about whom the financial information is presented.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Providing services to an employer using the CPA title"</emphasis> means providing to an entity services that require the substantial use of accounting, financial, tax, or other skills that are relevant, as determined by the Board.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Providing services to the public using the CPA title"</emphasis> means providing services that are subject to the guidance of the standard-setting authorities listed in the standards of conduct and practice in subdivisions 5 and 6 of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 54.1-4413.3"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 54.1-4413.3">§ 54.1-4413.3.<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000054#     1#       4413.3#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation></p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Sponsoring organization"</emphasis> means a Board-approved professional society or other organization responsible for the facilitation and administration of peer reviews through use of its peer review program and applicable peer review standards.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"State"</emphasis> means any state of the United States, the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, the District of Columbia, Guam, Puerto Rico, and the U.S.Virgin Islands.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Using the CPA title in Virginia"</emphasis> means using "CPA," "Certified Public Accountant," or "public accountant" (i) in any form or manner of verbal communication to persons or entities located in Virginia or (ii) in any form or manner of written communication to persons or entities located in Virginia, including but not limited to the use in any abbreviation, acronym, phrase, or title that appears in business cards, the CPA wall certificate, Internet postings, letterhead, reports, signs, tax returns, or any other document or device.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Virginia license"</emphasis> means a license that is issued by the Board giving a person the privilege of using the CPA title in Virginia or a firm the privilege of providing attest services, compilation services, and financial statement preparation services to persons and entities located in Virginia.</p></bodyText><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p><citation normalizedCite="2001 VA CH 832"><content><span normalizedCite="2001 Va. Ch. 832">2001, c. 832<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2001#000832#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2003 VA CH 291"><content><span normalizedCite="2003 Va. Ch. 291">2003, c. 291<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2003#000291#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2004 VA CH 602"><content><span normalizedCite="2004 Va. Ch. 602">2004, c. 602<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2004#000602#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2007 VA CH 804"><content><span normalizedCite="2007 Va. Ch. 804">2007, c. 804<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2007#000804#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2014 VA CH 40"><content><span normalizedCite="2014 Va. Ch. 40">2014, cc. 40<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2014#000040#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2014 VA CH 755"><content><span normalizedCite="2014 Va. Ch. 755">755<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2014#000755#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2015 VA CH 287"><content><span normalizedCite="2015 Va. Ch. 287">2015, c. 287<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2015#000287#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PV70-004G-K06J-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 54.1.</desig><title>PROFESSIONS AND OCCUPATIONS</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="subtitle"><heading><desig>SUBTITLE VI.</desig><title>PROFESSIONS REGULATED BY OTHER ENTITIES</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 44.</desig><title>PUBLIC ACCOUNTANTS</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Computer &amp; Internet Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Qzk0QUJBRENDQzhBNDc2MDk5OTAyQzI3QkRFMkU0OUU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Damages</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NkJEMTQzNDMzNjAzNDVBNUFGRDgwRUI4MDIyQjQ2NjA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDMxOEI4OTIwRTQ5NEVBQUJBRTU5RjM2RUM2QjAzMEE</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Governments</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjdEQjE4OUJDMzQxNDNEMEI0RTI1QUFCMzJENjEwRTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Licenses</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6N0IyQjkyQkVENEM2NDczNzg5MDUwQ0U5RDMzRjlDNUM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QURCRDNBRjBGRTE0NEFBRUEzNUU1MzFGQjg3MTM4MDI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Healthcare Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NkUxMkVDQjJDOEY5NDVDQ0E5NTFEMTlDMjIwNzVERjc7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OTFDMjk0MjFFMEJFNDQyMkE2OTcyOUU2NTYxRkY5RUY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6M0JBQTc2MDg4OUY4NDRDQzk5QkQ0OTVFMUVCQzY4NkY</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Tax Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OTNEM0E2OEE0RkQyNEY1MDhBQzdGMkQ4ODI4QTJDODE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Imposition of Tax</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Njg2QTVGMUU2NTE4NDgwNjgyNzg3QTY0RDUyRUMyRDE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QkI5NTVGNkFDOEU1NDVGNjhEQTZEOEJDRTIyMzVEODA</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification><classificationGroup classificationScheme="indexing-terms"><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem score="90"><className>Businesses &amp; Corporations</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjA4OEVGODBENzY4NDcxM0IyQzA1OTEwQzVDODRBOUE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></classificationGroup></metadata></legislativeDoc>