<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#958#0000000062#0000000001#     44.15#0000000051#">Va. Code Ann. § 62.1-44.15:51</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="hierarchy-note"><note><bodyText><p>This section has more than one version with varying effective dates.  To view a complete list of the versions of this section see Table of Contents.</p></bodyText></note><heading><title>§ 62.1-44.15:51. (For expiration date -- see note) Definitions</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><bodyText><p>As used in this article, unless the context requires a different meaning:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><bodyText><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Agreement in lieu of a plan"</emphasis> means a contract between the plan-approving authority and the owner that specifies conservation measures that must be implemented in the construction of a single-family residence; this contract may be executed by the plan-approving authority in lieu of a formal site plan.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Applicant"</emphasis> means any person submitting an erosion and sediment control plan for approval or requesting the issuance of a permit, when required, authorizing land-disturbing activities to commence.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Certified inspector"</emphasis> means an employee or agent of a VESCP authority who (i) holds a certificate of competence from the Board in the area of project inspection or (ii) is enrolled in the Board's training program for project inspection and successfully completes such program within one year after enrollment.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Certified plan reviewer"</emphasis> means an employee or agent of a VESCP authority who (i) holds a certificate of competence from the Board in the area of plan review, (ii) is enrolled in the Board's training program for plan review and successfully completes such program within one year after enrollment, or (iii) is licensed as a professional engineer, architect, landscape architect, land surveyor pursuant to Article 1 (<citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 54.1-400"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 54.1-400">§ 54.1-400<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000054#     1#          400#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> et seq.) of Chapter 4 of Title 54.1, or professional soil scientist as defined in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 54.1-2200"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 54.1-2200">§ 54.1-2200<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000054#     1#         2200#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Certified program administrator"</emphasis> means an employee or agent of a VESCP authority who (i) holds a certificate of competence from the Board in the area of program administration or (ii) is enrolled in the Board's training program for program administration and successfully completes such program within one year after enrollment.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Department"</emphasis> means the Department of Environmental Quality.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Director"</emphasis> means the Director of the Department of Environmental Quality.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"District"</emphasis> or <emphasis typeStyle="it">"soil and water conservation district"</emphasis> means a political subdivision of the Commonwealth organized in accordance with the provisions of Article 3 (<citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 10.1-506"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 10.1-506">§ 10.1-506<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000010#     1#          506#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> et seq.) of Chapter 5 of Title 10.1.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Erosion and sediment control plan"</emphasis> or <emphasis typeStyle="it">"plan"</emphasis> means a document containing material for the conservation of soil and water resources of a unit or group of units of land. It may include appropriate maps, an appropriate soil and water plan inventory and management information with needed interpretations, and a record of decisions contributing to conservation treatment. The plan shall contain all major conservation decisions to ensure that the entire unit or units of land will be so treated to achieve the conservation objectives.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Erosion impact area"</emphasis> means an area of land not associated with current land-disturbing activity but subject to persistent soil erosion resulting in the delivery of sediment onto neighboring properties or into state waters. This definition shall not apply to any lot or parcel of land of 10,000 square feet or less used for residential purposes or to shorelines where the erosion results from wave action or other coastal processes.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><bodyText><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Land-disturbing activity"</emphasis> means any man-made change to the land surface that may result in soil erosion from water or wind and the movement of sediments into state waters or onto lands in the Commonwealth, including, but not limited to, clearing, grading, excavating, transporting, and filling of land, except that the term shall not include:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Minor land-disturbing activities such as home gardens and individual home landscaping, repairs, and maintenance work;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Individual service connections;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Installation, maintenance, or repair of any underground public utility lines when such activity occurs on an existing hard surfaced road, street, or sidewalk, provided the land-disturbing activity is confined to the area of the road, street, or sidewalk that is hard surfaced;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_4"/><heading><desig>4.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Septic tank lines or drainage fields unless included in an overall plan for land-disturbing activity relating to construction of the building to be served by the septic tank system;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_5"/><heading><desig>5.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Permitted surface or deep mining operations and projects, or oil and gas operations and projects conducted pursuant to Title 45.1;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_6"/><heading><desig>6.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Tilling, planting, or harvesting of agricultural, horticultural, or forest crops, livestock feedlot operations, or as additionally set forth by the Board in regulation, including engineering operations as follows: construction of terraces, terrace outlets, check dams, desilting basins, dikes, ponds, ditches, strip cropping, lister furrowing, contour cultivating, contour furrowing, land drainage, and land irrigation; however, this exception shall not apply to harvesting of forest crops unless the area on which harvesting occurs is reforested artificially or naturally in accordance with the provisions of Chapter 11 (<citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 10.1-1100"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 10.1-1100">§ 10.1-1100<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000010#     1#         1100#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> et seq.) of Title 10.1 or is converted to bona fide agricultural or improved pasture use as described in subsection B of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 10.1-1163"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 10.1-1163">§ 10.1-1163<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000010#     1#         1163#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_7"/><heading><desig>7.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Repair or rebuilding of the tracks, rights-of-way, bridges, communication facilities, and other related structures and facilities of a railroad company;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_8"/><heading><desig>8.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Agricultural engineering operations, including but not limited to the construction of terraces, terrace outlets, check dams, desilting basins, dikes, ponds not required to comply with the provisions of the Dam Safety Act (<citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 10.1-604"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 10.1-604">§ 10.1-604<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000010#     1#          604#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> et seq.), ditches, strip cropping, lister furrowing, contour cultivating, contour furrowing, land drainage, and land irrigation;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_9"/><heading><desig>9.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Disturbed land areas of less than 10,000 square feet in size or 2,500 square feet in all areas of the jurisdictions designated as subject to the Chesapeake Bay Preservation Area Designation and Management Regulations; however, the governing body of the program authority may reduce this exception to a smaller area of disturbed land or qualify the conditions under which this exception shall apply;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_10"/><heading><desig>10.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Installation of fence and sign posts or telephone and electric poles and other kinds of posts or poles;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_11"/><heading><desig>11.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Shoreline erosion control projects on tidal waters when all of the land-disturbing activities are within the regulatory authority of and approved by local wetlands boards, the Marine Resources Commission, or the United States Army Corps of Engineers; however, any associated land that is disturbed outside of this exempted area shall remain subject to this article and the regulations adopted pursuant thereto; and</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_12"/><heading><desig>12.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Emergency work to protect life, limb, or property, and emergency repairs; however, if the land-disturbing activity would have required an approved erosion and sediment control plan, if the activity were not an emergency, then the land area disturbed shall be shaped and stabilized in accordance with the requirements of the VESCP authority.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><bodyText><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Natural channel design concepts"</emphasis> means the utilization of engineering analysis and fluvial geomorphic processes to create, rehabilitate, restore, or stabilize an open conveyance system for the purpose of creating or recreating a stream that conveys its bankfull storm event within its banks and allows larger flows to access its bankfull bench and its floodplain.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Owner"</emphasis> means the owner or owners of the freehold of the premises or lesser estate therein, mortgagee or vendee in possession, assignee of rents, receiver, executor, trustee, lessee, or other person, firm, or corporation in control of a property.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Peak flow rate"</emphasis> means the maximum instantaneous flow from a given storm condition at a particular location.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Permittee"</emphasis> means the person to whom the local permit authorizing land-disturbing activities is issued or the person who certifies that the approved erosion and sediment control plan will be followed.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Person"</emphasis> means any individual, partnership, firm, association, joint venture, public or private corporation, trust, estate, commission, board, public or private institution, utility, cooperative, county, city, town, or other political subdivision of the Commonwealth, governmental body, including a federal or state entity as applicable, any interstate body, or any other legal entity.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Runoff volume"</emphasis> means the volume of water that runs off the land development project from a prescribed storm event.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Town"</emphasis> means an incorporated town.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Virginia Erosion and Sediment Control Program"</emphasis> or <emphasis typeStyle="it">"VESCP"</emphasis> means a program approved by the Board that has been established by a VESCP authority for the effective control of soil erosion, sediment deposition, and nonagricultural runoff associated with a land-disturbing activity to prevent the unreasonable degradation of properties, stream channels, waters, and other natural resources and shall include such items where applicable as local ordinances, rules, permit requirements, annual standards and specifications, policies and guidelines, technical materials, and requirements for plan review, inspection, enforcement where authorized in this article, and evaluation consistent with the requirements of this article and its associated regulations.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Virginia Erosion and Sediment Control Program authority"</emphasis> or <emphasis typeStyle="it">"VESCP authority"</emphasis> means an authority approved by the Board to operate a Virginia Erosion and Sediment Control Program. An authority may include a state entity, including the Department; a federal entity; a district, county, city, or town; or for linear projects subject to annual standards and specifications, electric, natural gas, and telephone utility companies, interstate and intrastate natural gas pipeline companies, railroad companies, or authorities created pursuant to <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 15.2-5102"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 15.2-5102">§ 15.2-5102<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000015#     2#         5102#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Water quality volume"</emphasis> means the volume equal to the first one-half inch of runoff multiplied by the impervious surface of the land development project.</p></bodyText></level><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p>1973, c. 486, § 21-89.3; 1974, c. 265; 1977, c. 149; 1980, c. 305; 1988, cc. 690, 732, 891, <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 10.1-560"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 10.1-560">§ 10.1-560<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000010#     1#          560#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1990 VA CH 491"><content><span normalizedCite="1990 Va. Ch. 491">1990, c. 491<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1990#000491#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1991 VA CH 469"><content><span normalizedCite="1991 Va. Ch. 469">1991, c. 469<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1991#000469#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1992 VA CH 184"><content><span normalizedCite="1992 Va. Ch. 184">1992, c. 184<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1992#000184#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1993 VA CH 925"><content><span normalizedCite="1993 Va. Ch. 925">1993, c. 925<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1993#000925#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1994 VA CH 703"><content><span normalizedCite="1994 Va. Ch. 703">1994, c. 703<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1994#000703#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2003 VA CH 423"><content><span normalizedCite="2003 Va. Ch. 423">2003, c. 423<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2003#000423#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2004 VA CH 476"><content><span normalizedCite="2004 Va. Ch. 476">2004, c. 476<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2004#000476#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2005 VA CH 107"><content><span normalizedCite="2005 Va. Ch. 107">2005, c. 107<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2005#000107#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2006 VA CH 21"><content><span normalizedCite="2006 Va. Ch. 21">2006, c. 21<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2006#000021#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2009 VA CH 309"><content><span normalizedCite="2009 Va. Ch. 309">2009, c. 309<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2009#000309#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2012 VA CH 785"><content><span normalizedCite="2012 Va. Ch. 785">2012, cc. 785<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2012#000785#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2012 VA CH 819"><content><span normalizedCite="2012 Va. Ch. 819">819<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2012#000819#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2013 VA CH 756"><content><span normalizedCite="2013 Va. Ch. 756">2013, cc. 756<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2013#000756#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2013 VA CH 793"><content><span normalizedCite="2013 Va. Ch. 793">793<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2013#000793#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PW90-004G-K1G0-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 62.1.</desig><title>WATERS OF THE STATE, PORTS AND HARBORS</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 3.1.</desig><title>STATE WATER CONTROL LAW</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="article"><heading><desig>ARTICLE 2.4.</desig><title>EROSION AND SEDIMENT CONTROL LAW</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Distribution, Processing &amp; Storage of Food &amp; Agricultural Products</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NENGNzZCMDU5RjcyNEM0NEFFOUU4ODFCQkZCOThBRkI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NkVDMzM4QkJENTg3NDQ0RDg3NTA5OEM3RkMyQTlENDI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Energy &amp; Utilities Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OUUzODAyRDk1QzVFNEZGMEJDM0RGMDYxOTlEMEEzRDA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Easements &amp; Rights of Way</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RDgzRTU4RTJDRDk1NDk4NTg1RkQyRjE0QTI2OUI2Q0M7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjMwQzNCRThDRjkwNDY0QjlFNDJFQzY5QzVCMEE0MTY</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NEJFOTZCNDdFOEJCNEU2Mjg2OUI3QzU2NTExRTkxRDM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OTYxNzdCMkVBQkIyNEM2RTk2MDkzQjNEMTg4MzVFRTE</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OEYzQTU0QTkzNkQwNDFGN0I1QjU1MUIxNUU2QTIwOTE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NzM2RDMwRjcxMDA3NDcxNTg1RTFBQjE2NTVGMkI0RUU</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Natural Gas Transportation</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QTI4NjU3NDIxOTkzNDU4QUE1MzkzMURFMjI5OTQxMUE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjMwQzNCRThDRjkwNDY0QjlFNDJFQzY5QzVCMEE0MTY</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Environmental Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NzFDRDYyNkI2QjhBNDg3NTkyRjRDRkZEQjlCRkRBQzM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Wetlands Management</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QzY2NjI1NjQ3Qzk2NDE5NzlGQjFDNTkzQjg5QTAyMkQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NTkwMDY1RDExQ0YwNDQ1RTlERUVFMjUzMUI1MkFDOTU</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Governments</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjdEQjE4OUJDMzQxNDNEMEI0RTI1QUFCMzJENjEwRTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Distribution, Processing &amp; Storage</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NENGNzZCMDU5RjcyNEM0NEFFOUU4ODFCQkZCOThBRkI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NkVDMzM4QkJENTg3NDQ0RDg3NTA5OEM3RkMyQTlENDI</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Forest Lands</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RTkzOTc4NEQ2MTQwNDg0Q0E0NDNFRkRDRDU1QUE0OEU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6ODE4NDg4QUI2RDA3NDQ2RkI1QTRFNjA4OUM3QjA4MzA</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Real Property Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QUUyRTcxRURBNEY2NEE2MDk3QzBCNzRDOEY0NTZDQzk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Mortgagee's Interests</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MzQwOUI5Qjk2Qzg5NEJDNUFBODI4M0NFNjE0MzYwNzI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDhDNTc4RkY3N0RDNDhDRkI1ODk3RjI2RkEyRTMwNEI</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Surface Rights</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MTAzOUU2OENCRTk0NDQ3Mzk2NUMyNUQzN0U4QTNGOTU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjlCOEFBQzRBMkRDNERFMkIyQ0YzQUQ0ODFGQjQ3QzI</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Transfers by Mortgagees</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6REQ5RjYwMDdDOTE0NEU2NTgxNEQ3OEQ4QkJBNjFBMjg7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QThCNUQyMTcxQjZENEE3QTk4NjIyRDhBMkNBNUI3RDI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Transportation Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RTYzRTk5RDVBQkQ2NDcwQzk2NTU3ODQ5OEE3NDlBNzk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Engineers</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MTRGNUI2RDAxOTgyNDAzQUFGQTAwRDBGQkM3RjAzQkU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OEIxN0YxNkZFNzY5NEIyQjhGQTUwMjBBN0FBMzIzQzM</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification><classificationGroup classificationScheme="indexing-terms"><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem score="90"><className>Admiralty &amp; Maritime</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QzRDNDVDOTdGRUQ1NDE1M0I1RjRBRDFBRTI3ODFGMDk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem score="90"><className>Transportation</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RTYzRTk5RDVBQkQ2NDcwQzk2NTU3ODQ5OEE3NDlBNzk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></classificationGroup></metadata></legislativeDoc>