<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#349#000032#     1#          351#">Va. Code Ann. § 32.1-351</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_32.1-351"/><heading><desig>§ 32.1-351.</desig><title>Family Access to Medical Insurance Security Plan established</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a"/><heading><desig>A.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The Department of Medical Assistance Services shall amend the Virginia Children's Medical Security Insurance Plan to be renamed the Family Access to Medical Insurance Security (FAMIS) Plan. The Department of Medical Assistance Services shall provide coverage under the Family Access to Medical Insurance Security Plan for individuals under the age of 19 when such individuals (i) have family incomes at or below 200 percent of the federal poverty level or were enrolled on the date of federal approval of Virginia's FAMIS Plan in the Children's Medical Security Insurance Plan (CMSIP); such individuals shall continue to be enrolled in FAMIS for so long as they continue to meet the eligibility requirements of CMSIP; (ii) are not eligible for medical assistance services pursuant to Title XIX of the Social Security Act, as amended; (iii) are not covered under a group health plan or under health insurance coverage, as defined in § 2791 of the Public Health Service Act <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="42 USC 300GG-91"><content><span normalizedCite="42 U.S.C. 300GG-91">(42 U.S.C. § 300gg-91<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1828#142#000042#000000300gg#00000091#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>(a) and (b)(1)); and (iv) meet both the requirements of Title XXI of the Social Security Act, as amended, and the Family Access to Medical Insurance Security Plan. Eligible children, residing in Virginia, whose family income does not exceed 200 percent of the federal poverty level during the enrollment period shall receive 12 continuous months of coverage as permitted by Title XXI of the Social Security Act.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b"/><heading><desig>B.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The Department of Medical Assistance Services shall also provide coverage for children and pregnant women who meet the criteria set forth in clauses (i) through (iv) of subsection A during the first five years of lawful residence in the United States, pursuant to § 214 of the Children's Health Insurance Program Reauthorization Act of 2009 (P.L. 111-3).</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c"/><heading><desig>C.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Family Access to Medical Insurance Security Plan participants shall participate in cost-sharing to the extent allowed under Title XXI of the Social Security Act, as amended, and as set forth in the Virginia Plan for Title XXI of the Social Security Act. The annual aggregate cost-sharing for all eligible children in a family above 150 percent of the federal poverty level shall not exceed five percent of the family's gross income or as allowed by federal law and regulations. The annual aggregate cost-sharing for all eligible children in a family at or below 150 percent of the federal poverty level shall not exceed 2.5 percent of the family's gross income. The nominal copayments for all eligible children in a family shall not be less than those in effect on January 1, 2003. Cost-sharing shall not be required for well-child and preventive services including age-appropriate child immunizations.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d"/><heading><desig>D.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The Family Access to Medical Insurance Security Plan shall provide comprehensive health care benefits to program participants, including well-child and preventive services, to the extent required to comply with federal requirements of Title XXI of the Social Security Act. These benefits shall include comprehensive medical, dental, vision, mental health, and substance abuse services, and physical therapy, occupational therapy, speech-language pathology, and skilled nursing services for special education students. The mental health services required herein shall include intensive in-home services, case management services, day treatment, and 24-hour emergency response. The services shall be provided in the same manner and with the same coverage and service limitations as they are provided to children under the State Plan for Medical Assistance Services.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_e"/><heading><desig>E.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The Virginia Plan for Title XXI of the Social Security Act shall include a provision that participants in the Family Access to Medical Insurance Security Plan who have access to employer-sponsored health insurance coverage, as defined in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 32.1-351.1"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 32.1-351.1">§ 32.1-351.1<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000032#     1#        351.1#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, may, but shall not be required to, enroll in an employer's health plan, and the Department of Medical Assistance Services or its designee shall make premium payments to such employer's plan on behalf of eligible participants if the Department of Medical Assistance Services or its designee determines that such enrollment is cost-effective, as defined in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 32.1-351.1"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 32.1-351.1">§ 32.1-351.1.<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000032#     1#        351.1#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation></p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_f"/><heading><desig>F.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The Family Access to Medical Insurance Security Plan shall ensure that coverage under this program does not substitute for private health insurance coverage.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_g"/><heading><desig>G.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The health care benefits provided under the Family Access to Medical Insurance Security Plan shall be through existing Department of Medical Assistance Services' contracts with health maintenance organizations and other providers, or through new contracts with health maintenance organizations, health insurance plans, other similarly licensed entities, or other entities as deemed appropriate by the Department of Medical Assistance Services, or through employer-sponsored health insurance. All eligible individuals, insofar as feasible, shall be enrolled in health maintenance organizations.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_h"/><heading><desig>H.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The Department of Medical Assistance Services may establish a centralized processing site for the administration of the program to include responding to inquiries, distributing applications and program information, and receiving and processing applications. The Family Access to Medical Insurance Security Plan shall include a provision allowing a child's application to be filed by a parent, legal guardian, authorized representative or any other adult caretaker relative with whom the child lives. The Department of Medical Assistance Services may contract with third-party administrators to provide any additional administrative services. Duties of the third-party administrators may include, but shall not be limited to, enrollment, outreach, eligibility determination, data collection, premium payment and collection, financial oversight and reporting, and such other services necessary for the administration of the Family Access to Medical Insurance Security Plan. Any centralized processing site shall determine a child's eligibility for either Title XIX or Title XXI and shall enroll eligible children in Title XIX or Title XXI. A single application form shall be used to determine eligibility for Title XIX or Title XXI of the Social Security Act, as amended, and outreach, enrollment, re-enrollment and services delivery shall be coordinated with the FAMIS Plus program pursuant to <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 32.1-325"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 32.1-325">§ 32.1-325<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000032#     1#          325#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>. In the event that an application is denied, the applicant shall be notified of any services available in his locality that can be accessed by contacting the local department of social services.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_i"/><heading><desig>I.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The Virginia Plan for Title XXI of the Social Security Act, as amended, shall include a provision that, in addition to any centralized processing site, local social services agencies shall provide and accept applications for the Family Access to Medical Insurance Security Plan and shall assist families in the completion of applications. Contracting health plans, providers, and others may also provide applications for the Family Access to Medical Insurance Security Plan and may assist families in completion of the applications.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_j"/><heading><desig>J.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The Department of Medical Assistance Services shall develop and submit to the federal Secretary of Health and Human Services an amended Title XXI plan for the Family Access to Medical Insurance Security Plan and may revise such plan as may be necessary. Such plan and any subsequent revisions shall comply with the requirements of federal law, this chapter, and any conditions set forth in the appropriation act. In addition, the plan shall provide for coordinated implementation of publicity, enrollment, and service delivery with existing local programs throughout the Commonwealth that provide health care services, educational services, and case management services to children. In developing and revising the plan, the Department of Medical Assistance Services shall advise and consult with the Joint Commission on Health Care.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_k"/><heading><desig>K.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Funding for the Family Access to Medical Insurance Security Plan shall be provided through state and federal appropriations and shall include appropriations of any funds that may be generated through the Virginia Family Access to Medical Insurance Security Plan Trust Fund.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_l"/><heading><desig>L.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The Board of Medical Assistance Services, or the Director, as the case may be, shall adopt, promulgate, and enforce such regulations pursuant to the Administrative Process Act (<citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 2.2-4000"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 2.2-4000">§ 2.2-4000<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000002#     2#         4000#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> et seq.) as may be necessary for the implementation and administration of the Family Access to Medical Insurance Security Plan.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_m"/><heading><desig>M.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Children enrolled in the Virginia Plan for Title XXI of the Social Security Act prior to implementation of these amendments shall continue their eligibility under the Family Access to Medical Insurance Security Plan and shall be given reasonable notice of any changes in their benefit packages. Continuing eligibility in the Family Access to Medical Insurance Security Plan for children enrolled in the Virginia Plan for Title XXI of the Social Security Act prior to implementation of these amendments shall be determined in accordance with their regularly scheduled review dates or pursuant to changes in income status. Families may select among the options available pursuant to subsections D and F of this section.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_n"/><heading><desig>N.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The provisions of Chapter 9 (<citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 32.1-310"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 32.1-310">§ 32.1-310<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000032#     1#          310#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> et seq.) of this title relating to the regulation of medical assistance shall apply, mutatis mutandis, to the Family Access to Medical Insurance Security Plan.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_o"/><heading><desig>O.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> In addition, in any case in which any provision set forth in Title 38.2 excludes, exempts or does not apply to the Virginia plan for medical assistance services established pursuant to Title XIX of the Social Security Act, <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="42 USC 1396"><content><span normalizedCite="42 U.S.C. 1396">42 U.S.C. § 1396<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1828#123#000042#       1396#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> et seq. (Medicaid), such exclusion, exemption or carve out of application to Title XIX of the Social Security Act (Medicaid) shall be deemed to subsume and thus to include the Family Access to Medical Insurance Security (FAMIS) Plan, established pursuant to Title XXI of the Social Security Act, upon approval of FAMIS by the federal Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services as Virginia's State Children's Health Insurance Program.</p></bodyText></level><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p><citation normalizedCite="1997 VA CH 679"><content><span normalizedCite="1997 Va. Ch. 679">1997, c. 679<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1997#000679#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1999 VA CH 1034"><content><span normalizedCite="1999 Va. Ch. 1034">1999, c. 1034<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1999#001034#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2000 VA CH 824"><content><span normalizedCite="2000 Va. Ch. 824">2000, cc. 824<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2000#000824#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2000 VA CH 848"><content><span normalizedCite="2000 Va. Ch. 848">848<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2000#000848#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2001 VA CH 238"><content><span normalizedCite="2001 Va. Ch. 238">2001, cc. 238<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2001#000238#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2001 VA CH 735"><content><span normalizedCite="2001 Va. Ch. 735">735<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2001#000735#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2001 VA CH 756"><content><span normalizedCite="2001 Va. Ch. 756">756<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2001#000756#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2002 VA CH 640"><content><span normalizedCite="2002 Va. Ch. 640">2002, c. 640<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2002#000640#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2003 VA CH 66"><content><span normalizedCite="2003 Va. Ch. 66">2003, cc. 66<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2003#000066#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2003 VA CH 71"><content><span normalizedCite="2003 Va. Ch. 71">71<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2003#000071#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2003 VA CH 521"><content><span normalizedCite="2003 Va. Ch. 521">521<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2003#000521#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2005 VA CH 584"><content><span normalizedCite="2005 Va. Ch. 584">2005, c. 584<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2005#000584#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2006 VA CH 428"><content><span normalizedCite="2006 Va. Ch. 428">2006, c. 428<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2006#000428#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2007 VA CH 407"><content><span normalizedCite="2007 Va. Ch. 407">2007, c. 407<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2007#000407#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2012 VA CH 646"><content><span normalizedCite="2012 Va. Ch. 646">2012, cc. 646<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2012#000646#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2012 VA CH 689"><content><span normalizedCite="2012 Va. Ch. 689">689<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2012#000689#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2014 VA CH 9"><content><span normalizedCite="2014 Va. Ch. 9">2014, cc. 9<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2014#000009#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2014 VA CH 183"><content><span normalizedCite="2014 Va. Ch. 183">183<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2014#000183#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PV20-004G-K20D-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 32.1.</desig><title>HEALTH</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 13.</desig><title>FAMILY ACCESS TO MEDICAL INSURANCE SECURITY PLAN</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Health Maintenance Organizations</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MzNDMEYyOTY3NjdBNEE4MDlCQTlDMUQxRDMyMUZCNDM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NkUxMkVDQjJDOEY5NDVDQ0E5NTFEMTlDMjIwNzVERjc</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Healthcare Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NkUxMkVDQjJDOEY5NDVDQ0E5NTFEMTlDMjIwNzVERjc7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6ODAzM0Y2NDUyOUMxNEM3NTkwNkIwMzI3MDI5RkQ0Rjk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NzYzODNGRDdGNkNDNDE4MTlDNTU4REQ1MEE3MUNFOEI</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6ODZDMjQzOUU2MTM4NEJENzgxQTNDRjkzNkExRDcxNEU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUVGMzQ2NUZDREVCNEEwQkI0N0I4NjQ2RDVBQTFEQzI</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Health Maintenance Organizations</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MzNDMEYyOTY3NjdBNEE4MDlCQTlDMUQxRDMyMUZCNDM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUVGMzQ2NUZDREVCNEEwQkI0N0I4NjQ2RDVBQTFEQzI</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Nursing Facilities</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OTk0NDgxMUUxM0MzNDI5QzhDNEVGNzkwODVFN0MxRDg7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QUVDOEU4Qjg3REQzNEYxNDhCMUNGNzQ5NzNBRTVGNDk</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Insurance Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDM4MzQ2QUYzMTY0NDQzQTkxRDQwRUUzRUM5RDg0OEM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Eligibility Requirements</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6N0M0REU4MEJGM0FBNEQ0QThBRTkwQ0MyOUIzOEM4MzI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RDY2OUI1QTkwQkJCNEU4RTlFQTZGNEZERjI3RUFCNTc</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Labor &amp; Employment Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MTE3QUQwOTA0MUYzNDlCMEFFMjUwRUNDM0RDRkM5QzM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Definition of Employers</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6ODU0MDU3OTk2NjhCNDcxRUI0NkI2MTAwODczNUMyRjk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6M0Y4OTVEMTE3QTc3NDI5QTkwMjMwMkRBNjRBMUM2NkM</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Public Health &amp; Welfare Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDYwRTY1MDg3MTk5NDUyNkFFRDI1RjJBRERGQ0UxNzI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Alcoholism &amp; Drug Addictions</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RDQ0NzZCMzMxMzE4NEI2MEJBMDI4NEQwRkZBRkQxQkY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjI3RTIyRTFGQzU4NEJEMTkwQUQzRUYzRTk5MTlEOEM</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjIwNDlBNjZGM0IxNDc4MkE5MkI2QTVCNkNEQ0M0QzM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MTNCNURBMjAwMTdCNDU0NjhDREEwOUE4MUI1M0FFREI</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDAwREJBMUYzRDlGNEVGMEFDOTBFMUYyNzhENEVENkM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NERBMTY3MzNEMTY2NDg0QUI4Q0JCMjYzRkU2M0NFNDE</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RjM3NDdEQTcwRDVENDFENEI4QUJFMzQ5NzVGMTE1RDA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6REY3QUUxQ0YxMDFENEE3MTg3QTU4QTdBNkRGMEVCMDc</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NjEwRDdDREEzNjdENEYxNEEzNTI4NEM0QzY4NzUzQzI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6REEzRTlGRjlCQjc0NDYzQUFENzM0OEQzRkM4NDY0QzU</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NjNEMkM3MDg5QzI2NDMwNDhGQkIxMUE5ODdERTNFQzE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NjQ0NkMzMERDQTk0NEJDRjkzN0ZGMDA0RDQ1RTc5NDU</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NEQ3OEVEMjEwMEI4NEY1OTgyODZBMURDRkREMEM5RTg7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDZDNTZENUNCRjVBNEY4OEIyQzVBNjRDRTcyOEQ4NDQ</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Treatment</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QTE3NDlDOUQ4Mzg1NDcxNzhCNzQwNDc2MkEzMTkwRUI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RTA2N0I2MjA4MEMwNEExNjlBQzkzRjBGOTAxODRCNkY</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification><classificationGroup classificationScheme="indexing-terms"><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem score="90"><className>Healthcare</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NkUxMkVDQjJDOEY5NDVDQ0E5NTFEMTlDMjIwNzVERjc7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></classificationGroup></metadata></legislativeDoc>