<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#349#000023#     1#         2404#">Va. Code Ann. § 23.1-2404</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_23.1-2404"/><heading><desig>§ 23.1-2404.</desig><title>(Effective October 1, 2016) Powers of the Authority</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a"/><heading><desig>A.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The Authority has all the powers necessary or convenient to carry out the purposes and provisions of this chapter, including the power to:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Sue and be sued in its own name;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Have and alter an official seal;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Have perpetual duration and succession in its name;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_4"/><heading><desig>4.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Locate and maintain offices at such places as it may designate;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_5"/><heading><desig>5.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Make and execute contracts, guarantees, or any other instruments and agreements necessary or convenient for the exercise of its powers and functions, including contracts with hospitals or health care businesses to operate and manage any or all of the hospital facilities or operations, and incur liabilities and secure the obligations of any entity or individual;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_6"/><heading><desig>6.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Conduct or engage in any lawful business, activity, effort, or project consistent with the Authority's purposes or necessary or convenient to exercise its powers;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_7"/><heading><desig>7.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Exercise, in addition to its other powers, all powers that are (i) granted to corporations by the provisions of Title 13.1 or similar provisions of any successor law, except in those cases in which the power is confined to corporations created under such title, and (ii) not inconsistent with the purposes and intent of this chapter or the limitations included in this chapter;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_8"/><heading><desig>8.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Accept, hold, and enjoy any gift, devise, or bequest to the Authority or its predecessors to be held for the uses and purposes designated by the donor, if any, or if not so designated, for the general purposes of the Authority, whether given directly or indirectly, and accept, execute, and administer any trust or endowment fund in which it has or may have an interest under the terms of the instrument creating the trust or endowment fund;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_9"/><heading><desig>9.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Borrow money and issue bonds as provided in this chapter and purchase such bonds;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_10"/><heading><desig>10.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Seek financing from, incur or assume indebtedness to, and enter into contractual commitments with the Virginia Public Building Authority and the Virginia College Building Authority, which authorities are authorized to borrow money and make and issue negotiable notes, bonds, and other evidences of indebtedness to provide such financing relating to the hospital facilities or any project;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_11"/><heading><desig>11.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Seek financing from, incur or assume indebtedness to, and enter into contractual commitments with the Commonwealth as otherwise provided by law relating to the hospital facilities or any project;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_12"/><heading><desig>12.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Procure such insurance, participate in such insurance plans, or provide such self-insurance as it deems necessary or convenient to carry out the purposes and provisions of this chapter. The purchase of insurance, participation in an insurance plan, or creation of a self-insurance plan by the Authority is not a waiver or relinquishment of any sovereign immunity to which the Authority or its officers, directors, employees, or agents are otherwise entitled;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_13"/><heading><desig>13.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Develop policies and procedures generally applicable to the procurement of goods, services, and construction based upon competitive principles;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_14"/><heading><desig>14.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Except as to those hospital facilities or any part of such facilities that are leased to the Authority by the University, the control and disposition of which shall be determined by such lease instruments:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_14_a"/><heading><desig>a.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Own, hold, improve, use, and otherwise deal with real or personal property, tangible or intangible, or any right, easement, estate, or interest in such property, acquired by purchase, exchange, gift, assignment, transfer, foreclosure, lease, bequest, devise, operation of law, or other means on such terms and conditions and in such manner as it may deem proper;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_14_b"/><heading><desig>b.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Sell, assign, lease, encumber, mortgage, or otherwise dispose of any project, any other real or personal property, tangible or intangible, any right, easement, estate, or interest in such property, or any deed of trust or mortgage lien interest that it owns, that is under its control or custody or in its possession;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_14_c"/><heading><desig>c.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Release or relinquish any right, title, claim, lien, interest, easement, or demand however acquired, including any equity or right of redemption in property foreclosed by it; and</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_14_d"/><heading><desig>d.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Take any action pursuant to subdivision 14 by public or private sale or with or without public bidding, notwithstanding the provisions of any other law;</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_15"/><heading><desig>15.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Accept loans, grants, contributions, or other assistance from the federal government, the Commonwealth, any political subdivision of the Commonwealth, or any other public or private source to carry out any of the purposes of this chapter and enter into any agreement or contract regarding the acceptance, use, or repayment of any such loan, grant, contribution, or assistance in furtherance of the purposes of this chapter;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_16"/><heading><desig>16.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Exercise the power of eminent domain pursuant to the provisions of Chapter 2 (<citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 25.1-200"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 25.1-200">§ 25.1-200<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000025#     1#          200#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> et seq.) of Title 25.1 to acquire by condemnation any real property, including fixtures and improvements, that it may deem necessary to carry out the purposes of this chapter, upon (i) its adoption of a resolution declaring that the acquisition of such property is in the public interest and necessary for public use and (ii) the approval of the Governor. The Authority may acquire property already devoted to a public use, provided that no property belonging to any locality, religious corporation, unincorporated church, or charitable corporation may be acquired without its consent;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_17"/><heading><desig>17.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Fix, revise, charge, and collect rates, rentals, fees, and other charges for the services or facilities furnished by or on behalf of the Authority and establish policies, procedures, and regulations regarding any such service rendered or the use, occupancy or operation of any such facility. Such charges and policies, procedures, and regulations are not subject to supervision or regulation by any commission, board, bureau, or agency of the Commonwealth except as otherwise provided by law for the providers of health care;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_18"/><heading><desig>18.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Consistent with § 23.1-2407, create, assist in the creation of, own in whole or in part, control, participate in or with any public or private entity, purchase, receive, subscribe for, own, hold, vote, use, employ, sell, mortgage, lend, pledge, or otherwise acquire or dispose of any (i) shares or obligations of, or other interests in, any entities organized for any purpose within or outside the Commonwealth and (ii) obligations of any person or corporation;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_19"/><heading><desig>19.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Participate in joint ventures with individuals, corporations, governmental bodies or agencies, partnerships, associations, insurers, or other entities to facilitate any activities or programs consistent with the public purposes and intent of this chapter;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_20"/><heading><desig>20.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Create a nonprofit entity for the purpose of soliciting, accepting, and administering grants, outright gifts and bequests, endowment gifts and bequests, and gifts and bequests in trust. Such entity shall not engage in trust business or duplicate such activities by the University or its related foundations;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_21"/><heading><desig>21.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Provide appropriate assistance, including making loans and providing time of employees, to corporations, partnerships, associations, joint ventures, or other entities whether such entities are owned or controlled in whole or in part or directly or indirectly by the Authority;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_22"/><heading><desig>22.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Provide, promote, support, and sponsor education and scientific research in medicine, public health, and related fields and promote public knowledge in medicine, public health, and related fields;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_23"/><heading><desig>23.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Administer programs to assist in the delivery of medical and related services to the citizens of the Commonwealth and others;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_24"/><heading><desig>24.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Participate in and administer federal, state, and local programs affecting, supporting, or carrying out any of its purposes; and</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_25"/><heading><desig>25.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Exercise independently the powers conferred by this chapter in furtherance of its corporate and public purposes.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b"/><heading><desig>B.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The exercise of the powers permitted by this chapter shall be deemed the performance of essential governmental functions and matters of public necessity for the entire Commonwealth in the provision of health care, medical and health sciences education, and research for which public moneys may be borrowed, loaned, spent, or otherwise utilized and private property may be utilized or acquired.</p></bodyText></level><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p><citation normalizedCite="1996 VA CH 905"><content><span normalizedCite="1996 Va. Ch. 905">1996, cc. 905<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1996#000905#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1996 VA CH 1046"><content><span normalizedCite="1996 Va. Ch. 1046">1046<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1996#001046#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 23-50.16:2"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 23 -50.16:2">§§ 23-50.16:2<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#142#        23#     50.16#         2#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 23-50.16:6"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 23 -50.16:6">23-50.16:6<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#142#        23#     50.16#         6#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 23-50.16:11"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 23 -50.16:11">23-50.16:11<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#142#        23#     50.16#        11#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 23-50.16:12"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 23 -50.16:12">23-50.16:12<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#142#        23#     50.16#        12#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 23-50.16:13"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 23 -50.16:13">23-50.16:13<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#142#        23#     50.16#        13#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 23-50.16:14"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 23 -50.16:14">23-50.16:14<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#142#        23#     50.16#        14#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2003 VA CH 940"><content><span normalizedCite="2003 Va. Ch. 940">2003, c. 940<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2003#000940#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2006 VA CH 673"><content><span normalizedCite="2006 Va. Ch. 673">2006, c. 673<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2006#000673#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2016 VA CH 588"><content><span normalizedCite="2016 Va. Ch. 588">2016, c. 588<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2016#000588#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PWF0-004G-K3XN-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 23.1.</desig><title>INSTITUTIONS OF HIGHER EDUCATION; OTHER EDUCATIONAL AND CULTURAL INSTITUTIONS</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="subtitle"><heading><desig>SUBTITLE IV.</desig><title>PUBLIC INSTITUTIONS OF HIGHER EDUCATION</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 24.</desig><title>VIRGINIA COMMONWEALTH UNIVERSITY HEALTH SYSTEM AUTHORITY</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjA4OEVGODBENzY4NDcxM0IyQzA1OTEwQzVDODRBOUE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Formation</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QkQyNTA4NEI0QkY3NEQ1OThGQzU2MjA2QUQ4MDEwMzg7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RjYwQjM2NjQzMDM0NDZDOTk1OTdEM0NFMEJGNjA5OUY</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjhGRjg2MzY0NDI4NEVDNTg4M0ExRTk1MjY0MDI2NEU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RjYwQjM2NjQzMDM0NDZDOTk1OTdEM0NFMEJGNjA5OUY</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Joint Venturers</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjIyNEQwRDNCNDc2NEQwNkJGNkFEQTNFMDAxMDQyOUY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MkE1OTExQkYxN0UyNDU0NkIxRjRCOTVFM0UwQ0MxMTk</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Civil Procedure</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MzUxNjJDMEQ5N0YwNDMzM0JDMjEzM0UzOTYzMzI3OTU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDQ1MzNGQjY0MDg4NEFGNUI1M0MwNTNFRDREQjAwN0U7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RUQyRTFGQTg5NEU1NDQzODlBNUNCNUEzNTU5MjkzRTc</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Contracts Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QzY0RTZFMzE0RjkwNDdFQUI5M0U5N0ZFMjYyREMyQzU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QTdGQUE3QkZDMDlBNDQ1MTkzRjEzMEQ1OEUwNzdDOTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NjZEOEU3MEJBRUQ2NDNFNzhFRjAxRTk1OEU1QjY2QTc</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Personal Property</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6ODQzNUIwM0U1NzgzNDkyRDg0MTVFQzRBMUQ2RDM2RDE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QzY0RTZFMzE0RjkwNDdFQUI5M0U5N0ZFMjYyREMyQzU</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Education Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDkzNUEzQzFBNEZBNEFBREIxNDM5MTc1MUU5QjI4MTY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Bonds &amp; Other Indebtedness</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RUNENDg1ODI1NTc1NEREMUI4REY3QjA1RDRDQzExRDE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjZBQUM2RjM4QkI4NDlFMkFCNTBDMzJGNDg0MTgxOUU</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Estate, Gift &amp; Trust Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OENGNTY0MEQ2RTU2NDA2NTk4QjcyNzI2NTBERUU3NUI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NTM0MTFFRkQ3M0E2NEQwREFFMzc3QjBDQjhEQjZEOTM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RkJCNEFGNEQyOEM1NEZBQ0ExREJFNUQyMDM5N0U2Rjg</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Insurance Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDM4MzQ2QUYzMTY0NDQzQTkxRDQwRUUzRUM5RDg0OEM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Agent &amp; Broker Representations</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MEM2RjVEQkU1MDhCNDdEMDlBOTg1NDg5NzYyM0FEQjU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjVGMDBDMkY2QzA0NDYyOTg0MEU4QUQ1QzEwMTlFOEI</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6ODk1Qzg5MzA4MEQ2NDM4QUJGOTZBNkJDOEQ1MTUwNUQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RkE3MEM1QjNFMTFFNEY2MThGNDIwMzQzMzI4RTc4M0M</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Public Contracts Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDA5QTlFMDVCQUY0NEY0NUE1QzMyQzA1QkQyQzJGRUY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Sovereign Immunity</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NzE5NTZBMzJBRDFFNEY1MkI2NzYxMUFFNTc4MDlEQjA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NEY5Mzk4NDFFODQ2NENBRkFDQzIyQzU0NjY2N0M3Q0E</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Real Property Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QUUyRTcxRURBNEY2NEE2MDk3QzBCNzRDOEY0NTZDQzk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Assignments</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6ODVCN0FCRTQ3MEE4NEJCRkE3OTRGOUQzODE4RDZENjc7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDU3NDIyNUI2MzczNEUwMzk0M0Y4MkZDQjk2OUUyRTQ</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDE5OTJEQjEwMzJENEVFMjk3MTcwNDFGRjY0NUVFNjY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RkQ2NkEyQUQwRTRDNEIyNzk2MDhBRUJGRkFFMERDODI</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QzM1MEY0QkQzMjRCNEY3Q0IxMDdBN0U5RUFEMzZERTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QThCNUQyMTcxQjZENEE3QTk4NjIyRDhBMkNBNUI3RDI</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6N0RDOERDRDI5RDAxNDYxNDgwMkU4RTI5QTcxQ0FFNkQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6REY1N0QwQTgyRjkyNEQ2M0FDMDhDQzJCRTM1QTM4NTk</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Termination of Easements</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjkzNEZGNkREQzFCNERBREJDODlCMzJDNjIwRjVDMjI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6REY1N0QwQTgyRjkyNEQ2M0FDMDhDQzJCRTM1QTM4NTk</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Title Acquired</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RjBCODM4MUUxRDNDNDdFRkIwQjczODdCOUJEMTI0NkE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6REIxODFFNEY2NzhBNEMzMUJGOEY3MzRDQUZCMEIxMkY</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification><classificationGroup classificationScheme="indexing-terms"><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem score="90"><className>Education</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDkzNUEzQzFBNEZBNEFBREIxNDM5MTc1MUU5QjI4MTY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></classificationGroup></metadata></legislativeDoc>