<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#349#000058#     1#         3823#">Va. Code Ann. § 58.1-3823</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_58.1-3823"/><heading><desig>§ 58.1-3823.</desig><title>Additional transient occupancy tax for certain counties</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a"/><heading><desig>A.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> In addition to such transient occupancy taxes as are authorized by <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 58.1-3819"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 58.1-3819">§§ 58.1-3819<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000058#     1#         3819#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> through <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 58.1-3821"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 58.1-3821">58.1-3821<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000058#     1#         3821#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, Hanover County, Chesterfield County and Henrico County may impose:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> An additional transient occupancy tax not to exceed four percent of the amount of the charge for the occupancy of any room or space occupied. The tax imposed hereunder shall not apply to rooms or spaces rented and continuously occupied by the same individual or same group of individuals for 30 or more days. The revenues collected from the additional tax shall be designated and spent for promoting tourism, travel or business that generates tourism or travel in the Richmond metropolitan area; and</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> An additional transient occupancy tax not to exceed two percent of the amount of the charge for the occupancy of any room or space occupied. The tax imposed hereunder shall not apply to rooms or spaces rented and continuously occupied by the same individual or same group of individuals for 30 or more days. The revenues collected from the additional tax shall be designated and spent for expanding the Richmond Centre, a convention and exhibition facility in the City of Richmond.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> An additional transient occupancy tax not to exceed one percent of the amount of the charge for the occupancy of any room or space occupied. The tax imposed hereunder shall not apply to rooms or spaces rented and continuously occupied by the same individual or group of individuals for 30 or more days. The revenues collected from the additional tax shall be designated and spent for the development and improvement of the Virginia Performing Arts Foundation's facilities in Richmond, for promoting the use of the Richmond Centre and for promoting tourism, travel or business that generates tourism and travel in the Richmond metropolitan area.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b"/><heading><desig>B.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> In addition to such transient occupancy taxes as are authorized by <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 58.1-3819"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 58.1-3819">§§ 58.1-3819<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000058#     1#         3819#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> through <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 58.1-3821"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 58.1-3821">58.1-3821<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000058#     1#         3821#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, any county with the county manager plan of government may impose an additional transient occupancy tax not to exceed two percent of the amount of the charge for the occupancy of any room or space occupied, provided the county's governing body approves the construction of a county conference center. The tax imposed hereunder shall not apply to rooms or spaces rented and continuously occupied by the same individual or same group of individuals for 30 or more days. The revenues collected from the additional tax shall be designated and spent for the design, construction, debt payment, and operation of such conference center.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c"/><heading><desig>C.</desig></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> In addition to such transient occupancy taxes as are authorized by <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 58.1-3819"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 58.1-3819">§§ 58.1-3819<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000058#     1#         3819#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> through <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 58.1-3821"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 58.1-3821">58.1-3821<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000058#     1#         3821#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, the Counties of James City and York may impose an additional transient occupancy tax not to exceed $ 2 per room per night for the occupancy of any overnight guest room. The revenues collected from the additional tax shall be designated and expended solely for advertising the Historic Triangle area, which includes all of the City of Williamsburg and the Counties of James City and York, as an overnight tourism destination by the members of the Williamsburg Area Destination Marketing Committee of the Greater Williamsburg Chamber and Tourism Alliance. The tax imposed by this subsection shall not apply to travel campground sites or to rooms or spaces rented and continuously occupied by the same individual or same group of individuals for 30 or more days.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The Williamsburg Area Destination Marketing Committee shall consist of the members as provided herein. The governing bodies of the City of Williamsburg, the County of James City, and the County of York shall each designate one of their members to serve as members of the Williamsburg Area Destination Marketing Committee. These three members of the Committee shall have two votes apiece. In no case shall a person who is a member of the Committee by virtue of the designation of a local governing body be eligible to be selected a member of the Committee pursuant to subdivision a.</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c_2_a"/><heading><desig>a.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Further, one member of the Committee shall be selected by the Board of Directors of the Williamsburg Hotel and Motel Association; one member of the Committee shall be from The Colonial Williamsburg Foundation and shall be selected by the Foundation; one member of the Committee shall be an employee of Busch Gardens Europe/Water Country USA and shall be selected by Busch Gardens Europe/Water Country USA; one member of the Committee shall be from the Jamestown-Yorktown Foundation and shall be selected by the Foundation; one member of the Committee shall be selected by the Executive Committee of the Greater Williamsburg Chamber and Tourism Alliance; and one member of the Committee shall be the President and Chief Executive Officer of the VirginiaTourism Authority who shall serve ex officio. Each of these six members of the Committee shall have one vote apiece. The President of the Greater Williamsburg Chamber and Tourism Alliance shall serve ex officio with nonvoting privileges unless chosen by the Executive Committee of the Greater Williamsburg Chamber and Tourism Alliance to serve as its voting representative. The Executive Director of the Williamsburg Hotel and Motel Association shall serve ex officio with nonvoting privileges unless chosen by the Board of Directors of the Williamsburg Hotel and Motel Association to serve as its voting representative.</p><p><pre/>In no case shall more than one person of the same local government, including the governing body of the locality, serve as a member of the Committee at the same time.</p><p><pre/>If at any time a person who has been selected to the Committee by other than a local governing body becomes or is (a) a member of the local governing body of the City of Williamsburg, the County of James City, or the County of York, or (b) an employee of one of such local governments, the person shall be ineligible to serve as a member of the Committee while a member of the local governing body or an employee of one of such local governments. In such case, the body that selected the person to serve as a member of the Commission shall promptly select another person to serve as a member of the Committee.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The Williamsburg Area Destination Marketing Committee shall maintain all authorities granted by this section. The Greater Williamsburg Chamber and Tourism Alliance shall serve as the fiscal agent for the Williamsburg Area Destination Marketing Committee with specific responsibilities to be defined in a contract between such two entities. The contract shall include provisions to reimburse the Greater Williamsburg Chamber and Tourism Alliance for annual audits and any other agreed-upon expenditures. The Williamsburg Area Destination Marketing Committee shall also contract with the Greater Williamsburg Chamber and Tourism Alliance to provide administrative support services as the entities shall mutually agree.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c_4"/><heading><desig>4.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The provisions in subdivision 2 relating to the composition and voting powers of the Williamsburg Area Destination Marketing Committee shall be a condition of the authority to impose the tax provided herein.</p><p><pre/>For purposes of this subsection, "advertising the Historic Triangle area" as an overnight tourism destination means advertising that is intended to attract visitors from a sufficient distance so as to require an overnight stay of at least one night.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d"/><heading><desig>D.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> In addition to such transient occupancy taxes as are authorized by <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 58.1-3819"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 58.1-3819">§§ 58.1-3819<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000058#     1#         3819#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> through <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 58.1-3822"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 58.1-3822">58.1-3822<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000058#     1#         3822#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, Bedford County may impose an additional transient occupancy tax not to exceed two percent of the amount of the charge for the occupancy of any room or space occupied. The tax imposed hereunder shall not apply to rooms or spaces rented and continuously occupied by the same individual or same group of individuals for 30 or more days.</p><p>The revenues collected from the additional tax shall be designated and spent solely for tourism and travel; marketing of tourism; or initiatives that, as determined after consultation with local tourism industry organizations, including representatives of lodging properties located in the county, attract travelers to the locality, increase occupancy at lodging properties, and generate tourism revenues in the locality.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_e"/><heading><desig>E.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> In addition to such transient occupancy taxes as are authorized by <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 58.1-3819"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 58.1-3819">§§ 58.1-3819<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000058#     1#         3819#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> through <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 58.1-3822"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 58.1-3822">58.1-3822<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000058#     1#         3822#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, Botetourt County may impose an additional transient occupancy tax not to exceed two percent of the amount of the charge for the occupancy of any room or space occupied. The tax imposed hereunder shall not apply to rooms or spaces rented and continuously occupied by the same individual or same group of individuals for 30 or more days.</p><p>The revenue generated and collected from the two percent tax rate increase shall be designated and expended solely for advertising the Roanoke metropolitan area as an overnight tourist destination by members of the Roanoke Valley Convention and Visitors Bureau. For purposes of this subsection, "advertising the Roanoke metropolitan area as an overnight tourism destination" means advertising that is intended to attract visitors from a sufficient distance so as to require an overnight stay.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_f"/><heading><desig>F.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The county tax limitations imposed pursuant to <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 58.1-3711"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 58.1-3711">§ 58.1-3711<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000058#     1#         3711#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> shall apply to any tax levied under this section, mutatis mutandis.</p></bodyText></level><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p><citation normalizedCite="1996 VA CH 712"><content><span normalizedCite="1996 Va. Ch. 712">1996, c. 712<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1996#000712#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1998 VA CH 74"><content><span normalizedCite="1998 Va. Ch. 74">1998, cc. 74<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1998#000074#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1998 VA CH 444"><content><span normalizedCite="1998 Va. Ch. 444">444<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1998#000444#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2002 VA CH 173"><content><span normalizedCite="2002 Va. Ch. 173">2002, cc. 173<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2002#000173#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2002 VA CH 259"><content><span normalizedCite="2002 Va. Ch. 259">259<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2002#000259#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2004 VA CH 50"><content><span normalizedCite="2004 Va. Ch. 50">2004, cc. 50<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2004#000050#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2004 VA CH 610"><content><span normalizedCite="2004 Va. Ch. 610">610<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2004#000610#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2004 VA CH 828"><content><span normalizedCite="2004 Va. Ch. 828">828<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2004#000828#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2006 VA CH 377"><content><span normalizedCite="2006 Va. Ch. 377">2006, c. 377<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2006#000377#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2008 VA CH 839"><content><span normalizedCite="2008 Va. Ch. 839">2008, c. 839<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2008#000839#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2011 VA CH 677"><content><span normalizedCite="2011 Va. Ch. 677">2011, c. 677<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2011#000677#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2016 VA CH 52"><content><span normalizedCite="2016 Va. Ch. 52">2016, cc. 52<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2016#000052#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2016 VA CH 56"><content><span normalizedCite="2016 Va. Ch. 56">56<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2016#000056#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2016 VA CH 305"><content><span normalizedCite="2016 Va. Ch. 305">305<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2016#000305#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PV10-004G-K1HY-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 58.1.</desig><title>TAXATION</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="subtitle"><heading><desig>SUBTITLE III.</desig><title>LOCAL TAXES</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 38.</desig><title>MISCELLANEOUS TAXES</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="article"><heading><desig>ARTICLE 6.</desig><title>TRANSIENT OCCUPANCY TAX</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Governments</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjdEQjE4OUJDMzQxNDNEMEI0RTI1QUFCMzJENjEwRTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Finance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjMzOTBBRTg2MUVDNDdDNUE1M0QxNDk1RERCNjNCN0I7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Njg1MkM3RkYyNzIxNEVFRkJFMTI2NUM4NUU1ODdEM0Q</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Tax Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OTNEM0E2OEE0RkQyNEY1MDhBQzdGMkQ4ODI4QTJDODE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Collection of Taxes</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RTg5OTkxQ0U0RjIwNEY4Qjg2MkQ1OTZCRTM2RDY4MTM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjkxRkVDMkNDMjBGNDdFMkI1RDQ3Nzk4QjgwOTBGQjU</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MTdCMzZBOUNFNjAwNEZFM0E0NEU3ODJFM0EyRDMyNEI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RUYwREVBQ0NGQ0UxNDY2REE0MzMzMDE5RDRGNTEyNjg</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6REI3MDI2QkU5NDE2NEY4NTgyMUM5MTE5OUE4NjlDQ0Y7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NzQ2RjMxMjUxMEFCNDA1N0I5QUY0OUY5Qzc0RDkwNEI</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Imposition of Tax</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Q0U4RkI4RTU5QTQ0NDYzNThGNEFCRERBMDY3Q0Q0MzY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NzQ2RjMxMjUxMEFCNDA1N0I5QUY0OUY5Qzc0RDkwNEI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification><classificationGroup classificationScheme="indexing-terms"><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem score="90"><className>Tax</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OTNEM0E2OEE0RkQyNEY1MDhBQzdGMkQ4ODI4QTJDODE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></classificationGroup></metadata></legislativeDoc>