<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#142#        55#     210.3#        01#">Va. Code Ann. § 55-210.3:01</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_55-210.3_01"/><heading><desig>§ 55-210.3:01.</desig><title>Bank deposits and funds in financial organizations</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a"/><heading><desig>A.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Any demand, savings, or matured time deposit with a banking or financial organization, including deposits that are automatically renewable, and any funds paid toward the purchase of shares, a mutual investment certificate, or any other interest in a banking or financial organization is presumed abandoned unless the owner has, within five years:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> In the case of a deposit or ownership of shares, increased or decreased the amount of the deposit or the number of shares owned, or presented the passbook or other similar evidence of the deposit or ownership of shares for the crediting of interest or dividends, or negotiated a check in payment of interest or dividends on a time deposit or ownership of shares;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Communicated in writing with the banking or financial organization concerning the property;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Otherwise indicated an interest in the property as evidenced by a memorandum or other record on file prepared by an employee of the banking or financial organization;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_4"/><heading><desig>4.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Owned other property to which subdivision A 1, A 2, or A 3 is applicable if the banking or financial organization communicated in writing with the owner with regard to the property that would otherwise be presumed abandoned under this paragraph at the address to which communications regarding the other property regularly are sent;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_5"/><heading><desig>5.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Had another relationship with the banking or financial organization concerning which the owner has (i) communicated in writing with the banking or financial organization, or (ii) otherwise indicated an interest as evidenced by a memorandum or other record on file prepared by an employee of the banking or financial organization if the banking or financial organization communicates in writing with the owner with regard to the property that would otherwise be abandoned under this paragraph at the address to which communications regarding the other relationship regularly are sent; or</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_6"/><heading><desig>6.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A deposit made with or purchase of shares in a banking or financial organization by a court or by a guardian pursuant to order of a court or by any other person for the benefit of a person who was an infant at the time of the making of such deposit or purchase of shares, which deposit or ownership of shares is subject to withdrawal or transfer only upon the further order of such court or such guardian or other person, shall not be subject to the provisions of this chapter until one year after such infant attains the age of eighteen years or until one year after the death of such infant, whichever occurs sooner. These accounts are not subject to dormant service charges.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b"/><heading><desig>B.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Notwithstanding any other provision of this section, share accounts of a member of a state or federally chartered credit union that is subject to or covered by life savings insurance provided by the credit union at no additional charge to the member shall be presumed abandoned five years after the date of the second mailing of a statement of account or other notification or communication that was returned as undeliverable, or after the date the credit union discontinued the mailings to the member, whichever is earlier. Funds held or owing under the life savings insurance policy are presumed abandoned pursuant to <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 55-210.4:01"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 55 -210.4:01">§ 55-210.4:01.<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#142#        55#     210.4#        01#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation></p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c"/><heading><desig>C.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> For purposes of this section, "property" includes any interest or dividends thereon. No banking or financial organization may deduct any service charge or cease to accrue interest on any account, from the date the account is declared dormant or inactive by such organization except in conformity with cessation of interest or service charges generally assessed upon active accounts. With respect to any property described in this section, a holder may not impose any charges due to dormancy or inactivity which differ from those imposed on active accounts or cease to pay interest unless:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> There is an enforceable contract between the holder and the owner of the property pursuant to which the holder may impose those charges or cease payment of interest;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> For property in excess of $ 100, the holder, no more than three months prior to the initial imposition of those charges or cessation of interest, has given written notice to the owner of the amount of those charges at the last known address of the owner stating that those charges will be imposed or that interest will cease; however, such notice need not be given with respect to charges imposed or interest ceased before July 1, 1984; and</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> When the holder imposes those charges or ceases payment of interest, it does not for any reason other than to correct a documented internal error reverse or cancel those charges or retroactively credit interest with respect to such property. Notwithstanding any provision of this subsection to the contrary, a holder that is a state-chartered credit union may refund charges or reverse or cancel those charges or retroactively credit interest with respect to such property to the same extent that a federally-chartered credit union is authorized so to do pursuant to applicable provisions of federal law.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d"/><heading><desig>D.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Any automatically renewable property to which this section applies is matured upon the expiration of its initial time period. However, in the case of any renewal to which the owner consents at or about the time of renewal by communicating in writing with the banking or financial organization or otherwise indicates consent as specified in subsection A of this section, the property is matured upon the expiration of the last time period for which consent was given. If, at the time provided for delivery in subsection D of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 55-210.12"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 55 -210.12">§ 55-210.12<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#123#000055#    210.12#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, a penalty or forfeiture in the payment of interest would result from the delivery of the property, the time for delivery is extended until the time when no penalty or forfeiture would result. Notwithstanding any other provision of this section to the contrary, any automatically renewable time deposit that has matured shall be presumed abandoned five years after the date of the second mailing of a statement of account or other notification or communication that was returned as undeliverable, or after the date the holder discontinued the mailings to the apparent owner, whichever is earlier. However, any automatically renewable time deposit for which no such statement or other notification or mailing is required to be sent by the banking or financial organization shall be presumed abandoned as otherwise provided in this section.</p></bodyText></level><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p>1984, c. 121; 1985, c. 294; <citation normalizedCite="1991 VA CH 357"><content><span normalizedCite="1991 Va. Ch. 357">1991, c. 357<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1991#000357#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1995 VA CH 624"><content><span normalizedCite="1995 Va. Ch. 624">1995, c. 624<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1995#000624#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1996 VA CH 419"><content><span normalizedCite="1996 Va. Ch. 419">1996, c. 419<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1996#000419#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2000 VA CH 733"><content><span normalizedCite="2000 Va. Ch. 733">2000, cc. 733<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2000#000733#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2000 VA CH 745"><content><span normalizedCite="2000 Va. Ch. 745">745<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2000#000745#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2008 VA CH 90"><content><span normalizedCite="2008 Va. Ch. 90">2008, cc. 90<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2008#000090#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2008 VA CH 556"><content><span normalizedCite="2008 Va. Ch. 556">556<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2008#000556#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PTD0-004G-K31F-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 55.</desig><title>PROPERTY AND CONVEYANCES</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 11.1.</desig><title>DISPOSITION OF UNCLAIMED PROPERTY</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="article"><heading><desig>ARTICLE 2.</desig><title>PROPERTY ABANDONED OR ASSUMED ABANDONED</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Banking Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjQyMUFCOUJBNURBNEFDREE3MTNCNDk5QkQ4NUM3RjI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Federal Credit Unions</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MzU5NTEzOTI2M0JCNDhBOTgzNzFERUQ3OUYzNTJFMTk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RTc3MUQ5Rjg4MjYzNENDQzk2QjQ0NzA5RjFDNzY0RDk</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDREMDBDMEE3QUU4NEZDRkE2REY4QTFCOTFEOUEyN0M7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6N0Y1RjBFRTIyMTY1NEU3RUEyQTMwRDEzRTY2NTlBMEY</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Federal Credit Unions</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MzU5NTEzOTI2M0JCNDhBOTgzNzFERUQ3OUYzNTJFMTk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjQyMUFCOUJBNURBNEFDREE3MTNCNDk5QkQ4NUM3RjI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Criminal Law &amp; Procedure</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NEU0RkE1OUQwNUQwNDgxODhEODZCMjkzOTg3NThBNzk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Abandonment</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUYxM0E4OTIxQjI4NEQ4RDhDNjc3RDRGNkE2QTlENzM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUZDMDZDRkNGMDE4NEExRTkyNjY1NEY0NjI5RDA4RjA</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification><classificationGroup classificationScheme="indexing-terms"><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem score="90"><className>Real Property</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QUUyRTcxRURBNEY2NEE2MDk3QzBCNzRDOEY0NTZDQzk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></classificationGroup></metadata></legislativeDoc>