<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#958#0000000062#0000000001#     44.19#0000000020#">Va. Code Ann. § 62.1-44.19:20</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_62.1-44.19_20"/><heading><desig>§ 62.1-44.19:20.</desig><title>Nutrient credit certification</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a"/><heading><desig>A.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The Board may adopt regulations for the purpose of establishing procedures for the certification of point source nutrient credits except that no certification shall be required for point source nitrogen and point source phosphorus credits generated by point sources regulated under the Watershed General Virginia Pollutant Discharge Elimination System Permit issued pursuant to <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 62.1-44.19:14"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 62.1-44.19:14">§ 62.1-44.19:14.<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#958#0000000062#0000000001#     44.19#0000000014#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> The Board shall adopt regulations for the purpose of establishing procedures for the certification of nonpoint source nutrient credits.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b"/><heading><desig>B.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Regulations adopted pursuant to this section shall:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Establish procedures for the certification and registration of credits, including:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_1_a"/><heading><desig>a.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Certifying credits that may be generated from effective nutrient controls or removal practices, including activities associated with the types of facilities or practices historically regulated by the Board, such as water withdrawal and treatment and wastewater collection, treatment, and beneficial reuse;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_1_b"/><heading><desig>b.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Certifying credits that may be generated from agricultural and urban stormwater best management practices, use or management of manures, managed turf, land use conversion, stream or wetlands projects, shellfish aquaculture, algal harvesting, and other established or innovative methods of nutrient control or removal, as appropriate;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_1_c"/><heading><desig>c.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Establishing a process and standards for wetland or stream credits to be converted to nutrient credits. Such process and standards shall only apply to wetland or stream credits that were established after July 1, 2005, and have not been transferred or used. Under no circumstances shall such credits be used for both wetland or stream credit and nutrient credit purposes;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_1_d"/><heading><desig>d.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Certifying credits from multiple practices that are bundled as a package by the applicant;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_1_e"/><heading><desig>e.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Prohibiting the certification of credits generated from activities funded by federal or state water quality grant funds other than controls and practices under subdivision B 1 a; however, baseline levels may be achieved through the use of such grants;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_1_f"/><heading><desig>f.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Establishing a timely and efficient certification process including application requirements, a reasonable application fee schedule not to exceed $ 10,000 per application, and review and approval procedures;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_1_g"/><heading><desig>g.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Requiring public notification of a proposed nutrient credit-generating entity; and</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_1_h"/><heading><desig>h.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Establishing a timeline for the consideration of certification applications for land conversion projects. The timeline shall provide that within 30 days of receipt of an application the Department shall, if warranted, conduct a site visit and that within 45 days of receipt of an application the Department shall either determine that the application is complete or request additional specific information from the applicant. A determination that an application for a land conversion project is complete shall not require the Department to issue the certification. The Department shall deny, approve, or approve with conditions an application within 15 days of the Department's determination that the application is complete. When the request for credit release is made concurrently with the application for a land conversion project certification, the concurrent release shall be processed on the same timeline. When the request for credit release is from a previously approved land conversion project, the Department shall schedule a site visit, if warranted, within 30 days of the request and shall deny, approve, or approve with conditions the release within 15 days of the site visit or determination that a site visit is not warranted. The timelines set out in this subdivision shall be implemented prior to adoption of regulations. The Department shall release credits from a land conversion project after it is satisfied that the applicant has met the criteria for release in an approved nutrient reduction implementation plan.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Establish credit calculation procedures for proposed credit-generating practices, including the determination of:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_2_a"/><heading><desig>a.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Baselines for credits certified under subdivision B 1 a in accordance with any applicable provisions of the Virginia Chesapeake Bay TMDL Watershed Implementation Plan or approved TMDLs;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_2_b"/><heading><desig>b.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Baselines established for agricultural practices, which shall be those actions necessary to achieve a level of reduction assigned in the Virginia Chesapeake Bay TMDL Watershed Implementation Plan or approved TMDLs as implemented on the tract, field, or other land area under consideration;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_2_c"/><heading><desig>c.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Baselines for urban practices from new development and redevelopment, which shall be in compliance with postconstruction nutrient loading requirements of the Virginia Stormwater Management Program regulations. Baselines for all other existing development shall be at a level necessary to achieve the reductions assigned in the urban sector in the Virginia Chesapeake Bay TMDL Watershed Implementation Plan or approved TMDLs;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_2_d"/><heading><desig>d.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Baselines for land use conversion, which shall be based on the pre-conversion land use and the level of reductions assigned in the Virginia Chesapeake Bay TMDL Watershed Implementation Plan or approved TMDLs applicable to that land use;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_2_e"/><heading><desig>e.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Baselines for other nonpoint source credit-generating practices, which shall be based on the Virginia Chesapeake Bay TMDL Watershed Implementation Plan or approved TMDLs using the best available scientific and technical information;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_2_f"/><heading><desig>f.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Unless otherwise established by the Board, for certification within the Chesapeake Bay Watershed a credit-generating practice that involves land use conversion, which shall represent controls beyond those in place as of July 1, 2005. For other waters for which a TMDL has been approved, the practice shall represent controls beyond those in place at the time of TMDL approval;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_2_g"/><heading><desig>g.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Baseline dates for all other credit-generating practices, which shall be based on the Virginia Chesapeake Bay TMDL Watershed Implementation Plan or approved TMDLs; and</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_2_h"/><heading><desig>h.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Credit quantities, which shall be established using the best available scientific and technical information at the time of certification;</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Provide certification of credits on an appropriate temporal basis, such as annual, term of years, or perpetual, depending on the nature of the credit-generating practice. A credit shall be certified for a term of no less than 12 months;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_4"/><heading><desig>4.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Establish requirements to reasonably assure the generation of the credit depending on the nature of the credit-generating activity and use, such as legal instruments for perpetual credits, operation and maintenance requirements, and associated financial assurance requirements. Financial assurance requirements may include letters of credit, escrows, surety bonds, insurance, and where the credits are used or generated by a locality, authority, utility, sanitation district, or permittee operating an MS4 or a point source permitted under this article, its existing tax or rate authority;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_5"/><heading><desig>5.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Establish appropriate reporting requirements;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_6"/><heading><desig>6.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Provide for the ability of the Department to inspect or audit for compliance with the requirements of such regulations;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_7"/><heading><desig>7.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Provide that the option to acquire nutrient credits for compliance purposes shall not eliminate any requirement to comply with local water quality requirements;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_8"/><heading><desig>8.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Establish a credit retirement requirement whereby five percent of nonpoint source credits in the Chesapeake Bay Watershed other than controls and practices under subdivision B 1 a are permanently retired at the time of certification pursuant to this section for the purposes of offsetting growth in unregulated nutrient loads; and</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_9"/><heading><desig>9.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Establish such other requirements as the Board deems necessary and appropriate.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c"/><heading><desig>C.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Prior to the adoption of such regulations, the Board shall certify (i) credits that may be generated from effective nutrient controls or removal practices, including activities associated with the types of facilities or practices historically regulated by the Board, such as water withdrawal and treatment and wastewater collection, treatment, and beneficial reuse, on a case-by-case basis using the best available scientific and technical information and (ii) credits that are located in tributaries outside of the Chesapeake Bay watershed as defined in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 62.1-44.15:35"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 62.1-44.15:35">§ 62.1-44.15:35<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#958#0000000062#0000000001#     44.15#0000000035#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, using an average of the nutrient removal rates for each practice identified in Appendix A of the Department's document "Trading Nutrient Reductions from Nonpoint Source Best Management Practices in the Chesapeake Bay Watershed: Guidance for Agricultural Landowners and Your Potential Trading Partners. "</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d"/><heading><desig>D.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The Department shall establish and maintain an online Virginia Nutrient Credit Registry of credits as follows:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The registry shall include all nonpoint source credits certified pursuant to this article and may include point source nitrogen and point source phosphorus credits generated from point sources covered by the general permit issued pursuant to <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 62.1-44.19:14"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 62.1-44.19:14">§ 62.1-44.19:14<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#958#0000000062#0000000001#     44.19#0000000014#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> or point source nutrient credits certified pursuant to this section at the option of the owner. No other credits shall be valid for compliance purposes.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Registration of credits on the registry shall not preclude or restrict the right of the owner of such credits from transferring the credits on such commercial terms as may be established by and between the owner and the regulated or unregulated party acquiring the credits.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The Department shall establish procedures for the listing and tracking of credits on the registry, including but not limited to (i) notification of the availability of new nutrient credits to the locality where the credit-generating practice is implemented at least five business days prior to listing on the registry to provide the locality an opportunity to acquire such credits at fair market value for compliance purposes and (ii) notification that the listing of credits on the registry does not constitute a representation by the Board or the owner that the credits will satisfy the specific regulatory requirements applicable to the prospective user's intended use and that the prospective user is encouraged to contact the Board for technical assistance to identify limitations, if any, applicable to the intended use.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d_4"/><heading><desig>4.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The registry shall be publicly accessible without charge.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_e"/><heading><desig>E.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The owner or operator of a nonpoint source nutrient credit-generating entity that fails to comply with the provisions of this section shall be subject to the enforcement and penalty provisions of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 62.1-44.19:22"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 62.1-44.19:22">§ 62.1-44.19:22.<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#958#0000000062#0000000001#     44.19#0000000022#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation></p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_f"/><heading><desig>F.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Nutrient credits from stormwater nonpoint nutrient credit-generating facilities in receipt of a Nonpoint Nutrient Offset Authorization for Transfer letter from the Department prior to July 1, 2012, shall be considered certified nutrient credits and shall not be subject to further certification requirements or to the credit retirement requirement under subdivision B 8. However, such facilities shall be subject to the other provisions of this article, including registration, inspection, reporting, and enforcement.</p></bodyText></level><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p><citation normalizedCite="2012 VA CH 748"><content><span normalizedCite="2012 Va. Ch. 748">2012, cc. 748<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2012#000748#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2012 VA CH 808"><content><span normalizedCite="2012 Va. Ch. 808">808<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2012#000808#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2013 VA CH 756"><content><span normalizedCite="2013 Va. Ch. 756">2013, cc. 756<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2013#000756#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2013 VA CH 793"><content><span normalizedCite="2013 Va. Ch. 793">793<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2013#000793#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2016 VA CH 653"><content><span normalizedCite="2016 Va. Ch. 653">2016, c. 653<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2016#000653#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PVV0-004G-K4YF-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 62.1.</desig><title>WATERS OF THE STATE, PORTS AND HARBORS</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 3.1.</desig><title>STATE WATER CONTROL LAW</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="article"><heading><desig>ARTICLE 4.02.</desig><title>CHESAPEAKE BAY WATERSHED NUTRIENT CREDIT EXCHANGE PROGRAM.</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Wetlands</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RjlGMTcxQjZCNjVDNDVFQzhBMjE0MTE3MzI5NDU1REM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NjY0QzdBQjM3RUJDNDM0NEFGMjE1RUE5MUEzQzRCODI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Environmental Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NzFDRDYyNkI2QjhBNDg3NTkyRjRDRkZEQjlCRkRBQzM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Storm Water Discharges</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDI5NTAzOEE3MEE3NDI5NTlBMjJGNEI5Njc2MUEzODY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QzJFQjdFQzcwMkM5NDQwMDg4ODU0RTMyODkxRDFFMzI</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Wetlands</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RjlGMTcxQjZCNjVDNDVFQzhBMjE0MTE3MzI5NDU1REM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NjY0QzdBQjM3RUJDNDM0NEFGMjE1RUE5MUEzQzRCODI</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Wetlands Management</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QzY2NjI1NjQ3Qzk2NDE5NzlGQjFDNTkzQjg5QTAyMkQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NTkwMDY1RDExQ0YwNDQ1RTlERUVFMjUzMUI1MkFDOTU</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Real Property Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QUUyRTcxRURBNEY2NEE2MDk3QzBCNzRDOEY0NTZDQzk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Administrative Allocations</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MTg4OTREMDg3NzMyNDY4Rjg0Mzc4RjgzMTI1MTgxN0U7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6REQ5NzhGQjlGRUY3NEU0M0FCQTQwMDMyOTAxMTlENzY</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Administrative Procedure</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDVEOThDRjUzNTFDNDc4NEE2OEYzQzEzRjU3REYxNDg7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NjcyQTdEMEUxODYyNDY0OThFQTg1NUNGMjFBMTkxQ0M</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NzIxOUEwNTk5MTZCNEM3ODgxNjAzMkQ3MzIxMzQ1OUE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Nzg5NTlBMjdCREU3NDE1OTg1QjFCODExQkZENkM1Nzk</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification><classificationGroup classificationScheme="indexing-terms"><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem score="90"><className>Admiralty &amp; Maritime</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QzRDNDVDOTdGRUQ1NDE1M0I1RjRBRDFBRTI3ODFGMDk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem score="90"><className>Transportation</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RTYzRTk5RDVBQkQ2NDcwQzk2NTU3ODQ5OEE3NDlBNzk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></classificationGroup></metadata></legislativeDoc>