<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#349#000038#     2#       3521.1#">Va. Code Ann. § 38.2-3521.1</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_38.2-3521.1"/><heading><desig>§ 38.2-3521.1.</desig><title>Group accident and sickness insurance definitions</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><bodyText><p>Except as provided in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 38.2-3522.1"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 38.2-3522.1">§ 38.2-3522.1<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000038#     2#       3522.1#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, no policy of group accident and sickness insurance shall be delivered in this Commonwealth unless it conforms to one of the following descriptions:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a"/><heading><desig>A.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A policy issued to an employer, or to the trustees of a fund established by an employer, which employer or trustees shall be deemed the policyholder, to insure employees of the employer for the benefit of persons other than the employer, subject to the following requirements:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The employees eligible for insurance under the policy shall be all of the employees of the employer, or all of any class or classes thereof. The policy may provide that the term "employees" shall include the employees of one or more subsidiary corporations, and the employees, individual proprietors, and partners of one or more affiliated corporations, proprietorships or partnerships if the business of the employer and of such affiliated corporations, proprietorships or partnerships is under common control. The policy may provide that the term "employees" shall include retired employees, former employees and directors of a corporate employer. A policy issued to insure the employees of a public body may provide that the term "employees" shall include elected or appointed officials.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The premium for the policy shall be paid either from the employer's funds or from funds contributed by the insured employees, or from both. Except as provided in subdivision 3 of this subsection, a policy on which no part of the premium is to be derived from funds contributed by the insured employees must insure all eligible employees, except those who reject such coverage in writing.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> An insurer may exclude or limit the coverage on any person as to whom evidence of individual insurability is not satisfactory to the insurer, except as otherwise prohibited in this title.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b"/><heading><desig>B.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A policy which is:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Not subject to Chapter 37.1 (<citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 38.2-3727"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 38.2-3727">§ 38.2-3727<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000038#     2#         3727#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> et seq.) of this title, and</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Issued to a creditor or its parent holding company or to a trustee or trustees or agent designated by two or more creditors, which creditor, holding company, affiliate, trustee, trustees or agent shall be deemed the policyholder, to insure debtors of the creditor or creditors with respect to their indebtedness, subject to the following requirements:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_2_a"/><heading><desig>a.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The debtors eligible for insurance under the policy shall be all of the debtors of the creditor or creditors, or all of any class or classes thereof. The policy may provide that the term "debtors" shall include:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_2_a_1"/><heading><desig>(1)</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Borrowers of money or purchasers or lessees of goods, services, or property for which payment is arranged through a credit transaction;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_2_a_2"/><heading><desig>(2)</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The debtors of one or more subsidiary corporations; and</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_2_a_3"/><heading><desig>(3)</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The debtors of one or more affiliated corporations, proprietorships or partnerships if the business of the policyholder and of such affiliated corporations, proprietorships or partnerships is under common control.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_2_b"/><heading><desig>b.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The premium for the policy shall be paid either from the creditor's funds, or from charges collected from the insured debtors, or from both. Except as provided in subdivision 3 of this subsection, a policy on which no part of the premium is to be derived from funds contributed by insured debtors specifically for their insurance must insure all eligible debtors.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> An insurer may exclude any debtors as to whom evidence of individual insurability is not satisfactory to the insurer.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_4"/><heading><desig>4.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The total amount of insurance payable with respect to an indebtedness shall not exceed the greater of the scheduled or actual amount of unpaid indebtedness to the creditor. The insurer may exclude any payments which are delinquent on the date the debtor becomes disabled as defined in the policy.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_5"/><heading><desig>5.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The insurance may be payable to the creditor or any successor to the right, title, and interest of the creditor. Such payment or payments shall reduce or extinguish the unpaid indebtedness of the debtor to the extent of each such payment and any excess of the insurance shall be payable to the insured or the estate of the insured.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_6"/><heading><desig>6.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Notwithstanding the preceding provisions of this section, insurance on agricultural credit transaction commitments may be written up to the amount of the loan commitment. Insurance on educational credit transaction commitments may be written up to the amount of the loan commitment less the amount of any repayments made on the loan.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c"/><heading><desig>C.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A policy issued to a labor union, or similar employee organization, which labor union or organization shall be deemed to be the policyholder, to insure members of such union or organization for the benefit of persons other than the union or organization or any of its officials, representatives, or agents, subject to the following requirements:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The members eligible for insurance under the policy shall be all of the members of the union or organization, or all of any class or classes thereof.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The premium for the policy shall be paid either from funds of the union or organization, or from funds contributed by the insured members specifically for their insurance, or from both. Except as provided in subdivision 3 of this subsection, a policy on which no part of the premium is to be derived from funds contributed by the insured members specifically for their insurance must insure all eligible members, except those who reject such coverage in writing.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> An insurer may exclude or limit the coverage on any person as to whom evidence of individual insurability is not satisfactory to the insurer, except as otherwise prohibited in this title.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d"/><heading><desig>D.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A policy issued (i) to or for a multiple employer welfare arrangement, a rural electric cooperative, or a rural electric telephone cooperative as these terms are defined in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="29 USC 1002"><content><span normalizedCite="29 U.S.C. 1002">29 U.S.C. § 1002,<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1828#123#000029#       1002#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> or (ii) to a trust, or to the trustees of a fund, established or adopted by or for two or more employers, or by one or more labor unions of similar employee organizations, or by one or more employers and one or more labor unions or similar employee organizations, which trust or trustees shall be deemed the policyholder, to insure employees of the employers or members of the unions or organizations for the benefit of persons other than the employers or the unions or organizations, subject to the following requirements:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The persons eligible for insurance shall be all of the employees of the employers or all of the members of the unions or organizations, or all of any class or classes thereof. The policy may provide that the term "employee" shall include the employees of one or more subsidiary corporations, and the employees, individual proprietors, and partners of one or more affiliated corporations, proprietorships or partnerships if the business of the employer and of such affiliated corporations, proprietorships or partnerships is under common control. The policy may provide that the term "employees" shall include retired employees, former employees and directors of a corporate employer. The policy may provide that the term "employees" shall include the trustees or their employees, or both, if their duties are principally connected with such trusteeship.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The premium for the policy shall be paid from funds contributed by the employer or employers of the insured persons, or by the union or unions or similar employee organizations, or by both, or from funds contributed by the insured persons or from both the insured persons and the employers or unions or similar employee organizations. Except as provided in subdivision 3 of this subsection, a policy on which no part of the premium is to be derived from funds contributed by the insured persons specifically for their insurance must insure all eligible persons, except those who reject such coverage in writing.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> An insurer may exclude or limit the coverage on any person as to whom evidence of individual insurability is not satisfactory to the insurer, except as otherwise prohibited in this title.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_e"/><heading><desig>E.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> 1. A policy issued to an association or to a trust or to the trustees of a fund established, created, or maintained for the benefit of members of one or more associations which association or trust shall be deemed the policyholder. The association or associations shall:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_e_a"/><heading><desig>a.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Have at the outset a minimum of 100 persons;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_e_b"/><heading><desig>b.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Have been organized and maintained in good faith for purposes other than that of obtaining insurance;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_e_c"/><heading><desig>c.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Have been in active existence for at least five years;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_e_d"/><heading><desig>d.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Have a constitution and bylaws which provide that (i) the association or associations hold regular meetings not less than annually to further purposes of the members, (ii) except for credit unions, the association or associations collect dues or solicit contributions from members, and (iii) the members have voting privileges and representation on the governing board and committees;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_e_e"/><heading><desig>e.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Does not condition membership in the association on any health status-related factor relating to an individual (including an employee of an employer or a dependent of an employee);</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_e_f"/><heading><desig>f.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Makes health insurance coverage offered through the association available to all members regardless of any health status-related factor relating to such members (or individuals eligible for coverage through a member);</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_e_g"/><heading><desig>g.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Does not make health insurance coverage offered through the association available other than in connection with a member of the association; and</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_e_h"/><heading><desig>h.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Meets such additional requirements as may be imposed under the laws of this Commonwealth.</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_e_h_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The policy shall be subject to the following requirements:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_e_h_2_a"/><heading><desig>a.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The policy may insure members of such association or associations, employees thereof or employees of members, or one or more of the preceding or all of any class or classes thereof for the benefit of persons other than the employee's employer.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_e_h_2_b"/><heading><desig>b.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The premium for the policy shall be paid from funds contributed by the association or associations, or by employer members, or by both, or from funds contributed by the covered persons or from both the covered persons and the association, associations, or employer members.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_e_h_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Except as provided in subdivision 4 of this subsection, a policy on which no part of the premium is to be derived from funds contributed by the covered persons specifically for their insurance must insure all eligible persons, except those who reject such coverage in writing.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_e_h_4"/><heading><desig>4.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> An insurer may exclude or limit the coverage on any person as to whom evidence of individual insurability is not satisfactory to the insurer, except as otherwise prohibited in this title.</p></bodyText></level></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_f"/><heading><desig>F.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A policy issued to a credit union or to a trustee or trustees or agent designated by two or more credit unions, which credit union, trustee, trustees, or agent shall be deemed the policyholder, to insure members of such credit union or credit unions for the benefit of persons other than the credit union or credit unions, trustee or trustees, or agent or any of their officials, subject to the following requirements:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_f_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The members eligible for insurance shall be all of the members of the credit union or credit unions, or all of any class or classes thereof.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_f_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The premium for the policy shall be paid by the policyholder from the credit union's funds and, except as provided in subdivision 3 of this subsection, must insure all eligible members.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_f_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> An insurer may exclude or limit the coverage on any person as to whom evidence of individual insurability is not satisfactory to the insurer.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_g"/><heading><desig>G.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A policy issued to a health maintenance organization as provided in subsection B of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 38.2-4314"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 38.2-4314">§ 38.2-4314<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000038#     2#         4314#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_h"/><heading><desig>H.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A policy of blanket insurance issued in accordance with <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 38.2-3521.2"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 38.2-3521.2">§ 38.2-3521.2.<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000038#     2#       3521.2#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation></p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_i"/><heading><desig>I.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The provisions of this section shall not apply in any instance in which the provisions of this section are inconsistent or in conflict with a provision of Article 6 (<citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 38.2-3438"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 38.2-3438">§ 38.2-3438<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000038#     2#         3438#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> et seq.) of Chapter 34.</p></bodyText></level></level><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p><citation normalizedCite="1998 VA CH 154"><content><span normalizedCite="1998 Va. Ch. 154">1998, c. 154<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1998#000154#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2013 VA CH 751"><content><span normalizedCite="2013 Va. Ch. 751">2013, c. 751<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2013#000751#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2014 VA CH 350"><content><span normalizedCite="2014 Va. Ch. 350">2014, c. 350<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2014#000350#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PV30-004G-K2XM-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 38.2.</desig><title>INSURANCE</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 35.</desig><title>ACCIDENT AND SICKNESS INSURANCE POLICIES</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="article"><heading><desig>ARTICLE 3.</desig><title>GROUP ACCIDENT AND SICKNESS INSURANCE POLICIES</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Banking Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjQyMUFCOUJBNURBNEFDREE3MTNCNDk5QkQ4NUM3RjI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Federal Credit Unions</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MzU5NTEzOTI2M0JCNDhBOTgzNzFERUQ3OUYzNTJFMTk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RTc3MUQ5Rjg4MjYzNENDQzk2QjQ0NzA5RjFDNzY0RDk</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Federal Credit Unions</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MzU5NTEzOTI2M0JCNDhBOTgzNzFERUQ3OUYzNTJFMTk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjQyMUFCOUJBNURBNEFDREE3MTNCNDk5QkQ4NUM3RjI</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Health Maintenance Organizations</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MzNDMEYyOTY3NjdBNEE4MDlCQTlDMUQxRDMyMUZCNDM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NkUxMkVDQjJDOEY5NDVDQ0E5NTFEMTlDMjIwNzVERjc</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjA4OEVGODBENzY4NDcxM0IyQzA1OTEwQzVDODRBOUE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MTFDNUE2QkIzNDRENEMwMjlBRUJCQ0IyNURDNjIxNjE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QTNCQUY4MUFBQzI2NEY1QzhENjQzNDZDRjRERTcwNDQ</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NzQwNjJBMUVBRDAwNEVFNUIwNjE0M0JFQ0IwNjk5MDU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NTBBOERFMzlGNEE5NDI2OUEwMUFDNkNFOURENTQ5MDQ</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Contracts Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QzY0RTZFMzE0RjkwNDdFQUI5M0U5N0ZFMjYyREMyQzU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QUM3QzA3NThFNjA0NDc2NjhBQjQ0MDhBQkFCOEMwMjE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjlGQ0EyM0ZDOEIxNDA3ODkxMTUxMzE3MUE1OTFBN0U</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Estate, Gift &amp; Trust Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OENGNTY0MEQ2RTU2NDA2NTk4QjcyNzI2NTBERUU3NUI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Q0VEQ0U4QTFCMzc1NDkyQjgzMjNBQUJFREFDOEJCOTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NUQ4NThEMTk0MTQ4NDM3N0FGOEM5RkU2QUQ4RjA1MkQ</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Healthcare Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NkUxMkVDQjJDOEY5NDVDQ0E5NTFEMTlDMjIwNzVERjc7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6ODZDMjQzOUU2MTM4NEJENzgxQTNDRjkzNkExRDcxNEU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUVGMzQ2NUZDREVCNEEwQkI0N0I4NjQ2RDVBQTFEQzI</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Health Maintenance Organizations</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MzNDMEYyOTY3NjdBNEE4MDlCQTlDMUQxRDMyMUZCNDM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUVGMzQ2NUZDREVCNEEwQkI0N0I4NjQ2RDVBQTFEQzI</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Insurability</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QTQ5MEQ1NjI3QjU1NDA1RTg1MzU3QUM4NTA4RTJFRjg7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NzYzODNGRDdGNkNDNDE4MTlDNTU4REQ1MEE3MUNFOEI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Insurance Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDM4MzQ2QUYzMTY0NDQzQTkxRDQwRUUzRUM5RDg0OEM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Credit Life Insurance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MTFFRTIyRUQwMkQ2NDM4M0JGM0FEQjQ0RDcyMUNEQUI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MzFEOTQ4RjM2RDk4NDJDNEJERDY1NjREOEVGMTRCOTA</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QkY2NzY0REQ4QUI1NDYwMTkwNzUyMUIyRkE0OEIzMTQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QTE5QzNFREZGMzVFNEFGRDgzNjYyQUZFREU1Nzc4OEI</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RTFEMDYzQTAxQTZDNEYzQzkzODFBM0RBODNGNERDRDQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NzVCREFBMEI5RUMxNEVGNzhCNjRCRTNGODY5RTVBMTE</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MzlEMURCMkFEQTNDNDcxQUFGQjFCMzY4OEE1QjIwQkM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OUM1QjU1RTk4NjlCNEIwN0IwRjVBQjNFRjgzMTA4Rjc</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Policy Delivery</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OUYyOUJCOTEwRjgwNENENUE4M0JFRkZDRDVGMzc4Rjg7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Qjg2NDVEOEQ5Q0IxNEQ0RTg0MTkyQ0ZCMkNENDlBODY</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Labor &amp; Employment Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MTE3QUQwOTA0MUYzNDlCMEFFMjUwRUNDM0RDRkM5QzM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Claim Procedures</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDBGNzE4NThBMUU2NDY2Mjg3MEUzMzFFODBCRkVGRTQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NEFENzA0REZBQUNBNDVDMUJCMTgwMzc2MkQ0NzUwQUY</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Pensions &amp; Benefits Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QzNEOEE3NjhDNTJBNDhCOTgxRkQzNzc1Q0JCMkU4Q0I7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Multiple Employer Welfare Arrangements</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QzEyOUVBMDEyNjcyNEYxNzkwQThBQTg0Q0VDQUU4N0U7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QzEwOTVCREM3OTlDNEYxQkFCNUM5QUU2MDZFMDhDMTM</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification><classificationGroup classificationScheme="indexing-terms"><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem score="90"><className>Insurance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDM4MzQ2QUYzMTY0NDQzQTkxRDQwRUUzRUM5RDg0OEM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></classificationGroup></metadata></legislativeDoc>