<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#349#000008#    01#       581.17#">Va. Code Ann. § 8.01-581.17</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_8.01-581.17"/><heading><desig>§ 8.01-581.17.</desig><title>Privileged communications of certain committees and entities</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a"/><heading><desig>A.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> For the purposes of this section:</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Centralized credentialing service"</emphasis> means (i) gathering information relating to applications for professional staff privileges at any public or licensed private hospital or for participation as a provider in any health maintenance organization, preferred provider organization or any similar organization and (ii) providing such information to those hospitals and organizations that utilize the service.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Patient safety data"</emphasis> means reports made to patient safety organizations together with all health care data, interviews, memoranda, analyses, root cause analyses, products of quality assurance or quality improvement processes, corrective action plans or information collected or created by a health care provider as a result of an occurrence related to the provision of health care services.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Patient safety organization"</emphasis> means any organization, group, or other entity that collects and analyzes patient safety data for the purpose of improving patient safety and health care outcomes and that is independent and not under the control of the entity that reports patient safety data.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b"/><heading><desig>B.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The proceedings, minutes, records, and reports of any (i) medical staff committee, utilization review committee, or other committee, board, group, commission or other entity as specified in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 8.01-581.16"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 8.01-581.16">§ 8.01-581.16<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000008#    01#       581.16#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; (ii) nonprofit entity that provides a centralized credentialing service; or (iii) quality assurance, quality of care, or peer review committee established pursuant to guidelines approved or adopted by (a) a national or state physician peer review entity, (b) a national or state physician accreditation entity, (c) a national professional association of health care providers or Virginia chapter of a national professional association of health care providers, (d) a licensee of a managed care health insurance plan (MCHIP) as defined in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 38.2-5800"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 38.2-5800">§ 38.2-5800<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000038#     2#         5800#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, (e) the Office of Emergency Medical Services or any regional emergency medical services council, or (f) a statewide or local association representing health care providers licensed in the Commonwealth, together with all communications, both oral and written, originating in or provided to such committees or entities, are privileged communications which may not be disclosed or obtained by legal discovery proceedings unless a circuit court, after a hearing and for good cause arising from extraordinary circumstances being shown, orders the disclosure of such proceedings, minutes, records, reports, or communications. Additionally, for the purposes of this section, accreditation and peer review records of the American College of Radiology and the Medical Society of Virginia are considered privileged communications. Oral communications regarding a specific medical incident involving patient care, made to a quality assurance, quality of care, or peer review committee established pursuant to clause (iii), shall be privileged only to the extent made more than 24 hours after the occurrence of the medical incident. Nothing in this section shall be construed as providing any privilege to any health care provider, emergency medical services agency, community services board, or behavioral health authority with respect to any factual information regarding specific patient health care or treatment, including patient health care incidents, whether oral, electronic, or written. However, the analysis, findings, conclusions, recommendations, and the deliberative process of any medical staff committee, utilization review committee, or other committee, board, group, commission, or other entity specified in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 8.01-581.16"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 8.01-581.16">§ 8.01-581.16<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000008#    01#       581.16#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, as well as the proceedings, minutes, records, and reports, including the opinions and reports of experts, of such entities shall be privileged in their entirety under this section. Information known by a witness with knowledge of the facts or treating health care provider is not privileged or protected from discovery merely because it is provided to a committee, board, group, commission, or other entity specified in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 8.01-581.16"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 8.01-581.16">§ 8.01-581.16<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000008#    01#       581.16#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, and may be discovered by deposition or otherwise in the course of discovery. A person involved in the work of the entities referenced in this subsection shall not be made a witness with knowledge of the facts by virtue of his involvement in the quality assurance, peer review, or credentialing process.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c"/><heading><desig>C.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Nothing in this section shall be construed as providing any privilege to health care provider, emergency medical services agency, community services board, or behavioral health authority medical records kept with respect to a patient, whose treatment is at issue, in the ordinary course of business of operating a hospital, emergency medical services agency, community services board, or behavioral health authority nor to any facts or information contained in medical records, nor shall this section preclude or affect discovery of or production of evidence relating to hospitalization or treatment of such patient in the ordinary course of the patient's hospitalization or treatment. However, the proceedings, minutes, records, reports, analysis, findings, conclusions, recommendations, and the deliberative process, including opinions and reports of experts, of any medical staff committee, utilization review committee, or other committee, board, group, commission, or other entity specified in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 8.01-581.16"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 8.01-581.16">§ 8.01-581.16<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000008#    01#       581.16#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> shall not constitute medical records, are privileged in their entirety, and are not discoverable.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d"/><heading><desig>D.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Notwithstanding any other provision of this section, reports or patient safety data in possession of a patient safety organization, together with the identity of the reporter and all related correspondence, documentation, analysis, results or recommendations, shall be privileged and confidential and shall not be subject to a civil, criminal, or administrative subpoena or admitted as evidence in any civil, criminal, or administrative proceeding. Nothing in this subsection shall affect the discoverability or admissibility of facts, information or records referenced in subsection C as related to patient care from a source other than a patient safety organization.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_e"/><heading><desig>E.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Any patient safety organization shall promptly remove all patient-identifying information after receipt of a complete patient safety data report unless such organization is otherwise permitted by state or federal law to maintain such information. Patient safety organizations shall maintain the confidentiality of all patient-identifying information and shall not disseminate such information except as permitted by state or federal law.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_f"/><heading><desig>F.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Exchange of (i) patient safety data among health care providers or patient safety organizations that does not identify any patient or (ii) information privileged pursuant to subsection B between committees, boards, groups, commissions, or other entities specified in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 8.01-581.16"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 8.01-581.16">§ 8.01-581.16<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000008#    01#       581.16#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> shall not constitute a waiver of any privilege established in this section.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_g"/><heading><desig>G.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Reports of patient safety data to patient safety organizations shall not abrogate obligations to make reports to health regulatory boards or other agencies as required by state or federal law.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_h"/><heading><desig>H.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> No employer shall take retaliatory action against an employee who in good faith makes a report of patient safety data to a patient safety organization.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_i"/><heading><desig>I.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Reports produced solely for purposes of self-assessment of compliance with requirements or standards of a national accrediting organization granted authority by the Centers for Medicare and Medicaid Services to ensure compliance with Medicare conditions of participation pursuant to § 1865 of Title XVIII of the Social Security Act <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="42 USC 1395BB"><content><span normalizedCite="42 U.S.C. 1395BB">(42 U.S.C. § 1395bb)<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1828#123#000042#     1395bb#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> shall be privileged and confidential and shall not be subject to subpoena or admitted as evidence in a civil or administrative proceeding. Nothing in this subsection shall affect the discoverability or admissibility of facts, information, or records referenced in subsection C as related to patient care from a source other than such accreditation body. A health care provider's release of such reports to such accreditation body shall not constitute a waiver of any privilege provided under this section.</p></bodyText></level><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p>Code 1950, § 8-654.10; 1976, c. 611; 1977, c. 617; <citation normalizedCite="1995 VA CH 500"><content><span normalizedCite="1995 Va. Ch. 500">1995, c. 500<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1995#000500#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1997 VA CH 292"><content><span normalizedCite="1997 Va. Ch. 292">1997, c. 292<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1997#000292#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2001 VA CH 381"><content><span normalizedCite="2001 Va. Ch. 381">2001, c. 381<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2001#000381#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2002 VA CH 675"><content><span normalizedCite="2002 Va. Ch. 675">2002, c. 675<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2002#000675#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2004 VA CH 250"><content><span normalizedCite="2004 Va. Ch. 250">2004, c. 250<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2004#000250#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2006 VA CH 412"><content><span normalizedCite="2006 Va. Ch. 412">2006, cc. 412<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2006#000412#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2006 VA CH 678"><content><span normalizedCite="2006 Va. Ch. 678">678<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2006#000678#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2007 VA CH 530"><content><span normalizedCite="2007 Va. Ch. 530">2007, c. 530<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2007#000530#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2010 VA CH 196"><content><span normalizedCite="2010 Va. Ch. 196">2010, c. 196<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2010#000196#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2011 VA CH 15"><content><span normalizedCite="2011 Va. Ch. 15">2011, cc. 15<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2011#000015#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2011 VA CH 753"><content><span normalizedCite="2011 Va. Ch. 753">753<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2011#000753#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2014 VA CH 320"><content><span normalizedCite="2014 Va. Ch. 320">2014, c. 320<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2014#000320#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PSG0-004G-K133-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 8.01.</desig><title>CIVIL REMEDIES AND PROCEDURE</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 21.1.</desig><title>MEDICAL MALPRACTICE</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="article"><heading><desig>ARTICLE 2.</desig><title>MISCELLANEOUS PROVISIONS</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Administrative Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NjMxMjc0MUIzQjkzNEM4MEI4NkZGQjVCREJCRDk4OUM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Privileged Communications</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NUVFRUYzMjhDRjkyNDI3QkE1RDk0MjNERTQyRTkxQjE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NTlGN0ZFRjdEM0FGNEM0Nzg4QzgzNTBEQ0QzNEEzQzI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Accreditation</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MzkwMTVGOURFMEQ2NEY2NkIyNjA2MzhGM0Q3QUQ5QzA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MkIwM0E1RTM4NkY5NEU4QjhBM0RCNzc5QjE4RkIzOEI</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Health Maintenance Organizations</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MzNDMEYyOTY3NjdBNEE4MDlCQTlDMUQxRDMyMUZCNDM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NkUxMkVDQjJDOEY5NDVDQ0E5NTFEMTlDMjIwNzVERjc</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Civil Procedure</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MzUxNjJDMEQ5N0YwNDMzM0JDMjEzM0UzOTYzMzI3OTU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RURENTNCNzNFMkUyNDk4MkIxNDg3QzMxMDY3QUQyQTE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6REQ5NjdFN0M2ODlFNDVCMUEwRTRCMjQyNkNEREMyNDI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Criminal Law &amp; Procedure</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NEU0RkE1OUQwNUQwNDgxODhEODZCMjkzOTg3NThBNzk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QkI3QTJBN0RCRDMzNDAwNzlENjE0OUNCRERCMzk2Nzk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NjhBQTc4QkZENjIyNDNEQzkyMTcwRTVENjFCQTY4ODM</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Scope of Disclosure</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDVFQUUyOUJBRTlDNDA2RDgzREVERjBFQ0JEQkVCRjU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NjhBQTc4QkZENjIyNDNEQzkyMTcwRTVENjFCQTY4ODM</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Evidence</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUVGQkU0QjJFMTIzNDNBM0FCNTVEQjAxQTM3RDcwOTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Elements</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MzJBMTI2MDNBQTc4NDdDN0E1RjRCQkUwOEE3OTg0N0U7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NERENkFGQTgxMTFFNDcxNkI4RTlFNzEwQkNGNEE2MkM</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Exceptions</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NEJFMzlFNTc2NUI5NDJFOTgyODdEMUZBN0Q2MzYyRTk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QzBDMEM3QTE3RUU3NENGQzhEOTBCMEJENkI3QkNDNzI</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Exceptions</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MTVEMjI1NEI0REEwNDk0QTk1QzZCMTA0Mjc4ODI5Qzk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NERENkFGQTgxMTFFNDcxNkI4RTlFNzEwQkNGNEE2MkM</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MzYwQUQ2RDlBNDUzNEFBRTkwRDZBNEU1NUQxQTNDMzg7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDA2QUFEQUVBNTYyNDUxNUE2MjMzMDk5NzM1NkQ1Mjc</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6ODc2NTkzNjY3MDVGNDAyNjkxMDgzOEIyODc5MERBNDk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MkRGQzdERjA3NUQ0NDEyMDhGMTgxQkE2NjRDMjdCNzg</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NzA2QzU2MkFCMzMzNDgwNkEzMDIzRDE2ODgxRjUzMkY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QzBDMEM3QTE3RUU3NENGQzhEOTBCMEJENkI3QkNDNzI</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NUQ2QzBFOTlEMzVDNDFGRUJFMzEwMDc5REYzMzNENUM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NERENkFGQTgxMTFFNDcxNkI4RTlFNzEwQkNGNEE2MkM</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Scope</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QzA1MzkyNDJBMjhENDIwMDg0ODY5NDQyODE3M0JDMkM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NERENkFGQTgxMTFFNDcxNkI4RTlFNzEwQkNGNEE2MkM</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Waiver</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OTBFQUYxNjQxNUI3NERGODgzQjI2QTRDNkFENEM3MUY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NERENkFGQTgxMTFFNDcxNkI4RTlFNzEwQkNGNEE2MkM</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Healthcare Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NkUxMkVDQjJDOEY5NDVDQ0E5NTFEMTlDMjIwNzVERjc7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Accreditation</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MzkwMTVGOURFMEQ2NEY2NkIyNjA2MzhGM0Q3QUQ5QzA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MkIwM0E1RTM4NkY5NEU4QjhBM0RCNzc5QjE4RkIzOEI</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6N0U1NEQ5NkFBQjhENEUyMjhDMjM2MjRFQkVBOTFDODI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MkIwM0E1RTM4NkY5NEU4QjhBM0RCNzc5QjE4RkIzOEI</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MkM0RjM1NjlERDhBNDk2Q0I2RTZCOEIxM0Y0MjI0RDE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NTg4RTkyNjk5MUY0NEU4Q0FBMDg2MzI1ODBCRUQ3OEY</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OTFDMjk0MjFFMEJFNDQyMkE2OTcyOUU2NTYxRkY5RUY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6M0JBQTc2MDg4OUY4NDRDQzk5QkQ0OTVFMUVCQzY4NkY</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6ODZDMjQzOUU2MTM4NEJENzgxQTNDRjkzNkExRDcxNEU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUVGMzQ2NUZDREVCNEEwQkI0N0I4NjQ2RDVBQTFEQzI</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Health Maintenance Organizations</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MzNDMEYyOTY3NjdBNEE4MDlCQTlDMUQxRDMyMUZCNDM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUVGMzQ2NUZDREVCNEEwQkI0N0I4NjQ2RDVBQTFEQzI</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Organizations</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QzYyMzU0NUI2MTg4NDU5NEFFRkI3ODQxRUM2QTY2ODQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6M0JBQTc2MDg4OUY4NDRDQzk5QkQ0OTVFMUVCQzY4NkY</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Public Health &amp; Welfare Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDYwRTY1MDg3MTk5NDUyNkFFRDI1RjJBRERGQ0UxNzI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NTQyNEEyOTI3RDA1NDFBMkE1ODk5OThDMTcyQ0QwNkQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RDUwODU3NjY2MUVFNDNFQkEwNTE1Q0E3RkMxM0JBRDQ</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Torts</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDAwOEM2NTEzQkVDNEI4NzlGMEZERUEyRjQwODM4Njg7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Healthcare Providers</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OTYwQjdFN0UwQUY1NEYwNEJGNkRBNTRCMzUwMjM5Q0Q7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjkzQzRCMDhBOTZDNEY4NkE0Q0E1ODk5MDM2MUNGNkI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification><classificationGroup classificationScheme="indexing-terms"><classification classificationScheme="legal"/></classificationGroup></metadata></legislativeDoc>