<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#958#0000000062#0000000001#     44.15#0000000055#">Va. Code Ann. § 62.1-44.15:55</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><note><bodyText><p>This section has more than one version with varying effective dates.  To view a complete list of the versions of this section see Table of Contents.</p></bodyText></note><anchor id="_62.1-44.15_55"/><heading><desig>§ 62.1-44.15:55.</desig><title>(For effective date -- see notes) Regulated land-disturbing activities; submission and approval of erosion and sediment control plan</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a"/><heading><desig>A.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Except as provided in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 62.1-44.15:31"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 62.1-44.15:31">§ 62.1-44.15:31<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#958#0000000062#0000000001#     44.15#0000000031#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> for a land-disturbing activity conducted by a state agency, federal entity, or other specified entity, no person shall engage in any land-disturbing activity until he has submitted to the VESCP authority an erosion and sediment control plan for the land-disturbing activity and the plan has been reviewed and approved. Where Virginia Pollutant Discharge Elimination System permit coverage is required, a VESCP authority shall be required to obtain evidence of such coverage from the Department's online reporting system prior to approving the erosion and sediment control plan. A VESCP authority may enter into an agreement with an adjacent VESCP or VESMP authority regarding the administration of multijurisdictional projects specifying who shall be responsible for all or part of the administrative procedures. Should adjacent authorities fail to come to such an agreement, each shall be responsible for administering the area of the multijurisdictional project that lies within its jurisdiction. Where the land-disturbing activity results from the construction of a single-family residence, an agreement in lieu of a plan may be substituted for an erosion and sediment control plan if executed by the VESCP authority.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b"/><heading><desig>B.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The VESCP authority shall review erosion and sediment control plans submitted to it and grant written approval within 60 days of the receipt of the plan if it determines that the plan meets the requirements of this article and the Board's regulations and if the person responsible for carrying out the plan certifies that he will properly perform the erosion and sediment control measures included in the plan and shall comply with the provisions of this article. In addition, as a prerequisite to engaging in the land-disturbing activities shown on the approved plan, the person responsible for carrying out the plan shall provide the name of an individual holding a certificate to the VESCP authority, as provided by <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 62.1-44.15:52"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 62.1-44.15:52">§ 62.1-44.15:52<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#958#0000000062#0000000001#     44.15#0000000052#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, who will be in charge of and responsible for carrying out the land-disturbing activity. However, any VESCP authority may waive the certificate requirement for an agreement in lieu of a plan for construction of a single-family residence. If a violation occurs during the land-disturbing activity, then the person responsible for carrying out the agreement in lieu of a plan shall correct the violation and provide the name of an individual holding a certificate, as provided by <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 62.1-44.15:52"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 62.1-44.15:52">§ 62.1-44.15:52.<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#958#0000000062#0000000001#     44.15#0000000052#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> Failure to provide the name of an individual holding a certificate prior to engaging in land-disturbing activities may result in revocation of the approval of the plan and the person responsible for carrying out the plan shall be subject to the penalties provided in this article.</p><p>When a plan is determined to be inadequate, written notice of disapproval stating the specific reasons for disapproval shall be communicated to the applicant within 45 days. The notice shall specify the modifications, terms, and conditions that will permit approval of the plan. If no action is taken by the VESCP authority within the time specified in this subsection, the plan shall be deemed approved and the person authorized to proceed with the proposed activity. The VESCP authority shall act on any erosion and sediment control plan that has been previously disapproved within 45 days after the plan has been revised, resubmitted for approval, and deemed adequate.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c"/><heading><desig>C.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The VESCP authority may require changes to an approved plan in the following cases:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Where inspection has revealed that the plan is inadequate to satisfy applicable regulations; or</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Where the person responsible for carrying out the approved plan finds that because of changed circumstances or for other reasons the approved plan cannot be effectively carried out, and proposed amendments to the plan, consistent with the requirements of this article and associated regulations, are agreed to by the VESCP authority and the person responsible for carrying out the plan.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d"/><heading><desig>D.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> In order to prevent further erosion, a VESCP authority may require approval of an erosion and sediment control plan for any land identified by the VESCP authority as an erosion impact area.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_e"/><heading><desig>E.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> For the purposes of subsections A and B, when land-disturbing activity will be required of a contractor performing construction work pursuant to a construction contract, the preparation, submission, and approval of an erosion and sediment control plan shall be the responsibility of the owner.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_f"/><heading><desig>F.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Notwithstanding any other provisions of this article, the following activities are not required to comply with the requirements of this article unless otherwise required by federal law:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_f_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Disturbance of a land area of less than 10,000 square feet in size or less than 2,500 square feet in an area designated as a Chesapeake Bay Preservation Area pursuant to the Chesapeake Bay Preservation Act (<citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 62.1-44.15:67"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 62.1-44.15:67">§ 62.1-44.15:67<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#958#0000000062#0000000001#     44.15#0000000067#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> et seq.). However, the governing body of the program authority may reduce this exception to a smaller area of disturbed land or qualify the conditions under which this exception shall apply;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_f_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Minor land-disturbing activities such as home gardens and individual home landscaping, repairs, and maintenance work;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_f_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Installation, maintenance, or repair of any individual service connection;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_f_4"/><heading><desig>4.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Installation, maintenance, or repair of any underground utility line when such activity occurs on an existing hard surfaced road, street, or sidewalk, provided the land-disturbing activity is confined to the area of the road, street, or sidewalk that is hard surfaced;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_f_5"/><heading><desig>5.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Installation, maintenance, or repair of any septic tank line or drainage field unless included in an overall plan for land-disturbing activity relating to construction of the building to be served by the septic tank system;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_f_6"/><heading><desig>6.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Permitted surface or deep mining operations and projects, or oil and gas operations and projects conducted pursuant to Title 45.1;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_f_7"/><heading><desig>7.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Clearing of lands specifically for bona fide agricultural purposes; the management, tilling, planting, or harvesting of agricultural, horticultural, or forest crops; livestock feedlot operations; agricultural engineering operations, including construction of terraces, terrace outlets, check dams, desilting basins, dikes, ponds, ditches, strip cropping, lister furrowing, contour cultivating, contour furrowing, land drainage, and land irrigation; or as additionally set forth by the Board in regulations. However, this exception shall not apply to harvesting of forest crops unless the area on which harvesting occurs is reforested artificially or naturally in accordance with the provisions of Chapter 11 (<citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 10.1-1100"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 10.1-1100">§ 10.1-1100<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000010#     1#         1100#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> et seq.) of Title 10.1 or is converted to bona fide agricultural or improved pasture use as described in subsection B of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 10.1-1163"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 10.1-1163">§ 10.1-1163<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000010#     1#         1163#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_f_8"/><heading><desig>8.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Installation of fence and sign posts or telephone and electric poles and other kinds of posts or poles;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_f_9"/><heading><desig>9.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Shoreline erosion control projects on tidal waters when all of the land-disturbing activities are within the regulatory authority of and approved by local wetlands boards, the Marine Resources Commission, or the United States Army Corps of Engineers; however, any associated land that is disturbed outside of this exempted area shall remain subject to this article and the regulations adopted pursuant thereto;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_f_10"/><heading><desig>10.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Land-disturbing activities in response to a public emergency where the related work requires immediate authorization to avoid imminent endangerment to human health or the environment. In such situations, the VESMP authority shall be advised of the disturbance within seven days of commencing the land-disturbing activity, and compliance with the administrative requirements of subsection A is required within 30 days of commencing the land-disturbing activity;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_f_11"/><heading><desig>11.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Discharges to a sanitary sewer or a combined sewer system that are not from a land-disturbing activity; and</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_f_12"/><heading><desig>12.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Repair or rebuilding of the tracks, rights-of-way, bridges, communication facilities, and other related structures and facilities of a railroad company.</p></bodyText></level></level><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p>1973, c. 486, § 21-89.6; 1979, c. 432; 1988, cc. 732, 891, § 10.1-563; <citation normalizedCite="1993 VA CH 925"><content><span normalizedCite="1993 Va. Ch. 925">1993, c. 925<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1993#000925#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1999 VA CH 555"><content><span normalizedCite="1999 Va. Ch. 555">1999, c. 555<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1999#000555#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2001 VA CH 490"><content><span normalizedCite="2001 Va. Ch. 490">2001, c. 490<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2001#000490#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2003 VA CH 827"><content><span normalizedCite="2003 Va. Ch. 827">2003, cc. 827<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2003#000827#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2003 VA CH 966"><content><span normalizedCite="2003 Va. Ch. 966">966<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2003#000966#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2006 VA CH 466"><content><span normalizedCite="2006 Va. Ch. 466">2006, c. 466<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2006#000466#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2008 VA CH 23"><content><span normalizedCite="2008 Va. Ch. 23">2008, c. 23<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2008#000023#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2011 VA CH 720"><content><span normalizedCite="2011 Va. Ch. 720">2011, cc. 720<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2011#000720#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2011 VA CH 721"><content><span normalizedCite="2011 Va. Ch. 721">721<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2011#000721#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2012 VA CH 785"><content><span normalizedCite="2012 Va. Ch. 785">2012, cc. 785<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2012#000785#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2012 VA CH 819"><content><span normalizedCite="2012 Va. Ch. 819">819<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2012#000819#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2013 VA CH 756"><content><span normalizedCite="2013 Va. Ch. 756">2013, cc. 756<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2013#000756#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2013 VA CH 793"><content><span normalizedCite="2013 Va. Ch. 793">793<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2013#000793#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2016 VA CH 68"><content><span normalizedCite="2016 Va. Ch. 68">2016, cc. 68<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2016#000068#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2016 VA CH 758"><content><span normalizedCite="2016 Va. Ch. 758">758<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2016#000758#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PWF0-004G-K4CM-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 62.1.</desig><title>WATERS OF THE STATE, PORTS AND HARBORS</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 3.1.</desig><title>STATE WATER CONTROL LAW</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="article"><heading><desig>ARTICLE 2.4.</desig><title>EROSION AND SEDIMENT CONTROL LAW</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Energy &amp; Utilities Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OUUzODAyRDk1QzVFNEZGMEJDM0RGMDYxOTlEMEEzRDA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Easements &amp; Rights of Way</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RDgzRTU4RTJDRDk1NDk4NTg1RkQyRjE0QTI2OUI2Q0M7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjMwQzNCRThDRjkwNDY0QjlFNDJFQzY5QzVCMEE0MTY</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Environmental Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NzFDRDYyNkI2QjhBNDg3NTkyRjRDRkZEQjlCRkRBQzM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Wetlands Management</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QzY2NjI1NjQ3Qzk2NDE5NzlGQjFDNTkzQjg5QTAyMkQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NTkwMDY1RDExQ0YwNDQ1RTlERUVFMjUzMUI1MkFDOTU</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Governments</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjdEQjE4OUJDMzQxNDNEMEI0RTI1QUFCMzJENjEwRTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Forest Lands</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RTkzOTc4NEQ2MTQwNDg0Q0E0NDNFRkRDRDU1QUE0OEU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6ODE4NDg4QUI2RDA3NDQ2RkI1QTRFNjA4OUM3QjA4MzA</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Real Property Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QUUyRTcxRURBNEY2NEE2MDk3QzBCNzRDOEY0NTZDQzk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Surface Rights</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MTAzOUU2OENCRTk0NDQ3Mzk2NUMyNUQzN0U4QTNGOTU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjlCOEFBQzRBMkRDNERFMkIyQ0YzQUQ0ODFGQjQ3QzI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification><classificationGroup classificationScheme="indexing-terms"><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem score="90"><className>Admiralty &amp; Maritime</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QzRDNDVDOTdGRUQ1NDE1M0I1RjRBRDFBRTI3ODFGMDk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem score="90"><className>Transportation</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RTYzRTk5RDVBQkQ2NDcwQzk2NTU3ODQ5OEE3NDlBNzk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></classificationGroup></metadata></legislativeDoc>