<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#349#000022#     1#          316#">Va. Code Ann. § 22.1-316</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_22.1-316"/><heading><desig>§ 22.1-316.</desig><title>Agreement entered into and enacted into law; form of agreement</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><bodyText><p>The Interstate Agreement on Qualification of Educational Personnel is hereby enacted into law and entered into with all jurisdictions legally joined therein in the form substantially as follows:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><bodyText><p>INTERSTATE AGREEMENT ON QUALIFICATION<br/>OF EDUCATIONAL PERSONNEL </p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="article"><anchor id="_i"/><heading><desig>Article I.</desig></heading><bodyText><p>Purpose, Findings, and Policy. </p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_i_a"/><heading><desig>A.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The states party to this agreement, desiring by common action to improve their respective school systems by utilizing the teacher or other professional educational person wherever educated, declare that it is the policy of each of them, on the basis of cooperation with one another, to take advantage of the preparation and experience of such persons wherever gained, thereby serving the best interests of society, of education and of the teaching profession. It is the purpose of this agreement to provide for the development and execution of such programs of cooperation as will facilitate the movement of teachers and other professional educational personnel among the states party to it and to authorize specific interstate educational personnel contracts to achieve that end.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_i_b"/><heading><desig>B.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The party states find that included in the large movement of population among all sections of the nation are many qualified educational personnel who move for family and other personal reasons but who are hindered in using their professional skill and experience in their new locations. Variations from state to state in requirements for qualifying educational personnel discourage such personnel from taking the steps necessary to qualify in other states.  As a consequence, a significant number of professionally prepared and experienced educators is lost to our school systems. Facilitating the employment of qualified educational personnel without reference to their states of origin can increase the available educational resources. Participation in this compact can increase the availability of educational manpower.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="article"><anchor id="_ii"/><heading><desig>Article II.</desig></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><bodyText><p>Definitions. </p><p>As used in this agreement and contracts made pursuant to it, unless the context clearly requires otherwise:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_ii_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig><title><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Educational personnel"</emphasis></title></heading><bodyText><p> means persons who must meet requirements pursuant to state law as a condition of employment in educational programs.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_ii_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig><title><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Designated state official"</emphasis></title></heading><bodyText><p> means the educational official of a state selected by that state to negotiate and enter into, on behalf of his state, contracts pursuant to this agreement.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_ii_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig><title><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Accept"</emphasis></title></heading><bodyText><p> or any variant thereof means to recognize and give effect to one or more determinations of another state relating to the qualifications of educational personnel in lieu of making or requiring a like determination that would otherwise be required by or pursuant to the laws of a receiving state.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_ii_4"/><heading><desig>4.</desig><title><emphasis typeStyle="it">"State"</emphasis></title></heading><bodyText><p> means a state, territory, or possession of the United States; the District of Columbia; or the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_ii_5"/><heading><desig>5.</desig><title><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Originating state"</emphasis></title></heading><bodyText><p> means a state or subdivision thereof whose determination that certain educational personnel are qualified to be employed for specific duties in schools is acceptable in accordance with the terms of a contract made pursuant to Article III.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_ii_6"/><heading><desig>6.</desig><title><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Receiving state"</emphasis></title></heading><bodyText><p> means a state or subdivision thereof which accepts educational personnel in accordance with the terms of a contract made pursuant to Article III of this section.</p></bodyText></level></level></level><level levelType="article"><anchor id="_iii"/><heading><desig>Article III.</desig></heading><bodyText><p>Interstate Educational Personnel Contracts. </p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_iii_a"/><heading><desig>A.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The designated state official of a party state may make one or more contracts on behalf of his state with one or more other party states providing for the acceptance of educational personnel. Any such contract for the period of its duration shall be applicable to and binding on the states whose designated state officials enter into it and the subdivisions of those states with the same force and effect as if incorporated in this agreement.  A designated state official may enter into a contract pursuant to this article only with states in which he finds that there are programs of education, licensure standards or other acceptable qualifications that assure preparation or qualification of educational personnel on a basis sufficiently comparable even though not identical to that prevailing in his own state.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_iii_b"/><heading><desig>B.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Any such contract shall provide for:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_iii_b_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Its duration.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_iii_b_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The criteria to be applied by an originating state in qualifying educational personnel for acceptance by a receiving state.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_iii_b_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Such waivers, substitutions, and conditional acceptances as shall aid the practical effectuation of the contract without sacrifice of basic educational standards.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_iii_b_4"/><heading><desig>4.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Any other necessary matters.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_iii_c"/><heading><desig>C.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> No contract made pursuant to this agreement shall be for a term longer than five years but any such contract may be renewed for like or lesser periods.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_iii_d"/><heading><desig>D.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Any contract dealing with acceptance of educational personnel on the basis of their having completed an educational program shall specify the earliest date or dates on which originating state approval of the program or programs involved can have occurred. No contract made pursuant to this agreement shall require acceptance by a receiving state of any persons qualified because of successful completion of a program prior to January 1, 1954.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_iii_e"/><heading><desig>E.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The licensure or other acceptance of a person who has been accepted pursuant to the terms of a contract shall not be revoked or otherwise impaired because the contract has expired or been terminated.  Any license or other qualifying document may be revoked or suspended on any ground which would be sufficient for revocation or suspension of a license or other qualifying document initially granted or approved in the receiving state.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_iii_f"/><heading><desig>F.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A contract committee composed of the designated state officials of the contracting states or their representatives shall keep the contract under continuous review, study means of improving its administration, and report no less frequently than once a year to the heads of the appropriate education agencies of the contracting states.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="article"><anchor id="_iv"/><heading><desig>Article IV.</desig></heading><bodyText><p>Approved and Accepted Programs. </p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_iv_a"/><heading><desig>A.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Nothing in this agreement shall be construed to repeal or otherwise modify any law or regulation of a party state relating to the approval of programs of educational preparation having effect solely on the qualification of educational personnel within that state.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_iv_b"/><heading><desig>B.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> To the extent that contracts made pursuant to this agreement deal with the educational requirements for the proper qualification of educational personnel, acceptance of a program of educational preparation shall be in accordance with such procedures and requirements as may be provided in the applicable contract.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="article"><anchor id="_v"/><heading><desig>Article V.</desig></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><bodyText><p>Interstate Cooperation. </p><p>The party states agree that:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_v_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> They will, so far as practicable, prefer the making of multilateral contracts pursuant to Article III of this agreement.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_v_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> They will facilitate and strengthen cooperation in interstate licensure and other elements of educational personnel qualification and for this purpose shall cooperate with agencies, organizations, and associations interested in licensure and other elements of educational personnel qualification.</p></bodyText></level></level></level><level levelType="article"><anchor id="_vi"/><heading><desig>Article VI.</desig></heading><bodyText><p>Agreement Evaluation. </p><p>The designated state officials of any party states may meet from time to time as a group to evaluate progress under the agreement and to formulate recommendations for changes.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="article"><anchor id="_vii"/><heading><desig>Article VII.</desig></heading><bodyText><p>Other Arrangements. </p><p>Nothing in this agreement shall be construed to prevent or inhibit other arrangements or practices of any party state or states to facilitate the interchange of educational personnel.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="article"><anchor id="_viii"/><heading><desig>Article VIII.</desig></heading><bodyText><p>Effect and Withdrawal. </p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_viii_a"/><heading><desig>A.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> This agreement shall become effective when enacted into law by two states. Thereafter it shall become effective as to any state upon its enactment of this agreement.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_viii_b"/><heading><desig>B.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Any party state may withdraw from this agreement by enacting a statute repealing the same, but no such withdrawal shall take effect until one year after the governor of the withdrawing state has given notice in writing of the withdrawal to the governors of all other party states.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_viii_c"/><heading><desig>C.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> No withdrawal shall relieve the withdrawing state of any obligation imposed upon it by a contract to which it is a party. The duration of contracts and the methods and conditions of withdrawal therefrom shall be those specified in their terms.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="article"><anchor id="_ix"/><heading><desig>Article IX.</desig></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><bodyText><p>Construction and Severability. </p><p>This agreement shall be liberally construed so as to effectuate the purposes thereof. The provisions of this agreement shall be severable; and if any phrase, clause, sentence, or provision of this agreement is declared to be contrary to the constitution of any state or of the United States or if the application thereof to any government, agency, person, or circumstance is held invalid, the validity of the remainder of this agreement and the applicability thereof to any government, agency, person, or circumstance shall not be affected thereby. If this agreement shall be held contrary to the constitution of any state participating therein, the agreement shall remain in full force and effect as to the state affected as to all severable matters.</p></bodyText></level></level><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p>Code 1950, § 22-348; 1970, c. 193; 1980, c. 559; <citation normalizedCite="1992 VA CH 132"><content><span normalizedCite="1992 Va. Ch. 132">1992, c. 132<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1992#000132#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PT00-004G-K1NP-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 22.1.</desig><title>EDUCATION</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 15.</desig><title>TEACHERS, OFFICERS AND EMPLOYEES</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="article"><heading><desig>ARTICLE 5.</desig><title>INTERSTATE AGREEMENT ON QUALIFICATION OF EDUCATIONAL PERSONNEL</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Contracts Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QzY0RTZFMzE0RjkwNDdFQUI5M0U5N0ZFMjYyREMyQzU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Divisible Contracts</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RjJGODlBMDRBODQ3NDcwQTk2N0MxNEY5MzY5N0QzQzk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Qjg1NzgyRDNGQzg1NEM5Nzg3RjA3MEUwRTA1QUI0NkU</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Labor &amp; Employment Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MTE3QUQwOTA0MUYzNDlCMEFFMjUwRUNDM0RDRkM5QzM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Employment Contract Formation</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RkQzQUVENUE2OTM5NDFBRjg4OUY0QzIxNDBERThFNUI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MTVFNUFFREQyQzIwNEIwQThCMDMzQzEwNTBEN0U1QUU</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Public Contracts Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDA5QTlFMDVCQUY0NEY0NUE1QzMyQzA1QkQyQzJGRUY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Acceptances &amp; Awards</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjlCRjI1QTRDNzZBNDA4OUIzQUQ2NDU5NTExRjM2NjI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NjJFNjY4RTkxNDU0NDFGNzk0RTQ3RUNGRkZBODE4RDY</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification><classificationGroup classificationScheme="indexing-terms"><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem score="90"><className>Education</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDkzNUEzQzFBNEZBNEFBREIxNDM5MTc1MUU5QjI4MTY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></classificationGroup></metadata></legislativeDoc>