<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#123#000055#      58.1#">Va. Code Ann. § 55-58.1</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_55-58.1"/><heading><desig>§ 55-58.1.</desig><title>Requirements for trustees</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a"/><heading><desig>A.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> No person may be named or act, in person or by agent or attorney, as the trustee of a deed of trust conveying property to secure the payment of money or the performance of an obligation, either individually or as one of several trustees, unless such person is a resident of the Commonwealth. No corporation, limited liability company, partnership, or other entity may be named or act as the trustee or as one of the trustees of a deed of trust conveying property to secure the payment of money or the performance of an obligation, unless it is organized under the laws of the Commonwealth or of the United States of America. However, the foregoing requirements shall not apply to any deed of trust conveying property lying partly in the Commonwealth and partly outside the Commonwealth or to a deed of trust conveying property in the Commonwealth to secure bonds or obligations that are also secured by one or more deeds of trust or mortgages conveying property outside of the Commonwealth.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b"/><heading><desig>B.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A deed of trust conveying property to secure the payment of money or the performance of an obligation shall state the full residence or business address of the trustee or trustees named therein, including street address and zip code, which address shall be valid for purposes of all notices under the deed of trust to the trustee. Such address of the trustee or trustees may be changed by amendment of the deed of trust or by a separate instrument executed by the trustee or trustees, or by the beneficiary of such deed of trust, stating the changed address and otherwise in recordable form, and recorded in the office of the clerk of the circuit court where the deed of trust was recorded.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c"/><heading><desig>C.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Notwithstanding any other provisions of this section, if any deed of trust is admitted by a clerk for recordation it shall be conclusively presumed that such deed of trust complies with all the requirements of this section and it shall be deemed to be validly recorded.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d"/><heading><desig>D.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> All deeds of trusts, mortgages, bonds, or other instruments recorded by the clerk prior to January 1, 1999, without the residence or business address of the trustee or trustees named therein shall be valid for all purposes as if such address had been named therein, if such recordation be otherwise valid according to the law then in force, provided that this section shall not affect any right or remedy of any third party that accrued after the recordation of said instrument or before July 1, 1960.</p></bodyText></level><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p>1960, c. 565; 1962, c. 156; 1966, c. 398; 1974, c. 424; <citation normalizedCite="1998 VA CH 202"><content><span normalizedCite="1998 Va. Ch. 202">1998, c. 202<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1998#000202#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2014 VA CH 338"><content><span normalizedCite="2014 Va. Ch. 338">2014, c. 338<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2014#000338#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PTC0-004G-K2M7-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 55.</desig><title>PROPERTY AND CONVEYANCES</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 4.</desig><title>FORM AND EFFECT OF DEEDS AND COVENANTS; LIENS</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="article"><heading><desig>ARTICLE 2.</desig><title>FORM AND EFFECT OF DEEDS OF TRUST; SALES THEREUNDER; ASSIGNMENTS; RELEASES</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Governments</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjdEQjE4OUJDMzQxNDNEMEI0RTI1QUFCMzJENjEwRTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Clerks of Court</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6REVFMjkzRDI1MkU2NERDNjk3OEUxODY0REYwMUI1NjE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NURENzJGNTEyQzM0NEREQUI2RkVCRTM4RTc1RTZBREU</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification><classificationGroup classificationScheme="indexing-terms"><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem score="90"><className>Real Property</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QUUyRTcxRURBNEY2NEE2MDk3QzBCNzRDOEY0NTZDQzk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></classificationGroup></metadata></legislativeDoc>