<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#349#000033#     2#         1726#">Va. Code Ann. § 33.2-1726</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_33.2-1726"/><heading><desig>§ 33.2-1726.</desig><title>Incidental powers of the Board</title></heading><bodyText><p>The Board may make and enter into all contracts or agreements necessary or incidental to the execution of its powers under this chapter and may employ engineering, architectural, and construction experts and inspectors, brokers, and such other employees as may be deemed necessary, who shall be paid such compensation as may be provided in accordance with law. All such compensation and all expenses incurred in carrying out the provisions of this chapter shall be paid solely from funds provided under the authority of this chapter, and no liability or obligation shall be incurred pursuant to this chapter beyond the extent to which money has been provided under the authority of this chapter. The Board may exercise any powers that are necessary or convenient for the execution of its powers under this chapter.</p><p>The Board shall maintain and keep in good condition and repair, or cause to be maintained and kept in good condition and repair, the projects authorized under this chapter, when acquired or constructed and opened to traffic, including any project or part thereof that may include portions of existing streets or roads within a county, municipality, or other political subdivision.</p><p>The Board is authorized and empowered to establish regulations for the use of any one or more of the projects defined in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 33.2-1700"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 33.2-1700">§ 33.2-1700<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000033#     2#         1700#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, as amended, including reasonable regulations relating to (i) maximum and minimum speed limits applicable to motor vehicles using such project, any other provision of law to the contrary notwithstanding; (ii) the types, kinds, and sizes of vehicles that may use such projects; (iii) the nature, size, type of materials, or substances that shall not be transported over such project; and (iv) such other matters as may be necessary or expedient in the interest of public safety with respect to the use of such project, provided that as to the project authorized under the terms of subdivision 5 of the definition of "project" in § 33.2-1700, the provisions of clauses (i), (ii), (iii), and (iv) shall not apply to existing streets within a municipality and embraced by such project, except as may be otherwise agreed upon by the Board and the municipality.</p><p>The projects acquired or constructed under this chapter may be policed in whole or in part by State Police officers even though all or some portions of any such projects lie within the corporate limits of a municipality or other political subdivision. Such officers shall be under the exclusive control and direction of the Superintendent of State Police and shall be responsible for the preservation of public peace, prevention of crime, apprehension of criminals, protection of the rights of persons and property, and enforcement of the laws and regulations of the Commonwealth within the limits of any such projects. All other police officers of the Commonwealth and of each locality or other political subdivision through which any project, or portion thereof, extends shall have the same powers and jurisdiction within the limits of such projects as they have beyond such limits and shall have access to the projects at any time for the purpose of exercising such powers and jurisdiction.</p><p>The Board is authorized and empowered to employ and appoint "project guards" for the purpose of protecting the projects and to enforce the regulations of the Board, except those paralleling state law, established for the use of such projects. Such guards may issue summons to appear or arrest on view without warrant and conduct before the nearest officer authorized by law to admit to bail any persons violating, within or upon the projects, any such rule or regulation. The provisions of §§ 46.2-936 and 46.2-940 shall apply mutatis mutandis to the issuance of summons or arrests without warrants pursuant to this section.</p><p>The violation of any regulation adopted by the Board pursuant to the authority hereby granted shall be punishable as follows: If such violation would have been a violation of law if committed on any public street or highway in the county, city, or town in which such violation occurred, it shall be punishable in the same manner as if it had been committed on such public road, street, or highway; otherwise it shall be punishable as a Class 1 misdemeanor.</p><p>The powers and duties of the Board enumerated in this chapter shall not be construed as a limitation of the general powers or duties of the Board. The Board, in addition to the powers and duties enumerated in this chapter, shall do and perform any and all things and acts necessary in the construction or acquisition, maintenance, and operation of any project to be constructed or acquired under the provisions of this chapter, to the end that such project may become and be operated free of tolls as early as possible and practicable, subject only to the express limitations of this chapter and the limitations of other laws and constitutional provisions applicable thereto.</p></bodyText><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p>Code 1950, § 33-252; 1956, c. 158; 1958, c. 583; 1970, c. 322, § 33.1-292; <citation normalizedCite="2014 VA CH 805"><content><span normalizedCite="2014 Va. Ch. 805">2014, c. 805<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2014#000805#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2015 VA CH 256"><content><span normalizedCite="2015 Va. Ch. 256">2015, c. 256<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2015#000256#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PWB0-004G-K2F3-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 33.2.</desig><title>HIGHWAYS AND OTHER SURFACE TRANSPORTATION SYSTEMS</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="subtitle"><heading><desig>SUBTITLE III.</desig><title>TRANSPORTATION FUNDING AND DEVELOPMENT</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 17.</desig><title>TRANSPORTATION DEVELOPMENT AND REVENUE BOND ACT</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Governments</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjdEQjE4OUJDMzQxNDNEMEI0RTI1QUFCMzJENjEwRTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Administrative Boards</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QTYwRUFCMDc5MzQ5NDEyREFEQkU2NkE2MjRGQTlCNzY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Njg1MkM3RkYyNzIxNEVFRkJFMTI2NUM4NUU1ODdEM0Q</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUYzRDgzNzg0MTBGNEYyN0FFMzFCRTY5MjA1MTc2Q0Q7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MEY3NUIxODI2RjU2NEY0NzgwMDQyNjFDMEQ1QUExRjM</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Police Power</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MzMzRDQ0NDc5NDEzNEZEMUI2MUFENjIzM0MwMTU5RjA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Njg1MkM3RkYyNzIxNEVFRkJFMTI2NUM4NUU1ODdEM0Q</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Transportation Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RTYzRTk5RDVBQkQ2NDcwQzk2NTU3ODQ5OEE3NDlBNzk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Minimum Speeds</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6M0Q3MDgzQUIxOTYwNDE4QTlDOEExQkY2OTE2N0QyOUI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QzgxNEM2ODkxNDU4NEExOTk4OTUyNjdGODkzRDc4OUQ</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification><classificationGroup classificationScheme="indexing-terms"><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem score="90"><className>Transportation</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RTYzRTk5RDVBQkQ2NDcwQzk2NTU3ODQ5OEE3NDlBNzk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></classificationGroup></metadata></legislativeDoc>