<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#349#000038#     2#         1367#">Va. Code Ann. § 38.2-1367</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_38.2-1367"/><heading><desig>§ 38.2-1367.</desig><title>Actuarial opinion of reserves</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a"/><heading><desig>A.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The actuarial opinion prior to the operative date of the valuation manual shall require:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Every life insurance company doing business in the Commonwealth to annually submit the opinion of a qualified actuary as to whether the reserves and related actuarial items held in support of the policies and contracts specified by the Commission by regulation are computed appropriately, are based on assumptions that satisfy contractual provisions, are consistent with prior reported amounts, and comply with applicable laws of the Commonwealth. The Commission shall define by regulation the specifics of this opinion and add any other items deemed to be necessary to its scope.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Every life insurance company, except as exempted by regulation, to annually include in the opinion required by subdivision 1, an opinion of the same qualified actuary as to whether the reserves and related actuarial items held in support of the policies and contracts specified by the Commission by regulation, when considered in light of the assets held by the insurer with respect to the reserves and related actuarial items, including but not limited to the investment earnings on the assets and the considerations anticipated to be received and retained under the policies and contracts, make adequate provision for the insurer's obligations under the policies and contracts, including but not limited to the benefits under and expenses associated with the policies and contracts. The Commission shall specify by regulation the types of reserves and related actuarial items on which the opinion is to be expressed.</p><p><pre/>The Commission may provide by regulation for a transition period for establishing any higher reserves that the qualified actuary may deem necessary in order to render the opinion required by this section.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Each opinion required by subdivision 2 to be governed by the following provisions:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_3_a"/><heading><desig>a.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A memorandum, in form and substance acceptable to the Commission as specified by regulation, shall be prepared to support each actuarial opinion; and</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_3_b"/><heading><desig>b.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> If the insurance company fails to provide a supporting memorandum at the request of the Commission within a period specified by regulation or the Commission determines that the supporting memorandum provided by the insurance company fails to meet the standards prescribed by the regulations or is otherwise unacceptable to the Commission, the Commission may engage a qualified actuary at the expense of the insurance company to review the opinion and the basis for the opinion and prepare the supporting memorandum required by the Commission.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_4"/><heading><desig>4.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Every opinion required by this subsection to be governed by the following provisions:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_4_a"/><heading><desig>a.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The opinion shall be submitted with the annual statement filed pursuant to <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 38.2-1300"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 38.2-1300">§ 38.2-1300<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000038#     2#         1300#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> and shall reflect the valuation of such reserve liabilities for each year ending on or after December 31, 1992.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_4_b"/><heading><desig>b.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The opinion shall apply to all business in force including individual and group health insurance plans, in form and substance acceptable to the Commission as specified by regulation.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_4_c"/><heading><desig>c.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The opinion shall be based on standards adopted from time to time by the Actuarial Standards Board and on such additional standards as the Commission may by regulation prescribe.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_4_d"/><heading><desig>d.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> In the case of an opinion required to be submitted by a foreign or alien insurer, the Commission may accept the opinion filed by that insurer with the insurance supervisory official of another state if the Commission determines that the opinion reasonably meets the requirements applicable to an insurer domiciled in the Commonwealth.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_4_e"/><heading><desig>e.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> For the purposes of this section, "qualified actuary" means a member in good standing of the American Academy of Actuaries who meets the requirements set forth in regulations adopted by the Commission.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_4_f"/><heading><desig>f.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Except in cases of fraud or willful misconduct, the qualified actuary shall not be liable for damages to any person, other than the insurer and the Commission, for any act, error, omission, decision, or conduct with respect to the actuary's opinion.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_4_g"/><heading><desig>g.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Disciplinary action by the Commission against the insurer or the qualified actuary shall be defined in regulations adopted by the Commission.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_4_h"/><heading><desig>h.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Except as provided in subdivisions 4 l, m, and n, documents, materials, or other information in the possession or control of the Commission that is a memorandum in support of the opinion, and any other material provided by the insurer to the Commission in connection with the memorandum, shall be confidential by law and privileged, shall not be subject to subpoena, and shall not be subject to discovery or admissible in evidence in any private civil action. However, the Commission is authorized to use the documents, materials, or other information in the furtherance of any regulatory or legal action brought as a part of the Commission's official duties.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_4_i"/><heading><desig>i.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Neither the Commission nor any person who received documents, materials, or other information while acting under the authority of the Commission shall be permitted or required to testify in any private civil action concerning any confidential documents, materials, or information subject to subdivision 4 h.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_4_j"/><heading><desig>j.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> In order to assist in the performance of the Commission's duties, the Commission:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_4_j_1"/><heading><desig>(1)</desig></heading><bodyText><p> May share documents, materials, or other information, including the confidential and privileged documents, materials, or information subject to subdivision 4 h, with other state, federal, and international regulatory agencies, with the NAIC and its affiliates and subsidiaries, and with state, federal, and international law-enforcement authorities, provided that the recipient agrees to maintain the confidentiality and privileged status of the document, material, or other information;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_4_j_2"/><heading><desig>(2)</desig></heading><bodyText><p> May receive documents, materials, or information, including otherwise confidential and privileged documents, materials, or information, from the NAIC and its affiliates and subsidiaries, and from regulatory and law-enforcement officials of other foreign or domestic jurisdictions, and shall maintain as confidential or privileged any document, material, or information received with notice or the understanding that it is confidential or privileged under the laws of the jurisdiction that is the source of the document, material, or information; and</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_4_j_3"/><heading><desig>(3)</desig></heading><bodyText><p> May enter into agreements governing sharing and use of information consistent with subdivisions 4 h, i, and j.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_4_k"/><heading><desig>k.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> No waiver of any applicable privilege or claim of confidentiality in the documents, materials, or information shall occur as a result of disclosure to the Commission under this section or as a result of sharing as authorized in subdivision 4 j.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_4_l"/><heading><desig>l.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A memorandum in support of the opinion, and any other material provided by the insurer to the Commission in connection with the memorandum, may be subject to subpoena for the purpose of defending an action seeking damages from the actuary submitting the memorandum by reason of an action required by this section or by regulations adopted hereunder.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_4_m"/><heading><desig>m.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The memorandum or other material may otherwise be released by the Commission with the written consent of the insurer or to the American Academy of Actuaries upon request stating that the memorandum or other material is required for the purpose of professional disciplinary proceedings and setting forth procedures satisfactory to the Commission for preserving the confidentiality of the memorandum or other material.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_4_n"/><heading><desig>n.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Once any portion of the confidential memorandum is cited by the insurer in its marketing, is cited before a governmental agency other than a state insurance department, or is released by the insurer to the news media, all portions of the confidential memorandum shall be no longer confidential.</p></bodyText></level></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b"/><heading><desig>B.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The actuarial opinion of reserves after the operative date of the valuation manual shall require:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Every insurer with outstanding life insurance contracts, accident and health insurance contracts, or deposit-type contracts in the Commonwealth and subject to regulation by the Commission to annually submit the opinion of the appointed actuary as to whether the reserves and related actuarial items held in support of the policies and contracts are computed appropriately, are based on assumptions that satisfy contractual provisions, are consistent with prior reported amounts, and comply with applicable laws of the Commonwealth. The valuation manual will prescribe the specifics of this opinion, including any items deemed to be necessary to its scope.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Every insurer with outstanding life insurance contracts, accident and health insurance contracts, or deposit-type contracts in the Commonwealth and subject to regulation by the Commission, except as exempted in the valuation manual, to annually include in the opinion required by subdivision 1 an opinion of the same appointed actuary as to whether the reserves and related actuarial items held in support of the policies and contracts specified in the valuation manual, when considered in light of the assets held by the insurer with respect to the reserves and related actuarial items, including but not limited to the investment earnings on the assets and the considerations anticipated to be received and retained under the policies and contracts, make adequate provision for the insurer's obligations under the policies and contracts, including but not limited to the benefits under and expenses associated with the policies and contracts.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Each opinion required by subdivision 2 to be governed by the following provisions:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_3_a"/><heading><desig>a.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A memorandum, in form and substance as specified in the valuation manual, and acceptable to the Commission, shall be prepared to support each actuarial opinion.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_3_b"/><heading><desig>b.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> If the insurance company fails to provide a supporting memorandum at the request of the Commission within a period specified in the valuation manual or the Commission determines that the supporting memorandum provided by the insurance company fails to meet the standards prescribed by the valuation manual or is otherwise unacceptable to the Commission, the Commission may engage a qualified actuary at the expense of the insurer to review the opinion and the basis for the opinion and prepare the supporting memorandum required by the Commission.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_4"/><heading><desig>4.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Every opinion required by this subsection to be governed by the following provisions:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_4_a"/><heading><desig>a.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The opinion shall be in form and substance as specified in the valuation manual and acceptable to the Commission;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_4_b"/><heading><desig>b.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The opinion shall be submitted with the annual statement reflecting the valuation of such reserve liabilities for each year ending on or after the operative date of the valuation manual;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_4_c"/><heading><desig>c.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The opinion shall apply to all policies and contracts subject to subdivision 2, plus other actuarial liabilities as may be specified in the valuation manual;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_4_d"/><heading><desig>d.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The opinion shall be based on standards adopted from time to time by the Actuarial Standards Board or its successor, and on such additional standards as may be prescribed in the valuation manual;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_4_e"/><heading><desig>e.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> In the case of an opinion required to be submitted by a foreign or alien insurer, the Commission may accept the opinion filed by that insurer with the insurance supervisory official of another state if the Commission determines that the opinion reasonably meets the requirements applicable to an insurer domiciled in the Commonwealth;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_4_f"/><heading><desig>f.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Except in cases of fraud or willful misconduct, the appointed actuary shall not be liable for damages to any person, other than the insurance company and the Commission, for any act, error, omission, decision, or conduct with respect to the appointed actuary's opinion; and</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_4_g"/><heading><desig>g.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Disciplinary action by the Commission against the insurer or the appointed actuary shall be defined in regulations adopted by the Commission.</p></bodyText></level></level></level><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p><citation normalizedCite="2014 VA CH 571"><content><span normalizedCite="2014 Va. Ch. 571">2014, c. 571<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2014#000571#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PWB0-004G-K1W3-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 38.2.</desig><title>INSURANCE</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 13.</desig><title>REPORTS, RESERVES AND EXAMINATIONS, INSURANCE HOLDING COMPANIES, REINSURANCE INTERMEDIARIES, AND MANAGING GENERAL AGENTS</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="article"><heading><desig>ARTICLE 10.</desig><title>STANDARD VALUATION.</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Administrative Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NjMxMjc0MUIzQjkzNEM4MEI4NkZGQjVCREJCRDk4OUM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Privileged Communications</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NUVFRUYzMjhDRjkyNDI3QkE1RDk0MjNERTQyRTkxQjE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NTlGN0ZFRjdEM0FGNEM0Nzg4QzgzNTBEQ0QzNEEzQzI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Foreign Insurers</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjlGMEIzREZGNUFENERBRUJBRDg5NjgxQTlEOTE1N0Y7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OUE0QUQ4OUIxOURCNDA3RUEyQkY0NzhBREMxNzk1RTM</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>National Association of Insurance Commissioners</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RjBFNEI1QTM2QzNBNDlGNkI3NkQ3MjAxRTI1RDlGRjQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MEFDQTNCQjMxQjJDNEYwOTlEMUEwRUUzNDI5RUY3RjI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Civil Procedure</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MzUxNjJDMEQ5N0YwNDMzM0JDMjEzM0UzOTYzMzI3OTU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Supporting Memoranda</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NzIzMzU2NkJDQzdENDg0NjgyQjkxNDc1QTJGOTQ3MjE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MkEzM0JEQzAwNUM3NDQ2QjhBQTEzNjgwMzM5NUZFNTc</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Insurance Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDM4MzQ2QUYzMTY0NDQzQTkxRDQwRUUzRUM5RDg0OEM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Foreign Insurers</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjlGMEIzREZGNUFENERBRUJBRDg5NjgxQTlEOTE1N0Y7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OUE0QUQ4OUIxOURCNDA3RUEyQkY0NzhBREMxNzk1RTM</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NTUxNTQ1ODNFODA3NDQxOTkwRTkwNUE3M0Y2MThGNjE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDQ0MzAyMTAyNjY5NDRENEFDMzkyRjFDRUE4ODVGQjg</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Q0M1RjY0MTAyQUE5NEM3RUEwNERCRTU0NzI4QjgzMTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OTE2MzM3RDdDRDJCNDhFOUIxOEQwMTJCRTI1QjRBMkY</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OURFREJEQzQwMENCNDZGMkE2MzY3NTU5QzBDRTk2QkM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QzE0QTkzRDYwNjNCNDhFMEJDMTExNzcyNzgzMTAyQ0Q</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NURCMkIyODk4NDUwNDQ2NkE3RkQ0Qzg3RUVCOENGQUE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QTA3MzFBREE5RDkxNEIyNkExMzYyNTkwMEI4ODA2MTQ</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>National Association of Insurance Commissioners</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RjBFNEI1QTM2QzNBNDlGNkI3NkQ3MjAxRTI1RDlGRjQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MEFDQTNCQjMxQjJDNEYwOTlEMUEwRUUzNDI5RUY3RjI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>International Trade Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RTRDNDkyQ0UwRkRGNEQ0MjgwNzM2NzI3NjlGODE0ODk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6N0RCRTFFNkMzMjQ5NDU0NEI4MzEwNEY4MzA0QUY5NUE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NkQ3MzdDOTkyQ0U0NEQxODg3OTY1Nzk2N0JERDIwRUQ</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification><classificationGroup classificationScheme="indexing-terms"><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem score="90"><className>Insurance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDM4MzQ2QUYzMTY0NDQzQTkxRDQwRUUzRUM5RDg0OEM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></classificationGroup></metadata></legislativeDoc>