<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#123#000030#       280#">Va. Code Ann. § 30-280</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_30-280"/><heading><desig>§ 30-280.</desig><title>Submission by responsible public entities of detailed proposals for qualifying projects; exclusion of certain qualifying projects; review of detailed proposals; copies of interim and comprehensive agreements to be provided</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a"/><heading><desig>A.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Each responsible public entity receiving detailed proposals from private entities for a qualifying project shall provide copies of such proposals to the Chairman of the Commission, the chairmen of the House Committee on Appropriations, House Committee on Finance, and Senate Committee on Finance or their designees, and the Director of the Department of General Services prior to entering into the negotiation of an interim or comprehensive agreement.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b"/><heading><desig>B.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The following qualifying projects shall not be subject to review by the Commission:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Any proposed qualifying project with a total cost of less than $ 3 million.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Any proposed qualifying project with a total cost of more than $ 3 million but less than $ 50 million for which funds have been specifically appropriated as a public-private partnership in the general appropriation act or capital construction projects that have been authorized in the appropriation act, provided such project does not increase in size more than five percent beyond the plans and justifications that were the basis of the appropriation. For any qualifying project that will be completed in phases and for which no appropriation has been made for phases other than the current phase of the project, the Commission may undertake additional reviews of such projects.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c"/><heading><desig>C.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Within 10 days of receipt of a complete copy of the detailed proposals for a qualifying project, the Commission shall determine whether to accept or decline such proposals for review and notify the responsible public entity of its decision. If the Commission accepts a proposal for review, the findings and recommendations of the Commission shall be provided to the responsible public entity within 45 days of receiving complete copies of the detailed proposals. If no findings or recommendations are provided by the Commission to the responsible public entity within the 45-day period, the Commission shall be deemed to have no findings or recommendations. Upon acceptance for review, the responsible public entity shall provide any additional information regarding the qualifying project upon the request of the Commission, provided such information is available to or can be obtained by the responsible public entity.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d"/><heading><desig>D.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The Commission shall review accepted detailed proposals and provide findings and recommendations to the responsible public entity, including (i) whether the terms and conditions of the proposals and proposed qualifying project create state tax-supported debt taking into consideration the specific findings of the Secretary of Finance with respect to such recommendation, (ii) an analysis of the potential financial impact of the qualifying project, (iii) a review of the policy aspects of the detailed proposals and the qualifying project, and (iv) proposed general business terms and conditions. Review by the Commission shall not be construed to constitute approval of any appropriations necessary to implement any subsequent interim or comprehensive agreement.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_e"/><heading><desig>E.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The responsible public entity shall not commence negotiation of an interim or comprehensive agreement until the Commission has submitted its recommendations or declined to accept the detailed proposals for review.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_f"/><heading><desig>F.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The responsible public entity shall submit a copy of the proposed interim or comprehensive agreement to the Commission, the chairmen of the House Committee on Appropriations, House Committee on Finance, and Senate Committee on Finance or their designees, and the Director of the Department of General Services at least 30 days prior to execution of the agreement along with a report describing the extent to which the Commission's recommendations were addressed in the proposed interim or comprehensive agreement.</p></bodyText></level><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p><citation normalizedCite="2007 VA CH 764"><content><span normalizedCite="2007 Va. Ch. 764">2007, c. 764<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2007#000764#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2008 VA CH 712"><content><span normalizedCite="2008 Va. Ch. 712">2008, c. 712<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2008#000712#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2010 VA CH 450"><content><span normalizedCite="2010 Va. Ch. 450">2010, c. 450<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2010#000450#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PVJ0-004G-K0Y1-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 30.</desig><title>GENERAL ASSEMBLY</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 42.</desig><title>PUBLIC-PRIVATE PARTNERSHIP ADVISORY COMMISSION</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjA4OEVGODBENzY4NDcxM0IyQzA1OTEwQzVDODRBOUE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Authority to Act</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6ODlDNzk4QzgzQTAwNEQ1MUE4NkZBQTZBQTEwNjE5MDA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NjMzQjkyNzZDOUQ4NEQ2NEIyOEYxNkJCNzBGNTk1OEY</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification><classificationGroup classificationScheme="indexing-terms"><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem score="90"><className>Governments</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjdEQjE4OUJDMzQxNDNEMEI0RTI1QUFCMzJENjEwRTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></classificationGroup></metadata></legislativeDoc>