<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#349#000058#     1#          302#">Va. Code Ann. § 58.1-302</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_58.1-302"/><heading><desig>§ 58.1-302.</desig><title>Definitions</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><bodyText><p>For the purpose of this chapter and unless otherwise required by the context:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><bodyText><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Affiliated"</emphasis> means two or more corporations subject to Virginia income taxes whose relationship to each other is such that (i) one corporation owns at least 80 percent of the voting stock of the other or others or (ii) at least 80 percent of the voting stock of two or more corporations is owned by the same interests.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Compensation"</emphasis> means wages, salaries, commissions and any other form of remuneration paid or accrued to employees for personal services.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Corporation"</emphasis> includes associations, joint stock companies and insurance companies.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Domicile"</emphasis> means the permanent place of residence of a taxpayer and the place to which he intends to return even though he may actually reside elsewhere. In determining domicile, consideration may be given to the applicant's expressed intent, conduct, and all attendant circumstances including, but not limited to, financial independence, business pursuits, employment, income sources, residence for federal income tax purposes, marital status, residence of parents, spouse and children, if any, leasehold, sites of personal and real property owned by the applicant, motor vehicle and other personal property registration, residence for purposes of voting as proven by registration to vote, if any, and such other factors as may reasonably be deemed necessary to determine the person's domicile.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><bodyText><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Foreign source income"</emphasis> means:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Interest, other than interest derived from sources within the United States;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Dividends, other than dividends derived from sources within the United States;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Rents, royalties, license, and technical fees from property located or services performed without the United States or from any interest in such property, including rents, royalties, or fees for the use of or the privilege of using without the United States any patents, copyrights, secret processes and formulas, good will, trademarks, trade brands, franchises, and other like properties;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_4"/><heading><desig>4.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Gains, profits, or other income from the sale of intangible or real property located without the United States; and</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_5"/><heading><desig>5.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The amount of an individual's share of net income attributable to a foreign source qualified business unit of an electing small business corporation (S corporation). For purposes of this subsection, qualified business unit shall be defined by <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="26 USC 989"><content><span normalizedCite="26 U.S.C. 989">§ 989 of the Internal Revenue Code<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#29854#1127#00000000989#1#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, and the source of such income shall be determined in accordance with <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="26 USC 861"><content><span normalizedCite="26 U.S.C. 861">§§ 861<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#29854#1127#00000000861#1#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="26 USC 862"><content><span normalizedCite="26 U.S.C. 862">862<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#29854#1127#00000000862#1#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> and <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="26 USC 987"><content><span normalizedCite="26 U.S.C. 987">987 of the Internal Revenue Code<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#29854#1127#00000000987#1#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><bodyText><p><pre/>In determining the source of "foreign source income," the provisions of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="26 USC 861"><content><span normalizedCite="26 U.S.C. 861">§§ 861<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#29854#1127#00000000861#1#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="26 USC 862"><content><span normalizedCite="26 U.S.C. 862">862<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#29854#1127#00000000862#1#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, and <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="26 USC 863"><content><span normalizedCite="26 U.S.C. 863">863 of the Internal Revenue Code<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#29854#1127#00000000863#1#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> shall be applied except as specifically provided in subsection 5 above.</p><p><pre/><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Income and deductions from Virginia sources"</emphasis> includes:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_1_seq_2"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Items of income, gain, loss and deduction attributable to:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_1_a"/><heading><desig>a.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The ownership of any interest in real or tangible personal property in Virginia;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_1_b"/><heading><desig>b.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A business, trade, profession or occupation carried on in Virginia; or</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_1_c"/><heading><desig>c.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Prizes paid by the Virginia Lottery Department, and gambling winnings from wagers placed or paid at a location in Virginia.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_2_seq_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Income from intangible personal property, including annuities, dividends, interest, royalties and gains from the disposition of intangible personal property to the extent that such income is from property employed by the taxpayer in a business, trade, profession, or occupation carried on in Virginia.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><bodyText><p><pre/><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Income tax return preparer"</emphasis> means any person who prepares for compensation, or who employs one or more persons to prepare for compensation, any return of tax imposed by this chapter or any claim for refund of tax. For purposes of the preceding sentence, the preparation for compensation of any portion of a return or claim for refund shall be treated as if it were the preparation of the return or claim for refund. A person shall not be an "income tax return preparer" merely because the person:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_1_seq_3"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Furnishes typing, reproducing, or other mechanical assistance;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_2_seq_3"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Prepares a return or claim for refund of the employer (or of an officer or employee of the employer) by whom he is regularly and continuously employed;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_3_seq_2"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Prepares as a fiduciary a return or claim for refund for any person; or</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_4_seq_2"/><heading><desig>4.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Prepares an application for correction of an erroneous assessment or a protective claim for refund for a taxpayer in response to any assessment pursuant to <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 58.1-1812"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 58.1-1812">§ 58.1-1812<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000058#     1#         1812#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> issued to the taxpayer or in response to any waiver pursuant to <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 58.1-101"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 58.1-101">§ 58.1-101<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000058#     1#          101#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> or <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 58.1-220"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 58.1-220">58.1-220<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000058#     1#          220#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> after the commencement of an audit of the taxpayer or another taxpayer if a determination in such audit of such other taxpayer directly or indirectly affects the tax liability of such taxpayer.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><bodyText><p><pre/><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Individual"</emphasis> means all natural persons whether married or unmarried and fiduciaries acting for natural persons, but not fiduciaries acting for trusts or estates.</p><p><pre/><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Intangible expenses and costs"</emphasis> means:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_1_seq_4"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Expenses, losses and costs for, related to, or in connection directly or indirectly with the direct or indirect acquisition, use, maintenance or management, ownership, sale, exchange, lease, transfer, or any other disposition of intangible property to the extent such amounts are allowed as deductions or costs in determining taxable income;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_2_seq_4"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Losses related to or incurred in connection directly or indirectly with factoring transactions or discounting transactions;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_3_seq_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Royalty, patent, technical and copyright fees;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_4_seq_3"/><heading><desig>4.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Licensing fees; and</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_5_seq_2"/><heading><desig>5.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Other similar expenses and costs.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><bodyText><p><pre/><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Intangible property"</emphasis> means patents, patent applications, trade names, trademarks, service marks, copyrights and similar types of intangible assets.</p><p><pre/><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Interest expenses and costs"</emphasis> means amounts directly or indirectly allowed as deductions under <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="26 USC 163"><content><span normalizedCite="26 U.S.C. 163">§ 163 of the Internal Revenue Code<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#29854#1127#00000000163#1#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> for purposes of determining taxable income under the Internal Revenue Code to the extent such expenses and costs are directly or indirectly for, related to, or in connection with the direct or indirect acquisition, use, maintenance, management, ownership, sale, exchange, lease, transfer, or disposition of intangible property.</p><p><pre/><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Nonresident estate or trust"</emphasis> means an estate or trust which is not a resident estate or trust.</p><p><pre/><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Related entity"</emphasis> means:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_1_seq_5"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A stockholder who is an individual, or a member of the stockholder's family enumerated in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="26 USC 318"><content><span normalizedCite="26 U.S.C. 318">§ 318 of the Internal Revenue Code<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#29854#1127#00000000318#1#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, if the stockholder and the members of the stockholder's family own, directly, indirectly, beneficially or constructively, in the aggregate, at least 50 percent of the value of the taxpayer's outstanding stock;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_2_seq_5"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A stockholder, or a stockholder's partnership, limited liability company, estate, trust or corporation, if the stockholder and the stockholder's partnerships, limited liability companies, estates, trusts and corporations own directly, indirectly, beneficially or constructively, in the aggregate, at least 50 percent of the value of the taxpayer's outstanding stock; or</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_3_seq_4"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A corporation, or a party related to the corporation in a manner that would require an attribution of stock from the corporation to the party or from the party to the corporation under the attribution rules of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="26 USC 318"><content><span normalizedCite="26 U.S.C. 318">§ 318 of the Internal Revenue Code<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#29854#1127#00000000318#1#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, if the taxpayer owns, directly, indirectly, beneficially or constructively, at least 50 percent of the value of the corporation's outstanding stock. The attribution rules of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="26 USC 318"><content><span normalizedCite="26 U.S.C. 318">§ 318 of the Internal Revenue Code<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#29854#1127#00000000318#1#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> shall apply for purposes of determining whether the ownership requirements of this subdivision have been met.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><bodyText><p><pre/><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Related member"</emphasis> means a person that, with respect to the taxpayer during all or any portion of the taxable year, is a related entity, a component member as defined in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="26 USC 1563"><content><span normalizedCite="26 U.S.C. 1563">§ 1563(b) of the Internal Revenue Code<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#29854#1127#00000001563#1#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, or is a person to or from whom there is attribution of stock ownership in accordance with <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="26 USC 1563"><content><span normalizedCite="26 U.S.C. 1563">§ 1563(e) of the Internal Revenue Code<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#29854#1127#00000001563#1#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p><p><pre/><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Resident"</emphasis> applies only to natural persons and includes, for the purpose of determining liability for the taxes imposed by this chapter upon the income of any taxable year every person domiciled in Virginia at any time during the taxable year and every other person who, for an aggregate of more than 183 days of the taxable year, maintained his place of abode within Virginia, whether domiciled in Virginia or not. The word "resident" shall not include any member of the United States Congress who is domiciled in another state.</p><p><pre/><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Resident estate or trust"</emphasis> means:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_1_seq_6"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The estate of a decedent who at his death was domiciled in the Commonwealth;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_2_seq_6"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A trust created by will of a decedent who at his death was domiciled in the Commonwealth;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_3_seq_5"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A trust created by or consisting of property of a person domiciled in the Commonwealth; or</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_4_seq_4"/><heading><desig>4.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A trust or estate which is being administered in the Commonwealth.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><bodyText><p><pre/><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Sales"</emphasis> means all gross receipts of the corporation not allocated under <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 58.1-407"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 58.1-407">§ 58.1-407<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000058#     1#          407#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, except the sale or other disposition of intangible property shall include only the net gain realized from the transaction.</p><p><pre/><emphasis typeStyle="it">"State"</emphasis> means for purposes of Article 10 of this chapter any state of the United States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, any territory or possession of the United States, and any foreign country.</p><p><pre/><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Trust"</emphasis> or <emphasis typeStyle="it">"estate"</emphasis> means a trust or estate, or a fiduciary thereof, which is required to file a fiduciary income tax return under the laws of the United States.</p><p><pre/><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Virginia fiduciary adjustment"</emphasis> means the net amount of the applicable modifications described in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 58.1-322"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 58.1-322">§ 58.1-322<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000058#     1#          322#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> (including subsection E thereof if the estate or trust is a beneficiary of another estate or trust) which relate to items of income, gain, loss or deduction of an estate or trust. The fiduciary adjustment shall not include the modification in subsection D of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 58.1-322"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 58.1-322">§ 58.1-322<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000058#     1#          322#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, except that the amount of state income taxes excluded from federal taxable income shall be included. The fiduciary adjustment shall also include the modification in subsection D of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 58.1-322"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 58.1-322">§ 58.1-322<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000058#     1#          322#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, regarding the deduction for the purchase of a prepaid tuition contract or contribution to a savings trust account.</p></bodyText></level><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p>Code 1950, §§ 58-151.02, 58-151.013, 58-151.023, 58-151.034, 58-151.081; 1971, Ex. Sess., c. 171; 1972, cc. 310, 827; 1973, cc. 198, 345, 458; 1974, c. 682; 1975, c. 46; 1976, cc. 528, 694, 781; 1977, cc. 297, 612; 1978, cc. 67, 158; 1979, cc. 226, 404, 596; 1981, cc. 402, 414; 1982, c. 633; 1983, cc. 452, 472; 1984, cc. 153, 162, 636, 674, 675, 729; <citation normalizedCite="1990 VA CH 294"><content><span normalizedCite="1990 Va. Ch. 294">1990, c. 294<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1990#000294#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1992 VA CH 678"><content><span normalizedCite="1992 Va. Ch. 678">1992, c. 678<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1992#000678#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1995 VA CH 602"><content><span normalizedCite="1995 Va. Ch. 602">1995, c. 602<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1995#000602#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2000 VA CH 382"><content><span normalizedCite="2000 Va. Ch. 382">2000, cc. 382<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2000#000382#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2000 VA CH 400"><content><span normalizedCite="2000 Va. Ch. 400">400<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2000#000400#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2004 VA CH 3"><content><span normalizedCite="2004 Va. Ch. 3">2004, Sp. Sess. I, c. 3<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2004#000003#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2005 VA CH 48"><content><span normalizedCite="2005 Va. Ch. 48">2005, c. 48<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2005#000048#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PV10-004G-K15K-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><relatedContent><relatedContentGroup contentType="lexisnexis-practice-insights"><heading><title>LexisNexis Practice Insights</title></heading><relatedContentItem><relatedContentLink><link service="DOCUMENT"><marker>Payments Made by Partnership May be Considered Ordinary Income of Nonresident in Virginia</marker><locator><locatorKey><keyName name="lni"/><keyValue value="4PKD-CDY0-R03M-14MR-00000-00"/></locatorKey></locator></link></relatedContentLink></relatedContentItem><relatedContentItem><relatedContentLink><link service="DOCUMENT"><marker>Implementing FIN48: Intercompany Transactions, Economic Presence, and Affiliate Nexus</marker><locator><locatorKey><keyName name="lni"/><keyValue value="4T82-5M30-R03M-J0Y1-00000-00"/></locatorKey></locator></link></relatedContentLink></relatedContentItem><relatedContentItem><relatedContentLink><link service="DOCUMENT"><marker>Understanding Residence and Domicile in Virginia</marker><locator><locatorKey><keyName name="lni"/><keyValue value="4P9W-6J50-R03N-60D2-00000-00"/></locatorKey></locator></link></relatedContentLink></relatedContentItem><relatedContentItem><relatedContentLink><link service="DOCUMENT"><marker>Implementing FIN 48: Overview of Sales and Support Activities in Nexus Analysis</marker><locator><locatorKey><keyName name="lni"/><keyValue value="4PXP-T7P0-R03K-K3FS-00000-00"/></locatorKey></locator></link></relatedContentLink></relatedContentItem><relatedContentItem><relatedContentLink><link service="DOCUMENT"><marker>Implementing FIN 48: Solicitation Activity</marker><locator><locatorKey><keyName name="lni"/><keyValue value="4PXP-T6M0-R03M-7337-00000-00"/></locatorKey></locator></link></relatedContentLink></relatedContentItem><relatedContentItem><relatedContentLink><link service="DOCUMENT"><marker>Implementing FIN 48: Attributional and Economic Nexus</marker><locator><locatorKey><keyName name="lni"/><keyValue value="4PXP-T5N0-R03K-C2PP-00000-00"/></locatorKey></locator></link></relatedContentLink></relatedContentItem></relatedContentGroup></relatedContent><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 58.1.</desig><title>TAXATION</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="subtitle"><heading><desig>SUBTITLE I.</desig><title>TAXES ADMINISTERED BY THE DEPARTMENT OF TAXATION</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 3.</desig><title>INCOME TAX</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="article"><heading><desig>ARTICLE 1.</desig><title>GENERAL PROVISIONS</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Assistance With False Returns</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MkVBMUIzN0JGQUIxNDI1RDg3MDRFOUJERDAxRjA3RDQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjQxMDU4NkE3MUE4NDEzQjg0NDJBM0I2Q0REOUM3NEI</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Requirements for S Election</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDYxRjczQzJFMEFGNEZBQTk4MzY3MjhBMUFFNjEzN0I7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Mzc5NjFFQjM2M0U3NEQ2NUI5RjMyNzFDRjU5NEY4NjI</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Royalties</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MTRCNzA4RkUwRjk3NDQ4NTg4N0QzNjkxRTAzNUQwMTQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6ODVDRTlENUFGQzU3NDMyNEJEQ0I3QjRENUQ3NDBDRDg</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjA4OEVGODBENzY4NDcxM0IyQzA1OTEwQzVDODRBOUE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDc1MERFNzE3ODExNDEyMDgwM0RDMTdBRjUxMDQwQUQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NkU1RUZCODkyMDJCNDgzODlDREYzQkNBQkZDNTNBMzc</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NUUwRjE5Nzk1QUU0NEZGQTgxNjExMzg4QjMxQTYwMzI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NUFDMUUyMjFERDQ1NDg3NTg1NzVCNzQyMTU5QzlBODI</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Member Duties &amp; Liabilities</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDM4QzlDMjYxODY0NDYwNjg2OUFBMjVGNzYyQjFGMzQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NUFDMUUyMjFERDQ1NDg3NTg1NzVCNzQyMTU5QzlBODI</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Qualifications</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QUI1N0JGNTUwRTJGNDcxRTlBQjc0MjEzQTNEMTc4RkM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NkU1RUZCODkyMDJCNDgzODlDREYzQkNBQkZDNTNBMzc</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Contracts Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QzY0RTZFMzE0RjkwNDdFQUI5M0U5N0ZFMjYyREMyQzU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QTdGQUE3QkZDMDlBNDQ1MTkzRjEzMEQ1OEUwNzdDOTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NjZEOEU3MEJBRUQ2NDNFNzhFRjAxRTk1OEU1QjY2QTc</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Personal Property</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6ODQzNUIwM0U1NzgzNDkyRDg0MTVFQzRBMUQ2RDM2RDE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QzY0RTZFMzE0RjkwNDdFQUI5M0U5N0ZFMjYyREMyQzU</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Copyright Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MzM3NEE0Qjk0NzRCNDhFM0E0NjM2RTE4M0QzNTczMTU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QkE0RUU1QTBFMEY2NDlFMTkwMDk1MEI0QzgxMUM1NEU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RERBRjM1MDQxMjMwNEQyRDk4QTg1NTVFQTkwRDhFN0M</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Estate, Gift &amp; Trust Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OENGNTY0MEQ2RTU2NDA2NTk4QjcyNzI2NTBERUU3NUI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Q0VEQ0U4QTFCMzc1NDkyQjgzMjNBQUJFREFDOEJCOTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NUQ4NThEMTk0MTQ4NDM3N0FGOEM5RkU2QUQ4RjA1MkQ</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Governments</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjdEQjE4OUJDMzQxNDNEMEI0RTI1QUFCMzJENjEwRTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Fiduciaries</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RDRDQjYwNDkxREQ4NDE4Nzk4QzY0QTIyMzYzOTM0REQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjdEQjE4OUJDMzQxNDNEMEI0RTI1QUFCMzJENjEwRTA</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Labor &amp; Employment Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MTE3QUQwOTA0MUYzNDlCMEFFMjUwRUNDM0RDRkM5QzM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Fiduciary Responsibilities</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NTIyRjEyMTdERjgzNEE0RkExQUQxRDA4QkJGMDlBQjE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjdBMEI3Mzc0MDA3NDVFNTlDQzRGM0MxRDE4MjI2MTc</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Patent Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QkQzRkZBQjVFNkJCNDdGOEE3MjZGQUY1NkVCRUQ1QjU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Royalties</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MTRCNzA4RkUwRjk3NDQ4NTg4N0QzNjkxRTAzNUQwMTQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6ODVDRTlENUFGQzU3NDMyNEJEQ0I3QjRENUQ3NDBDRDg</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Tax Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OTNEM0E2OEE0RkQyNEY1MDhBQzdGMkQ4ODI4QTJDODE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Administrative Expenses &amp; Losses</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6REYxRDRGNkRBRTUzNDlFOTg3RjAwMjkyODk3RDUzMTQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MTZDRDdCMEZBNjE0NEMwMDhDMjAxOEU2ODc5OEE4QTU</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Assistance With False Returns</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MkVBMUIzN0JGQUIxNDI1RDg3MDRFOUJERDAxRjA3RDQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjQxMDU4NkE3MUE4NDEzQjg0NDJBM0I2Q0REOUM3NEI</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Attribution of Stock</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RkNFQ0EwNUY1MjVBNDQzN0FEQTA0QjM2RTM2NTJEREY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NThFNzVCQTRENzQ4NEIxQzkyQjVFQTI5NUY5QjE3RTU</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Credits, Overassessments &amp; Refunds</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RDIzQ0FEMkREOTRBNDk4RTlENjI2MDc2NDlBMzk5REQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjkxRkVDMkNDMjBGNDdFMkI1RDQ3Nzk4QjgwOTBGQjU</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6REFFOTk2NDVCNzFENDhGMUE5QkRBQTUxQzFDMzIwNUY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6N0I1MTE4OEZENzQzNDM5QTg0MUY2OURBMzhFNkE3MUE</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RDA5Rjk3QjhFNkE1NDk0OEE4NkEwNEEwREFCNzI4MjE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RjgzOTg4MERGN0Y4NEU5MEI1QkQyMDgzNTE0QzRGMjM</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RTNEMkY5QUE4QjNENDJCMzk2QzA4QUM5QzExRjYxMUQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OTc1NTlCNTZDODRENDVBRUE4Q0MyMjFGRkJDQTA0NzI</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MTQ5REQwRkJBN0E0NDQ4RjgwRTA0QzJDREMyQkFERUY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MzRBQTc5MTY4MDFCNEU4MEJGQzk3Q0ZGQzlBQ0NCMTc</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjM3MjAwMDJEMDk3NEE2N0ExQ0EwOTI1RkE5NkFFMDg7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NkQxRTgzQkY4MTRBNEVENThCQ0I1RTU3N0VFODVFNkQ</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDJFQzVCQzk2QjMxNDQ5NEJEMDE1QkE3MUMyQTkzMUE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QTUwMTgzQjdBNzg5NDIwRjhGRjY5MTc0OTExMjAwODc</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6M0JERTkzQkIzQUEwNERDM0JBMUMwODk3NTc5QjY0OUU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjAyNTlCQjA2MDA1NDg4MkE1MjEyNDI4MkQ2Q0EwMjI</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Imposition of Tax</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MTA3QkY0QTZFREYwNENGM0JENEE3RERCNDQ5MURBRTE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjAyNTlCQjA2MDA1NDg4MkE1MjEyNDI4MkQ2Q0EwMjI</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Requirements for S Election</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDYxRjczQzJFMEFGNEZBQTk4MzY3MjhBMUFFNjEzN0I7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NkQxRTgzQkY4MTRBNEVENThCQ0I1RTU3N0VFODVFNkQ</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Wagering Losses</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NEU2M0FDNjk0NUMxNDU5RkJCQUE5RjlDOTlGOTgyMjg7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MzRBQTc5MTY4MDFCNEU4MEJGQzk3Q0ZGQzlBQ0NCMTc</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Trade Secrets Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RkE5RkIzRDg2MDIzNDY1Mjg0OURCRDlFNTQ3NkE0NDA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Statute of Limitations</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MzY1MTlFRDg4ODdGNDg3MUFDMUEyM0FENTEyRDdCOTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MzlCOEQ1MDlDMUZGNEQ4QkIxNjhEMUFBOEM1NkMxNUE</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Trademark Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QUY4QzQ2QTdDQjY1NEFGMjlGQjMwMTYzM0FDN0IxRTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OTJGOTE4NkMyQ0M2NDcyQzlGMEQ3RTczNTg0MzBBM0E7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NkUwRDYyOTFBOTE1NDdCMjhGQjI0NjdDQ0M0NzEwMzY</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjExNjU3NDgxOUJGNEZBNjk2MEVENUM5NUNFNkJGNEI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RDYzOTE2MUM1OThGNEQ4QTlDRjY5N0ExMjRCNjZEMzU</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification><classificationGroup classificationScheme="indexing-terms"><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem score="90"><className>Tax</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OTNEM0E2OEE0RkQyNEY1MDhBQzdGMkQ4ODI4QTJDODE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></classificationGroup></metadata></legislativeDoc>