<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#349#000059#     1#        207.8#">Va. Code Ann. § 59.1-207.8</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_59.1-207.8"/><heading><desig>§ 59.1-207.8.</desig><title>Protection against defective agricultural equipment; applicability of chapter</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a"/><heading><desig>A.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> If agricultural equipment does not conform to all applicable express written warranties, and the consumer reports the nonconformity to the manufacturer, its agent or its authorized dealer during the term of such express written warranties or during the period of one year following the date of original delivery of the equipment to the first consumer, whichever is the earlier date, the manufacturer, its agent or its authorized dealers shall make such repairs as are necessary to conform the equipment to such express written warranties, notwithstanding the fact that such repairs are made after the expiration of such term or such one-year period.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b"/><heading><desig>B.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> If the manufacturer or its authorized dealers do not conform the equipment to any applicable express written warranty by repairing or correcting any defect or condition which substantially impairs the use and market value of the equipment to the consumer after a reasonable number of attempts, the manufacturer or its authorized dealer shall replace the equipment with comparable equipment acceptable to the consumer, charging the consumer only a reasonable allowance for the consumer's prior use of the equipment, or accept the return of the equipment from the consumer and refund to the consumer the cash purchase price, including sales tax, license fees, registration fees and any similar governmental charges, less such a reasonable allowance for prior use. Refunds shall be made to the consumer and lien holder or holder of a security interest, if any, as their interests may appear.</p><p>The reasonable allowance for prior use, which shall be no less than the fair rental value of the equipment, shall be the sum of (i) that amount attributable to use by the consumer or others prior to the consumer's first report of the nonconformity to the manufacturer or its authorized dealers, (ii) that amount attributable to use by the consumer or others during any period subsequent to such report when the vehicle is not out of service by reason of repair of the reported nonconformity, and (iii) that amount attributable to use by the consumer of equipment provided by the manufacturer or its authorized dealers while the equipment is out of service by reason of repair of the reported nonconformity.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c"/><heading><desig>C.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> For purposes of this chapter, it shall be presumed that a reasonable number of attempts have been undertaken to conform equipment to the applicable express written warranties if, within the express written warranty term or during the period of one year following the date of the original delivery of the equipment to the first consumer, whichever is the earlier date, (i) the same nonconformity has been subject to repair four or more times by the manufacturer or its authorized dealers, but such nonconformity continues to exist or (ii) the equipment is out of service by reason of repair for a cumulative total of thirty or more calendar days. However, those days shall not be counted when the consumer has been provided by the manufacturer or its authorized dealers with the use of other equipment which performs the same function or has been offered the use of such equipment.</p><p>The term of an express written warranty, such one-year period, and such thirty-day period shall be extended by any period of time during which repair services are not available to the consumer because of war, invasion, strike, fire, flood, or other natural disasters.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d"/><heading><desig>D.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> In no event shall the presumption provided in this section apply against a manufacturer unless the manufacturer has received prior direct written notification from or on behalf of the consumer and been offered an opportunity to cure the alleged defect. If the address of the manufacturer is not readily available to the consumer, such written notification shall be mailed to an authorized dealer. The authorized dealer shall upon receipt forward such notification to the manufacturer.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_e"/><heading><desig>E.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> It shall be an affirmative defense to any claim under this chapter that (i) an alleged nonconformity does not substantially impair such use and market value or (ii) a nonconformity is the result of abuse or neglect, or of modifications or alterations of the equipment not authorized by the manufacturer.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_f"/><heading><desig>F.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Any action brought under this chapter shall be commenced within six months following (i) expiration of the express written warranty term, or (ii) eighteen months following the date of the original delivery of the equipment to the consumer, whichever is the later date.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_g"/><heading><desig>G.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> This chapter shall apply to agricultural equipment sold after January 1, 1985.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_h"/><heading><desig>H.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Nothing in this chapter shall in any way limit or impair the rights or remedies which are otherwise available to a consumer under any other law.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_i"/><heading><desig>I.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Any consumer who suffers a loss by reason of a violation of any provision of this chapter may bring a civil action to enforce such provision.</p></bodyText></level><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p>1984, c. 503.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PTM0-004G-K0CJ-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 59.1.</desig><title>TRADE AND COMMERCE</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 17.2.</desig><title>AGRICULTURAL EQUIPMENT WARRANTIES</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Contracts Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QzY0RTZFMzE0RjkwNDdFQUI5M0U5N0ZFMjYyREMyQzU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QkFCNkU4QjM3MUM3NDg2NDg0QzYyRTBBRkMyNjJFQkY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NzgwNzJFRTk0NEIwNDhBQzlGMzBBMjIzMUVEMzgyM0I</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NTIyN0VDOEMzMDExNEIyQjg1MEYzMDFEQ0E1QTg2RjE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6M0IwMzUyMDFGOEYyNDMyQUI5RUFERDExM0VDQzZGNDc</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NEREREIyNjFBM0ZFNDI3REFFRjUwQkUxNUYyNjczRjU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OUY4QjU3NUExRDY1NEIwQjlDODhBODYxQ0U5QTU4NDk</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6ODVGQzdGODUyRjlGNDA4NTgyMThBQjg5REU2RjcwN0Y7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6ODlGRDE1QkREQjc5NDVCQzkxRjMxN0JERDBDNTgyM0U</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MzcwMDU2QkM2MUI3NDZGNUIxMTI0NTlCRjQ1MTkwRUQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NjMyQTk5NTFEQTg3NDM5NDk2RjAxOTA3MzY3MjczNUM</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NjEwODk4NDI0QjE4NDVCNDhDNTRGOUQ1MzY2REU0RjM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RThCQjU4NEM5NUVDNEY3ODlGMEY0MDFFODdEQzY4QTY</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Leases</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QzZGMjA5MTAyMDMyNEE1NkFFODI1NEZGQjAxMUFBOTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QzY2QTZCNkQ4MEJGNDZBNEIxN0I0Qzg0RjgwN0QzNkQ</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Governments</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjdEQjE4OUJDMzQxNDNEMEI0RTI1QUFCMzJENjEwRTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Time Limitations</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDU5MENDQ0RCNEUyNEZBQjk1MkZGNTZGMzg1RTgyQjI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OUMyNDcyQTZEN0MxNDEzMEI0RDFFOTYwOTFFQjRDNzE</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification><classificationGroup classificationScheme="indexing-terms"><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem score="90"><className>Antitrust</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6REEyRTNDM0JGQzYyNEMyOEFGNTAwNUJEOUU1MDg4NjU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></classificationGroup></metadata></legislativeDoc>