<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#349#000062#     1#        69.34#">Va. Code Ann. § 62.1-69.34</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_62.1-69.34"/><heading><desig>§ 62.1-69.34.</desig><title>Virginia Roanoke River Basin Advisory Committee established; purpose; membership; terms; meetings</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a"/><heading><desig>A.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The Virginia Roanoke River Basin Advisory Committee, hereinafter referred to as the "Committee," is hereby established in the executive branch of state government as an advisory committee to the Virginia delegation to the Roanoke River Basin Bi-State Commission. The Committee shall assist the delegation in fulfilling its duties and carrying out the objectives of the Commission, pursuant to <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 62.1-69.39"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 62.1-69.39">§ 62.1-69.39.<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000062#     1#        69.39#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> The advisory committee shall be composed of 23 members as follows: two members of the Senate, whose districts include a part of the Virginia portion of the Roanoke River Basin, to be appointed by the Senate Committee on Rules; four members of the House of Delegates, whose districts include a part of the Virginia portion of the Roanoke River Basin, to be appointed by the Speaker of the House of Delegates in accordance with the principles of proportional representation contained in the Rules of the House of Delegates; one nonlegislative citizen member at large appointed by the Senate Committee on Rules; one nonlegislative citizen member at large appointed by the Speaker of the House of Delegates; 11 nonlegislative citizen members selected by the legislative members of the advisory committee such that two are chosen from recommendations of each of the following: the Central Virginia Planning District Commission, the West Piedmont Planning District Commission, the Southside Planning District Commission, the Piedmont Planning District Commission, and the Roanoke Valley Alleghany Planning District Commission; and one member selected by the legislative members of the advisory committee from among recommendations submitted by the New River Valley Planning District Commission; and the Virginia member of the United States House of Representatives, whose district includes the largest portion of the Basin, or his designee, and three representatives of the State of North Carolina appointed in a manner as the General Assembly of North Carolina may determine appropriate. Except for the representatives of North Carolina, all nonlegislative citizen members shall be citizens of the Commonwealth of Virginia. The Virginia member of the United States House of Representatives, the members of the Virginia General Assembly, and the representatives of North Carolina shall serve ex officio without voting privileges. Of the recommendations submitted by planning district commissions authorized to recommend two members, one member shall be a nonlegislative citizen who resides within the respective planning district. However, the New River Valley Planning District Commission may recommend either one nonlegislative citizen at large who resides within the planning district or one member, who at the time of the recommendation, is serving as an elected member or an employee of a local governing body, or one member of the board of directors or an employee of the planning district commission. All persons recommended by the planning district commissions to serve as members of the advisory committee shall reside within the Basin's watershed, represent the diversity of interests in the jurisdictions comprising the respective planning district commissions, and demonstrate interest, experience, or expertise in water-related Basin issues.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b"/><heading><desig>B.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> State and federal legislative members and local government officials appointed to the advisory committee shall serve terms coincident with their terms of office. Nonlegislative citizen members appointed by the Senate Committee on Rules and the Speaker of the House of Delegates to serve on the advisory committee, and ex officio members representing the State of North Carolina shall serve a term of two years. Initially, planning district commissions authorized to recommend two nonlegislative citizen members to the advisory committee shall recommend one member for a term of two years and one member for a term of one year. However, the nonlegislative citizen member recommended to serve on the advisory committee by the New River Valley Planning District Commission shall serve a term of one year. After the initial staggering of terms, the term of office of nonlegislative citizen members recommended by the planning district commissions shall be for two years. Nonlegislative citizen members recommended by planning district commissions shall be eligible for reappointment, if such members shall have attended at least one-half of all meetings of the Commission during their current term of service. Appointments to fill vacancies, other than by expiration of a term, shall be made for the unexpired terms. Vacancies shall be filled in the same manner as the original appointment.</p><p>The advisory committee shall elect a chairman and a vice-chairman from among its voting members. A majority of the voting members shall constitute a quorum. The meetings of the advisory committee shall be held at the call of the chairman or whenever the majority of the voting members so request.</p></bodyText></level><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p><citation normalizedCite="2002 VA CH 657"><content><span normalizedCite="2002 Va. Ch. 657">2002, cc. 657<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2002#000657#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2002 VA CH 843"><content><span normalizedCite="2002 Va. Ch. 843">843<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2002#000843#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2003 VA CH 885"><content><span normalizedCite="2003 Va. Ch. 885">2003, c. 885<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2003#000885#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2004 VA CH 403"><content><span normalizedCite="2004 Va. Ch. 403">2004, c. 403<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2004#000403#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2010 VA CH 394"><content><span normalizedCite="2010 Va. Ch. 394">2010, cc. 394<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2010#000394#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2010 VA CH 729"><content><span normalizedCite="2010 Va. Ch. 729">729<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2010#000729#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PVB0-004G-K251-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 62.1.</desig><title>WATERS OF THE STATE, PORTS AND HARBORS</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 5.4.</desig><title>VIRGINIA ROANOKE RIVER BASIN ADVISORY COMMITTEE</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Governments</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjdEQjE4OUJDMzQxNDNEMEI0RTI1QUFCMzJENjEwRTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Employees &amp; Officials</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDNCMDQzRTY3RDY3NDNEOEE4RDg2OUFEOTRBNDREQzg7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Njg1MkM3RkYyNzIxNEVFRkJFMTI2NUM4NUU1ODdEM0Q</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification><classificationGroup classificationScheme="indexing-terms"><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem score="90"><className>Admiralty &amp; Maritime</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QzRDNDVDOTdGRUQ1NDE1M0I1RjRBRDFBRTI3ODFGMDk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem score="90"><className>Transportation</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RTYzRTk5RDVBQkQ2NDcwQzk2NTU3ODQ5OEE3NDlBNzk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></classificationGroup></metadata></legislativeDoc>