<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#349#000032#     1#        122.6#">Va. Code Ann. § 32.1-122.6</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_32.1-122.6"/><heading><desig>§ 32.1-122.6.</desig><title>Conditional grants for certain medical students</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a"/><heading><desig>A.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> With such funds as are appropriated for this purpose, the Board of Health shall establish annual medical scholarships for students who intend to enter the designated specialties of family practice medicine, general internal medicine, pediatrics, and obstetrics/gynecology and who are in good standing at a medical school in the United States that has received accreditation or provisional accreditation from the Liaison Committee on Medical Education or the Bureau of Professional Education of the American Osteopathic Association. No recipient shall be awarded more than five scholarships. The amount and number of such scholarships shall be determined annually as provided in the appropriation act. The Commissioner shall act as fiscal agent for the Board in administration of the scholarship funds.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b"/><heading><desig>B.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The Board shall promulgate regulations to administer this scholarship program that shall include:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Qualifications of applicants;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Criteria for award of the scholarships to assure that recipients will fulfill the practice obligations established in this section;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Standards to assure that these scholarships increase access to primary health care for individuals who are indigent or who are recipients of public assistance;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_4"/><heading><desig>4.</desig><title><emphasis typeStyle="it"> (Effective until October 1, 2016)</emphasis></title></heading><bodyText><p> Assurances that bona fide residents of Virginia, as determined by <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 23-7.4"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 23 -7.4">§ 23-7.4<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#123#000023#       7.4#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, students of economically disadvantaged backgrounds and residents of medically underserved areas are given preference over nonresidents in determining scholarship eligibility and awards;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_4_seq_2"/><heading><desig>4.</desig><title><emphasis typeStyle="it"> (Effective October 1, 2016)</emphasis></title></heading><bodyText><p> Assurances that bona fide residents of Virginia, as determined by § 23.1-502, students of economically disadvantaged backgrounds and residents of medically underserved areas are given preference over nonresidents in determining scholarship eligibility and awards;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_5"/><heading><desig>5.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Assurances that scholarship recipients will begin medical practice in one of the designated specialties in an underserved area of the Commonwealth within two years following completion of their residencies;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_6"/><heading><desig>6.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Methods for reimbursement of the Commonwealth by recipients who fail to complete medical school or who fail to honor the obligation to engage in medical practice for a period of years equal to the number of annual scholarships received;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_7"/><heading><desig>7.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Procedures for reimbursing any recipient who has repaid the Commonwealth for part or all of any scholarship and who later fulfills the terms of his contract; and</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_8"/><heading><desig>8.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Reporting of data related to the recipients of the scholarships by the medical schools.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c"/><heading><desig>C.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Prior to the award of any scholarship, the applicant shall sign a contract in which he agrees to engage continuously in one of the designated specialties of medical practice in an underserved area in Virginia for a period of years equal to the number of annual scholarships received. The contract shall specify that no form of medical practice such as military service or public health service may be substituted for the obligation to practice in one of the designated specialties in an underserved area in the Commonwealth.</p><p>The contract shall provide that the applicant will not voluntarily obligate himself for more than the minimum period of military service required for physicians by the laws of the United States and that, upon completion of this minimum period of obligatory military service, the applicant will promptly begin to practice in an underserved area in one of the designated specialties for the requisite number of years. The contract shall include other provisions as considered necessary by the Attorney General and the Commissioner.</p><p>The contract may be terminated by the recipient while the recipient is enrolled in medical school upon providing notice and immediate repayment of the total amount of scholarship funds received plus interest at the prevailing bank rate for similar amounts of unsecured debt.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d"/><heading><desig>D.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> In the event the recipient fails to maintain a satisfactory scholastic standing, the recipient may, upon certification of the Commissioner, be relieved of the obligations under the contract to engage in medical practice in an underserved area upon repayment to the Commonwealth of the total amount of scholarship funds received plus interest at the prevailing bank rate for similar amounts of unsecured debt.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_e"/><heading><desig>E.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> In the event the recipient dies or becomes permanently disabled so as not to be able to engage in the practice of medicine, the recipient or his estate may, upon certification of the Commissioner, be relieved of the obligation under the contract to engage in medical practice in an underserved area upon repayment to the Commonwealth of the total amount of scholarship funds plus interest on such amount computed at eight percent per annum from the date of receipt of scholarship funds. This obligation may be waived in whole or in part by the Commissioner in his discretion upon application by the recipient or his estate to the Commissioner with proof of hardship or inability to pay.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_f"/><heading><desig>F.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Except as provided in subsections D and E, any recipient of a scholarship who fails or refuses to fulfill his obligation to practice medicine in one of the designated specialties in an underserved area for a period of years equal to the number of annual scholarships received shall reimburse the Commonwealth three times the total amount of the scholarship funds received plus interest at the prevailing bank rate for similar amounts of unsecured debt. If the recipient has fulfilled part of his contractual obligations by serving in an underserved area in one of the designated specialties, the total amount of the scholarship funds received shall be reduced by the amount of the annual scholarship multiplied by the number of years served.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_g"/><heading><desig>G.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The Commissioner shall collect all repayments required by this section and may establish a schedule of payments for reimbursement consistent with the regulations of the Board. No schedule of payments shall amortize the total amount due for a period of longer than two years following the completion of the recipient's postgraduate training or the recipient's entrance into the full-time practice of medicine, whichever is later. All such funds, including any interest thereon, shall be used only for the purposes of this section and shall not revert to the general fund. If any recipient fails to make any payment when and as due, the Commissioner shall notify the Attorney General. The Attorney General shall take such action as he deems proper. In the event court action is required to collect a delinquent scholarship account, the recipient shall be responsible for the court costs and reasonable attorney fees incurred by the Commonwealth in such collection.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_h"/><heading><desig>H.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> For purposes of this section, the term "underserved area" includes those medically underserved areas designated by the Board pursuant to <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 32.1-122.5"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 32.1-122.5">§ 32.1-122.5<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000032#     1#        122.5#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> and health professional shortage areas designated in accordance with the criteria established in 42 C.F.R. Part 5.</p></bodyText></level><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p><citation normalizedCite="1990 VA CH 874"><content><span normalizedCite="1990 Va. Ch. 874">1990, cc. 874<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1990#000874#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1990 VA CH 877"><content><span normalizedCite="1990 Va. Ch. 877">877<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1990#000877#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1991 VA CH 134"><content><span normalizedCite="1991 Va. Ch. 134">1991, c. 134<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1991#000134#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1994 VA CH 281"><content><span normalizedCite="1994 Va. Ch. 281">1994, cc. 281<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1994#000281#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1994 VA CH 867"><content><span normalizedCite="1994 Va. Ch. 867">867<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1994#000867#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2000 VA CH 926"><content><span normalizedCite="2000 Va. Ch. 926">2000, c. 926<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2000#000926#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2001 VA CH 188"><content><span normalizedCite="2001 Va. Ch. 188">2001, c. 188<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2001#000188#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2002 VA CH 87"><content><span normalizedCite="2002 Va. Ch. 87">2002, cc. 87<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2002#000087#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2002 VA CH 478"><content><span normalizedCite="2002 Va. Ch. 478">478<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2002#000478#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2015 VA CH 532"><content><span normalizedCite="2015 Va. Ch. 532">2015, c. 532<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2015#000532#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PV00-004G-K0PH-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 32.1.</desig><title>HEALTH</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 4.</desig><title>HEALTH CARE PLANNING</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="article"><heading><desig>ARTICLE 6.</desig><title>PRIMARY HEALTH CARE SYSTEM</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Banking Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjQyMUFCOUJBNURBNEFDREE3MTNCNDk5QkQ4NUM3RjI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDREMDBDMEE3QUU4NEZDRkE2REY4QTFCOTFEOUEyN0M7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6N0Y1RjBFRTIyMTY1NEU3RUEyQTMwRDEzRTY2NTlBMEY</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Education Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDkzNUEzQzFBNEZBNEFBREIxNDM5MTc1MUU5QjI4MTY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Disadvantaged Students</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QkM5NDhGNDY2QUMwNEU0NjlEODU1RkM0QjlFQUVFQUU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QzMyRkUwN0EzNzQ2NENEMUJEMDY4MEYxRjJCNzUxODE</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Eligibility for Financial Aid</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MURBQTRCMkI1OTAxNEQ0MzlFMTA5NDQ1RUEyNkY1NEU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Njk4RUMyMDg4ODMwNDIwNUI1NEQwMDE0OUU3REYyOTM</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Public Health &amp; Welfare Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDYwRTY1MDg3MTk5NDUyNkFFRDI1RjJBRERGQ0UxNzI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NUVCNTZERDE5OTI4NDJDRUEzMDVFNjQ3NkEyMjI5QUI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MTlCM0Q3MTlFNUQ0NDA5OTgwQTEwQjE1M0ZGMTlFQjc</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification><classificationGroup classificationScheme="indexing-terms"><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem score="90"><className>Healthcare</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NkUxMkVDQjJDOEY5NDVDQ0E5NTFEMTlDMjIwNzVERjc7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></classificationGroup></metadata></legislativeDoc>