<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#349#000059#     1#          333#">Va. Code Ann. § 59.1-333</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_59.1-333"/><heading><desig>§ 59.1-333.</desig><title>Nondisturbance provisions</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><bodyText><p>With respect to any property in this Commonwealth acquired and put into operation by a membership camping operator after July 1, 1985, the membership camping operator shall neither offer nor execute a membership camping contract in this Commonwealth granting the right to use such property until:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Each person holding an interest in a blanket encumbrance shall have executed and delivered a nondisturbance agreement which includes the following provisions: (i) that the rights of the owner or owners of the blanket encumbrance in the affected campground are subordinate to the rights of purchasers, and (ii) that any person who acquires the affected campground or any portion thereof by the exercise of any right of sale or foreclosure contained in such agreement shall take the same subject to the rights of the purchasers, and (iii) that the owner or owners of the blanket encumbrance shall not use or cause the property to be used in any manner which interferes with the right of the purchasers to use the campground and its facilities in accordance with the terms and conditions of the membership camping contract. Such agreement shall be recorded in the clerk's office of the circuit court in which the property is located; and</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Every financial institution providing a major hypothecation loan to the membership camping operator (the "hypothecation lender") which has a lien on, or security interest in the membership camping operator's ownership interest in the campground shall have executed and delivered a nondisturbance agreement and recorded such agreement in the clerk's office of the circuit court in which the campground is located. In addition, each person holding an interest in a blanket encumbrance superior to the interest held by the hypothecation lender shall have executed, delivered and recorded an instrument stating that such person shall give the hypothecation lender notice of, and at least thirty days to cure, any default under the blanket encumbrance before such person commences any foreclosure action affecting the campground. For the purposes of this provision, a major hypothecation loan to a membership camping operator is a loan or line of credit secured by substantially all of the contracts receivable arising from the membership camping operator's sale of membership camping contracts; or</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> There shall have been delivered to and accepted by the Commissioner a surety bond or letter of credit satisfying the following requirements: The surety bond or letter of credit shall be issued to the Commissioner for the benefit of purchasers and shall be in an amount which is not less than 105 percent of the remaining principal balance of every indebtedness secured by a blanket encumbrance affecting the campground. Such bond shall be issued by a surety authorized to do business in this Commonwealth and having sufficient net worth to satisfy the indebtedness. Such letter of credit shall be irrevocable and shall be drawn upon a bank, savings and loan, or financial institution and shall be in form and content acceptable to the Commissioner. The bond or letter of credit shall provide for payment of all amounts secured by the blanket encumbrance, including costs, expenses, and legal fees of the lien holder, if for any reason the blanket encumbrance is enforced. The bond or letter of credit may be reduced at the option of the membership camping operator periodically in proportion to the reductions of the amounts secured by the blanket encumbrance.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_4"/><heading><desig>4.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The nondisturbance agreement may be amended provided the provisions of this section are not diminished or altered by the amendment.</p></bodyText></level></level><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p>1985, c. 409.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PTM0-004G-K0H1-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 59.1.</desig><title>TRADE AND COMMERCE</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 25.</desig><title>VIRGINIA MEMBERSHIP CAMPING ACT</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="article"><heading><desig>ARTICLE 3.</desig><title>PROTECTION OF PURCHASERS</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Banking Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjQyMUFCOUJBNURBNEFDREE3MTNCNDk5QkQ4NUM3RjI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6ODU3OEVBMUY0ODg3NDY5ODgxQjY1QkI1M0QzQjUxQjc7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MkQ2RDkwNzExNkE4NDgwOUI3MDEyMDU4RDY4MEI0QkQ</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Letters of Credit</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NEQ5NTI4QTQ4OTFDNDM3QkE1RTVBNkQyQzA1NUVDOEM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MkQ2RDkwNzExNkE4NDgwOUI3MDEyMDU4RDY4MEI0QkQ</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Commercial Law (UCC)</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QUI5QjdCNzBDNjY0NEY3QzlGRTNCQTMzQ0IwQ0MzRUQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Costs &amp; Attorney Fees</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QkUxMDJDRDc1MkJENEI5MEFDOTdGODg5QTZBODVCNzU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDgyNUFFNDU3NTk2NERDQUJGODcwNzhEMDA1ODA0RjA</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Contracts Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QzY0RTZFMzE0RjkwNDdFQUI5M0U5N0ZFMjYyREMyQzU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Deliveries</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MTE3MkJDREQ2MThFNERFMEI3QjJBRDBFQTg1QUE0RTU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NTNFRjkzQzZEMEM4NDg2QUJFODE1MzFCMjNDNUY3OTA</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification><classificationGroup classificationScheme="indexing-terms"><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem score="90"><className>Antitrust</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6REEyRTNDM0JGQzYyNEMyOEFGNTAwNUJEOUU1MDg4NjU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></classificationGroup></metadata></legislativeDoc>