<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#349#000062#     1#          199#">Va. Code Ann. § 62.1-199</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_62.1-199"/><heading><desig>§ 62.1-199.</desig><title>Definitions</title></heading><bodyText><p>As used in this chapter, unless a different meaning clearly appears from the context:</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Authority"</emphasis> means the Virginia Resources Authority created by this chapter.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Board of Directors"</emphasis> means the Board of Directors of the Authority.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Bonds"</emphasis> means any bonds, notes, debentures, interim certificates, bond, grant or revenue anticipation notes, lease and sale-leaseback transactions or any other obligations of the Authority for the payment of money.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Capital Reserve Fund"</emphasis> means the reserve fund created and established by the Authority in accordance with <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 62.1-215"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 62.1-215">§ 62.1-215<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000062#     1#          215#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Cost,"</emphasis> as applied to any project financed under the provisions of this chapter, means the total of all costs incurred by the local government as reasonable and necessary for carrying out all works and undertakings necessary or incident to the accomplishment of any project. It includes, without limitation, all necessary developmental, planning and feasibility studies, surveys, plans and specifications, architectural, engineering, financial, legal or other special services, the cost of acquisition of land and any buildings and improvements thereon, including the discharge of any obligations of the sellers of such land, buildings or improvements, real estate appraisals, site preparation and development, including demolition or removal of existing structures, construction and reconstruction, labor, materials, machinery and equipment, the reasonable costs of financing incurred by the local government in the course of the development of the project, including the cost of any credit enhancements, carrying charges incurred before placing the project in service, interest on local obligations issued to finance the project to a date subsequent to the estimated date the project is to be placed in service, necessary expenses incurred in connection with placing the project in service, the funding of accounts and reserves which the Authority may require and the cost of other items which the Authority determines to be reasonable and necessary. It also includes the amount of any contribution, grant or aid which a local government may make or give to any adjoining state, the District of Columbia or any department, agency or instrumentality thereof to pay the costs incident and necessary to the accomplishment of any project, including, without limitation, the items set forth above. The term also includes interest and principal payments pursuant to any installment purchase agreement.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Credit enhancements"</emphasis> means surety bonds, insurance policies, letters of credit, guarantees and other forms of collateral or security.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Defective drywall"</emphasis> means the same as that term is defined in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 36-156.1"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 36 -156.1">§ 36-156.1.<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#123#000036#     156.1#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation></p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Federal facility"</emphasis> means any building or infrastructure used or to be used by the federal government, including any building or infrastructure located on lands owned by the federal government.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Federal government"</emphasis> means the United States of America, or any department, agency or instrumentality, corporate or otherwise, of the United States of America.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Former federal facility"</emphasis> means any federal facility formerly used by the federal government or in transition from use by the federal government to a facility all or part of which is to serve any local government.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Local government"</emphasis> means any county, city, town, municipal corporation, authority, district, commission or political subdivision created by the General Assembly or pursuant to the Constitution and laws of the Commonwealth or any combination of any two or more of the foregoing.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Local obligations"</emphasis> means any bonds, notes, debentures, interim certificates, bond, grant or revenue anticipation notes, leases, credit enhancements, or any other obligations of a local government for the payment of money.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Minimum capital reserve fund requirement"</emphasis> means, as of any particular date of computation, the amount of money designated as the minimum capital reserve fund requirement which may be established in the resolution of the Authority authorizing the issuance of, or the trust indenture securing, any outstanding issue of bonds or credit enhancement.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Project"</emphasis> means (i) any water supply or wastewater treatment facility including a facility for receiving and stabilizing septage or a soil drainage management facility and any solid waste treatment, disposal, or management facility, recycling facility, federal facility or former federal facility, or resource recovery facility located or to be located in the Commonwealth, the District of Columbia or any adjoining state, all or part of which facility serves or is to serve any local government; and (ii) any federal facility located or to be located in the Commonwealth, provided that both the Board of Directors of the Authority and the governing body of the local government receiving the benefit of the loan, grant, or credit enhancement from the Authority make a determination or finding to be embodied in a resolution or ordinance that the undertaking and financing of such facility is necessary for the location or retention of such facility and the related use by the federal government in the Commonwealth. The term includes, without limitation, water supply and intake facilities; water treatment and filtration facilities; water storage facilities; water distribution facilities; sewage and wastewater (including surface and ground water) collection, treatment and disposal facilities; drainage facilities and projects; solid waste treatment, disposal or management facilities; recycling facilities; resource recovery facilities; related office, administrative, storage, maintenance and laboratory facilities; and interests in land related thereto. The term also includes energy conservation measures and facility technology infrastructure as defined in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 11-34.2"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 11 -34.2">§ 11-34.2<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#123#000011#      34.2#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> and other energy objectives as defined in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 67-101"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 67 -101">§ 67-101<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#123#000067#       101#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>. The term also means any heavy rail transportation facilities operated by a transportation district, created under the Transportation District Act of 1964 (<citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 33.2-1900"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 33.2-1900">§ 33.2-1900<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000033#     2#         1900#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> et seq.), which operates heavy rail freight service, including rolling stock, barge loading facilities, and any related marine or rail equipment. The term also means, without limitation, the design and construction of roads, the construction of local government buildings, including administrative and operations systems and other local government equipment and infrastructure, public parking garages and other public transportation facilities, and facilities for public transportation by commuter rail. In addition, the term means any project as defined in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 5.1-30.1"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 5.1-30.1">§ 5.1-30.1<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000005#     1#         30.1#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> and any professional sports facility, including a major league baseball stadium as defined in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 15.2-5800"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 15.2-5800">§ 15.2-5800<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000015#     2#         5800#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, provided that the specific professional sports facility projects have been designated by the General Assembly as eligible for assistance from the Authority. The term also means any equipment, facilities, and technology infrastructure designed to provide broadband service. The term also means facilities supporting, related to, or otherwise used for public safety including, but not limited to, law-enforcement training facilities and emergency response, fire, rescue and police stations. The term also means the remediation, redevelopment and rehabilitation of property contaminated by the release of hazardous substances, hazardous wastes, solid wastes or petroleum where such remediation has not clearly been mandated by the United States Environmental Protection Agency, the Department of Environmental Quality, or a court pursuant to the Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation and Liability Act <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="42 USC 9601"><content><span normalizedCite="42 U.S.C. 9601">(42 U.S.C. § 9601<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1828#123#000042#       9601#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> et seq.), the Resource Conservation and Recovery Act <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="42 USC 6901"><content><span normalizedCite="42 U.S.C. 6901">(42 U.S.C. § 6901<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1828#123#000042#       6901#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> et seq.), the Virginia Waste Management Act (<citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 10.1-1400"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 10.1-1400">§ 10.1-1400<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000010#     1#         1400#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> et seq.), the State Water Control Law (§ 62.1-44.2 et seq.), or other applicable statutory or common law or where jurisdiction of those statutes has been waived. The term also means any program or project for land conservation, parks, park facilities, land for recreational purposes, or land preservation, including but not limited to any program or project involving the acquisition of rights or interests in land for the conservation or preservation of such land. The term also means any oyster restoration project, including planting and replanting with seed oysters, oyster shells, or other material that will catch, support, and grow oysters. The term also means any program or project to perform site acquisition or site development work for the benefit of economic and community development projects for any local government. The term also means any undertaking by a local government to build or facilitate the building of a recovered gas energy facility; and any local government renewable energy project, including solar, wind, biomass, waste-to-energy, and geothermal projects. The term also means any undertaking by a local government to facilitate the remediation of residential properties contaminated by the presence of defective drywall.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Recovered gas energy facility"</emphasis> means a facility, located at or adjacent to (i) a solid waste management facility permitted by the Department of Environmental Quality or (ii) a sewerage system or sewage treatment work described in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 62.1-44.18"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 62.1-44.18">§ 62.1-44.18<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000062#     1#        44.18#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> that is constructed and operated for the purpose of treating sewage and wastewater for discharge to state waters, which facility or work is constructed and operated for the purpose of (a) reclaiming or collecting methane or other combustible gas from the biodegradation or decomposition of solid waste, as defined in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 10.1-1400"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 10.1-1400">§ 10.1-1400<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000010#     1#         1400#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, that has been deposited in the solid waste management facility or sewerage system or sewage treatment work and (b) either using such gas to generate electric energy or upgrading the gas to pipeline quality and transmitting it off premises for sale or delivery to commercial or industrial purchasers or to a public utility or locality.</p></bodyText><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p>1984, c. 699; 1985, c. 67; 1986, c. 331; 1987, cc. 117, 133; <citation normalizedCite="1989 VA CH 533"><content><span normalizedCite="1989 Va. Ch. 533">1989, cc. 533<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1989#000533#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1989 VA CH 551"><content><span normalizedCite="1989 Va. Ch. 551">551<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1989#000551#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1990 VA CH 506"><content><span normalizedCite="1990 Va. Ch. 506">1990, c. 506<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1990#000506#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1998 VA CH 399"><content><span normalizedCite="1998 Va. Ch. 399">1998, c. 399<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1998#000399#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1999 VA CH 897"><content><span normalizedCite="1999 Va. Ch. 897">1999, c. 897<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1999#000897#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2000 VA CH 790"><content><span normalizedCite="2000 Va. Ch. 790">2000, c. 790<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2000#000790#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2001 VA CH 652"><content><span normalizedCite="2001 Va. Ch. 652">2001, cc. 652<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2001#000652#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2001 VA CH 661"><content><span normalizedCite="2001 Va. Ch. 661">661<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2001#000661#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2005 VA CH 727"><content><span normalizedCite="2005 Va. Ch. 727">2005, cc. 727<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2005#000727#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2005 VA CH 769"><content><span normalizedCite="2005 Va. Ch. 769">769<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2005#000769#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2007 VA CH 81"><content><span normalizedCite="2007 Va. Ch. 81">2007, cc. 81<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2007#000081#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2007 VA CH 649"><content><span normalizedCite="2007 Va. Ch. 649">649<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2007#000649#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2007 VA CH 663"><content><span normalizedCite="2007 Va. Ch. 663">663<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2007#000663#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2008 VA CH 3"><content><span normalizedCite="2008 Va. Ch. 3">2008, cc. 3<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2008#000003#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2008 VA CH 24"><content><span normalizedCite="2008 Va. Ch. 24">24<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2008#000024#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2008 VA CH 238"><content><span normalizedCite="2008 Va. Ch. 238">238<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2008#000238#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2008 VA CH 259"><content><span normalizedCite="2008 Va. Ch. 259">259<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2008#000259#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2008 VA CH 504"><content><span normalizedCite="2008 Va. Ch. 504">504<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2008#000504#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2008 VA CH 605"><content><span normalizedCite="2008 Va. Ch. 605">605<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2008#000605#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2008 VA CH 613"><content><span normalizedCite="2008 Va. Ch. 613">613<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2008#000613#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2009 VA CH 14"><content><span normalizedCite="2009 Va. Ch. 14">2009, cc. 14<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2009#000014#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2009 VA CH 246"><content><span normalizedCite="2009 Va. Ch. 246">246<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2009#000246#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2009 VA CH 311"><content><span normalizedCite="2009 Va. Ch. 311">311<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2009#000311#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2009 VA CH 543"><content><span normalizedCite="2009 Va. Ch. 543">543<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2009#000543#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2009 VA CH 632"><content><span normalizedCite="2009 Va. Ch. 632">632<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2009#000632#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2010 VA CH 42"><content><span normalizedCite="2010 Va. Ch. 42">2010, cc. 42<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2010#000042#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2010 VA CH 724"><content><span normalizedCite="2010 Va. Ch. 724">724<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2010#000724#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2010 VA CH 820"><content><span normalizedCite="2010 Va. Ch. 820">820<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2010#000820#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2011 VA CH 270"><content><span normalizedCite="2011 Va. Ch. 270">2011, cc. 270<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2011#000270#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2011 VA CH 616"><content><span normalizedCite="2011 Va. Ch. 616">616<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2011#000616#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PTM0-004G-K13R-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 62.1.</desig><title>WATERS OF THE STATE, PORTS AND HARBORS</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 21.</desig><title>VIRGINIA RESOURCES AUTHORITY</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Distribution, Processing &amp; Storage of Food &amp; Agricultural Products</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NENGNzZCMDU5RjcyNEM0NEFFOUU4ODFCQkZCOThBRkI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NkVDMzM4QkJENTg3NDQ0RDg3NTA5OEM3RkMyQTlENDI</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Hazardous Materials</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QzM5RkFCRDVCNzgyNERFQkEyNjFGODU0NjYxN0U2NTc7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QzczQ0MwNDEzMjhGNDIxQ0FEM0ExM0EwQjk0QjI0RTk</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Resource Recovery &amp; Recycling</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RTk4QTlBODAyQTJDNEM3NUJDNTMxOENDQUVDMDZEN0M7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OTVBMjY4ODg4OEM2NEIyMDg1MDBFQTVDQTgwNTczRTc</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Contracts Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QzY0RTZFMzE0RjkwNDdFQUI5M0U5N0ZFMjYyREMyQzU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Installment Contracts</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QTdFNDEzOUYwMzlDNDQ0MUI5MDI0NjJGNDBCNDJCNTE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Qjg1NzgyRDNGQzg1NEM5Nzg3RjA3MEUwRTA1QUI0NkU</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Energy &amp; Utilities Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OUUzODAyRDk1QzVFNEZGMEJDM0RGMDYxOTlEMEEzRDA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Electricity Transmission</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6M0FEMjU2NjgxQUJCNDYwOEE2RTU4OUUxOEYxNjQ5MDc7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjMwQzNCRThDRjkwNDY0QjlFNDJFQzY5QzVCMEE0MTY</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6ODcxOEQ3MjY5MjY4NDIwQUFFODlGNTYxQTcxQzkyOUY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NTAwOTgyMTVBNkJFNENFMzgyODE3NEYxNzdBQTU4RkM</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Qzk3MzQ5NjhDQjRGNEJBNzhBOEI5MkE3RjBEMTZDOUU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Rjk2NTk2ODk2RkMwNDZGQjgxNUI1RjE0MDk4MTNDQzY</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Environmental Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NzFDRDYyNkI2QjhBNDg3NTkyRjRDRkZEQjlCRkRBQzM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Disposal Standards</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MEZBQUU3OTJGRDU4NDE1Nzg0Q0I1QTBBM0M2QzMyMEI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OTVBMjY4ODg4OEM2NEIyMDg1MDBFQTVDQTgwNTczRTc</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Flow Control</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6ODMxMzUzNTRGQzgyNDU4RkE1OEI3Mzc2N0YxOEEyQTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OTVBMjY4ODg4OEM2NEIyMDg1MDBFQTVDQTgwNTczRTc</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RjZGMjIxQkQ4REVFNEU2NkFCMTAxOENGQ0FBNjY0ODA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OTQ2QTA0MkM1NTUxNDNBQ0I0RjQ1NzQ1NTBGODdFRjI</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Resource Recovery &amp; Recycling</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RTk4QTlBODAyQTJDNEM3NUJDNTMxOENDQUVDMDZEN0M7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OTVBMjY4ODg4OEM2NEIyMDg1MDBFQTVDQTgwNTczRTc</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Transporters</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NUU2MUMyNEVDMTNDNERDQjlBNDk0MjI1N0Q5QkNGREI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDc0NzYwNUQyNjQ4NEFBRjg3RjlBQjRCNzlCQjhGM0Q</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Governments</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjdEQjE4OUJDMzQxNDNEMEI0RTI1QUFCMzJENjEwRTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Administrative Boards</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QTYwRUFCMDc5MzQ5NDEyREFEQkU2NkE2MjRGQTlCNzY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Njg1MkM3RkYyNzIxNEVFRkJFMTI2NUM4NUU1ODdEM0Q</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Distribution, Processing &amp; Storage</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NENGNzZCMDU5RjcyNEM0NEFFOUU4ODFCQkZCOThBRkI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NkVDMzM4QkJENTg3NDQ0RDg3NTA5OEM3RkMyQTlENDI</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Duties &amp; Powers</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Njk1NTNGMzM0RTc3NDcyMUI4MENCQUQ1RDhEN0M1RUM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Njg1MkM3RkYyNzIxNEVFRkJFMTI2NUM4NUU1ODdEM0Q</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Finance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjMzOTBBRTg2MUVDNDdDNUE1M0QxNDk1RERCNjNCN0I7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Njg1MkM3RkYyNzIxNEVFRkJFMTI2NUM4NUU1ODdEM0Q</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RTVDMDgxQjQzQjJFNEE4RDlEODcxQkE3MEVBQkVCNDI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MkM1MTYwRDE0NkJBNEVFMEIxQjM3RUE2NDRFQUFEODY</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Property</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDhDNkM0Q0Y5QTIwNDlCODhEMkJFMUY4QzQxQTA2QkI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MkM1MTYwRDE0NkJBNEVFMEIxQjM3RUE2NDRFQUFEODY</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Real Property Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QUUyRTcxRURBNEY2NEE2MDk3QzBCNzRDOEY0NTZDQzk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Construction Loans</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RDNGMDlENjQ4NUYyNEM0MEIxRTAwMjAyRTdFRUNBRkY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MTY1MzRERDhBMDZCNDFBMDk0QUEwRjcyN0ZFNEY3REM</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Sale Leaseback Transactions</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MkQ4NzI0RkVBOUU1NDlDOUI0MThCMzNENDhBOTQwQzM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QkExOTIxOTg3RUQxNDgzNEFEQjczOTlGNzdBRjhBMkM</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Transportation Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RTYzRTk5RDVBQkQ2NDcwQzk2NTU3ODQ5OEE3NDlBNzk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Hazardous Materials</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QzM5RkFCRDVCNzgyNERFQkEyNjFGODU0NjYxN0U2NTc7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QzczQ0MwNDEzMjhGNDIxQ0FEM0ExM0EwQjk0QjI0RTk</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification><classificationGroup classificationScheme="indexing-terms"><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem score="90"><className>Admiralty &amp; Maritime</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QzRDNDVDOTdGRUQ1NDE1M0I1RjRBRDFBRTI3ODFGMDk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem score="90"><className>Transportation</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RTYzRTk5RDVBQkQ2NDcwQzk2NTU3ODQ5OEE3NDlBNzk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></classificationGroup></metadata></legislativeDoc>