<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#349#000038#     2#         2114#">Va. Code Ann. § 38.2-2114</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_38.2-2114"/><heading><desig>§ 38.2-2114.</desig><title>Grounds and procedure for termination of policy; contents of notice; review by Commissioner; exceptions; immunity from liability</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a"/><heading><desig>A.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Notwithstanding the provisions of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 38.2-2105"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 38.2-2105">§ 38.2-2105<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000038#     2#         2105#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, no policy or contract written to insure owner-occupied dwellings shall be canceled by an insurer unless written notice is mailed or delivered to the named insured at the address stated in the policy, or is delivered electronically to the address provided by the named insured, and cancellation is for one of the following reasons:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Failure to pay the premium when due;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Conviction of a crime arising out of acts increasing the probability that a peril insured against will occur;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Discovery of fraud or material misrepresentation;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_4"/><heading><desig>4.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Willful or reckless acts or omissions increasing the probability that a peril insured against will occur as determined from a physical inspection of the insured premises;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_5"/><heading><desig>5.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Physical changes in the property which result in the property becoming uninsurable as determined from a physical inspection of the insured premises; or</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_6"/><heading><desig>6.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Foreclosure efforts by the secured party against the subject property covered by the policy that have resulted in the sale of the property by a trustee under a deed of trust as duly recorded in the land title records of the jurisdiction in which the property is located.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b"/><heading><desig>B.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> No policy or contract written to insure owner-occupied dwellings shall be terminated by an insurer by refusal to renew except at the expiration of the stated policy period or term and unless the insurer or its agent acting on behalf of the insurer mails or delivers to the named insured, at the address stated in the policy, or delivers electronically to the address provided by the named insured, written notice of the insurer's refusal to renew the policy or contract.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c"/><heading><desig>C.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A written notice of cancellation of or refusal to renew a policy or contract written to insure owner-occupied dwellings shall:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> State the date that the insurer proposes to terminate the policy or contract, which shall be at least 30 days after mailing or delivering to the named insured the notice of cancellation or refusal to renew. However, when the policy is being terminated for the reason set forth in subdivision 1 of subsection A of this section, the date that the insurer proposes to terminate the policy may be less than 30 days but at least 10 days from the date of mailing or delivery;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> State the specific reason for terminating the policy or contract and provide for the notification required by the provisions of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 38.2-608"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 38.2-608">§§ 38.2-608<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000038#     2#          608#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> and <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 38.2-609"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 38.2-609">38.2-609<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000038#     2#          609#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> and subsection B of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 38.2-610"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 38.2-610">§ 38.2-610<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000038#     2#          610#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>. However, those notification requirements shall not apply when the policy is being canceled or not renewed for the reason set forth in subdivision 1 of subsection A of this section;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Advise the insured that within 10 days of receipt of the notice of termination he may request in writing that the Commissioner review the action of the insurer in terminating the policy or contract;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c_4"/><heading><desig>4.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Advise the insured of his possible eligibility for fire insurance coverage through the Virginia Property Insurance Association; and</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c_5"/><heading><desig>5.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Be in a type size authorized by <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 38.2-311"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 38.2-311">§ 38.2-311<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000038#     2#          311#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d"/><heading><desig>D.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Within 10 days of receipt of the notice of termination any insured or his attorney shall be entitled to request in writing to the Commissioner that he review the action of the insurer in terminating a policy or contract written to insure owner-occupied dwellings. Upon receipt of the request, the Commissioner shall promptly initiate a review to determine whether the insurer's cancellation or refusal to renew complies with the requirements of this section and of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 38.2-2113"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 38.2-2113">§ 38.2-2113<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000038#     2#         2113#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, if sent by mail or delivered electronically. The policy shall remain in full force and effect during the pendency of the review by the Commissioner except where the cancellation or refusal to renew is for reason of nonpayment of premium, in which case the policy shall terminate as of the date stated in the notice. Where the Commissioner finds from the review that the cancellation or refusal to renew has not complied with the requirements of this section or of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 38.2-2113"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 38.2-2113">§ 38.2-2113<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000038#     2#         2113#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, if sent by mail or delivered electronically, he shall immediately notify the insurer, the insured, and any other person to whom notice of cancellation or refusal to renew was required to be given by the terms of the policy that the cancellation or refusal to renew is not effective. Nothing in this section authorizes the Commissioner to substitute his judgment as to underwriting for that of the insurer.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_e"/><heading><desig>E.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Nothing in this section shall apply:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_e_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> To any policy written to insure owner-occupied dwellings that has been in effect for less than 90 days when the notice of termination is mailed or delivered to the insured, unless it is a renewal policy;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_e_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> If the insurer or its agent acting on behalf of the insurer has manifested its willingness to renew by issuing or offering to issue a renewal policy, certificate or other evidence of renewal, or has otherwise manifested its willingness to renew in writing to the insured. The written manifestation shall include the name of a proposed insurer, the expiration date of the policy, the type of insurance coverage and information regarding the estimated renewal premium;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_e_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> If the named insured or his duly constituted attorney-in-fact has notified the insurer or its agent orally, or in writing, if the insurer requires such notification to be in writing, that he wishes the policy to be canceled, or that he does not wish the policy to be renewed, or if, prior to the date of expiration, he fails to accept the offer of the insurer to renew the policy;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_e_4"/><heading><desig>4.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> To any contract or policy written through the Virginia Property Insurance Association or any residual market facility established pursuant to Chapter 27 (<citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 38.2-2700"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 38.2-2700">§ 38.2-2700<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000038#     2#         2700#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> et seq.) of this title; or</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_e_5"/><heading><desig>5.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> If an affiliated insurer has manifested its willingness to provide coverage at a lower premium than would have been charged for the same exposures on the expiring policy. The affiliated insurer shall manifest its willingness to provide coverage by issuing a policy with the types and limits of coverage at least equal to those contained in the expiring policy unless the named insured has requested a change in coverage or limits. When such offer is made by an affiliated insurer, an offer of renewal shall not be required of the insurer of the expiring policy, and the policy issued by the affiliated insurer shall be deemed to be a renewal policy.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_f"/><heading><desig>F.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Each insurer shall maintain, for at least one year, records of cancellation and refusal to renew and copies of every notice or statement referred to in subsection E of this section that it sends to any of its insureds.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_g"/><heading><desig>G.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> There shall be no liability on the part of and no cause of action of any nature shall arise against the Commissioner or his subordinates; any insurer, its authorized representative, its agents, or its employees; or any firm, person or corporation furnishing to the insurer information as to reasons for cancellation or refusal to renew, for any statement made by any of them in complying with this section or for providing information pertaining to the cancellation or refusal to renew.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_h"/><heading><desig>H.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Nothing in this section requires an insurer to renew a policy written to insure owner-occupied dwellings, if the insured does not conform to the occupational or membership requirements of an insurer who limits its writings to an occupation or membership of an organization.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_i"/><heading><desig>I.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> No insurer or agent shall refuse to renew a policy written to insure an owner-occupied dwelling, solely because of any one or more of the following factors:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_i_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Age;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_i_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Sex;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_i_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Residence;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_i_4"/><heading><desig>4.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Race;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_i_5"/><heading><desig>5.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Color;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_i_6"/><heading><desig>6.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Creed;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_i_7"/><heading><desig>7.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> National origin;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_i_8"/><heading><desig>8.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Ancestry;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_i_9"/><heading><desig>9.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Marital status;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_i_10"/><heading><desig>10.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Lawful occupation, including the military service; however, nothing in this subsection shall require any insurer to renew a policy for an insured where the insured's occupation has changed so as to increase materially the risk;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_i_11"/><heading><desig>11.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Credit information contained in a "consumer report," as defined in the federal Fair Credit Reporting Act, <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="15 USC 1681"><content><span normalizedCite="15 U.S.C. 1681">15 U.S.C. § 1681<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1828#123#000015#       1681#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> et seq., bearing on a natural person's creditworthiness, credit standing or credit capacity. If credit information is used, in part, as the basis for the nonrenewal, such credit information shall be based on a consumer report procured within 120 days from the effective date of the nonrenewal;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_i_12"/><heading><desig>12.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Any claim resulting primarily from natural causes;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_i_13"/><heading><desig>13.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> One or more claims that were incurred more than 60 months immediately prior to the expiration of the current policy period; or</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_i_14"/><heading><desig>14.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Any inquiry from an insured about his insurance coverage or policy provisions. For purposes of this subdivision, "inquiry" means a written or oral communication by an insured seeking information regarding coverage or policy provisions that does not notify the insurer of a loss, incident or accident, and that does not provide information indicating an increase in the hazard insured against. An insurer shall not report any inquiry as a claim to a loss history database maintained by a consumer reporting agency or insurance support organization.</p><p><pre/>Nothing in this section prohibits any insurer from setting rates in accordance with relevant actuarial data.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_j"/><heading><desig>J.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> No insurer shall cancel or refuse to renew a policy written to insure an owner-occupied dwelling because an insured under the policy is a foster parent and foster children reside at the insured dwelling.</p></bodyText></level><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p>1972, c. 110, § 38.1-371.2; 1975, c. 350; 1978, c. 441; 1983, c. 371; 1986, c. 562; <citation normalizedCite="1990 VA CH 293"><content><span normalizedCite="1990 Va. Ch. 293">1990, c. 293<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1990#000293#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1995 VA CH 3"><content><span normalizedCite="1995 Va. Ch. 3">1995, c. 3<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1995#000003#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1996 VA CH 237"><content><span normalizedCite="1996 Va. Ch. 237">1996, c. 237<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1996#000237#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1998 VA CH 142"><content><span normalizedCite="1998 Va. Ch. 142">1998, c. 142<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1998#000142#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2003 VA CH 543"><content><span normalizedCite="2003 Va. Ch. 543">2003, cc. 543<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2003#000543#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2003 VA CH 553"><content><span normalizedCite="2003 Va. Ch. 553">553<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2003#000553#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2004 VA CH 300"><content><span normalizedCite="2004 Va. Ch. 300">2004, c. 300<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2004#000300#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2005 VA CH 872"><content><span normalizedCite="2005 Va. Ch. 872">2005, c. 872<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2005#000872#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2008 VA CH 58"><content><span normalizedCite="2008 Va. Ch. 58">2008, cc. 58<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2008#000058#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2008 VA CH 221"><content><span normalizedCite="2008 Va. Ch. 221">221<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2008#000221#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2009 VA CH 215"><content><span normalizedCite="2009 Va. Ch. 215">2009, cc. 215<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2009#000215#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2009 VA CH 442"><content><span normalizedCite="2009 Va. Ch. 442">442<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2009#000442#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2013 VA CH 257"><content><span normalizedCite="2013 Va. Ch. 257">2013, c. 257<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2013#000257#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PT40-004G-K4M6-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 38.2.</desig><title>INSURANCE</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 21.</desig><title>FIRE INSURANCE POLICIES</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Banking Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjQyMUFCOUJBNURBNEFDREE3MTNCNDk5QkQ4NUM3RjI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Consumer Reports</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NkZDNDZGMzE5Mjk2NDE0RkIyQjI1NTFDMkQzRTE0QzE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NTBENkY4NTNENTk0NEE0RUJBMDVBMTYyNjJBNjU2Njc</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NzIwNzNERjZDMUNCNEY5Mzk0OUY2NjdFM0E3N0ZBQTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NTBENkY4NTNENTk0NEE0RUJBMDVBMTYyNjJBNjU2Njc</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Fair Credit Reporting Act</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDVCNDg1QjUyNEJENDdCRUFCNUQ2NUYxOTI2NzhBRTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDZBQjAwRjNDNUNDNEJGQkE1QjQ1NjJDRTMxNkQyRTA</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Contracts Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QzY0RTZFMzE0RjkwNDdFQUI5M0U5N0ZFMjYyREMyQzU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Discharge &amp; Termination</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MkYzNDBBRjgzQjhENDZBRjg1MkNGNzc4NTE0Mzg0NDQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OTdCODg3NEVGQTY5NENDQ0EzRkEwMzNGOTVBQTE0NEY</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Material Misrepresentations</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6N0I5NDY3NTRCNjFGNDUzOTkyQkFCRDYwQUU4NjBENzg7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NUVEMDJCNUI3RTA0NEI4OEEwRjUzMEIzMkFFNjUzMzM</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Criminal Law &amp; Procedure</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NEU0RkE1OUQwNUQwNDgxODhEODZCMjkzOTg3NThBNzk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Elements</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OTRGRDE5NTkxQTdBNDM0RTk3NUU0OTY4NTU4MDExNTU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUQ1QjVBOEQzRTdGNENBQjg2NTgwM0JCRjFBNDIyQzk</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Insurance Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDM4MzQ2QUYzMTY0NDQzQTkxRDQwRUUzRUM5RDg0OEM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Fair Credit Reporting Act</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDVCNDg1QjUyNEJENDdCRUFCNUQ2NUYxOTI2NzhBRTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDZBQjAwRjNDNUNDNEJGQkE1QjQ1NjJDRTMxNkQyRTA</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Fire Insurance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NzcwRjdBM0IxRjQzNEY1N0FGMjM4QkY0QTg3OTYyNjE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QzZFRUM3RDQ3M0Y1NDc1RUE2N0E4M0ZGQjY0MDk1MTY</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Fraudulent Intent</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RThEMTgyMkVFNDVDNEUyRkE1NTU0RjFCNzJBNjFCQzU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MEVBQUY4MEE4MTAxNEFDREJBRDYzMjdDOTZDMjM4NTI</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Qjg3NDkyQTRCRTg3NEI1QzgxQzY2QjBBMDI3NENFNDU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RkE2MEIwQkEwRTExNDVGOUJCRDhBRUQ3QTRGNDdDNTI</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Qzk5RUVBMkQ4Qzk3NDUwNEIyMTJBQkE2MzE2RTc0NDU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MEVBQUY4MEE4MTAxNEFDREJBRDYzMjdDOTZDMjM4NTI</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OTkzRDNCRkNDRUM3NDE2M0FGOUMzQjZEQzJFNkNDQUE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Q0Y1RUQ5MjUzRjRCNENENzlGQzc1RDJDMjc3ODAxNEU</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MTFDNEI4Q0Y0MTk0NDgyRTkzOEY5NDY2ODM1MkJFRUY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QzZFRUM3RDQ3M0Y1NDc1RUE2N0E4M0ZGQjY0MDk1MTY</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Materiality</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RjI5OTc3NEI1M0IzNDQzRjlFNTk0QTc2MkZEQUVCMDg7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MEVBQUY4MEE4MTAxNEFDREJBRDYzMjdDOTZDMjM4NTI</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Nonpayment of Premiums</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MTU2MDE4RkM3MUMzNEFEMzhCQzJGRTIxNUJFN0NCRTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RkE2MEIwQkEwRTExNDVGOUJCRDhBRUQ3QTRGNDdDNTI</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Notice Requirements</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MkUwNjY2QUVERDA1NDJEMEE3NDRFREUzQUFEMkQ2QUQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RkE2MEIwQkEwRTExNDVGOUJCRDhBRUQ3QTRGNDdDNTI</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Offer &amp; Acceptance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MTNGMjIyRkU5RkJCNDU1RkIwNDMzMDgxMjJBMjNCRkU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Qjg2NDVEOEQ5Q0IxNEQ0RTg0MTkyQ0ZCMkNENDlBODY</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Policy Delivery</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OUYyOUJCOTEwRjgwNENENUE4M0JFRkZDRDVGMzc4Rjg7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Qjg2NDVEOEQ5Q0IxNEQ0RTg0MTkyQ0ZCMkNENDlBODY</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Labor &amp; Employment Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MTE3QUQwOTA0MUYzNDlCMEFFMjUwRUNDM0RDRkM5QzM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Express Contracts</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDVCMTYzRjVCM0VFNERFOEExOEFBNzkzMkFFQTAzQUE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MTVFNUFFREQyQzIwNEIwQThCMDMzQzEwNTBEN0U1QUU</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification><classificationGroup classificationScheme="indexing-terms"><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem score="90"><className>Insurance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDM4MzQ2QUYzMTY0NDQzQTkxRDQwRUUzRUM5RDg0OEM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></classificationGroup></metadata></legislativeDoc>