<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#349#000040#     1#          102#">Va. Code Ann. § 40.1-102</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_40.1-102"/><heading><desig>§ 40.1-102.</desig><title>Issuance of theatrical permit</title></heading><bodyText><p>No permit shall be issued unless the Commissioner is satisfied that the environment in which the drama, play, performance, concert or entertainment is to be produced is a proper environment for the child and that the conditions of such employment are not detrimental to the health or morals of such child and that the child's education will not be neglected or hampered by its participation in such drama, play, performance, concert or entertainment. Applications for permits and every permit granted shall specify the name, age and sex of each child, together with such other facts as may be necessary for the proper identification of each child and the dates when, and the theaters or other places of amusement in which such drama, play, performance, concert or entertainment is to be produced and shall specify the name of the drama, play, performance, concert or entertainment in which each child is permitted to participate. Such application shall be filed with the Commissioner not less than five days before the date of such drama, play, performance, concert or entertainment. A permit shall be revocable by the Commissioner should it be found that the environment in which the drama, play, performance, concert or entertainment is being produced is not a proper environment for the child and that the conditions of such employment are detrimental to the health or morals of such child. The Commissioner shall prescribe and supply the forms required for carrying out the provisions of this section.</p></bodyText><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p>Code 1950, § 40-111; 1960, c. 434; 1970, c. 321.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PT70-004G-K0BG-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 40.1.</desig><title>LABOR AND EMPLOYMENT</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 5.</desig><title>CHILD LABOR</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classificationGroup classificationScheme="indexing-terms"><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem score="90"><className>Labor &amp; Employment</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MTE3QUQwOTA0MUYzNDlCMEFFMjUwRUNDM0RDRkM5QzM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></classificationGroup></metadata></legislativeDoc>