<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#349#000060#     2#          615#">Va. Code Ann. § 60.2-615</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_60.2-615"/><heading><desig>§ 60.2-615.</desig><title>Benefits based on employment by state or political subdivision, certain hospitals, educational institutions and charitable, etc., organizations</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><bodyText><p>Benefits based on service in employment defined in subsection A of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 60.2-213"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 60.2-213">§ 60.2-213<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000060#     2#          213#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> shall be payable in the same amount on the same terms and subject to the same conditions as benefits payable on the basis of other service subject to this title, except that:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a"/><heading><desig>A.</desig></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Benefits based on service in an instructional, research, or principal administrative capacity for an educational institution shall not be paid to an individual for any week of unemployment commencing during the period between two successive academic years or terms, or during a similar period between two regular but not successive terms, or during a period of paid sabbatical leave provided for in the individual's contract, if the individual performs such services in the first of such academic years or terms and if there is a contract or a reasonable assurance that such individual will perform services in any such capacity for any educational institution in the second of such academic years or terms.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The provisions of this subsection relating to the denial of benefits shall apply to an individual who performs such services on a part-time or substitute basis.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b"/><heading><desig>B.</desig></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Benefits based on service in any capacity, other than an instructional, research, or principal administrative capacity, for an educational institution shall not be paid to any individual for any week which commences during a period between two successive academic years or terms if such individual performs such services in the first of such academic years or terms and there is a reasonable assurance that such individual will perform such services in the second of such academic years or terms.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The provisions of this subsection relating to the denial of benefits shall apply to an individual who performs such services on a part-time or substitute basis.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> If compensation is denied to any individual for any week which occurs during the period between academic years or terms under this subsection and such individual was not offered an opportunity to perform such services for the educational institution for the second of such academic years or terms, such individual shall be entitled to a retroactive payment of the compensation for each week for which the individual filed a timely claim for compensation and for which compensation was denied solely by reason of this subsection.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c"/><heading><desig>C.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Benefits based on services performed in an educational institution while employed by an educational service agency shall not be payable to any individual who provided such services under the same circumstances and subject to the same terms and conditions as described in subsections A, B and E of this section. For purposes of this subsection "educational service agency" means a governmental agency or governmental entity which is established and operated exclusively for the purpose of providing such services to one or more educational institutions.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d"/><heading><desig>D.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Benefits based on services provided to or on behalf of an educational institution while employed by a governmental entity or nonprofit organization shall not be payable to any individual who provided such services under the same circumstances and subject to the same terms and conditions as described in subsections A, B, C and E of this section.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_e"/><heading><desig>E.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> For services described in subsections A and B of this section, compensation payable on the basis of such services shall be denied to any individual for any week which commences during an established and customary vacation period or holiday recess if such individual performs such services in the period immediately before such vacation period or holiday recess, and there is a reasonable assurance that such individual will perform such services in the period immediately following such vacation period or holiday recess.</p></bodyText></level></level><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p>1971, Ex. Sess., c. 235, § 60.1-52.3; 1977, c. 330; 1979, c. 652; 1981, c. 328; 1983, c. 14; 1984, cc. 204, 458; 1985, c. 152; 1986, c. 480.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PTM0-004G-K0RP-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 60.2.</desig><title>UNEMPLOYMENT COMPENSATION</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 6.</desig><title>BENEFITS</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="article"><heading><desig>ARTICLE 4.</desig><title>ELIGIBILITY CRITERIA</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjA4OEVGODBENzY4NDcxM0IyQzA1OTEwQzVDODRBOUE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MzFGQzZBOEY1NkZDNDBFQkE5NkJENDU4QzZCMkQ5ODA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RjM5OTQwMzlEOUNGNDY4OThCRDRFQTkyQkZFMDhBQjk</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Labor &amp; Employment Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MTE3QUQwOTA0MUYzNDlCMEFFMjUwRUNDM0RDRkM5QzM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NkQ3NTU4M0UyNTk2NDZCQzhEOTg1MUE5RkY2NzcxRTQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NTc1ODA5RTExMjE1NDRFNThBOTc4RkYyNkM3ODQyMzI</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RUMxMEM5Mzk5NjdBNEQyMDg1NzYzNTNFMTc3QjExNkQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MEUyNDQ5RTc4RDI2NDc3Q0I3MUE0OEE2NTA3QjYzRkM</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MzE4REVFNzc1ODJCNEQyNTk4MThCNzdBNTU4NTExMDg7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDk1NzZDQzBDM0M1NENCOUE1ODc3ODI4QkI3MkYyMEY</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></metadata></legislativeDoc>