<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#958#0000000022#0000000001#    253.13#0000000002#">Va. Code Ann. § 22.1-253.13:2</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_22.1-253.13_2"/><heading><desig>§ 22.1-253.13:2.</desig><title>Standard 2. Instructional, administrative, and support personnel</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a"/><heading><desig>A.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The Board shall establish requirements for the licensing of teachers, principals, superintendents, and other professional personnel.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b"/><heading><desig>B.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> School boards shall employ licensed instructional personnel qualified in the relevant subject areas.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c"/><heading><desig>C.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Each school board shall assign licensed instructional personnel in a manner that produces divisionwide ratios of students in average daily membership to full-time equivalent teaching positions, excluding special education teachers, principals, assistant principals, counselors, and librarians, that are not greater than the following ratios: (i) 24 to one in kindergarten with no class being larger than 29 students; if the average daily membership in any kindergarten class exceeds 24 pupils, a full-time teacher's aide shall be assigned to the class; (ii) 24 to one in grades one, two, and three with no class being larger than 30 students; (iii) 25 to one in grades four through six with no class being larger than 35 students; and (iv) 24 to one in English classes in grades six through 12. After September 30 of any school year, anytime the number of students in a class exceeds the class size limit established by this subsection, the local school division shall notify the parent of each student in such class of such fact no later than 10 days after the date on which the class exceeded the class size limit. Such notification shall state the reason that the class size exceeds the class size limit and describe the measures that the local school division will take to reduce the class size to comply with this subsection.</p><p>Within its regulations governing special education programs, the Board shall seek to set pupil/teacher ratios for pupils with intellectual disability that do not exceed the pupil/teacher ratios for self-contained classes for pupils with specific learning disabilities.</p><p>Further, school boards shall assign instructional personnel in a manner that produces schoolwide ratios of students in average daily memberships to full-time equivalent teaching positions of 21 to one in middle schools and high schools. School divisions shall provide all middle and high school teachers with one planning period per day or the equivalent, unencumbered of any teaching or supervisory duties.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d"/><heading><desig>D.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Each local school board shall employ with state and local basic, special education, gifted, and career and technical education funds a minimum number of licensed, full-time equivalent instructional personnel for each 1,000 students in average daily membership (ADM) as set forth in the appropriation act. Calculations of kindergarten positions shall be based on full-day kindergarten programs. Beginning with the March 31 report of average daily membership, those school divisions offering half-day kindergarten with pupil/teacher ratios that exceed 30 to one shall adjust their average daily membership for kindergarten to reflect 85 percent of the total kindergarten average daily memberships, as provided in the appropriation act.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_e"/><heading><desig>E.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> In addition to the positions supported by basic aid and in support of regular school year programs of prevention, intervention, and remediation, state funding, pursuant to the appropriation act, shall be provided to fund certain full-time equivalent instructional positions for each 1,000 students in grades K through 12 who are identified as needing prevention, intervention, and remediation services. State funding for prevention, intervention, and remediation programs provided pursuant to this subsection and the appropriation act may be used to support programs for educationally at-risk students as identified by the local school boards.</p><p>To provide algebra readiness intervention services required by <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 22.1-253.13:1"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 22.1-253.13:1">§ 22.1-253.13:1<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#958#0000000022#0000000001#    253.13#0000000001#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, school divisions may employ mathematics teacher specialists to provide the required algebra readiness intervention services. School divisions using the Standards of Learning Algebra Readiness Initiative funding in this manner shall only employ instructional personnel licensed by the Board of Education.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_f"/><heading><desig>F.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> In addition to the positions supported by basic aid and those in support of regular school year programs of prevention, intervention, and remediation, state funding, pursuant to the appropriation act, shall be provided to support 17 full-time equivalent instructional positions for each 1,000 students identified as having limited English proficiency.</p><p>To provide flexibility in the instruction of English language learners who have limited English proficiency and who are at risk of not meeting state accountability standards, school divisions may use state and local funds from the Standards of Quality Prevention, Intervention, and Remediation account to employ additional English language learner teachers to provide instruction to identified limited English proficiency students. Using these funds in this manner is intended to supplement the instructional services provided in this section. School divisions using the SOQ Prevention, Intervention, and Remediation funds in this manner shall employ only instructional personnel licensed by the Board of Education.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_g"/><heading><desig>G.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> In addition to the full-time equivalent positions required elsewhere in this section, each local school board shall employ the following reading specialists in elementary schools, one full-time in each elementary school at the discretion of the local school board.</p><p>To provide reading intervention services required by <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 22.1-253.13:1"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 22.1-253.13:1">§ 22.1-253.13:1<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#958#0000000022#0000000001#    253.13#0000000001#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, school divisions may employ reading specialists to provide the required reading intervention services. School divisions using the Early Reading Intervention Initiative funds in this manner shall employ only instructional personnel licensed by the Board of Education.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_h"/><heading><desig>H.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Each local school board shall employ, at a minimum, the following full-time equivalent positions for any school that reports fall membership, according to the type of school and student enrollment:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_h_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Principals in elementary schools, one half-time to 299 students, one full-time at 300 students; principals in middle schools, one full-time, to be employed on a 12-month basis; principals in high schools, one full-time, to be employed on a 12-month basis;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_h_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Assistant principals in elementary schools, one half-time at 600 students, one full-time at 900 students; assistant principals in middle schools, one full-time for each 600 students; assistant principals in high schools, one full-time for each 600 students; and school divisions that employ a sufficient number of assistant principals to meet this staffing requirement may assign assistant principals to schools within the division according to the area of greatest need, regardless of whether such schools are elementary, middle, or secondary;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_h_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Librarians in elementary schools, one part-time to 299 students, one full-time at 300 students; librarians in middle schools, one-half time to 299 students, one full-time at 300 students, two full-time at 1,000 students; librarians in high schools, one half-time to 299 students, one full-time at 300 students, two full-time at 1,000 students. Local school divisions that employ a sufficient number of librarians to meet this staffing requirement may assign librarians to schools within the division according to the area of greatest need, regardless of whether such schools are elementary, middle, or secondary; and</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_h_4"/><heading><desig>4.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Guidance counselors in elementary schools, one hour per day per 100 students, one full-time at 500 students, one hour per day additional time per 100 students or major fraction thereof; guidance counselors in middle schools, one period per 80 students, one full-time at 400 students, one additional period per 80 students or major fraction thereof; guidance counselors in high schools, one period per 70 students, one full-time at 350 students, one additional period per 70 students or major fraction thereof. Local school divisions that employ a sufficient number of guidance counselors to meet this staffing requirement may assign guidance counselors to schools within the division according to the area of greatest need, regardless of whether such schools are elementary, middle, or secondary.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_i"/><heading><desig>I.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Local school boards shall employ five full-time equivalent positions per 1,000 students in grades kindergarten through five to serve as elementary resource teachers in art, music, and physical education.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_j"/><heading><desig>J.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Local school boards shall employ two full-time equivalent positions per 1,000 students in grades kindergarten through 12, one to provide technology support and one to serve as an instructional technology resource teacher.</p><p>To provide flexibility, school divisions may use the state and local funds for instructional technology resource teachers to employ a data coordinator position, an instructional technology resource teacher position, or a data coordinator/instructional resource teacher blended position. The data coordinator position is intended to serve as a resource to principals and classroom teachers in the area of data analysis and interpretation for instructional and school improvement purposes, as well as for overall data management and administration of state assessments. School divisions using these funds in this manner shall employ only instructional personnel licensed by the Board of Education.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_k"/><heading><desig>K.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Local school boards may employ additional positions that exceed these minimal staffing requirements. These additional positions may include, but are not limited to, those funded through the state's incentive and categorical programs as set forth in the appropriation act.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_l"/><heading><desig>L.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A combined school, such as kindergarten through 12, shall meet at all grade levels the staffing requirements for the highest grade level in that school; this requirement shall apply to all staff, except for guidance counselors, and shall be based on the school's total enrollment; guidance counselor staff requirements shall, however, be based on the enrollment at the various school organization levels, i.e., elementary, middle, or high school. The Board of Education may grant waivers from these staffing levels upon request from local school boards seeking to implement experimental or innovative programs that are not consistent with these staffing levels.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_m"/><heading><desig>M.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> School boards shall, however, annually, on or before January 1, report to the public the actual pupil/teacher ratios in elementary school classrooms by school for the current school year. Such actual ratios shall include only the teachers who teach the grade and class on a full-time basis and shall exclude resource personnel. School boards shall report pupil/teacher ratios that include resource teachers in the same annual report. Any classes funded through the voluntary kindergarten through third grade class size reduction program shall be identified as such classes. Any classes having waivers to exceed the requirements of this subsection shall also be identified. Schools shall be identified; however, the data shall be compiled in a manner to ensure the confidentiality of all teacher and pupil identities.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_n"/><heading><desig>N.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Students enrolled in a public school on a less than full-time basis shall be counted in ADM in the relevant school division. Students who are either (i) enrolled in a nonpublic school or (ii) receiving home instruction pursuant to <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 22.1-254.1"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 22.1-254.1">§ 22.1-254.1<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000022#     1#        254.1#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, and who are enrolled in public school on a less than full-time basis in any mathematics, science, English, history, social science, career and technical education, fine arts, foreign language, or health education or physical education course shall be counted in the ADM in the relevant school division on a pro rata basis as provided in the appropriation act. Each such course enrollment by such students shall be counted as 0.25 in the ADM; however, no such nonpublic or home school student shall be counted as more than one-half a student for purposes of such pro rata calculation. Such calculation shall not include enrollments of such students in any other public school courses.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_o"/><heading><desig>O.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Each local school board shall provide those support services that are necessary for the efficient and cost-effective operation and maintenance of its public schools.</p><p>For the purposes of this title, unless the context otherwise requires, "support services positions" shall include the following:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_o_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Executive policy and leadership positions, including school board members, superintendents and assistant superintendents;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_o_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Fiscal and human resources positions, including fiscal and audit operations;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_o_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Student support positions, including (i) social workers and social work administrative positions; (ii) guidance administrative positions not included in subdivision H 4; (iii) homebound administrative positions supporting instruction; (iv) attendance support positions related to truancy and dropout prevention; and (v) health and behavioral positions, including school nurses and school psychologists;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_o_4"/><heading><desig>4.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Instructional personnel support, including professional development positions and library and media positions not included in subdivision H 3;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_o_5"/><heading><desig>5.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Technology professional positions not included in subsection J;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_o_6"/><heading><desig>6.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Operation and maintenance positions, including facilities; pupil transportation positions; operation and maintenance professional and service positions; and security service, trade, and laborer positions;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_o_7"/><heading><desig>7.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Technical and clerical positions for fiscal and human resources, student support, instructional personnel support, operation and maintenance, administration, and technology; and</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_o_8"/><heading><desig>8.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> School-based clerical personnel in elementary schools; part-time to 299 students, one full-time at 300 students; clerical personnel in middle schools; one full-time and one additional full-time for each 600 students beyond 200 students and one full-time for the library at 750 students; clerical personnel in high schools; one full-time and one additional full-time for each 600 students beyond 200 students and one full-time for the library at 750 students. Local school divisions that employ a sufficient number of school-based clerical personnel to meet this staffing requirement may assign the clerical personnel to schools within the division according to the area of greatest need, regardless of whether such schools are elementary, middle, or secondary.</p><p><pre/>Pursuant to the appropriation act, support services shall be funded from basic school aid.</p><p><pre/>School divisions may use the state and local funds for support services to provide additional instructional services.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_p"/><heading><desig>P.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Notwithstanding the provisions of this section, when determining the assignment of instructional and other licensed personnel in subsections C through J, a local school board shall not be required to include full-time students of approved virtual school programs.</p></bodyText></level><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p>1988, cc. 645, 682; <citation normalizedCite="1991 VA CH 480"><content><span normalizedCite="1991 Va. Ch. 480">1991, c. 480<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1991#000480#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1997 VA CH 828"><content><span normalizedCite="1997 Va. Ch. 828">1997, c. 828<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1997#000828#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2004 VA CH 939"><content><span normalizedCite="2004 Va. Ch. 939">2004, cc. 939<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2004#000939#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2004 VA CH 955"><content><span normalizedCite="2004 Va. Ch. 955">955<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2004#000955#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2005 VA CH 331"><content><span normalizedCite="2005 Va. Ch. 331">2005, cc. 331<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2005#000331#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2005 VA CH 450"><content><span normalizedCite="2005 Va. Ch. 450">450<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2005#000450#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2010 VA CH 537"><content><span normalizedCite="2010 Va. Ch. 537">2010, cc. 537<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2010#000537#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2010 VA CH 817"><content><span normalizedCite="2010 Va. Ch. 817">817<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2010#000817#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2011 VA CH 55"><content><span normalizedCite="2011 Va. Ch. 55">2011, cc. 55<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2011#000055#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2011 VA CH 74"><content><span normalizedCite="2011 Va. Ch. 74">74<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2011#000074#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2012 VA CH 476"><content><span normalizedCite="2012 Va. Ch. 476">2012, cc. 476<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2012#000476#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2012 VA CH 507"><content><span normalizedCite="2012 Va. Ch. 507">507<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2012#000507#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2013 VA CH 123"><content><span normalizedCite="2013 Va. Ch. 123">2013, cc. 123<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2013#000123#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2013 VA CH 157"><content><span normalizedCite="2013 Va. Ch. 157">157<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2013#000157#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2013 VA CH 158"><content><span normalizedCite="2013 Va. Ch. 158">158<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2013#000158#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2013 VA CH 224"><content><span normalizedCite="2013 Va. Ch. 224">224<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2013#000224#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2016 VA CH 646"><content><span normalizedCite="2016 Va. Ch. 646">2016, c. 646<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2016#000646#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PT00-004G-K1KN-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 22.1.</desig><title>EDUCATION</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 13.2.</desig><title>STANDARDS OF QUALITY</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Requirements for Certification &amp; Licensure</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6ODdGQUMyN0E0NTVBNDM3NThEMTg2Mzc2RDg5NUU3NUY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDkzNUEzQzFBNEZBNEFBREIxNDM5MTc1MUU5QjI4MTY</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Education Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDkzNUEzQzFBNEZBNEFBREIxNDM5MTc1MUU5QjI4MTY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Allocation of Funds</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RTk0MTc3MzdGQkU0NDI1OEFGOTA3NTkyRTJFM0VCQTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjZBQUM2RjM4QkI4NDlFMkFCNTBDMzJGNDg0MTgxOUU</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDBDMzRDODQwQzY3NDNCRDkxNDE1REEyOEFGMzBBNjE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDU1QkREN0FDNThENDhDMTk1MTk4MTQ3OUMzRjAwQjI</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Limited English Proficiency</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6M0ZBRjU1RTM1MzIzNEIyMkE2QzNEMjg2MUY2RjY3NkU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QzMyRkUwN0EzNzQ2NENEMUJEMDY4MEYxRjJCNzUxODE</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Requirements for Certification &amp; Licensure</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6ODdGQUMyN0E0NTVBNDM3NThEMTg2Mzc2RDg5NUU3NUY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDk4Mzg2MUI0QzJCNDc2RjkwMDM5QUMzQUY2NEI5Mzk</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Support Staff</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUNDQ0ZFMjRCRDNGNDdERTk4Q0UxMTEyRkNDRjAwQUQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6REI2NEE4Nzk1Nzc3NEIzQkFFMzE2ODAyNUQzQkQ2Q0I</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Governments</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjdEQjE4OUJDMzQxNDNEMEI0RTI1QUFCMzJENjEwRTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Libraries</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Rjk2OTRDNjYyN0JBNDJFM0EzRTkzODQzQ0M5NkRFMzc7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Njg1MkM3RkYyNzIxNEVFRkJFMTI2NUM4NUU1ODdEM0Q</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification><classificationGroup classificationScheme="indexing-terms"><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem score="90"><className>Education</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDkzNUEzQzFBNEZBNEFBREIxNDM5MTc1MUU5QjI4MTY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></classificationGroup></metadata></legislativeDoc>