<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#349#000002#     2#       2203.4#">Va. Code Ann. § 2.2-2203.4</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_2.2-2203.4"/><heading><desig>§ 2.2-2203.4.</desig><title>Trust for postemployment benefits authorized; administration</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a"/><heading><desig>A.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The Authority is hereby authorized to establish and maintain a trust or equivalent arrangement for the purpose of accumulating and investing assets to fund postemployment benefits other than pensions, as defined herein. Such trust or equivalent arrangement shall be irrevocable. The assets of such trust or similar arrangement (i) shall be dedicated to providing benefits to retirees and their beneficiaries in accordance with the terms of the plan or programs providing postemployment benefits other than pensions and (ii) shall be exempt from taxation and execution, attachment, garnishment, or any other process against the Authority or a retiree or beneficiary. The funds of the trust or similar arrangement shall be deemed separate and independent trust funds, shall be segregated from all other funds of the Authority, and shall be invested and administered solely in the interests of the active or former employees (and their dependents or beneficiaries) entitled to postemployment benefits other than pensions.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b"/><heading><desig>B.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The Authority may make appropriations to any such trust or equivalent arrangement, and the Authority may require active and former employees covered by a postemployment benefit program to contribute to the trust or equivalent arrangement through payments or deductions from their wages, salaries, or pensions.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c"/><heading><desig>C.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Nothing in this section shall be construed to inhibit the Authority's right to revise or discontinue its plans or programs providing such postemployment benefits other than pensions for its active and former officers and employees as it may deem necessary. If all plans or programs providing such postemployment benefits other than pensions for which the trust or equivalent arrangement is established are repealed or terminated by the Authority, then there shall be no continuing responsibility of the Authority to continue to make appropriations to such trust or equivalent arrangement, and the assets of such trust or equivalent arrangement shall be used to provide any benefits continuing to be due to active or former employees (and their dependents or beneficiaries) under such plans or programs. If there are no active or former employees (or dependents or beneficiaries) due a benefit under any plan or program providing such postemployment benefits other than pensions for which the trust or equivalent arrangement was established, then any remaining assets may revert to the Authority.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d"/><heading><desig>D.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Postemployment benefits other than pensions shall be defined by the Authority pursuant to applicable accounting standards and law. Such benefits may include, but are not limited to, medical, prescription drug, dental, vision, hearing, life, or accident insurance (not provided through a pension plan), long-term care benefits, and long-term disability benefits (not covered under a pension plan) provided to individuals who have terminated their service and to the dependents of such individuals, and may be provided by purchasing insurance, by a program of self-insurance, or by a combination of both. However, postemployment benefits other than pensions shall not include defined benefit pension plans for retirees and eligible dependents of retirees, termination benefits, or other pension benefits. Such postemployment benefits other than pensions may be provided to the officers and employees or to their dependents, estates, or designated beneficiaries. Any benefits arising from any postemployment benefits other than pension programs shall be clearly defined and strictly construed.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_e"/><heading><desig>E.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the moneys and other property comprising the trust or equivalent arrangement established hereunder shall be invested, reinvested, and managed by the Authority or the trust company or bank having powers of a trust company within or without the Commonwealth that is selected by the Board to act as a trustee for the trust or equivalent arrangement with the care, skill, prudence, and diligence under the circumstances then prevailing that a prudent person acting in a like capacity and familiar with such matters would use in the conduct of an enterprise of like character and with the same aims. Such investments shall be diversified so as to minimize the risk of large losses unless under the circumstances it is clearly prudent not to do so. Such investments shall not be limited by Chapter 45 (§ 2.2-4500 et seq.).</p></bodyText></level><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p><citation normalizedCite="2012 VA CH 779"><content><span normalizedCite="2012 Va. Ch. 779">2012, cc. 779<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2012#000779#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2012 VA CH 817"><content><span normalizedCite="2012 Va. Ch. 817">817<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2012#000817#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PVV0-004G-K54T-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 2.2.</desig><title>ADMINISTRATION OF GOVERNMENT</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="subtitle"><heading><desig>SUBTITLE I.</desig><title>ORGANIZATION OF STATE GOVERNMENT</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="part"><heading><desig>PART D.</desig><title>STATE AUTHORITIES, BOARDS, COMMISSIONS, COUNCILS, FOUNDATIONS AND OTHER COLLEGIAL BODIES</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 22.</desig><title>AUTHORITIES</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="article"><heading><desig>ARTICLE 2.</desig><title>COMMERCIAL SPACE FLIGHT AUTHORITY</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Estate, Gift &amp; Trust Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OENGNTY0MEQ2RTU2NDA2NTk4QjcyNzI2NTBERUU3NUI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Q0VEQ0U4QTFCMzc1NDkyQjgzMjNBQUJFREFDOEJCOTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NUQ4NThEMTk0MTQ4NDM3N0FGOEM5RkU2QUQ4RjA1MkQ</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QUYyRTI1QTg1RDVENEM1RUExOTczNDU0MkEzRDhFOTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NzgwQzFGOTA0NDM5NDVGMEE5NkRCNjQ1NEM2NkZEN0Y</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Standards of Care</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjY3Nzk5NzcxOUM2NEE1MTg4NEY2MDg5NjhFMkVDNTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RDUzQjA0REZDODBDNDA4RDlGQ0JEMzcxQjU1RTkxNEQ</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Labor &amp; Employment Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MTE3QUQwOTA0MUYzNDlCMEFFMjUwRUNDM0RDRkM5QzM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MEU3M0E2RTJENUY0NDBBNzkyRTEyRTEyRTVEMkRGQkY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NTQ5RjUxOTZCOTk0NDRDNjg2NzJCMURBODk2NzZFOUY</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RDY5MEREQjZCQzFBNDk5NUE1NTU1QTBDMjYwNUJGMjA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MzBEMkJFMTg2NTJDNEVGRjlGREQ2Nzg2ODkzMzkwQTQ</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Types of Disabilities</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MzE5QkExM0Y1OEI2NEIyQjgyNDM3OTAzOTg0NDlEMkQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NTQ5RjUxOTZCOTk0NDRDNjg2NzJCMURBODk2NzZFOUY</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Pensions &amp; Benefits Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QzNEOEE3NjhDNTJBNDhCOTgxRkQzNzc1Q0JCMkU4Q0I7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Defined Benefit Plans</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MkJBNDM4MDk1RkUzNEI2MkEyOTUwRDhCRkQ2OEJCN0I7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NEQ3RDY2N0I1RjQ0NDNEODk2RDA3ODA0NkE2MENBQ0U</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Workers' Compensation &amp; SSDI</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NTNGOEUzQTYwRUQ1NEFCN0FGMjg0Rjc5MjI3NjBDMEI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Continuing Disability Standards</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDM1NDUzMEFGM0FFNEU1NTg2MDcxNTA1OUU2ODY1RkE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RDRFMTYzNDc5RjQ5NDdCQzlCNjcwMURFRjkyNjFCMkM</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification><classificationGroup classificationScheme="indexing-terms"><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem score="90"><className>Governments</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjdEQjE4OUJDMzQxNDNEMEI0RTI1QUFCMzJENjEwRTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></classificationGroup></metadata></legislativeDoc>