<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#349#000037#     2#          808#">Va. Code Ann. § 37.2-808</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_37.2-808"/><heading><desig>§ 37.2-808.</desig><title>Emergency custody; issuance and execution of order</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a"/><heading><desig>A.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Any magistrate shall issue, upon the sworn petition of any responsible person, treating physician, or upon his own motion, an emergency custody order when he has probable cause to believe that any person (i) has a mental illness and that there exists a substantial likelihood that, as a result of mental illness, the person will, in the near future, (a) cause serious physical harm to himself or others as evidenced by recent behavior causing, attempting, or threatening harm and other relevant information, if any, or (b) suffer serious harm due to his lack of capacity to protect himself from harm or to provide for his basic human needs, (ii) is in need of hospitalization or treatment, and (iii) is unwilling to volunteer or incapable of volunteering for hospitalization or treatment. Any emergency custody order entered pursuant to this section shall provide for the disclosure of medical records pursuant to <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 37.2-804.2"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 37.2-804.2">§ 37.2-804.2.<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000037#     2#        804.2#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> This subsection shall not preclude any other disclosures as required or permitted by law.</p><p>When considering whether there is probable cause to issue an emergency custody order, the magistrate may, in addition to the petition, consider (1) the recommendations of any treating or examining physician or psychologist licensed in Virginia, if available, (2) any past actions of the person, (3) any past mental health treatment of the person, (4) any relevant hearsay evidence, (5) any medical records available, (6) any affidavits submitted, if the witness is unavailable and it so states in the affidavit, and (7) any other information available that the magistrate considers relevant to the determination of whether probable cause exists to issue an emergency custody order.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b"/><heading><desig>B.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Any person for whom an emergency custody order is issued shall be taken into custody and transported to a convenient location to be evaluated to determine whether the person meets the criteria for temporary detention pursuant to <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 37.2-809"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 37.2-809">§ 37.2-809<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000037#     2#          809#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> and to assess the need for hospitalization or treatment. The evaluation shall be made by a person designated by the community services board who is skilled in the diagnosis and treatment of mental illness and who has completed a certification program approved by the Department.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c"/><heading><desig>C.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The magistrate issuing an emergency custody order shall specify the primary law-enforcement agency and jurisdiction to execute the emergency custody order and provide transportation. However, the magistrate shall consider any request to authorize transportation by an alternative transportation provider in accordance with this section, whenever an alternative transportation provider is identified to the magistrate, which may be a person, facility, or agency, including a family member or friend of the person who is the subject of the order, a representative of the community services board, or other transportation provider with personnel trained to provide transportation in a safe manner, upon determining, following consideration of information provided by the petitioner; the community services board or its designee; the local law-enforcement agency, if any; the person's treating physician, if any; or other persons who are available and have knowledge of the person, and, when the magistrate deems appropriate, the proposed alternative transportation provider, either in person or via two-way electronic video and audio or telephone communication system, that the proposed alternative transportation provider is available to provide transportation, willing to provide transportation, and able to provide transportation in a safe manner. When transportation is ordered to be provided by an alternative transportation provider, the magistrate shall order the specified primary law-enforcement agency to execute the order, to take the person into custody, and to transfer custody of the person to the alternative transportation provider identified in the order. In such cases, a copy of the emergency custody order shall accompany the person being transported pursuant to this section at all times and shall be delivered by the alternative transportation provider to the community services board or its designee responsible for conducting the evaluation. The community services board or its designee conducting the evaluation shall return a copy of the emergency custody order to the court designated by the magistrate as soon as is practicable. Delivery of an order to a law-enforcement officer or alternative transportation provider and return of an order to the court may be accomplished electronically or by facsimile.</p><p>Transportation under this section shall include transportation to a medical facility as may be necessary to obtain emergency medical evaluation or treatment that shall be conducted immediately in accordance with state and federal law. Transportation under this section shall include transportation to a medical facility for a medical evaluation if a physician at the hospital in which the person subject to the emergency custody order may be detained requires a medical evaluation prior to admission.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d"/><heading><desig>D.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> In specifying the primary law-enforcement agency and jurisdiction for purposes of this section, the magistrate shall order the primary law-enforcement agency from the jurisdiction served by the community services board that designated the person to perform the evaluation required in subsection B to execute the order and, in cases in which transportation is ordered to be provided by the primary law-enforcement agency, provide transportation. If the community services board serves more than one jurisdiction, the magistrate shall designate the primary law-enforcement agency from the particular jurisdiction within the community services board's service area where the person who is the subject of the emergency custody order was taken into custody or, if the person has not yet been taken into custody, the primary law-enforcement agency from the jurisdiction where the person is presently located to execute the order and provide transportation.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_e"/><heading><desig>E.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The law-enforcement agency or alternative transportation provider providing transportation pursuant to this section may transfer custody of the person to the facility or location to which the person is transported for the evaluation required in subsection B, G, or H if the facility or location (i) is licensed to provide the level of security necessary to protect both the person and others from harm, (ii) is actually capable of providing the level of security necessary to protect the person and others from harm, and (iii) in cases in which transportation is provided by a law-enforcement agency, has entered into an agreement or memorandum of understanding with the law-enforcement agency setting forth the terms and conditions under which it will accept a transfer of custody, provided, however, that the facility or location may not require the law-enforcement agency to pay any fees or costs for the transfer of custody.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_f"/><heading><desig>F.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A law-enforcement officer may lawfully go or be sent beyond the territorial limits of the county, city, or town in which he serves to any point in the Commonwealth for the purpose of executing an emergency custody order pursuant to this section.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_g"/><heading><desig>G.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A law-enforcement officer who, based upon his observation or the reliable reports of others, has probable cause to believe that a person meets the criteria for emergency custody as stated in this section may take that person into custody and transport that person to an appropriate location to assess the need for hospitalization or treatment without prior authorization. A law-enforcement officer who takes a person into custody pursuant to this subsection or subsection H may lawfully go or be sent beyond the territorial limits of the county, city, or town in which he serves to any point in the Commonwealth for the purpose of obtaining the assessment. Such evaluation shall be conducted immediately. The period of custody shall not exceed eight hours from the time the law-enforcement officer takes the person into custody.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_h"/><heading><desig>H.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A law-enforcement officer who is transporting a person who has voluntarily consented to be transported to a facility for the purpose of assessment or evaluation and who is beyond the territorial limits of the county, city, or town in which he serves may take such person into custody and transport him to an appropriate location to assess the need for hospitalization or treatment without prior authorization when the law-enforcement officer determines (i) that the person has revoked consent to be transported to a facility for the purpose of assessment or evaluation, and (ii) based upon his observations, that probable cause exists to believe that the person meets the criteria for emergency custody as stated in this section. The period of custody shall not exceed eight hours from the time the law-enforcement officer takes the person into custody.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_i"/><heading><desig>I.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Nothing herein shall preclude a law-enforcement officer or alternative transportation provider from obtaining emergency medical treatment or further medical evaluation at any time for a person in his custody as provided in this section.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_j"/><heading><desig>J.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A representative of the primary law-enforcement agency specified to execute an emergency custody order or a representative of the law-enforcement agency employing a law-enforcement officer who takes a person into custody pursuant to subsection G or H shall notify the community services board responsible for conducting the evaluation required in subsection B, G, or H as soon as practicable after execution of the emergency custody order or after the person has been taken into custody pursuant to subsection G or H.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_k"/><heading><desig>K.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The person shall remain in custody until a temporary detention order is issued, until the person is released, or until the emergency custody order expires. An emergency custody order shall be valid for a period not to exceed eight hours from the time of execution.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_l"/><heading><desig>L.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Nothing in this section shall preclude the issuance of an order for temporary detention for testing, observation, or treatment pursuant to <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 37.2-1104"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 37.2-1104">§ 37.2-1104<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000037#     2#         1104#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> for a person who is also the subject of an emergency custody order issued pursuant to this section. In any case in which an order for temporary detention for testing, observation, or treatment is issued for a person who is also the subject of an emergency custody order, the person may be detained by a hospital emergency room or other appropriate facility for testing, observation, and treatment for a period not to exceed 24 hours, unless extended by the court as part of an order pursuant to <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 37.2-1101"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 37.2-1101">§ 37.2-1101<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000037#     2#         1101#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, in accordance with subsection A of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 37.2-1104"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 37.2-1104">§ 37.2-1104<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000037#     2#         1104#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>. Upon completion of testing, observation, or treatment pursuant to <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 37.2-1104"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 37.2-1104">§ 37.2-1104<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000037#     2#         1104#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, the hospital emergency room or other appropriate facility in which the person is detained shall notify the nearest community services board, and the designee of the community services board shall, as soon as is practicable and prior to the expiration of the order for temporary detention issued pursuant to <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 37.2-1104"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 37.2-1104">§ 37.2-1104<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000037#     2#         1104#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, conduct an evaluation of the person to determine if he meets the criteria for temporary detention pursuant to <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 37.2-809"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 37.2-809">§ 37.2-809<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000037#     2#          809#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_m"/><heading><desig>M.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Any person taken into emergency custody pursuant to this section shall be given a written summary of the emergency custody procedures and the statutory protections associated with those procedures.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_n"/><heading><desig>N.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> If an emergency custody order is not executed within eight hours of its issuance, the order shall be void and shall be returned unexecuted to the office of the clerk of the issuing court or, if such office is not open, to any magistrate serving the jurisdiction of the issuing court.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_o"/><heading><desig>O.</desig><title><emphasis typeStyle="it"> (Expires June 30, 2018)</emphasis></title></heading><bodyText><p> In addition to the eight-hour period of emergency custody set forth in subsection G, H, or K, if the individual is detained in a state facility pursuant to subsection E of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 37.2-809"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 37.2-809">§ 37.2-809<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000037#     2#          809#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, the state facility and an employee or designee of the community services board as defined in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 37.2-809"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 37.2-809">§ 37.2-809<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000037#     2#          809#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> may, for an additional four hours, continue to attempt to identify an alternative facility that is able and willing to provide temporary detention and appropriate care to the individual.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_p"/><heading><desig>P.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Payments shall be made pursuant to <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 37.2-804"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 37.2-804">§ 37.2-804<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000037#     2#          804#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> to licensed health care providers for medical screening and assessment services provided to persons with mental illnesses while in emergency custody.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_q"/><heading><desig>Q.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> No person who provides alternative transportation pursuant to this section shall be liable to the person being transported for any civil damages for ordinary negligence in acts or omissions that result from providing such alternative transportation.</p></bodyText></level><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p><citation normalizedCite="1995 VA CH 844"><content><span normalizedCite="1995 Va. Ch. 844">1995, c. 844<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1995#000844#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, § 37.1-67.01; <citation normalizedCite="1996 VA CH 893"><content><span normalizedCite="1996 Va. Ch. 893">1996, c. 893<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1996#000893#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1998 VA CH 611"><content><span normalizedCite="1998 Va. Ch. 611">1998, c. 611<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1998#000611#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2004 VA CH 737"><content><span normalizedCite="2004 Va. Ch. 737">2004, c. 737<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2004#000737#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2005 VA CH 716"><content><span normalizedCite="2005 Va. Ch. 716">2005, c. 716<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2005#000716#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2007 VA CH 7"><content><span normalizedCite="2007 Va. Ch. 7">2007, c. 7<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2007#000007#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2008 VA CH 202"><content><span normalizedCite="2008 Va. Ch. 202">2008, cc. 202<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2008#000202#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2008 VA CH 551"><content><span normalizedCite="2008 Va. Ch. 551">551<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2008#000551#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2008 VA CH 691"><content><span normalizedCite="2008 Va. Ch. 691">691<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2008#000691#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2008 VA CH 775"><content><span normalizedCite="2008 Va. Ch. 775">775<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2008#000775#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2008 VA CH 779"><content><span normalizedCite="2008 Va. Ch. 779">779<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2008#000779#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2008 VA CH 782"><content><span normalizedCite="2008 Va. Ch. 782">782<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2008#000782#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2008 VA CH 784"><content><span normalizedCite="2008 Va. Ch. 784">784<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2008#000784#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2008 VA CH 793"><content><span normalizedCite="2008 Va. Ch. 793">793<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2008#000793#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2008 VA CH 850"><content><span normalizedCite="2008 Va. Ch. 850">850<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2008#000850#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2008 VA CH 870"><content><span normalizedCite="2008 Va. Ch. 870">870<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2008#000870#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2009 VA CH 21"><content><span normalizedCite="2009 Va. Ch. 21">2009, cc. 21<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2009#000021#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2009 VA CH 112"><content><span normalizedCite="2009 Va. Ch. 112">112<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2009#000112#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2009 VA CH 383"><content><span normalizedCite="2009 Va. Ch. 383">383<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2009#000383#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2009 VA CH 455"><content><span normalizedCite="2009 Va. Ch. 455">455<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2009#000455#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2009 VA CH 555"><content><span normalizedCite="2009 Va. Ch. 555">555<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2009#000555#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2009 VA CH 607"><content><span normalizedCite="2009 Va. Ch. 607">607<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2009#000607#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2009 VA CH 697"><content><span normalizedCite="2009 Va. Ch. 697">697<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2009#000697#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2009 VA CH 838"><content><span normalizedCite="2009 Va. Ch. 838">838<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2009#000838#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2010 VA CH 778"><content><span normalizedCite="2010 Va. Ch. 778">2010, cc. 778<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2010#000778#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2010 VA CH 825"><content><span normalizedCite="2010 Va. Ch. 825">825<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2010#000825#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2011 VA CH 249"><content><span normalizedCite="2011 Va. Ch. 249">2011, c. 249<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2011#000249#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2013 VA CH 371"><content><span normalizedCite="2013 Va. Ch. 371">2013, c. 371<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2013#000371#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2014 VA CH 691"><content><span normalizedCite="2014 Va. Ch. 691">2014, cc. 691<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2014#000691#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2014 VA CH 761"><content><span normalizedCite="2014 Va. Ch. 761">761<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2014#000761#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2015 VA CH 297"><content><span normalizedCite="2015 Va. Ch. 297">2015, cc. 297<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2015#000297#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2015 VA CH 308"><content><span normalizedCite="2015 Va. Ch. 308">308<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2015#000308#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2015 VA CH 659"><content><span normalizedCite="2015 Va. Ch. 659">659<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2015#000659#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PVG0-004G-K55N-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 37.2.</desig><title>BEHAVIORAL HEALTH AND DEVELOPMENTAL SERVICES</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="subtitle"><heading><desig>SUBTITLE 3.</desig><title>ADMISSIONS AND DISPOSITIONS</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 8.</desig><title>EMERGENCY CUSTODY AND VOLUNTARY AND INVOLUNTARY CIVIL ADMISSIONS</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="article"><heading><desig>ARTICLE 4.</desig><title>EMERGENCY CUSTODY AND INVOLUNTARY TEMPORARY DETENTION</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Administrative Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NjMxMjc0MUIzQjkzNEM4MEI4NkZGQjVCREJCRDk4OUM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Jurisdiction</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDdDMUQxNjkyQjI3NEQ4Njg0Q0VFN0FDQTU1QzVEMUQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OUI5OEJCMjM0REM0NERGQ0EyQUI4MUY5RkJFQUNBQjU</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Enforcement Provisions</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6N0FGOTFGN0U5MURFNDZGOEJBMjVBNDFFOUU4Q0QwOTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OUYwRjQ2MEQ2RjgxNDE1REI0NDk0REYzNDA4Q0ZEMUU</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Governments</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjdEQjE4OUJDMzQxNDNEMEI0RTI1QUFCMzJENjEwRTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Administrative Boards</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QTYwRUFCMDc5MzQ5NDEyREFEQkU2NkE2MjRGQTlCNzY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Njg1MkM3RkYyNzIxNEVFRkJFMTI2NUM4NUU1ODdEM0Q</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Clerks of Court</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6REVFMjkzRDI1MkU2NERDNjk3OEUxODY0REYwMUI1NjE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NURENzJGNTEyQzM0NEREQUI2RkVCRTM4RTc1RTZBREU</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Finance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjMzOTBBRTg2MUVDNDdDNUE1M0QxNDk1RERCNjNCN0I7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Njg1MkM3RkYyNzIxNEVFRkJFMTI2NUM4NUU1ODdEM0Q</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Judges</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OTg1QUIzNkIwNzk5NDQ4NzhGMDdDQjVGNEYyRjY5OTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NURENzJGNTEyQzM0NEREQUI2RkVCRTM4RTc1RTZBREU</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Healthcare Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NkUxMkVDQjJDOEY5NDVDQ0E5NTFEMTlDMjIwNzVERjc7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6REIzOUJERjYzNEE1NEI2QUFENjZDQTBERkIzNTk0RjY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NjM2NTg4ODQ2MEU0NENDOUE4NzlDN0E2QjM5MjJFQjg</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Labor &amp; Employment Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MTE3QUQwOTA0MUYzNDlCMEFFMjUwRUNDM0RDRkM5QzM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Enforcement Provisions</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6N0FGOTFGN0U5MURFNDZGOEJBMjVBNDFFOUU4Q0QwOTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OUYwRjQ2MEQ2RjgxNDE1REI0NDk0REYzNDA4Q0ZEMUU</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Transportation Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RTYzRTk5RDVBQkQ2NDcwQzk2NTU3ODQ5OEE3NDlBNzk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MTA0MzBBMUI0MkVCNDIzNDkxNkY4MTU5REUxOTE0ODA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RTYzRTk5RDVBQkQ2NDcwQzk2NTU3ODQ5OEE3NDlBNzk</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></metadata></legislativeDoc>