<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#349#000033#     2#         2200#">Va. Code Ann. § 33.2-2200</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_33.2-2200"/><heading><desig>§ 33.2-2200.</desig><title>Definitions</title></heading><bodyText><p>As used in this chapter, unless the context requires a different meaning:</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Bonds"</emphasis> means bonds, notes, bond anticipation notes, or other obligations of the District, notwithstanding any contrary provision in this chapter, which may be issued in certificated or uncertificated form as current interest or capital appreciation bonds, or a hybrid thereof, and may bear interest at a rate, which may be fixed, zero, or at a floating or variable rate of interest established by reference to indices or formulae, that may be in excess of the rate now permitted by law and payable at such times as the Commission may determine. Bonds may be issued under a system of book entry for recording the ownership and transfer of ownership of rights to receive payments of principal and premium, if any, and interest on the bonds. Bonds may be sold in such manner and for such price as the Commission may determine to be for the best interests of the District.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Commission"</emphasis> means the governing body of the District known as the Chesapeake Bay Bridge and Tunnel Commission.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Cost,"</emphasis> as applied to the project, means any or all of the following: the cost of construction; the cost of the acquisition of all land, rights-of-way, property, rights, franchises, easements, and interests acquired by the Commission for such construction; the cost of demolishing or removing any buildings or structures on land so acquired, including the cost of acquiring any lands to which such buildings or structures may be moved; the cost of all machinery and equipment; provision for reasonable working capital, financing charges, and interest prior to and during construction; and, if deemed advisable by the Commission, for a period not exceeding one year after completion of construction, the cost of traffic estimates and of engineering and legal services, plans, specifications, surveys, estimates of cost and of revenues, and other expenses necessary or incident to determining the feasibility or practicability of constructing the project; administrative expenses; and such other expenses as may be necessary or incident to the construction of the project, the financing of such construction, and the placing of the project in operation. Any obligation or expense hereafter incurred by the Commonwealth Transportation Board with the approval of the Commission for traffic surveys, borings, preparation of plans and specifications, and other engineering services in connection with the construction of the project shall be regarded as a part of the cost of the project and shall be reimbursed to the Commonwealth Transportation Board out of the proceeds of revenue bonds issued for the project as authorized in this chapter.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"District"</emphasis> means the political subdivision of the Commonwealth known as the Chesapeake Bay Bridge and Tunnel District.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Owner"</emphasis> includes all persons as defined in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 1-230"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 1 -230">§ 1-230<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#123#000001#       230#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> having any interest or title in and to property, rights, franchises, easements, and interests authorized to be acquired by this chapter.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Project"</emphasis> means a bridge or tunnel or a bridge and tunnel project, including the existing bridge and tunnel crossing operated by the Commission and all or a part of an additional and generally parallel bridge and tunnel crossing, from any point within the boundaries of the District to a point in the County of Northampton, including such approaches and approach highways as the Commission deems necessary to facilitate the flow of traffic in the vicinity of such project or to connect such project with the highway system or other traffic facilities in the Commonwealth, and including all overpasses, underpasses, interchanges, entrance plazas, toll houses, service stations, garages, restaurants, and administration, storage, and other buildings and facilities that the Commission may deem necessary for the operation of such project, together with all property, rights, franchises, easements, and interests that may be required by the Commission for the construction or the operation of such project.</p></bodyText><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p>1956, c. 714; 1959, Extra Session, c. 24; <citation normalizedCite="1990 VA CH 203"><content><span normalizedCite="1990 Va. Ch. 203">1990, c. 203<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1990#000203#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2014 VA CH 805"><content><span normalizedCite="2014 Va. Ch. 805">2014, c. 805<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2014#000805#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PWC0-004G-K2JJ-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 33.2.</desig><title>HIGHWAYS AND OTHER SURFACE TRANSPORTATION SYSTEMS</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="subtitle"><heading><desig>SUBTITLE IV.</desig><title>LOCAL AND REGIONAL TRANSPORTATION</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 22.</desig><title>CHESAPEAKE BAY BRIDGE AND TUNNEL DISTRICT AND COMMISSION</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Governments</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjdEQjE4OUJDMzQxNDNEMEI0RTI1QUFCMzJENjEwRTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Financing</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Q0QyN0IxRDI1MTE0NDQ3NkEzMzZCMTBCMkE2QkM3RTM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MEY3NUIxODI2RjU2NEY0NzgwMDQyNjFDMEQ1QUExRjM</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Real Property Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QUUyRTcxRURBNEY2NEE2MDk3QzBCNzRDOEY0NTZDQzk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Construction Loans</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RDNGMDlENjQ4NUYyNEM0MEIxRTAwMjAyRTdFRUNBRkY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MTY1MzRERDhBMDZCNDFBMDk0QUEwRjcyN0ZFNEY3REM</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Transportation Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RTYzRTk5RDVBQkQ2NDcwQzk2NTU3ODQ5OEE3NDlBNzk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NTkyRUE5REJENDMwNDE4OTg3OTg5NTg0OEVEOUE3M0E7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjVCODE3RDNEMENDNDkxRjg5MzBBNTJFQkNCRDlFOEU</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification><classificationGroup classificationScheme="indexing-terms"><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem score="90"><className>Transportation</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RTYzRTk5RDVBQkQ2NDcwQzk2NTU3ODQ5OEE3NDlBNzk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></classificationGroup></metadata></legislativeDoc>