<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#349#000063#     2#         1503#">Va. Code Ann. § 63.2-1503</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_63.2-1503"/><heading><desig>§ 63.2-1503.</desig><title>Local departments to establish child-protective services; duties</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a"/><heading><desig>A.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Each local department shall establish child-protective services under a departmental coordinator within such department or with one or more adjacent local departments that shall be staffed with qualified personnel pursuant to regulations adopted by the Board. The local department shall be the public agency responsible for receiving and responding to complaints and reports, except that (i) in cases where the reports or complaints are to be made to the court and the judge determines that no local department within a reasonable geographic distance can impartially respond to the report, the court shall assign the report to the court services unit for evaluation; and (ii) in cases where an employee at a private or state-operated hospital, institution or other facility, or an employee of a school board is suspected of abusing or neglecting a child in such hospital, institution or other facility, or public school, the local department shall request the Department and the relevant private or state-operated hospital, institution or other facility, or school board to assist in conducting a joint investigation in accordance with regulations adopted by the Board, in consultation with the Departments of Education, Health, Medical Assistance Services, Behavioral Health and Developmental Services, Juvenile Justice and Corrections.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b"/><heading><desig>B.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The local department shall ensure, through its own personnel or through cooperative arrangements with other local agencies, the capability of receiving reports or complaints and responding to them promptly on a 24-hours-a-day, seven-days-per-week basis.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c"/><heading><desig>C.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The local department shall widely publicize a telephone number for receiving complaints and reports.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d"/><heading><desig>D.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The local department shall notify the local attorney for the Commonwealth and the local law-enforcement agency of all complaints of suspected child abuse or neglect involving (i) any death of a child; (ii) any injury or threatened injury to the child in which a felony or Class 1 misdemeanor is also suspected; (iii) any sexual abuse, suspected sexual abuse or other sexual offense involving a child, including but not limited to the use or display of the child in sexually explicit visual material, as defined in § 18.2-374.1; (iv) any abduction of a child; (v) any felony or Class 1 misdemeanor drug offense involving a child; or (vi) contributing to the delinquency of a minor in violation of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 18.2-371"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 18.2-371">§ 18.2-371<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000018#     2#          371#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, immediately, but in no case more than two hours of receipt of the complaint, and shall provide the attorney for the Commonwealth and the local law-enforcement agency with records and information of the local department, including records related to any complaints of abuse or neglect involving the victim or the alleged perpetrator, related to the investigation of the complaint. The local department shall not allow reports of the death of the victim from other local agencies to substitute for direct reports to the attorney for the Commonwealth and the local law-enforcement agency. The local department shall develop, when practicable, memoranda of understanding for responding to reports of child abuse and neglect with local law enforcement and the attorney for the Commonwealth.</p><p>In each case in which the local department notifies the local law-enforcement agency of a complaint pursuant to this subsection, the local department shall, within two business days of delivery of the notification, complete a written report, on a form provided by the Board for such purpose, which shall include (a) the name of the representative of the local department providing notice required by this subsection; (b) the name of the local law-enforcement officer who received such notice; (c) the date and time that notification was made; (d) the identity of the victim; (e) the identity of the person alleged to have abused or neglected the child, if known; (f) the clause or clauses in this subsection that describe the reasons for the notification; and (g) the signatures, which may be electronic signatures, of the representatives of the local department making the notification and the local law-enforcement officer receiving the notification. Such report shall be included in the record of the investigation and may be submitted either in writing or electronically.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_e"/><heading><desig>E.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> When abuse or neglect is suspected in any case involving the death of a child, the local department shall report the case immediately to the regional medical examiner and the local law-enforcement agency.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_f"/><heading><desig>F.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The local department shall use reasonable diligence to locate (i) any child for whom a report of suspected abuse or neglect has been received and is under investigation, receiving family assessment, or for whom a founded determination of abuse and neglect has been made and a child-protective services case opened and (ii) persons who are the subject of a report that is under investigation or receiving family assessment, if the whereabouts of the child or such persons are unknown to the local department.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_g"/><heading><desig>G.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> When an abused or neglected child and the persons who are the subject of an open child-protective services case have relocated out of the jurisdiction of the local department, the local department shall notify the child-protective services agency in the jurisdiction to which such persons have relocated, whether inside or outside of the Commonwealth, and forward to such agency relevant portions of the case record. The receiving local department shall arrange protective and rehabilitative services as required by this section.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_h"/><heading><desig>H.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> When a child for whom a report of suspected abuse or neglect has been received and is under investigation or receiving family assessment and the child and the child's parents or other persons responsible for the child's care who are the subject of the report that is under investigation or family assessment have relocated out of the jurisdiction of the local department, the local department shall notify the child-protective services agency in the jurisdiction to which the child and such persons have relocated, whether inside or outside of the Commonwealth, and complete such investigation or family assessment by requesting such agency's assistance in completing the investigation or family assessment. The local department that completes the investigation or family assessment shall forward to the receiving agency relevant portions of the case record in order for the receiving agency to arrange protective and rehabilitative services as required by this section.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_i"/><heading><desig>I.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Upon receipt of a report of child abuse or neglect, the local department shall determine the validity of such report and shall make a determination to conduct an investigation pursuant to <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 63.2-1505"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 63.2-1505">§ 63.2-1505<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000063#     2#         1505#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> or, if designated as a child-protective services differential response agency by the Department according to <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 63.2-1504"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 63.2-1504">§ 63.2-1504<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000063#     2#         1504#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, a family assessment pursuant to <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 63.2-1506"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 63.2-1506">§ 63.2-1506<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000063#     2#         1506#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_j"/><heading><desig>J.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The local department shall foster, when practicable, the creation, maintenance and coordination of hospital and community-based multidisciplinary teams that shall include where possible, but not be limited to, members of the medical, mental health, social work, nursing, education, legal and law-enforcement professions. Such teams shall assist the local departments in identifying abused and neglected children; coordinating medical, social, and legal services for the children and their families; developing innovative programs for detection and prevention of child abuse; promoting community concern and action in the area of child abuse and neglect; and disseminating information to the general public with respect to the problem of child abuse and neglect and the facilities and prevention and treatment methods available to combat child abuse and neglect. These teams may be the family assessment and planning teams established pursuant to § 2.2-5207. Multidisciplinary teams may develop agreements regarding the exchange of information among the parties for the purposes of the investigation and disposition of complaints of child abuse and neglect, delivery of services and child protection. Any information exchanged in accordance with the agreement shall not be considered to be a violation of the provisions of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 63.2-102"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 63.2-102">§ 63.2-102<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000063#     2#          102#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 63.2-104"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 63.2-104">63.2-104<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000063#     2#          104#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, or <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 63.2-105"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 63.2-105">63.2-105<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000063#     2#          105#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p><p>The local department shall also coordinate its efforts in the provision of these services for abused and neglected children with the judge and staff of the court.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_k"/><heading><desig>K.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The local department may develop multidisciplinary teams to provide consultation to the local department during the investigation of selected cases involving child abuse or neglect, and to make recommendations regarding the prosecution of such cases. These teams may include, but are not limited to, members of the medical, mental health, legal and law-enforcement professions, including the attorney for the Commonwealth or his designee; a local child-protective services representative; and the guardian ad litem or other court-appointed advocate for the child. Any information exchanged for the purpose of such consultation shall not be considered a violation of § 63.2-102, 63.2-104, or 63.2-105.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_l"/><heading><desig>L.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The local department shall report annually on its activities concerning abused and neglected children to the court and to the Child-Protective Services Unit in the Department on forms provided by the Department.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_m"/><heading><desig>M.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Statements, or any evidence derived therefrom, made to local department child-protective services personnel, or to any person performing the duties of such personnel, by any person accused of the abuse, injury, neglect or death of a child after the arrest of such person, shall not be used in evidence in the case-in-chief against such person in the criminal proceeding on the question of guilt or innocence over the objection of the accused, unless the statement was made after such person was fully advised (i) of his right to remain silent, (ii) that anything he says may be used against him in a court of law, (iii) that he has a right to the presence of an attorney during any interviews, and (iv) that if he cannot afford an attorney, one will be appointed for him prior to any questioning.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_n"/><heading><desig>N.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the local department, in accordance with Board regulations, shall transmit information regarding founded complaints or family assessments and may transmit other information regarding reports, complaints, family assessments and investigations involving active duty military personnel or members of their household to family advocacy representatives of the United States Armed Forces.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_o"/><heading><desig>O.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The local department shall notify the custodial parent and make reasonable efforts to notify the noncustodial parent as those terms are defined in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 63.2-1900"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 63.2-1900">§ 63.2-1900<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000063#     2#         1900#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> of a report of suspected abuse or neglect of a child who is the subject of an investigation or is receiving family assessment, in those cases in which such custodial or noncustodial parent is not the subject of the investigation.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_p"/><heading><desig>P.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The local department shall notify the Superintendent of Public Instruction when an individual holding a license issued by the Board of Education is the subject of a founded complaint of child abuse or neglect and shall transmit identifying information regarding such individual if the local department knows the person holds a license issued by the Board of Education and after all rights to any appeal provided by <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 63.2-1526"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 63.2-1526">§ 63.2-1526<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000063#     2#         1526#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> have been exhausted. Any information exchanged for the purpose of this subsection shall not be considered a violation of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 63.2-102"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 63.2-102">§ 63.2-102<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000063#     2#          102#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 63.2-104"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 63.2-104">63.2-104<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000063#     2#          104#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, or <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 63.2-105"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 63.2-105">63.2-105<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000063#     2#          105#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></level><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p>1975, c. 341, § 63.1-248.6; 1978, c. 747; 1979, cc. 347, 348; 1984, c. 392; 1987, c. 443; <citation normalizedCite="1989 VA CH 109"><content><span normalizedCite="1989 Va. Ch. 109">1989, cc. 109<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1989#000109#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1989 VA CH 547"><content><span normalizedCite="1989 Va. Ch. 547">547<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1989#000547#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1991 VA CH 644"><content><span normalizedCite="1991 Va. Ch. 644">1991, c. 644<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1991#000644#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1992 VA CH 214"><content><span normalizedCite="1992 Va. Ch. 214">1992, cc. 214<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1992#000214#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1992 VA CH 837"><content><span normalizedCite="1992 Va. Ch. 837">837<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1992#000837#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1992 VA CH 880"><content><span normalizedCite="1992 Va. Ch. 880">880<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1992#000880#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1993 VA CH 506"><content><span normalizedCite="1993 Va. Ch. 506">1993, cc. 506<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1993#000506#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1993 VA CH 955"><content><span normalizedCite="1993 Va. Ch. 955">955<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1993#000955#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1994 VA CH 643"><content><span normalizedCite="1994 Va. Ch. 643">1994, cc. 643<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1994#000643#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1994 VA CH 675"><content><span normalizedCite="1994 Va. Ch. 675">675<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1994#000675#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1994 VA CH 840"><content><span normalizedCite="1994 Va. Ch. 840">840<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1994#000840#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1996 VA CH 858"><content><span normalizedCite="1996 Va. Ch. 858">1996, cc. 858<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1996#000858#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1996 VA CH 863"><content><span normalizedCite="1996 Va. Ch. 863">863<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1996#000863#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1998 VA CH 704"><content><span normalizedCite="1998 Va. Ch. 704">1998, cc. 704<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1998#000704#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1998 VA CH 716"><content><span normalizedCite="1998 Va. Ch. 716">716<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1998#000716#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2000 VA CH 500"><content><span normalizedCite="2000 Va. Ch. 500">2000, cc. 500<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2000#000500#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2000 VA CH 854"><content><span normalizedCite="2000 Va. Ch. 854">854<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2000#000854#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2002 VA CH 747"><content><span normalizedCite="2002 Va. Ch. 747">2002, c. 747<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2002#000747#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2004 VA CH 114"><content><span normalizedCite="2004 Va. Ch. 114">2004, cc. 114<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2004#000114#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2004 VA CH 220"><content><span normalizedCite="2004 Va. Ch. 220">220<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2004#000220#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2004 VA CH 886"><content><span normalizedCite="2004 Va. Ch. 886">886<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2004#000886#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2008 VA CH 474"><content><span normalizedCite="2008 Va. Ch. 474">2008, cc. 474<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2008#000474#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2008 VA CH 827"><content><span normalizedCite="2008 Va. Ch. 827">827<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2008#000827#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2009 VA CH 813"><content><span normalizedCite="2009 Va. Ch. 813">2009, cc. 813<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2009#000813#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2009 VA CH 840"><content><span normalizedCite="2009 Va. Ch. 840">840<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2009#000840#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2014 VA CH 300"><content><span normalizedCite="2014 Va. Ch. 300">2014, cc. 300<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2014#000300#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2014 VA CH 565"><content><span normalizedCite="2014 Va. Ch. 565">565<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2014#000565#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PVB0-004G-K2R1-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 63.2.</desig><title>WELFARE (SOCIAL SERVICES)</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="subtitle"><heading><desig>SUBTITLE III.</desig><title>SOCIAL SERVICES PROGRAMS</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 15.</desig><title>CHILD ABUSE AND NEGLECT</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="article"><heading><desig>ARTICLE 1.</desig><title>GENERAL PROVISIONS</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Criminal Law &amp; Procedure</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NEU0RkE1OUQwNUQwNDgxODhEODZCMjkzOTg3NThBNzk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Elements</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MEFGQzU4MUJCNUNFNDA5QkJFMThBMEQ1QkJGM0VEQkQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDgzMDZDQ0YyRTM1NDcxRDhFQkU4NTQyMjFGNkFBOEI</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OEQ2QjlGNTc0QkU3NEFDQTkzN0Q1QjgxNUYwMUMzQ0Y7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NjE5MEI0RUExOTZENDdFM0EwQTlFMjYyMkQzNkM0OEQ</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OEIwNEZGODRBMEM4NERCM0I1MDM3NTQzNjYwRTIwOEM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6REY3MDM3ODdDMzBENEMxNjg0NTJENjE0Rjc3Mzk0OEM</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDIwRjc0N0I2NkE2NDI3QjkyMzI4NjFGNTc5MzQ1NEE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NEU4N0IwOEEwRjdCNEM5MzhCQzE0Njc3NTNFMDVGMTA</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Education Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDkzNUEzQzFBNEZBNEFBREIxNDM5MTc1MUU5QjI4MTY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NjA2NDg3NzhDRjYxNDNFMTk0NkY5OTdFRjhGMjBGMUY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QTU5MTJDNDBCQkU0NEY2MEIyREVGRkM0Qzg1NjY5RTQ</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>School Superintendents</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RURFMjkzRTlDNTkwNDFFNThBNTJEMkM5RUJBMjBCM0Y7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjM5NDM0MDA1M0Y0NDY0RTgxMEQ5OEQ3QzJBQzhENzk</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Evidence</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUVGQkU0QjJFMTIzNDNBM0FCNTVEQjAxQTM3RDcwOTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MzYwQUQ2RDlBNDUzNEFBRTkwRDZBNEU1NUQxQTNDMzg7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDA2QUFEQUVBNTYyNDUxNUE2MjMzMDk5NzM1NkQ1Mjc</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Family Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NEI4M0U5Qzg3RTk0NDdBRUJGNDRGNkZEQkU3RDdFNDU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Abuse, Endangerment &amp; Neglect</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OEI5RTc4NDg3RDY5NDM4Qzg2RkZFRDk0QTI2REFGNUI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RkE2MkE5MTUwMzk5NEJFN0E5RUFCRUIyNDg3RkU4Rjc</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Appointment</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RkFERUQxQTg2MjBCNEQ5OTg4NEE2MDEzQjk4QTg1RTM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDkyNkUxNzIzNzZFNDI3OUI1MTI2NTBEOUMyNERGNTE</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NkQzNDVBNDkwRkM2NDY2RkFEOUI2MzZENjREMkRCODg7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QUJCOTZBNkIyQjFFNDI2MDlGN0I2M0I4ODA5NzE5OTk</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Q0RCREM3QzU5OEVDNDlEM0FGRDgxQkQwRTFBOEREQzU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6N0UzRjg5QjhFNTdFNDQ3N0FEMUY0NTVEQkEzQ0M2RTA</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6REI1MDI3OTE1NDZENDYzRjlCNDgyNzFEMDc3MDNFQUE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RkE2MkE5MTUwMzk5NEJFN0E5RUFCRUIyNDg3RkU4Rjc</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Military &amp; Veterans Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NzM1OUEyRDNERTdENEU2MTk3RTlCNEJCRUY0NjRGRjQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>In Personam Jurisdiction</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MEEyMDUzQUY5QUQxNDdBMzk1MTc0NjAwOTc1NEFCNDQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MkEzNUFERDI2NTQyNERGQzlCQzQ1MDUzNTA5QUQyQUE</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Proper Warnings</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QUU5MDM5OTE2MjcwNEEyRkFGQTAyQ0Q1NjA5M0VDM0Q7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NTZGRDRGNjMyRDRENEE4NEEzRDFFNzlFRUVBODU0OTk</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification><classificationGroup classificationScheme="indexing-terms"><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem score="90"><className>Public Health &amp; Welfare</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDYwRTY1MDg3MTk5NDUyNkFFRDI1RjJBRERGQ0UxNzI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></classificationGroup></metadata></legislativeDoc>