<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#349#000053#     1#          216#">Va. Code Ann. § 53.1-216</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_53.1-216"/><heading><desig>§ 53.1-216.</desig><title>Governor to execute; form of compact</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><bodyText><p>The Governor is authorized and requested to execute, on behalf of the Commonwealth, with any other state or states legally joining therein a compact which shall be in form substantially as follows:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><bodyText><p>The contracting states solemnly agree that:</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="article"><anchor id="_i"/><heading><desig>ARTICLE I.</desig></heading><bodyText><p>The party states, desiring by common action to fully utilize and improve their institutional facilities and provide adequate programs for the confinement, treatment and rehabilitation of various types of offenders, declare that it is the policy of each of the party states to provide such facilities and programs on a basis of cooperation with one another, and with the Federal Government, thereby serving the best interest of such offenders and of society and effecting economies in capital expenditures and operational costs. The purpose of this compact is to provide for the mutual development and execution of such programs of cooperation for the confinement, treatment and rehabilitation of offenders with the most economical use of human and material resources.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="article"><anchor id="_ii"/><heading><desig>ARTICLE II.</desig></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><bodyText><p>As used in this compact, unless the context clearly requires otherwise:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_ii_a"/><heading><desig>a.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> "State" means a state of the United States; the United States of America; a territory or possession of the United States; the District of Columbia; the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_ii_b"/><heading><desig>b.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> "Sending state" means a state party to this compact in which conviction or court commitment was had.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_ii_c"/><heading><desig>c.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> "Receiving state" means a state party to this compact to which an inmate is sent for confinement other than a state in which conviction or court commitment was had.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_ii_d"/><heading><desig>d.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> "Inmate" means a male or female offender who is committed, under sentence to or confined in a penal or correctional institution.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_ii_e"/><heading><desig>e.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> "Institution" means any penal or correctional facility, including but not limited to a facility for individuals with mental illness or intellectual disability, in which inmates as defined in d above may lawfully be confined.</p></bodyText></level></level></level><level levelType="article"><anchor id="_iii"/><heading><desig>ARTICLE III.</desig></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_iii_a"/><heading><desig>a.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Each party state may make one or more contracts with any one or more of the other party states, or with the Federal Government, for the confinement of inmates on behalf of a sending state in institutions situated within receiving states. Any such contract shall provide for:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_iii_a_1"/><heading><desig>(1)</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Its duration.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_iii_a_2"/><heading><desig>(2)</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Payments to be made to the receiving state or to the Federal Government, by the sending state for inmate maintenance, extraordinary medical and dental expenses, and any participation in or receipt by inmates of rehabilitative or correctional services, facilities, programs or treatment not reasonably included as part of normal maintenance.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_iii_a_3"/><heading><desig>(3)</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Participation in programs of inmate employment, if any; the disposition or crediting of any payments received by inmates on account thereof; and the crediting of proceeds from or disposal of any products resulting therefrom.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_iii_a_4"/><heading><desig>(4)</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Delivery and retaking of inmates.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_iii_a_5"/><heading><desig>(5)</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Such other matters as may be necessary and appropriate to fix the obligations, responsibilities and rights of the sending and receiving states.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_iii_b"/><heading><desig>b.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The terms and provisions of this compact shall be a part of any contract entered into by the authority of or pursuant thereto and nothing in any such contract shall be inconsistent therewith.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="article"><anchor id="_iv"/><heading><desig>ARTICLE IV.</desig></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_iv_a"/><heading><desig>a.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Whenever the duly constituted authorities in a state party to this compact, and which has entered into a contract pursuant to Article III, shall decide that confinement in, or transfer of an inmate to, an institution within the territory of another party state is necessary or desirable in order to provide adequate quarters and care or an appropriate program of rehabilitation or treatment, said officials may direct that the confinement be within an institution within the territory of said other party state, the receiving state to act in that regard solely as agent for the sending state.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_iv_b"/><heading><desig>b.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The appropriate officials of any state party to this compact shall have access, at all reasonable times, to any institution in which it has a contractual right to confine inmates for the purpose of inspecting the facilities thereof and visiting such of its inmates as may be confined in the institution.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_iv_c"/><heading><desig>c.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Inmates confined in an institution pursuant to the terms of this compact shall at all times be subject to the jurisdiction of the sending state and may at any time be removed therefrom for transfer to a prison or other institution within the sending state, for transfer to another institution in which the sending state may have a contractual or other right to confine inmates, for release on probation or parole, for discharge, or for any other purpose permitted by the laws of the sending state; provided that the sending state shall continue to be obligated to such payments as may be required pursuant to the terms of any contract entered into under the terms of Article III.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_iv_d"/><heading><desig>d.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Each receiving state shall provide regular reports to each sending state on the inmates of that sending state in institutions pursuant to this compact including a conduct record of each inmate and certify said record to the official designated by the sending state, in order that each inmate may have official review of his or her record in determining and altering the disposition of said inmate in accordance with the law which may obtain in the sending state and in order that the same may be a source of information for the sending state.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_iv_e"/><heading><desig>e.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> All inmates who may be confined in an institution pursuant to the provisions of this compact shall be treated in a reasonable and humane manner and shall be treated equally with such similar inmates of the receiving state as may be confined in the same institution. The fact of confinement in a receiving state shall not deprive any inmate so confined of any legal rights which said inmate would have had if confined in an appropriate institution of the sending state.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_iv_f"/><heading><desig>f.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Any hearing or hearings to which an inmate confined pursuant to this compact may be entitled by the laws of the sending state may be had before the appropriate authorities of the sending state, or of the receiving state if authorized by the sending state. The receiving state shall provide adequate facilities for such hearings as may be conducted by the appropriate officials of a sending state. In the event such hearing or hearings are had before officials of the receiving state, the governing law shall be that of the sending state and a record of the hearing or hearings as prescribed by the sending state shall be made. Said record together with any recommendations of the hearing officials shall be transmitted forthwith to the official or officials before whom the hearing would have been had if it had taken place in the sending state. In any and all proceedings had pursuant to the provisions of this subdivision, the officials of the receiving state shall act solely as agents of the sending state and no final determination shall be made in any matter except by the appropriate officials of the sending state.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_iv_g"/><heading><desig>g.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Any inmate confined pursuant to this compact shall be released within the territory of the sending state unless the inmate, and the sending and receiving states, shall agree upon release in some other place. The sending state shall bear the cost of such return to its territory.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_iv_h"/><heading><desig>h.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Any inmate confined pursuant to the terms of this compact shall have any and all rights to participate in and derive any benefits or incur or be relieved of any obligations or have such obligations modified or his status changed on account of any action or proceeding in which he could have participated if confined in any appropriate institution of the sending state located within such state.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_iv_i"/><heading><desig>i.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The parents, guardian, trustee, or other person or persons entitled under the laws of the sending state to act for, advise or otherwise function with respect to any inmate shall not be deprived of or restricted in his exercise of any power in respect of any inmate confined pursuant to the terms of this compact.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="article"><anchor id="_v"/><heading><desig>ARTICLE V.</desig></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_v_a"/><heading><desig>a.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Any decision of the sending state in respect of any matter over which it retains jurisdiction pursuant to this compact shall be conclusive upon and not reviewable within the receiving state, but if at the time the sending state seeks to remove an inmate from an institution in the receiving state there is pending against the inmate within such state any criminal charge or if the inmate is formally accused of having committed within such state a criminal offense, the inmate shall not be returned without the consent of the receiving state until discharge from prosecution or other form of proceeding, imprisonment or detention for such offense. The duly accredited officers of the sending state shall be permitted to transport inmates pursuant to this compact through any and all states party to this compact without interference.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_v_b"/><heading><desig>b.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> An inmate who escapes from an institution in which he is confined pursuant to this compact shall be deemed a fugitive from the sending state and from the state in which the institution is situated. In the case of an escape to a jurisdiction other than the sending or receiving state, the responsibility for institution of extradition or rendition proceedings shall be that of the sending state, but nothing contained herein shall be construed to prevent or affect the activities of officers and agencies of any jurisdiction directed toward the apprehension and return of an escapee.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="article"><anchor id="_vi"/><heading><desig>ARTICLE VI.</desig></heading><bodyText><p>Any state party to this compact may accept federal aid for use in connection with any institution or program, the use of which is or may be affected by this compact or any contract pursuant hereto and any inmate in a receiving state pursuant to this compact may participate in any such federally-aided program or activity for which the sending and receiving states have made contractual provision, provided that if such program or activity is not part of the customary correctional regimen the express consent of the appropriate official of the sending state shall be required therefor.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="article"><anchor id="_vii"/><heading><desig>ARTICLE VII.</desig></heading><bodyText><p>This compact shall enter into force and become effective and binding upon the states so acting when it has been enacted into law by any two states. Thereafter, this compact shall enter into force and become effective and binding as to any other of said states upon similar action by such state.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="article"><anchor id="_viii"/><heading><desig>ARTICLE VIII.</desig></heading><bodyText><p>This compact shall continue in force and remain binding upon a party state until it shall have enacted a statute repealing the same and providing for the sending of formal written notice of withdrawal from the compact to the appropriate official of all other party states. An actual withdrawal shall not take effect until one year after the notice provided in said statute has been sent. Such withdrawal shall not relieve the withdrawing state from its obligations assumed hereunder prior to the effective date of withdrawal. Before effective date of withdrawal, a withdrawing state shall remove to its territory, at its own expense, such inmates as it may have confined pursuant to the provisions of this compact.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="article"><anchor id="_ix"/><heading><desig>ARTICLE IX.</desig></heading><bodyText><p>Nothing contained in this compact shall be construed to abrogate or impair any agreement or other arrangement which a party state may have with a nonparty state for the confinement, rehabilitation or treatment of inmates nor to repeal any other laws of a party state authorizing the making of cooperative institutional arrangements.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="article"><anchor id="_x"/><heading><desig>ARTICLE X</desig></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><bodyText><p>The provisions of this compact shall be liberally construed and shall be severable. If any phrase, clause, sentence or provision of this compact is declared to be contrary to the constitution of any participating state or of the United States or the applicability thereof to any government, agency, person or circumstance is held invalid, the validity of the remainder of this compact and the applicability thereof to any government, agency, person or circumstance shall not be affected thereby. If this compact shall be held contrary to the constitution of any state participating therein, the compact shall remain in full force and effect as to the remaining states and in full force and effect as to the state affected as to all severable matters.</p></bodyText></level></level><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p>Code 1950, § 53-304.9; 1977, c. 339; 1982, c. 636; <citation normalizedCite="2012 VA CH 476"><content><span normalizedCite="2012 Va. Ch. 476">2012, cc. 476<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2012#000476#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2012 VA CH 507"><content><span normalizedCite="2012 Va. Ch. 507">507<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2012#000507#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PT90-004G-K1VS-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 53.1.</desig><title>PRISONS AND OTHER METHODS OF CORRECTION</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 9.</desig><title>INTERSTATE CORRECTIONS COMPACT</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Civil Rights Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NURDOUM5MEJFQUZGNEFBMDgzMkM0RTgwODdDNTMxREM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Transfers</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6N0MwODM2M0FENzNBNDIzNDlBMDY2QTYyREJDNjA3MDE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OTM3NjVDMkYzMzkwNDJFNDg3M0EyRTZERDBDRkFCNDY</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Criminal Law &amp; Procedure</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NEU0RkE1OUQwNUQwNDgxODhEODZCMjkzOTg3NThBNzk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Imprisonment</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NURCMTExOEEzNDJBNDk4RjhFQTQ0NzEwMzc0OTg3RTE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QTFGRjg4NjA3RTg1NDA2RkIzMDk4QzdGREIyQzVGMDk</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Substance Abuse Programs</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RTVFMjYwRkVBNUYwNDI4MUE2NEY3RUZBMkZDQUYwNjU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QUM4NjRENzc2NUY4NEQwMUEyQTdBNkM4MDhEQURCQjU</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Governments</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjdEQjE4OUJDMzQxNDNEMEI0RTI1QUFCMzJENjEwRTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Operability</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OUIyMzFENUM0RUFCNDIwOEFDQjkwNEQyMTI3MThGRUY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MTkwNDc4Q0NCRDkxNDdCMUI4MjFBQzg4NjlDMUZCMjI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></metadata></legislativeDoc>