<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#123#000036#     55.50#">Va. Code Ann. § 36-55.50</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_36-55.50"/><heading><desig>§ 36-55.50.</desig><title>Liberal construction</title></heading><bodyText><p>Neither this chapter nor anything herein contained is or shall be construed as a restriction or limitation upon any powers which HDA might otherwise have under any laws of this Commonwealth, and this chapter is cumulative to any such powers. This chapter does and shall be construed to provide a complete, additional, and alternative method for the doing of the things authorized thereby and shall be regarded as supplemental and additional to powers conferred by other laws. However, the issuance of bonds, notes and other obligations and refunding bonds under the provisions of this chapter need not comply with the requirements of any other state law applicable to the issuance of bonds, notes and other obligations, and contracts for the construction and acquisition of any housing developments undertaken pursuant to this chapter need not comply with the provisions of any other state law applicable to contracts for the construction and acquisition of state-owned property. No proceedings, notice or approval shall be required for the issuance of any bonds, notes and other obligations or any instrument as security therefor, except as is provided in this chapter.</p></bodyText><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p>1972, c. 830.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PT30-004G-K3WC-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 36.</desig><title>HOUSING</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 1.2.</desig><title>VIRGINIA HOUSING DEVELOPMENT AUTHORITY ACT</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy></metadata></legislativeDoc>