<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#349#000015#     2#         5113#">Va. Code Ann. § 15.2-5113</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_15.2-5113"/><heading><desig>§ 15.2-5113.</desig><title>Members of authority board; chief administrative or executive officer</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a"/><heading><desig>A.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The powers of each authority created by the governing body of a single locality shall be exercised by an authority board of five members, or at the option of the board of supervisors of a county, a number of board members equal to the number of members of the board of supervisors. The powers of each authority created by the governing bodies of two or more localities shall be exercised by the number of authority board members specified in its articles of incorporation, which shall be not less than one member from each participating locality and not less than a total of five members. The board members of an authority shall be selected in the manner and for the terms provided by the agreement or ordinance or resolution or concurrent ordinances or resolutions creating the authority. One or more members of the governing body or one or more directors of an industrial or economic development authority of a locality may be appointed board members of the authority, the provisions of any other law to the contrary notwithstanding. No board member shall be appointed for a term of more than four years. When one or more additional political subdivisions join an existing authority, each of such joining political subdivisions shall have at least one member on the board. Board members shall hold office until their successors have been appointed and may succeed themselves. The board members of the authority shall elect one of their number chairman, and shall elect a secretary and treasurer who need not be members. The offices of secretary and treasurer may be combined.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b"/><heading><desig>B.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A majority of board members shall constitute a quorum and the vote of a majority of board members shall be necessary for any action taken by the authority. An authority may, by bylaw, provide a method to resolve tie votes or deadlocked issues.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c"/><heading><desig>C.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> No vacancy in the board membership of the authority shall impair the right of a quorum to exercise all the rights and perform all the duties of the authority. If a vacancy occurs by reason of the death, disqualification or resignation of a board member, the governing body of the political subdivision which appointed the authority board member shall appoint a successor to fill the unexpired term. Whenever a political subdivision withdraws its membership from an authority, the term of any board member appointed to the board of the authority from such political subdivision shall immediately terminate. Board members shall receive such compensation as fixed by resolution of the governing body or bodies which are members of the authority, and shall be reimbursed for any actual expenses necessarily incurred in the performance of their duties.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d"/><heading><desig>D.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Alternate board members may also be selected. Such alternates shall be selected in the same manner and shall have the same qualifications as the board members except that an alternate for an elected board member need not be an elected official. The term of each alternate shall be the same as the term of the board member for whom each serves as an alternate; however, the alternate's term shall not expire because of the board member's death, disqualification, resignation, or termination of employment with the member's political subdivision. If a board member is not present at a meeting of the authority, the alternate for that board member shall have all the voting and other rights of a board member and shall be counted for purposes of determining a quorum.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_e"/><heading><desig>E.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The board members may appoint a chief administrative or executive officer who shall serve at the pleasure of the board members. He shall execute and enforce the orders and resolutions adopted by the board members and perform such duties as may be delegated to him by the board members.</p></bodyText></level><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p>Code 1950, § 15-764.11; 1950, p. 1317; 1962, c. 623, § 15.1-1249; 1968, c. 355; 1972, c. 544; 1973, cc. 135, 521; 1974, c. 276; 1979, cc. 273, 280; 1980, c. 67; <citation normalizedCite="1995 VA CH 285"><content><span normalizedCite="1995 Va. Ch. 285">1995, c. 285<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1995#000285#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1997 VA CH 587"><content><span normalizedCite="1997 Va. Ch. 587">1997, c. 587<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1997#000587#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2009 VA CH 655"><content><span normalizedCite="2009 Va. Ch. 655">2009, c. 655<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2009#000655#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PSM0-004G-K3VF-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 15.2.</desig><title>COUNTIES, CITIES AND TOWNS</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="subtitle"><heading><desig>SUBTITLE IV.</desig><title>OTHER GOVERNMENTAL ENTITIES</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 51.</desig><title>VIRGINIA WATER AND WASTE AUTHORITIES ACT</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="article"><heading><desig>ARTICLE 3.</desig><title>FUNCTIONS OF AUTHORITIES</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Governments</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjdEQjE4OUJDMzQxNDNEMEI0RTI1QUFCMzJENjEwRTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Administrative Boards</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QTYwRUFCMDc5MzQ5NDEyREFEQkU2NkE2MjRGQTlCNzY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Njg1MkM3RkYyNzIxNEVFRkJFMTI2NUM4NUU1ODdEM0Q</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Finance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjMzOTBBRTg2MUVDNDdDNUE1M0QxNDk1RERCNjNCN0I7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Njg1MkM3RkYyNzIxNEVFRkJFMTI2NUM4NUU1ODdEM0Q</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification><classificationGroup classificationScheme="indexing-terms"><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem score="90"><className>Governments</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjdEQjE4OUJDMzQxNDNEMEI0RTI1QUFCMzJENjEwRTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></classificationGroup></metadata></legislativeDoc>