<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#349#000046#     2#      1573.17#">Va. Code Ann. § 46.2-1573.17</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_46.2-1573.17"/><heading><desig>§ 46.2-1573.17.</desig><title>Other coercion of dealers; transfer, grant, succession to and cancellation of dealer franchises; delivery of trailers, parts, and accessories</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><bodyText><p>It shall be unlawful for any manufacturer, factory branch, distributor, or distributor branch, or any field representative, officer, agent, or their representatives:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> To coerce or attempt to coerce any dealer to accept delivery of any trailer or trailers, parts or accessories therefor, or any other commodities that have not been ordered by the dealer.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> To coerce or attempt to coerce any dealer to enter into an agreement with the manufacturer, factory branch, distributor, or distributor branch, or representative thereof, or do any other act unfair to the dealer, by threatening to cancel any franchise existing between the manufacturer, factory branch, distributor, distributor branch, or representative thereof and the dealer.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> To coerce or attempt to coerce any dealer to join, contribute to, or affiliate with any advertising association.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_4"/><heading><desig>4.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> To prevent or refuse to approve the sale or transfer of the ownership of a dealership by the sale of the business, stock transfer, or otherwise, or the transfer, sale, or assignment of a dealer franchise, or a change in the executive management or principal operator of the dealership, unless the franchisor provides written notice to the dealer of its objection and the reasons therefor at least 30 days prior to the proposed effective date of the transfer, sale, assignment, or change. No such objection shall be effective to prevent the sale, transfer, assignment, or change if the Commissioner has determined, if requested in writing by the dealer within 30 days after receipt of an objection to the proposed sale, transfer, or change, and after a hearing on the matter, that the failure to permit or honor the sale, transfer, assignment, or change is unreasonable under the circumstances. No franchise may be sold, assigned, or transferred unless (i) the franchisor has been given at least 90 days' prior written notice by the dealer as to the identity, financial ability, and qualifications of the proposed transferee and (ii) the sale or transfer of the franchise and business will not involve, without the franchisor's consent, a relocation of the business.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_5"/><heading><desig>5.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> To grant an additional franchise for a particular line-make of trailer in a relevant market area in which a dealer or dealers in that line-make are already located unless the franchisor has first advised in writing all other dealers in the line-make in the relevant market area. No such additional franchise may be established at the proposed site unless the Commissioner has determined, if requested by a dealer of the same line-make in the relevant market area within 30 days after receipt of the franchisor's notice of intention to establish the additional franchise, and after a hearing on the matter, that there is reasonable evidence that after the grant of the new franchise, the market will support all of the dealers in that line-make in the relevant market area. Establishing a franchised dealer in a relevant market area to replace a franchised dealer that has not been in operation for more than two years shall constitute the establishment of a new franchise subject to the terms of this subdivision. The two-year period for replacing a franchised dealer shall begin on the day the franchise was terminated or, if a termination hearing was held, on the day the franchisor was legally permitted finally to terminate the franchise. This subdivision shall not apply to (i) the relocation of an existing dealer within that dealer's relevant market area if the relocation site is to be more than 10 miles distant from any other dealer for the same line-make; (ii) the relocation of an existing dealer within that dealer's relevant market area if the relocation site is to be more distant than the existing site from all other dealers of the same line-make in that relevant market area; or (iii) the relocation of an existing new trailer dealer within two miles of the existing site of the relocating dealer.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_6"/><heading><desig>6.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Except as otherwise provided in this subdivision and notwithstanding the terms of any franchise, to terminate, cancel, or refuse to renew the franchise of any dealer without good cause and unless (i) the dealer and the Commissioner have received written notice of the franchisor's intentions at least 60 days prior to the effective date of such termination, cancellation, or the expiration date of the franchise, setting forth the specific grounds for the action, and (ii) the Commissioner has determined, if requested in writing by the dealer within the 60-day period, and after a hearing on the matter, that there is good cause for the termination, cancellation, or nonrenewal of the franchise. In any case where a petition is made to the Commissioner for a determination as to good cause for the termination, cancellation, or nonrenewal of a franchise, the franchise in question shall continue in effect pending the Commissioner's decision or, if that decision is appealed to the circuit court, pending the decision of the circuit court. In any case in which a franchisor neither advises a dealer that it does not intend to renew a franchise nor takes any action to renew a franchise beyond its expiration date, the franchise in question shall continue in effect on the terms last agreed to by the parties. Notwithstanding the other provisions of this subdivision, notice of termination, cancellation, or nonrenewal may be provided to a dealer by a franchisor not less than 15 days prior to the effective date of such termination, cancellation, or nonrenewal when the grounds for such action are any of the following:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_6_a"/><heading><desig>a.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Insolvency of the franchised trailer dealer or filing of any petition by or against the franchised trailer dealer, under any bankruptcy or receivership law, leading to liquidation or that is intended to lead to liquidation of the franchisee's business;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_6_b"/><heading><desig>b.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Failure of the franchised trailer dealer to conduct its customary sales and service operations during its posted business hours for seven consecutive business days, except where the failure results from acts of God or circumstances beyond the direct control of the franchised trailer dealer;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_6_c"/><heading><desig>c.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Revocation of any license that the franchised trailer dealer is required to have to operate a dealership; or</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_6_d"/><heading><desig>d.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Conviction of the dealer or any principal of the dealer of a felony.</p><p><pre/>The change or discontinuance of a marketing or distribution system of a particular line-make product by a manufacturer or distributor, while the name identification of the product is continued in substantial form by the same or different manufacturer or distributor, may be considered to be a franchise termination, cancellation, or nonrenewal.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_7"/><heading><desig>7.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> To fail to provide continued parts and service support to a dealer that holds a franchise in a discontinued line-make for at least five years from the date of such discontinuance.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_8"/><heading><desig>8.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> To fail to allow a dealer the right at any time to designate a member of his family as a successor to the dealership in the event of the death or incapacity of the dealer. It shall be unlawful to prevent or refuse to honor the succession to a dealership by a member of the family of a deceased or incapacitated dealer if the franchisor has not provided to the member of the family previously designated by the dealer as his successor written notice of its objections to the succession and of such person's right to seek a hearing on the matter before the Commissioner pursuant to this article, and the Commissioner determines, if requested in writing by such member of the family within 30 days of receipt of such notice from the franchisor, and after a hearing on the matter before the Commissioner pursuant to this article, that the failure to permit or honor the succession is unreasonable under the circumstances. No member of the family may succeed to a franchise unless (i) the franchisor has been given written notice as to the identity, financial ability, and qualifications of the member of the family in question and (ii) the succession to the franchise will not involve, without the franchisor's consent, a relocation of the business.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_9"/><heading><desig>9.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> To fail to ship monthly to any dealer, if ordered by the dealer, the number of new trailers of each make, series, and model needed by the dealer to receive a percentage of total new trailer sales of each make, series, and model equitably related to the total new trailer production or importation currently being achieved nationally by each make, series, and model covered under the franchise. Upon the written request of any dealer holding its sales or sales and service franchise, the manufacturer or distributor shall disclose to the dealer in writing the basis upon which new trailers are allocated, scheduled, and delivered to the dealers of the same line-make. If allocation is at issue in a request for a hearing, the dealer may demand the Commissioner to direct that the manufacturer or distributor provide to the dealer, within 30 days of such demand, all records of sales and all records of distribution of all trailers to the same line-make dealers who compete with the dealer requesting the hearing.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_10"/><heading><desig>10.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> To require or otherwise coerce a dealer to underutilize the dealer's facilities.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_11"/><heading><desig>11.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> To include in any franchise with a trailer dealer terms that are contrary to, prohibited by, or otherwise inconsistent with the requirements of this chapter.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_12"/><heading><desig>12.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> To require under any franchise agreement a trailer dealer to pay the attorney fees of the manufacturer or distributor related to hearings and appeals brought under this article.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_13"/><heading><desig>13.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> To fail to include in any franchise with a trailer dealer the following language: "If any provision herein contravenes the laws or regulations of any state or other jurisdiction wherein this agreement is to be performed, or denies access to the procedures, forums, or remedies provided for by such laws or regulations, such provision shall be deemed to be modified to conform to such laws or regulations, and all other terms and provisions shall remain in full force," or words to that effect.</p></bodyText></level></level><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p><citation normalizedCite="1996 VA CH 1043"><content><span normalizedCite="1996 Va. Ch. 1043">1996, cc. 1043<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1996#001043#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1996 VA CH 1052"><content><span normalizedCite="1996 Va. Ch. 1052">1052<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1996#001052#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, § 46.2-1992.69; <citation normalizedCite="2015 VA CH 615"><content><span normalizedCite="2015 Va. Ch. 615">2015, c. 615<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2015#000615#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PWC0-004G-K32F-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 46.2.</desig><title>MOTOR VEHICLES</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="subtitle"><heading><desig>SUBTITLE IV.</desig><title>DEALERS AND DRIVER TRAINING SCHOOLS</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 15.</desig><title>MOTOR VEHICLE DEALERS</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="article"><heading><desig>ARTICLE 7.3.</desig><title>TRAILER FRANCHISES.</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjA4OEVGODBENzY4NDcxM0IyQzA1OTEwQzVDODRBOUE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Assignments &amp; Transfers</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OUUzQ0IwQzJGMzA1NEJERDhGMkRCQjRGQjBEQTAwNEQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NTRDNjY1QjAxNkE5NDlERThCNjhFRTg4RjdCMTkzRTk</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OTJGRjkyRTUzRkNBNEQwREIxNEFEN0RBNDI2MUY4Njc7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RTJBRjkwRkE2Qzg2NDNBQzhFODJEN0I1M0JGNjZCMzU</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Good Cause</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RTU2RTZBM0Q1RTExNEU2NThGNTMxRTNDMzFGNDI4MzA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RTJBRjkwRkE2Qzg2NDNBQzhFODJEN0I1M0JGNjZCMzU</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Grounds</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFCOEE2MTc4OUMxNEY0Mzg4RkU4RTM2OTRCMzVCNTM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RTJBRjkwRkE2Qzg2NDNBQzhFODJEN0I1M0JGNjZCMzU</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Notice Requirements</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RUI3NDJBQjFCN0EwNDYxMUFDMDI3NUY5M0VCMzExNDU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RTJBRjkwRkE2Qzg2NDNBQzhFODJEN0I1M0JGNjZCMzU</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Tax Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OTNEM0E2OEE0RkQyNEY1MDhBQzdGMkQ4ODI4QTJDODE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Franchise, Trade Name &amp; Trademark Transfers</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QTU5MDAzMjJFMDk3NDM0Rjk4NUJBQjE2Q0NBNEYyMjM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NzFFNkI2OUQzQUQ5NDU1QkI5MzRCNkUxQzk1MTRBN0U</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification><classificationGroup classificationScheme="indexing-terms"><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem score="90"><className>Transportation</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RTYzRTk5RDVBQkQ2NDcwQzk2NTU3ODQ5OEE3NDlBNzk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></classificationGroup></metadata></legislativeDoc>