<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#349#000063#     2#         1509#">Va. Code Ann. § 63.2-1509</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_63.2-1509"/><heading><desig>§ 63.2-1509.</desig><title>Requirement that certain injuries to children be reported by physicians, nurses, teachers, etc.; penalty for failure to report</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a"/><heading><desig>A.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The following persons who, in their professional or official capacity, have reason to suspect that a child is an abused or neglected child, shall report the matter immediately to the local department of the county or city wherein the child resides or wherein the abuse or neglect is believed to have occurred or to the Department's toll-free child abuse and neglect hotline:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Any person licensed to practice medicine or any of the healing arts;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Any hospital resident or intern, and any person employed in the nursing profession;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Any person employed as a social worker or family-services specialist;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_4"/><heading><desig>4.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Any probation officer;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_5"/><heading><desig>5.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Any teacher or other person employed in a public or private school, kindergarten or nursery school;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_6"/><heading><desig>6.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Any person providing full-time or part-time child care for pay on a regularly planned basis;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_7"/><heading><desig>7.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Any mental health professional;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_8"/><heading><desig>8.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Any law-enforcement officer or animal control officer;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_9"/><heading><desig>9.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Any mediator eligible to receive court referrals pursuant to <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 8.01-576.8"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 8.01-576.8">§ 8.01-576.8<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000008#    01#        576.8#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_10"/><heading><desig>10.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Any professional staff person, not previously enumerated, employed by a private or state-operated hospital, institution or facility to which children have been committed or where children have been placed for care and treatment;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_11"/><heading><desig>11.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Any person 18 years of age or older associated with or employed by any public or private organization responsible for the care, custody or control of children;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_12"/><heading><desig>12.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Any person who is designated a court-appointed special advocate pursuant to Article 5 (<citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 9.1-151"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 9.1-151">§ 9.1-151<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000009#     1#          151#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> et seq.) of Chapter 1 of Title 9.1;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_13"/><heading><desig>13.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Any person 18 years of age or older who has received training approved by the Department of Social Services for the purposes of recognizing and reporting child abuse and neglect;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_14"/><heading><desig>14.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Any person employed by a local department as defined in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 63.2-100"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 63.2-100">§ 63.2-100<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000063#     2#          100#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> who determines eligibility for public assistance;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_15"/><heading><desig>15.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Any emergency medical services provider certified by the Board of Health pursuant to <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 32.1-111.5"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 32.1-111.5">§ 32.1-111.5<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000032#     1#        111.5#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, unless such provider immediately reports the matter directly to the attending physician at the hospital to which the child is transported, who shall make such report forthwith;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_16"/><heading><desig>16.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Any athletic coach, director or other person 18 years of age or older employed by or volunteering with a private sports organization or team;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_17"/><heading><desig>17.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Administrators or employees 18 years of age or older of public or private day camps, youth centers and youth recreation programs; and</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_18"/><heading><desig>18.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Any person employed by a public or private institution of higher education other than an attorney who is employed by a public or private institution of higher education as it relates to information gained in the course of providing legal representation to a client.</p><p>This subsection shall not apply to any regular minister, priest, rabbi, imam, or duly accredited practitioner of any religious organization or denomination usually referred to as a church as it relates to (i) information required by the doctrine of the religious organization or denomination to be kept in a confidential manner or (ii) information that would be subject to <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 8.01-400"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 8.01-400">§ 8.01-400<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000008#    01#          400#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> or <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 19.2-271.3"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 19.2-271.3">19.2-271.3<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000019#     2#        271.3#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> if offered as evidence in court.</p><p>If neither the locality in which the child resides nor where the abuse or neglect is believed to have occurred is known, then such report shall be made to the local department of the county or city where the abuse or neglect was discovered or to the Department's toll-free child abuse and neglect hotline.</p><p>If an employee of the local department is suspected of abusing or neglecting a child, the report shall be made to the court of the county or city where the abuse or neglect was discovered. Upon receipt of such a report by the court, the judge shall assign the report to a local department that is not the employer of the suspected employee for investigation or family assessment. The judge may consult with the Department in selecting a local department to respond to the report or the complaint.</p><p>If the information is received by a teacher, staff member, resident, intern or nurse in the course of professional services in a hospital, school or similar institution, such person may, in place of said report, immediately notify the person in charge of the institution or department, or his designee, who shall make such report forthwith. If the initial report of suspected abuse or neglect is made to the person in charge of the institution or department, or his designee, pursuant to this subsection, such person shall notify the teacher, staff member, resident, intern or nurse who made the initial report when the report of suspected child abuse or neglect is made to the local department or to the Department's toll-free child abuse and neglect hotline, and of the name of the individual receiving the report, and shall forward any communication resulting from the report, including any information about any actions taken regarding the report, to the person who made the initial report.</p><p>The initial report may be an oral report but such report shall be reduced to writing by the child abuse coordinator of the local department on a form prescribed by the Board. Any person required to make the report pursuant to this subsection shall disclose all information that is the basis for his suspicion of abuse or neglect of the child and, upon request, shall make available to the child-protective services coordinator and the local department, which is the agency of jurisdiction, any information, records, or reports that document the basis for the report. All persons required by this subsection to report suspected abuse or neglect who maintain a record of a child who is the subject of such a report shall cooperate with the investigating agency and shall make related information, records and reports available to the investigating agency unless such disclosure violates the federal Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="20 USC 1232G"><content><span normalizedCite="20 U.S.C. 1232G">(20 U.S.C. § 1232g).<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1828#123#000020#      1232g#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> Provision of such information, records, and reports by a health care provider shall not be prohibited by <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 8.01-399"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 8.01-399">§ 8.01-399<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000008#    01#          399#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>. Criminal investigative reports received from law-enforcement agencies shall not be further disseminated by the investigating agency nor shall they be subject to public disclosure.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b"/><heading><desig>B.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> For purposes of subsection A, "reason to suspect that a child is abused or neglected" shall include (i) a finding made by a health care provider within six weeks of the birth of a child that the results of toxicology studies of the child indicate the presence of a controlled substance not prescribed for the mother by a physician; (ii) a finding made by a health care provider within six weeks of the birth of a child that the child was born dependent on a controlled substance which was not prescribed by a physician for the mother and has demonstrated withdrawal symptoms; (iii) a diagnosis made by a health care provider at any time following a child's birth that the child has an illness, disease or condition which, to a reasonable degree of medical certainty, is attributable to in utero exposure to a controlled substance which was not prescribed by a physician for the mother or the child; or (iv) a diagnosis made by a health care provider at any time following a child's birth that the child has a fetal alcohol spectrum disorder attributable to in utero exposure to alcohol. When "reason to suspect" is based upon this subsection, such fact shall be included in the report along with the facts relied upon by the person making the report.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c"/><heading><desig>C.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Any person who makes a report or provides records or information pursuant to subsection A or who testifies in any judicial proceeding arising from such report, records, or information shall be immune from any civil or criminal liability or administrative penalty or sanction on account of such report, records, information, or testimony, unless such person acted in bad faith or with malicious purpose.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d"/><heading><desig>D.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Any person required to file a report pursuant to this section who fails to do so as soon as possible, but not longer than 24 hours after having reason to suspect a reportable offense of child abuse or neglect, shall be fined not more than $ 500 for the first failure and for any subsequent failures not less than $ 1,000. In cases evidencing acts of rape, sodomy, or object sexual penetration as defined in Article 7 (<citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 18.2-61"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 18.2-61">§ 18.2-61<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000018#     2#           61#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> et seq.) of Chapter 4 of Title 18.2, a person who knowingly and intentionally fails to make the report required pursuant to this section shall be guilty of a Class 1 misdemeanor.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_e"/><heading><desig>E.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> No person shall be required to make a report pursuant to this section if the person has actual knowledge that the same matter has already been reported to the local department or the Department's toll-free child abuse and neglect hotline.</p></bodyText></level><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p>1975, c. 341, § 63.1-248.3; 1976, c. 348; 1978, c. 747; <citation normalizedCite="1993 VA CH 443"><content><span normalizedCite="1993 Va. Ch. 443">1993, c. 443<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1993#000443#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1994 VA CH 840"><content><span normalizedCite="1994 Va. Ch. 840">1994, c. 840<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1994#000840#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1995 VA CH 810"><content><span normalizedCite="1995 Va. Ch. 810">1995, c. 810<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1995#000810#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1998 VA CH 704"><content><span normalizedCite="1998 Va. Ch. 704">1998, cc. 704<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1998#000704#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1998 VA CH 716"><content><span normalizedCite="1998 Va. Ch. 716">716<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1998#000716#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1999 VA CH 606"><content><span normalizedCite="1999 Va. Ch. 606">1999, c. 606<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1999#000606#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2000 VA CH 500"><content><span normalizedCite="2000 Va. Ch. 500">2000, c. 500<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2000#000500#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2001 VA CH 853"><content><span normalizedCite="2001 Va. Ch. 853">2001, c. 853<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2001#000853#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2002 VA CH 747"><content><span normalizedCite="2002 Va. Ch. 747">2002, cc. 747<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2002#000747#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2002 VA CH 860"><content><span normalizedCite="2002 Va. Ch. 860">860<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2002#000860#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2006 VA CH 530"><content><span normalizedCite="2006 Va. Ch. 530">2006, cc. 530<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2006#000530#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2006 VA CH 801"><content><span normalizedCite="2006 Va. Ch. 801">801<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2006#000801#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2008 VA CH 43"><content><span normalizedCite="2008 Va. Ch. 43">2008, cc. 43<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2008#000043#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2008 VA CH 268"><content><span normalizedCite="2008 Va. Ch. 268">268<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2008#000268#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2012 VA CH 391"><content><span normalizedCite="2012 Va. Ch. 391">2012, cc. 391<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2012#000391#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2012 VA CH 504"><content><span normalizedCite="2012 Va. Ch. 504">504<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2012#000504#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2012 VA CH 640"><content><span normalizedCite="2012 Va. Ch. 640">640<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2012#000640#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2012 VA CH 698"><content><span normalizedCite="2012 Va. Ch. 698">698<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2012#000698#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2012 VA CH 728"><content><span normalizedCite="2012 Va. Ch. 728">728<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2012#000728#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2012 VA CH 740"><content><span normalizedCite="2012 Va. Ch. 740">740<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2012#000740#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2012 VA CH 815"><content><span normalizedCite="2012 Va. Ch. 815">815<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2012#000815#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2013 VA CH 72"><content><span normalizedCite="2013 Va. Ch. 72">2013, cc. 72<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2013#000072#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2013 VA CH 331"><content><span normalizedCite="2013 Va. Ch. 331">331<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2013#000331#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2014 VA CH 285"><content><span normalizedCite="2014 Va. Ch. 285">2014, c. 285<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2014#000285#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PVJ0-004G-K11D-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 63.2.</desig><title>WELFARE (SOCIAL SERVICES)</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="subtitle"><heading><desig>SUBTITLE III.</desig><title>SOCIAL SERVICES PROGRAMS</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 15.</desig><title>CHILD ABUSE AND NEGLECT</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="article"><heading><desig>ARTICLE 2.</desig><title>COMPLAINTS</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Criminal Law &amp; Procedure</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NEU0RkE1OUQwNUQwNDgxODhEODZCMjkzOTg3NThBNzk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Elements</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MEFGQzU4MUJCNUNFNDA5QkJFMThBMEQ1QkJGM0VEQkQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDgzMDZDQ0YyRTM1NDcxRDhFQkU4NTQyMjFGNkFBOEI</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OEQ2QjlGNTc0QkU3NEFDQTkzN0Q1QjgxNUYwMUMzQ0Y7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NjE5MEI0RUExOTZENDdFM0EwQTlFMjYyMkQzNkM0OEQ</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Reporting Requirements</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RjM5QjFERTJBQUZCNDY2Mzk0MzdEQkMwREY2ODI3Q0M7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDgzMDZDQ0YyRTM1NDcxRDhFQkU4NTQyMjFGNkFBOEI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Education Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDkzNUEzQzFBNEZBNEFBREIxNDM5MTc1MUU5QjI4MTY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Disclosure &amp; Release</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RkE5MUVCNzdBNzc2NERCN0E2NjkzNDI3M0JGOUVFREQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RUJEOTY3MTE2NDdBNDQ3RkFFNkE0NDhENEMwMUM0M0I</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Statutory Duties</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RDM1NjA2MEI1Q0E2NDIwNDhEQzY4NTdFQzM4RDMwNzg7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QzYyMEY0Njc5M0VDNDc4RTg5REYxODcwOEVDQTBFNUE</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Family Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NEI4M0U5Qzg3RTk0NDdBRUJGNDRGNkZEQkU3RDdFNDU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Abuse, Endangerment &amp; Neglect</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OEI5RTc4NDg3RDY5NDM4Qzg2RkZFRDk0QTI2REFGNUI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RkE2MkE5MTUwMzk5NEJFN0E5RUFCRUIyNDg3RkU4Rjc</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Q0RCREM3QzU5OEVDNDlEM0FGRDgxQkQwRTFBOEREQzU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6N0UzRjg5QjhFNTdFNDQ3N0FEMUY0NTVEQkEzQ0M2RTA</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6REI1MDI3OTE1NDZENDYzRjlCNDgyNzFEMDc3MDNFQUE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RkE2MkE5MTUwMzk5NEJFN0E5RUFCRUIyNDg3RkU4Rjc</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Torts</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDAwOEM2NTEzQkVDNEI4NzlGMEZERUEyRjQwODM4Njg7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MkQwMTc0MUU5MzkxNEMwQzhEQkU0QjA2REQzQzNGMTc7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RjMzQjNFQ0U1MDdFNEQzMjg0MTA0MTY4MUZCQTZBM0U</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification><classificationGroup classificationScheme="indexing-terms"><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem score="90"><className>Public Health &amp; Welfare</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDYwRTY1MDg3MTk5NDUyNkFFRDI1RjJBRERGQ0UxNzI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></classificationGroup></metadata></legislativeDoc>