<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#349#000015#     2#         2286#">Va. Code Ann. § 15.2-2286</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_15.2-2286"/><heading><desig>§ 15.2-2286.</desig><title>Permitted provisions in zoning ordinances; amendments; applicant to pay delinquent taxes; penalties</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a"/><heading><desig>A.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A zoning ordinance may include, among other things, reasonable regulations and provisions as to any or all of the following matters:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> For variances or special exceptions, as defined in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 15.2-2201"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 15.2-2201">§ 15.2-2201<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000015#     2#         2201#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, to the general regulations in any district.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> For the temporary application of the ordinance to any property coming into the territorial jurisdiction of the governing body by annexation or otherwise, subsequent to the adoption of the zoning ordinance, and pending the orderly amendment of the ordinance.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> For the granting of special exceptions under suitable regulations and safeguards; notwithstanding any other provisions of this article, the governing body of any locality may reserve unto itself the right to issue such special exceptions. Conditions imposed in connection with residential special use permits, wherein the applicant proposes affordable housing, shall be consistent with the objective of providing affordable housing. When imposing conditions on residential projects specifying materials and methods of construction or specific design features, the approving body shall consider the impact of the conditions upon the affordability of housing.</p><p><pre/>The governing body or the board of zoning appeals of the City of Norfolk may impose a condition upon any special exception relating to retail alcoholic beverage control licensees which provides that such special exception will automatically expire upon a change of ownership of the property, a change in possession, a change in the operation or management of a facility or upon the passage of a specific period of time.</p><p><pre/>The governing body of the City of Richmond may impose a condition upon any special use permit issued after July 1, 2000, relating to retail alcoholic beverage licensees which provides that such special use permit shall be subject to an automatic review by the governing body upon a change in possession, a change in the owner of the business, or a transfer of majority control of the business entity. Upon review by the governing body, it may either amend or revoke the special use permit after notice and a public hearing as required by <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 15.2-2206"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 15.2-2206">§ 15.2-2206<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000015#     2#         2206#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_4"/><heading><desig>4.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> For the administration and enforcement of the ordinance including the appointment or designation of a zoning administrator who may also hold another office in the locality. The zoning administrator shall have all necessary authority on behalf of the governing body to administer and enforce the zoning ordinance. His authority shall include (i) ordering in writing the remedying of any condition found in violation of the ordinance; (ii) insuring compliance with the ordinance, bringing legal action, including injunction, abatement, or other appropriate action or proceeding subject to appeal pursuant to <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 15.2-2311"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 15.2-2311">§ 15.2-2311<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000015#     2#         2311#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; and (iii) in specific cases, making findings of fact and, with concurrence of the attorney for the governing body, conclusions of law regarding determinations of rights accruing under § 15.2-2307 or subsection C of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 15.2-2311"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 15.2-2311">§ 15.2-2311<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000015#     2#         2311#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p><p><pre/>Whenever the zoning administrator has reasonable cause to believe that any person has engaged in or is engaging in any violation of a zoning ordinance that limits occupancy in a residential dwelling unit, which is subject to a civil penalty that may be imposed in accordance with the provisions of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 15.2-2209"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 15.2-2209">§ 15.2-2209<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000015#     2#         2209#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, and the zoning administrator, after a good faith effort to obtain the data or information necessary to determine whether a violation has occurred, has been unable to obtain such information, he may request that the attorney for the locality petition the judge of the general district court for his jurisdiction for a subpoena duces tecum against any such person refusing to produce such data or information. The judge of the court, upon good cause shown, may cause the subpoena to be issued. Any person failing to comply with such subpoena shall be subject to punishment for contempt by the court issuing the subpoena. Any person so subpoenaed may apply to the judge who issued the subpoena to quash it.</p><p><pre/>Notwithstanding the provisions of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 15.2-2311"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 15.2-2311">§ 15.2-2311<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000015#     2#         2311#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, a zoning ordinance may prescribe an appeal period of less than 30 days, but not less than 10 days, for a notice of violation involving temporary or seasonal commercial uses, parking of commercial trucks in residential zoning districts, maximum occupancy limitations of a residential dwelling unit, or similar short-term, recurring violations.</p><p><pre/>Where provided by ordinance, the zoning administrator may be authorized to grant a modification from any provision contained in the zoning ordinance with respect to physical requirements on a lot or parcel of land, including but not limited to size, height, location or features of or related to any building, structure, or improvements, if the administrator finds in writing that: (i) the strict application of the ordinance would produce undue hardship; (ii) such hardship is not shared generally by other properties in the same zoning district and the same vicinity; and (iii) the authorization of the modification will not be of substantial detriment to adjacent property and the character of the zoning district will not be changed by the granting of the modification. Prior to the granting of a modification, the zoning administrator shall give, or require the applicant to give, all adjoining property owners written notice of the request for modification, and an opportunity to respond to the request within 21 days of the date of the notice. The zoning administrator shall make a decision on the application for modification and issue a written decision with a copy provided to the applicant and any adjoining landowner who responded in writing to the notice sent pursuant to this paragraph. The decision of the zoning administrator shall constitute a decision within the purview of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 15.2-2311"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 15.2-2311">§ 15.2-2311<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000015#     2#         2311#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, and may be appealed to the board of zoning appeals as provided by that section. Decisions of the board of zoning appeals may be appealed to the circuit court as provided by <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 15.2-2314"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 15.2-2314">§ 15.2-2314<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000015#     2#         2314#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p><p><pre/>The zoning administrator shall respond within 90 days of a request for a decision or determination on zoning matters within the scope of his authority unless the requester has agreed to a longer period.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_5"/><heading><desig>5.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> For the imposition of penalties upon conviction of any violation of the zoning ordinance. Any such violation shall be a misdemeanor punishable by a fine of not less than $ 10 nor more than $ 1,000. If the violation is uncorrected at the time of the conviction, the court shall order the violator to abate or remedy the violation in compliance with the zoning ordinance, within a time period established by the court. Failure to remove or abate a zoning violation within the specified time period shall constitute a separate misdemeanor offense punishable by a fine of not less than $ 10 nor more than $ 1,000, and any such failure during any succeeding 10-day period shall constitute a separate misdemeanor offense for each 10-day period punishable by a fine of not less than $ 100 nor more than $ 1,500.</p><p><pre/>However, any conviction resulting from a violation of provisions regulating the number of unrelated persons in single-family residential dwellings shall be punishable by a fine of up to $ 2,000. Failure to abate the violation within the specified time period shall be punishable by a fine of up to $ 5,000, and any such failure during any succeeding 10-day period shall constitute a separate misdemeanor offense for each 10-day period punishable by a fine of up to $ 7,500. However, no such fine shall accrue against an owner or managing agent of a single-family residential dwelling unit during the pendency of any legal action commenced by such owner or managing agent of such dwelling unit against a tenant to eliminate an overcrowding condition in accordance with Chapter 13 or Chapter 13.2 of Title 55, as applicable. A conviction resulting from a violation of provisions regulating the number of unrelated persons in single-family residential dwellings shall not be punishable by a jail term.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_6"/><heading><desig>6.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> For the collection of fees to cover the cost of making inspections, issuing permits, advertising of notices and other expenses incident to the administration of a zoning ordinance or to the filing or processing of any appeal or amendment thereto.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_7"/><heading><desig>7.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> For the amendment of the regulations or district maps from time to time, or for their repeal. Whenever the public necessity, convenience, general welfare, or good zoning practice requires, the governing body may by ordinance amend, supplement, or change the regulations, district boundaries, or classifications of property. Any such amendment may be initiated (i) by resolution of the governing body; (ii) by motion of the local planning commission; or (iii) by petition of the owner, contract purchaser with the owner's written consent, or the owner's agent therefor, of the property which is the subject of the proposed zoning map amendment, addressed to the governing body or the local planning commission, who shall forward such petition to the governing body; however, the ordinance may provide for the consideration of proposed amendments only at specified intervals of time, and may further provide that substantially the same petition will not be reconsidered within a specific period, not exceeding one year. Any such resolution or motion by such governing body or commission proposing the rezoning shall state the above public purposes therefor.</p><p><pre/>In any county having adopted such zoning ordinance, all motions, resolutions or petitions for amendment to the zoning ordinance, and/or map shall be acted upon and a decision made within such reasonable time as may be necessary which shall not exceed 12 months unless the applicant requests or consents to action beyond such period or unless the applicant withdraws his motion, resolution or petition for amendment to the zoning ordinance or map, or both. In the event of and upon such withdrawal, processing of the motion, resolution or petition shall cease without further action as otherwise would be required by this subdivision.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_8"/><heading><desig>8.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> For the submission and approval of a plan of development prior to the issuance of building permits to assure compliance with regulations contained in such zoning ordinance.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_9"/><heading><desig>9.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> For areas and districts designated for mixed use developments or planned unit developments as defined in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 15.2-2201"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 15.2-2201">§ 15.2-2201<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000015#     2#         2201#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_10"/><heading><desig>10.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> For the administration of incentive zoning as defined in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 15.2-2201"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 15.2-2201">§ 15.2-2201<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000015#     2#         2201#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_11"/><heading><desig>11.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> For provisions allowing the locality to enter into a voluntary agreement with a landowner that would result in the downzoning of the landowner's undeveloped or underdeveloped property in exchange for a tax credit equal to the amount of excess real estate taxes that the landowner has paid due to the higher zoning classification. The locality may establish reasonable guidelines for determining the amount of excess real estate tax collected and the method and duration for applying the tax credit. For purposes of this section, "downzoning" means a zoning action by a locality that results in a reduction in a formerly permitted land use intensity or density.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_12"/><heading><desig>12.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Provisions for requiring and considering Phase I environmental site assessments based on the anticipated use of the property proposed for the subdivision or development that meet generally accepted national standards for such assessments, such as those developed by the American Society for Testing and Materials, and Phase II environmental site assessments, that also meet accepted national standards, such as, but not limited to, those developed by the American Society for Testing and Materials, if the locality deems such to be reasonably necessary, based on findings in the Phase I assessment, and in accordance with regulations of the United States Environmental Protection Agency and the American Society for Testing and Materials. A reasonable fee may be charged for the review of such environmental assessments. Such fees shall not exceed an amount commensurate with the services rendered, taking into consideration the time, skill, and administrative expense involved in such review.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_13"/><heading><desig>13.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Provisions for requiring disclosure and remediation of contamination and other adverse environmental conditions of the property prior to approval of subdivision and development plans.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_14"/><heading><desig>14.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> For the enforcement of provisions of the zoning ordinance that regulate the number of persons permitted to occupy a single-family residential dwelling unit, provided such enforcement is in compliance with applicable local, state and federal fair housing laws.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_15"/><heading><desig>15.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> For the issuance of inspection warrants by a magistrate or court of competent jurisdiction. The zoning administrator or his agent may make an affidavit under oath before a magistrate or court of competent jurisdiction and, if such affidavit establishes probable cause that a zoning ordinance violation has occurred, request that the magistrate or court grant the zoning administrator or his agent an inspection warrant to enable the zoning administrator or his agent to enter the subject dwelling for the purpose of determining whether violations of the zoning ordinance exist. After issuing a warrant under this section, the magistrate or judge shall file the affidavit in the manner prescribed by <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 19.2-54"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 19.2-54">§ 19.2-54<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000019#     2#           54#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>. After executing the warrant, the zoning administrator or his agents shall return the warrant to the clerk of the circuit court of the city or county wherein the inspection was made. The zoning administrator or his agent shall make a reasonable effort to obtain consent from the owner or tenant of the subject dwelling prior to seeking the issuance of an inspection warrant under this section.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b"/><heading><desig>B.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Prior to the initiation of an application by the owner of the subject property, the owner's agent, or any entity in which the owner holds an ownership interest greater than 50 percent, for a special exception, special use permit, variance, rezoning or other land disturbing permit, including building permits and erosion and sediment control permits, or prior to the issuance of final approval, the authorizing body may require the applicant to produce satisfactory evidence that any delinquent real estate taxes, nuisance charges, stormwater management utility fees, and any other charges that constitute a lien on the subject property, that are owed to the locality and have been properly assessed against the subject property, have been paid.</p></bodyText></level><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p>Code 1950, § 15-968.5; 1962, c. 407, § 15.1-491; 1964, c. 564; 1966, c. 455; 1968, cc. 543, 595; 1973, c. 286; 1974, c. 547; 1975, cc. 99, 575, 579, 582, 641; 1976, cc. 71, 409, 470, 683; 1977, c. 177; 1978, c. 543; 1979, c. 182; 1982, c. 44; 1983, c. 392; 1984, c. 238; 1987, c. 8; 1988, cc. 481, 856; <citation normalizedCite="1989 VA CH 359"><content><span normalizedCite="1989 Va. Ch. 359">1989, cc. 359<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1989#000359#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1989 VA CH 384"><content><span normalizedCite="1989 Va. Ch. 384">384<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1989#000384#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1990 VA CH 672"><content><span normalizedCite="1990 Va. Ch. 672">1990, cc. 672<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1990#000672#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1990 VA CH 868"><content><span normalizedCite="1990 Va. Ch. 868">868<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1990#000868#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1992 VA CH 380"><content><span normalizedCite="1992 Va. Ch. 380">1992, c. 380<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1992#000380#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1993 VA CH 672"><content><span normalizedCite="1993 Va. Ch. 672">1993, c. 672<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1993#000672#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1994 VA CH 802"><content><span normalizedCite="1994 Va. Ch. 802">1994, c. 802<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1994#000802#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1995 VA CH 351"><content><span normalizedCite="1995 Va. Ch. 351">1995, cc. 351<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1995#000351#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1995 VA CH 475"><content><span normalizedCite="1995 Va. Ch. 475">475<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1995#000475#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1995 VA CH 584"><content><span normalizedCite="1995 Va. Ch. 584">584<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1995#000584#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1995 VA CH 603"><content><span normalizedCite="1995 Va. Ch. 603">603<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1995#000603#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1996 VA CH 451"><content><span normalizedCite="1996 Va. Ch. 451">1996, c. 451<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1996#000451#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1997 VA CH 529"><content><span normalizedCite="1997 Va. Ch. 529">1997, cc. 529<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1997#000529#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1997 VA CH 543"><content><span normalizedCite="1997 Va. Ch. 543">543<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1997#000543#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1997 VA CH 587"><content><span normalizedCite="1997 Va. Ch. 587">587<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1997#000587#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1998 VA CH 385"><content><span normalizedCite="1998 Va. Ch. 385">1998, c. 385<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1998#000385#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1999 VA CH 792"><content><span normalizedCite="1999 Va. Ch. 792">1999, c. 792<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1999#000792#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2000 VA CH 764"><content><span normalizedCite="2000 Va. Ch. 764">2000, cc. 764<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2000#000764#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2000 VA CH 817"><content><span normalizedCite="2000 Va. Ch. 817">817<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2000#000817#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2001 VA CH 240"><content><span normalizedCite="2001 Va. Ch. 240">2001, c. 240<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2001#000240#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2002 VA CH 547"><content><span normalizedCite="2002 Va. Ch. 547">2002, cc. 547<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2002#000547#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2002 VA CH 703"><content><span normalizedCite="2002 Va. Ch. 703">703<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2002#000703#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2005 VA CH 625"><content><span normalizedCite="2005 Va. Ch. 625">2005, cc. 625<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2005#000625#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2005 VA CH 677"><content><span normalizedCite="2005 Va. Ch. 677">677<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2005#000677#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2006 VA CH 304"><content><span normalizedCite="2006 Va. Ch. 304">2006, cc. 304<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2006#000304#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2006 VA CH 514"><content><span normalizedCite="2006 Va. Ch. 514">514<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2006#000514#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2006 VA CH 533"><content><span normalizedCite="2006 Va. Ch. 533">533<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2006#000533#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2006 VA CH 903"><content><span normalizedCite="2006 Va. Ch. 903">903<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2006#000903#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2007 VA CH 821"><content><span normalizedCite="2007 Va. Ch. 821">2007, cc. 821<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2007#000821#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2007 VA CH 937"><content><span normalizedCite="2007 Va. Ch. 937">937<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2007#000937#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2008 VA CH 297"><content><span normalizedCite="2008 Va. Ch. 297">2008, cc. 297<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2008#000297#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2008 VA CH 317"><content><span normalizedCite="2008 Va. Ch. 317">317<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2008#000317#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2008 VA CH 343"><content><span normalizedCite="2008 Va. Ch. 343">343<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2008#000343#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2008 VA CH 581"><content><span normalizedCite="2008 Va. Ch. 581">581<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2008#000581#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2008 VA CH 593"><content><span normalizedCite="2008 Va. Ch. 593">593<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2008#000593#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2008 VA CH 720"><content><span normalizedCite="2008 Va. Ch. 720">720<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2008#000720#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2008 VA CH 777"><content><span normalizedCite="2008 Va. Ch. 777">777<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2008#000777#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2009 VA CH 721"><content><span normalizedCite="2009 Va. Ch. 721">2009, c. 721<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2009#000721#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2012 VA CH 304"><content><span normalizedCite="2012 Va. Ch. 304">2012, cc. 304<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2012#000304#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2012 VA CH 318"><content><span normalizedCite="2012 Va. Ch. 318">318<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2012#000318#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2014 VA CH 354"><content><span normalizedCite="2014 Va. Ch. 354">2014, c. 354<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2014#000354#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PV00-004G-K0N9-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 15.2.</desig><title>COUNTIES, CITIES AND TOWNS</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="subtitle"><heading><desig>SUBTITLE II.</desig><title>POWERS OF LOCAL GOVERNMENT</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 22.</desig><title>PLANNING, SUBDIVISION OF LAND AND ZONING</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="article"><heading><desig>ARTICLE 7.</desig><title>ZONING</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Enforcement Actions</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QURFMDU2QkJBRUZENEJEOEFDM0Y5MDk1Rjg5MkIyQkQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NUIzQzREN0NDOEQ2NEJENUI1MDMyMzZGMENGQkFEMjc</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Civil Procedure</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MzUxNjJDMEQ5N0YwNDMzM0JDMjEzM0UzOTYzMzI3OTU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Subpoenas</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NUUwMEFDNDQyNkMyNDU2QzhBRDVDRTRBMUE5NzI3Q0Y7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6N0U4MkI2QTY1RDhFNEVBRjk4ODdGNjUwQ0RERjU0NjU</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Civil Rights Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NURDOUM5MEJFQUZGNEFBMDgzMkM0RTgwODdDNTMxREM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Enforcement Actions</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QURFMDU2QkJBRUZENEJEOEFDM0Y5MDk1Rjg5MkIyQkQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NUIzQzREN0NDOEQ2NEJENUI1MDMyMzZGMENGQkFEMjc</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Criminal Law &amp; Procedure</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NEU0RkE1OUQwNUQwNDgxODhEODZCMjkzOTg3NThBNzk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Fines</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NUY4M0RBNUNERDlGNEI1QUJFMDc4QzU5OTU4RjNDRTY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUIzQ0NGRDZERUU3NERCODg2MEZFMDI2RTI0RTA3RTc</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6ODYxRDY4Q0Q3OTVDNEU4MkI4ODI5RDUwMjM5NUFDOUY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NUVDOUNENjUwNEQ2NDBCREEzNUYyRTQzNDU0NEY3QzY</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Time Limitations</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Q0ZGNTQxRjIxNzUwNDYyQ0IyNEQ2NUUxMTNFQjExMDg7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OTc1RTJCQzAyOTFGNDE4MDg5NzhBNUMwMjQ3MjI5RjI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Environmental Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NzFDRDYyNkI2QjhBNDg3NTkyRjRDRkZEQjlCRkRBQzM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MkJDMzEzRDkxMDVBNDA3N0FDRjNDODI2NUIzMzZDMDQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjI3QUU4NUZEQzZFNEYzRThENkZBRTA1MkUyQTAwQTA</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Governments</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjdEQjE4OUJDMzQxNDNEMEI0RTI1QUFCMzJENjEwRTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Clerks of Court</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6REVFMjkzRDI1MkU2NERDNjk3OEUxODY0REYwMUI1NjE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NURENzJGNTEyQzM0NEREQUI2RkVCRTM4RTc1RTZBREU</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Finance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjMzOTBBRTg2MUVDNDdDNUE1M0QxNDk1RERCNjNCN0I7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Njg1MkM3RkYyNzIxNEVFRkJFMTI2NUM4NUU1ODdEM0Q</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OTkzODE2NDgzNzg2NDA0QUExMUI0RjZEOTg0QzEwQTk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Q0M3QUYzNjlBN0UzNEVBMDk4OEIyMzdBMDlGQzA2RjI</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Licenses</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QUQzRDFDRDE0OTA0NDU2OEIwMUZCNDZEQTBBODdCODA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Njg1MkM3RkYyNzIxNEVFRkJFMTI2NUM4NUU1ODdEM0Q</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Ordinances &amp; Regulations</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NjQ1MzRDRUY1OTZBNDRDNTlDODQzRDRCMUFCNDc2RTU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Njg1MkM3RkYyNzIxNEVFRkJFMTI2NUM4NUU1ODdEM0Q</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Real Property Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QUUyRTcxRURBNEY2NEE2MDk3QzBCNzRDOEY0NTZDQzk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Administrative Procedure</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDVEOThDRjUzNTFDNDc4NEE2OEYzQzEzRjU3REYxNDg7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NjcyQTdEMEUxODYyNDY0OThFQTg1NUNGMjFBMTkxQ0M</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Annexation</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RDg5RjQzMzIwRTBGNDhCNUE0NzFGOUI3RkU1OEI1Qzk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NjcyQTdEMEUxODYyNDY0OThFQTg1NUNGMjFBMTkxQ0M</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Building &amp; Housing Codes</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDZGNTdFRUIyNEQ2NDQ1QjlBMzEwRDQyOUZFRUFCRjM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NjcyQTdEMEUxODYyNDY0OThFQTg1NUNGMjFBMTkxQ0M</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Constitutional Limits</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Q0U1MkREMzg2NTAwNDQ2ODkzMDVBNDQwRjAwNERFRkI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NjcyQTdEMEUxODYyNDY0OThFQTg1NUNGMjFBMTkxQ0M</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RjBBQTVENjZENjJFNEEzNjlBRDE1QjZDRjQyM0FBNkM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NjcyQTdEMEUxODYyNDY0OThFQTg1NUNGMjFBMTkxQ0M</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Local Regulations</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NUE4NDYxMTk4MEI0NDlDODgyODIxNzBDMjAyOTZENkM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Nzg5NTlBMjdCREU3NDE1OTg1QjFCODExQkZENkM1Nzk</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Ordinances</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDYxNkVDMTk2RTI1NDg2NEJGRDFCN0I4Qjk4MEJFMkU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NjcyQTdEMEUxODYyNDY0OThFQTg1NUNGMjFBMTkxQ0M</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Planned Unit Developments</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6ODY2N0Y0QTEyQzhBNEYxNjg2MTNFNzQ3REJDNzhGOEU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NjcyQTdEMEUxODYyNDY0OThFQTg1NUNGMjFBMTkxQ0M</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Variances</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RkIxOThDMjUxN0JFNEEwNkI3MDNEMTA2NzdBMzU5REI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NjcyQTdEMEUxODYyNDY0OThFQTg1NUNGMjFBMTkxQ0M</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Tax Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OTNEM0E2OEE0RkQyNEY1MDhBQzdGMkQ4ODI4QTJDODE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QzQzNERBRTAxRDI0NDg4OUI1NzY1RjU4Q0IzRDVDODc7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjkxRkVDMkNDMjBGNDdFMkI1RDQ3Nzk4QjgwOTBGQjU</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MEMzQzdEM0Q2NEEyNDg5RDhDMEE3NDAwMDNGOUU2MkM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MEI0QjM4RDg1M0IxNDk1RDkwOTVGMEMxRTQxQTg1ODU</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RTc0QzJDRUM0OTI1NDkyQTgyQzExM0RFMDAwRTAzOEI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RUE2N0VFNDM5OUY4NENCQjlDQjQ1NjdGMkU4NkFFREQ</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification><classificationGroup classificationScheme="indexing-terms"><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem score="90"><className>Governments</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjdEQjE4OUJDMzQxNDNEMEI0RTI1QUFCMzJENjEwRTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></classificationGroup></metadata></legislativeDoc>