<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#123#000055#     79.54#">Va. Code Ann. § 55-79.54</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_55-79.54"/><heading><desig>§ 55-79.54.</desig><title>Contents of declaration</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a"/><heading><desig>(a)</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The declaration for every condominium shall contain the following:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_1"/><heading><desig>(1)</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The name of the condominium, which name shall include the word "condominium" or be followed by the words "a condominium."</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_2"/><heading><desig>(2)</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The name of the city or county in which the condominium is located.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_3"/><heading><desig>(3)</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A legal description by metes and bounds of the land submitted to this chapter.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_4"/><heading><desig>(4)</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A description or delineation of the boundaries of the units, including the horizontal (upper and lower) boundaries, if any, as well as the vertical (lateral or perimetric) boundaries.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_5"/><heading><desig>(5)</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A description or delineation of any limited common elements, other than those which are limited common elements by virtue of subsection (e) of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 55-79.50"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 55 -79.50">§ 55-79.50<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#123#000055#     79.50#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, showing or designating the unit or units to which each is assigned.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_6"/><heading><desig>(6)</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A description or delineation of all common elements not within the boundaries of any convertible lands which may subsequently be assigned as limited common elements, together with a statement that (i) they may be so assigned and a description of the method whereby any such assignments shall be made in accordance with the provisions of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 55-79.57"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 55 -79.57">§ 55-79.57<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#123#000055#     79.57#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> or (ii) once assigned, the conditions under which they may be unassigned and converted to common elements in accordance with <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 55-79.57"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 55 -79.57">§ 55-79.57.<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#123#000055#     79.57#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation></p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_7"/><heading><desig>(7)</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The allocation to each unit of an undivided interest in the common elements in accordance with the provisions of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 55-79.55"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 55 -79.55">§ 55-79.55.<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#123#000055#     79.55#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation></p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_7a"/><heading><desig>(7a)</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A statement of the extent of the declarant's obligation to complete improvements labeled "(NOT YET COMPLETED)" or to begin and complete improvements labeled "(NOT YET BEGUN)" on plats recorded pursuant to the requirements of this chapter. Such statement shall be specific as to the type and quality of materials to be used, the size or capacity of the improvements, when material, and the time by which such improvements shall be completed.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_8"/><heading><desig>(8)</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Such other matters as the declarant deems appropriate.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b"/><heading><desig>(b)</desig></heading><bodyText><p> If the condominium contains any convertible land, the declaration shall also contain the following:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_1"/><heading><desig>(1)</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A legal description by metes and bounds of each convertible land within the condominium.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_2"/><heading><desig>(2)</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A statement of the maximum number of units that may be created within each such convertible land.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_3"/><heading><desig>(3)</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A statement, with respect to each such convertible land, of the maximum percentage of the aggregate land and floor area of all units that may be created therein that may be occupied by units not restricted exclusively to residential use.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_4"/><heading><desig>(4)</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A statement of the extent to which any structure erected on any convertible land will be compatible with structures on other portions of the submitted land in terms of quality of construction, the principal materials to be used, and architectural style.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_5"/><heading><desig>(5)</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A description of all other improvements that may be made on each convertible land within the condominium.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_6"/><heading><desig>(6)</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A statement that any units created within each convertible land will be substantially identical to the units on other portions of the submitted land, or a statement describing in detail what other types of units may be created therein.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_7"/><heading><desig>(7)</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A description of the declarant's reserved right, if any, to create limited common elements within any convertible land, and/or to designate common elements therein which may subsequently be assigned as limited common elements, in terms of the types, sizes, and maximum number of such elements within each such convertible land.</p><p><pre/>Provided, that plats and plans may be recorded with the declaration and identified therein to supplement information furnished pursuant to items (1), (4), (5), (6), and (7), and that item (3) need not be complied with if none of the units on other portions of the submitted land are restricted exclusively to residential use.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c"/><heading><desig>(c)</desig></heading><bodyText><p> If the condominium is an expandable condominium, the declaration shall also contain the following:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c_1"/><heading><desig>(1)</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The explicit reservation of an option to expand the condominium.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c_2"/><heading><desig>(2)</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A statement of any limitations on that option, including, without limitation, a statement as to whether the consent of any unit owners shall be required, and if so, a statement as to the method whereby such consent shall be ascertained; or a statement that there are no such limitations.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c_3"/><heading><desig>(3)</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A time limit, not exceeding 10 years from the recording of the declaration, upon which the option to expand the condominium shall expire, together with a statement of the circumstances, if any, which will terminate that option prior to the expiration of the time limit so specified. After the expiration of any period of declarant control reserved pursuant to subsection A of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 55-79.74"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 55 -79.74">§ 55-79.74<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#123#000055#     79.74#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, such time limit may be extended by an amendment to the declaration made pursuant to <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 55-79.71"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 55 -79.71">§ 55-79.71.<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#123#000055#     79.71#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation></p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c_4"/><heading><desig>(4)</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A legal description by metes and bounds of all land that may be added to the condominium, henceforth referred to as "additional land."</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c_5"/><heading><desig>(5)</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A statement as to whether, if any of the additional land is added to the condominium, all of it or any particular portion of it must be added, and if not, a statement of any limitations as to what portions may be added or a statement that there are no such limitations.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c_6"/><heading><desig>(6)</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A statement as to whether portions of the additional land may be added to the condominium at different times, together with any limitations fixing the boundaries of those portions by legal descriptions setting forth the metes and bounds thereof and/or regulating the order in which they may be added to the condominium.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c_7"/><heading><desig>(7)</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A statement of any limitations as to the locations of any improvements that may be made on any portions of the additional land added to the condominium, or a statement that no assurances are made in that regard.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c_8"/><heading><desig>(8)</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A statement of the maximum number of units that may be created on the additional land. If portions of the additional land may be added to the condominium and the boundaries of those portions are fixed in accordance with item (6), the declaration shall also state the maximum number of units that may be created on each such portion added to the condominium. If portions of the additional land may be added to the condominium and the boundaries of those portions are not fixed in accordance with item (6), then the declaration shall also state the maximum number of units per acre that may be created on any such portion added to the condominium.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c_9"/><heading><desig>(9)</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A statement, with respect to the additional land and to any portion or portions thereof that may be added to the condominium, of the maximum percentage of the aggregate land and floor area of all units that may be created thereon that may be occupied by units not restricted exclusively to residential use.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c_10"/><heading><desig>(10)</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A statement of the extent to which any structures erected on any portion of the additional land added to the condominium will be compatible with structures on the submitted land in terms of quality of construction, the principal materials to be used, and architectural style, or a statement that no assurances are made in those regards.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c_11"/><heading><desig>(11)</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A description of all other improvements that will be made on any portion of the additional land added to the condominium, or a statement of any limitations as to what other improvements may be made thereon, or a statement that no assurances are made in that regard.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c_12"/><heading><desig>(12)</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A statement that any units created on any portion of the additional land added to the condominium will be substantially identical to the units on the submitted land, or a statement of any limitations as to what types of units may be created thereon, or a statement that no assurances are made in that regard.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c_13"/><heading><desig>(13)</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A description of the declarant's reserved right, if any, to create limited common elements within any portion of the additional land added to the condominium, and/or to designate common elements therein which may subsequently be assigned as limited common elements, in terms of the types, sizes, and maximum number of such elements within each such portion, or a statement that no assurances are made in those regards.</p><p><pre/>Provided, that plats and plans may be recorded with the declaration and identified therein to supplement information furnished pursuant to items (4), (5), (6), (7), (10), (11), (12), and (13), and that item (9) need not be complied with if none of the units on the submitted land are restricted exclusively to residential use.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d"/><heading><desig>(d)</desig></heading><bodyText><p> If the condominium is a contractable condominium, the declaration shall also contain the following:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d_1"/><heading><desig>(1)</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The explicit reservation of an option to contract the condominium.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d_2"/><heading><desig>(2)</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A statement of any limitations on that option, including, without limitation, a statement as to whether the consent of any unit owners shall be required, and if so, a statement as to the method whereby such consent shall be ascertained; or a statement that there are no such limitations.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d_3"/><heading><desig>(3)</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A time limit, not exceeding 10 years from the recording of the declaration, upon which the option to contract the condominium shall expire, together with a statement of the circumstances, if any, which will terminate that option prior to the expiration of the time limit so specified.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d_4"/><heading><desig>(4)</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A legal description by metes and bounds of all land that may be withdrawn from the condominium, henceforth referred to as "withdrawable land."</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d_5"/><heading><desig>(5)</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A statement as to whether portions of the withdrawable land may be withdrawn from the condominium at different times, together with any limitations fixing the boundaries of those portions by legal descriptions setting forth the metes and bounds thereof and/or regulating the order in which they may be withdrawn from the condominium.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d_6"/><heading><desig>(6)</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A legal description by metes and bounds of all of the submitted land to which the option to contract the condominium does not extend.</p><p><pre/>Provided, that plats may be recorded with the declaration and identified therein to supplement information furnished pursuant to items (4), (5), and (6), and that item (6) shall not be construed in derogation of any right the declarant may have to terminate the condominium in accordance with the provisions of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 55-79.72:1"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 55 -79.72:1">§ 55-79.72:1.<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#142#        55#     79.72#         1#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation></p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_e"/><heading><desig>(e)</desig></heading><bodyText><p> If the condominium is a leasehold condominium, then with respect to any ground lease or other leases the expiration or termination of which will or may terminate or contract the condominium, the declaration shall set forth the city or county wherein the same are recorded and the deed book and page number where the first page of each such lease is recorded; and the declaration shall also contain the following:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_e_1"/><heading><desig>(1)</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The date upon which each such lease is due to expire.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_e_2"/><heading><desig>(2)</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A statement as to whether any land and/or improvements will be owned by the unit owners in fee simple, and if so, either (a) a description of the same, including without limitation a legal description by metes and bounds of any such land, or (b) a statement of any rights the unit owners shall have to remove such improvements within a reasonable time after the expiration or termination of the lease or leases involved, or a statement that they shall have no such rights.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_e_3"/><heading><desig>(3)</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A statement of the rights the unit owners shall have to redeem the reversion or any of the reversions, or a statement that they shall have no such rights.</p><p><pre/>Provided, that after the recording of the declaration, no lessor who executed the same, and no successor in interest to such lessor, shall have any right or power to terminate any part of the leasehold interest of any unit owner who makes timely payment of his share of the rent to the person or persons designated in the declaration for the receipt of such rent and who otherwise complies with all covenants which, if violated, would entitle the lessor to terminate the lease. Acquisition or reacquisition of such a leasehold interest by the owner of the reversion or remainder shall not cause a merger of the leasehold and fee simple interests unless all leasehold interests in the condominium are thus acquired or reacquired.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_f"/><heading><desig>(f)</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Wherever this section requires a legal description by metes and bounds of land that is submitted to this chapter or that may be added to or withdrawn from the condominium, such requirement shall be deemed satisfied by any legally sufficient description and shall be deemed to require a legally sufficient description of any easements that are submitted to this chapter or that may be added to or withdrawn from the condominium, as the case may be. In the case of each such easement, the declaration shall contain the following:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_f_1"/><heading><desig>(1)</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A description of the permitted use or uses.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_f_2"/><heading><desig>(2)</desig></heading><bodyText><p> If less than all of those entitled to the use of all of the units may utilize such easement, a statement of the relevant restrictions and limitations on utilization.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_f_3"/><heading><desig>(3)</desig></heading><bodyText><p> If any persons other than those entitled to the use of the units may utilize such easement, a statement of the rights of others to utilization of the same.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_g"/><heading><desig>(g)</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Wherever this section requires a legal description by metes and bounds of land that is submitted to this chapter or that may be added to or withdrawn from the condominium, an added requirement shall be a separate legally sufficient description of all lands in which the unit owners shall or may be tenants in common or joint tenants with any other persons, and a separate legally sufficient description of all lands in which the unit owners shall or may be life tenants. No units shall be situated on any such lands, however, and the declaration shall describe the nature of the unit owners' estate therein. No such lands shall be shown on the same plat or plats showing other portions of the condominium, but shall be shown instead on separate plats.</p></bodyText></level><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p>1974, c. 416; 1975, c. 415; 1977, c. 428; 1982, c. 545; <citation normalizedCite="1993 VA CH 667"><content><span normalizedCite="1993 Va. Ch. 667">1993, c. 667<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1993#000667#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1998 VA CH 32"><content><span normalizedCite="1998 Va. Ch. 32">1998, c. 32<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1998#000032#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2012 VA CH 520"><content><span normalizedCite="2012 Va. Ch. 520">2012, c. 520<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2012#000520#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PTC0-004G-K2RW-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 55.</desig><title>PROPERTY AND CONVEYANCES</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 4.2.</desig><title>CONDOMINIUM ACT</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="article"><heading><desig>ARTICLE 2.</desig><title>CREATION, ALTERATION AND TERMINATION OF CONDOMINIUMS</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Contracts Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QzY0RTZFMzE0RjkwNDdFQUI5M0U5N0ZFMjYyREMyQzU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QTdGQUE3QkZDMDlBNDQ1MTkzRjEzMEQ1OEUwNzdDOTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NjZEOEU3MEJBRUQ2NDNFNzhFRjAxRTk1OEU1QjY2QTc</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Governments</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjdEQjE4OUJDMzQxNDNEMEI0RTI1QUFCMzJENjEwRTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Boundaries</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDEyQzA0NjVBQjA3NDRDOUJDNkExQkIzRkEzNzE2MTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Njg1MkM3RkYyNzIxNEVFRkJFMTI2NUM4NUU1ODdEM0Q</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Real Property Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QUUyRTcxRURBNEY2NEE2MDk3QzBCNzRDOEY0NTZDQzk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Formation</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QTMyMEFDRDJFMjExNDU0NUE2NkI4RUEwMEFCODUyRUQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUMzQTI2Qzg3NkJDNDI5MEI1MTU1QkM0RDlGN0JENUU</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjJCOTVGQkMzRkQzNEQ2RjkzOEFGNzY4QUVBNEUzRTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjQxMkNBNkE1ODE5NDg0NUJDMTkzNzA1NTMwQzRFQ0M</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MkIzQTQ1QTc0REQ4NDUxOTg4MzU0NTMzNTk3ODBEREI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUMzQTI2Qzg3NkJDNDI5MEI1MTU1QkM0RDlGN0JENUU</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NTQwQjZGM0VDNUVENEQzMUE1QUNDNTM5ODY2NzlCMTc7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NTk0MkNDNEVCNEUyNDc5NTgxMDMyMzBEMUVFOTU1RTU</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Joint Tenancies</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6N0EyOTIyRjhFMzQ4NDhDNTgwQTBDQTRBMTMyQzU0OTM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RURDNEUyQzNBMTcwNDU4REJDQTM0NjRFQzI0QjNBQjY</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Leasehold &amp; Real Estates</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QTlCNjdCQjExODgyNDgyODk0MUVEQTQ3MDY0MEFFQTQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjZEODAxMDMxMjkwNEQzQTlGQzJEQjFERDI1OUEzNTM</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Leases</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QkNFM0ZCQzgzODg0NERCQzg5MkRBMDFGOEM0QUU4ODY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUMzQTI2Qzg3NkJDNDI5MEI1MTU1QkM0RDlGN0JENUU</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Life Estates</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QzY2NDhCOEIwQTlENERDNDlCNTRDOEVBMjE0QUUxQzI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjZEODAxMDMxMjkwNEQzQTlGQzJEQjFERDI1OUEzNTM</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Management</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDQwRTc5MEY0MjE3NDRDRUFCRjFFODhBMUY5NDU2MDA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUMzQTI2Qzg3NkJDNDI5MEI1MTU1QkM0RDlGN0JENUU</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Power to Reenter &amp; Terminate</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MkEwNzc0N0FCODk1NEQ0QjlEREY5QTIxODAwMEUxMzQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QUZDQTAzRTdEMTMzNDZEOTg4N0M3OUMyOUNEMjI0MTQ</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Purchase &amp; Sale</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDNDNTc1MDExODM4NDA0NUEyRjMzNURBMDk0MTQxNTM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUMzQTI2Qzg3NkJDNDI5MEI1MTU1QkM0RDlGN0JENUU</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Reversions &amp; Reverter</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUJENjRGMTg1QUVFNEQwMzlBQUI5NzdFMjA4RTJFOTY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RDYwODMxODEzOTIxNDY1QTg1MDY2RUI5M0Y4NjhEQ0U</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Tenancies in Common</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QzQ1NTNBRTU4OEVGNDY1REI1RjRFNDNFQTYxRDgwODk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RURDNEUyQzNBMTcwNDU4REJDQTM0NjRFQzI0QjNBQjY</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Termination</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjA1Nzc5Mzg4QkRGNDY4MzhBMjgxM0E5Mzg1ODZCMTU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUMzQTI2Qzg3NkJDNDI5MEI1MTU1QkM0RDlGN0JENUU</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification><classificationGroup classificationScheme="indexing-terms"><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem score="90"><className>Real Property</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QUUyRTcxRURBNEY2NEE2MDk3QzBCNzRDOEY0NTZDQzk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></classificationGroup></metadata></legislativeDoc>