<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#349#000032#     1#          164#">Va. Code Ann. § 32.1-164</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_32.1-164"/><heading><desig>§ 32.1-164.</desig><title>Powers and duties of Board; regulations; fees; onsite soil evaluators; letters in lieu of permits; inspections; civil penalties</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a"/><heading><desig>A.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The Board shall have supervision and control over the safe and sanitary collection, conveyance, transportation, treatment, and disposal of sewage by onsite sewage systems and alternative discharging sewage systems, and treatment works as they affect the public health and welfare. The Board shall also have supervision and control over the maintenance, inspection, and reuse of alternative onsite sewage systems as they affect the public health and welfare. In discharging the responsibility to supervise and control the safe and sanitary treatment and disposal of sewage as they affect the public health and welfare, the Board shall exercise due diligence to protect the quality of both surface water and ground water. Upon the final adoption of a general Virginia Pollutant Discharge Elimination permit by the State Water Control Board, the Board of Health shall assume the responsibility for permitting alternative discharging sewage systems as defined in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 32.1-163"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 32.1-163">§ 32.1-163<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000032#     1#          163#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>. All such permits shall comply with the applicable regulations of the State Water Control Board and be registered with the State Water Control Board.</p><p>In the exercise of its duty to supervise and control the treatment and disposal of sewage, the Board shall require and the Department shall conduct regular inspections of alternative discharging sewage systems. The Board shall also establish requirements for maintenance contracts for alternative discharging sewage systems. The Board may require, as a condition for issuing a permit to operate an alternative discharging sewage system, that the applicant present an executed maintenance contract. Such contract shall be maintained for the life of any general Virginia Pollutant Discharge Elimination System permit issued by the State Water Control Board.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b"/><heading><desig>B.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The regulations of the Board shall govern the collection, conveyance, transportation, treatment and disposal of sewage by onsite sewage systems and alternative discharging sewage systems and the maintenance, inspection, and reuse of alternative onsite sewage systems. Such regulations shall be designed to protect the public health and promote the public welfare and may include, without limitation:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A requirement that the owner obtain a permit from the Commissioner prior to the construction, installation, modification or operation of a sewerage system or treatment works except in those instances where a permit is required pursuant to Chapter 3.1 (<citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 62.1-44.2"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 62.1-44.2">§ 62.1-44.2<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000062#     1#         44.2#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> et seq.) of Title 62.1.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Criteria for the granting or denial of such permits.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Standards for the design, construction, installation, modification and operation of sewerage systems and treatment works for permits issued by the Commissioner.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_4"/><heading><desig>4.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Standards governing disposal of sewage on or in soils.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_5"/><heading><desig>5.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Standards specifying the minimum distance between sewerage systems or treatment works and:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_5_a"/><heading><desig>(a)</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Public and private wells supplying water for human consumption,</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_5_b"/><heading><desig>(b)</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Lakes and other impounded waters,</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_5_c"/><heading><desig>(c)</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Streams and rivers,</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_5_d"/><heading><desig>(d)</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Shellfish waters,</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_5_e"/><heading><desig>(e)</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Ground waters,</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_5_f"/><heading><desig>(f)</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Areas and places of human habitation,</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_5_g"/><heading><desig>(g)</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Property lines.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_6"/><heading><desig>6.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Standards as to the adequacy of an approved water supply.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_7"/><heading><desig>7.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Standards governing the transportation of sewage.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_8"/><heading><desig>8.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A prohibition against the discharge of untreated sewage onto land or into waters of the Commonwealth.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_9"/><heading><desig>9.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A requirement that such residences, buildings, structures and other places designed for human occupancy as the Board may prescribe be provided with a sewerage system or treatment works.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_10"/><heading><desig>10.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Criteria for determining the demonstrated ability of alternative onsite systems, which are not permitted through the then current sewage handling and disposal regulations, to treat and dispose of sewage as effectively as approved methods.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_11"/><heading><desig>11.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Standards for inspections of and requirements for maintenance contracts for alternative discharging sewage systems.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_12"/><heading><desig>12.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Notwithstanding the provisions of subdivision 1 above and Chapter 3.1 of Title 62.1, a requirement that the owner obtain a permit from the Commissioner prior to the construction, installation, modification, or operation of an alternative discharging sewage system as defined in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 32.1-163"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 32.1-163">§ 32.1-163<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000032#     1#          163#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_13"/><heading><desig>13.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Criteria for granting, denying, and revoking of permits for alternative discharging sewage systems.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_14"/><heading><desig>14.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Procedures for issuing letters recognizing onsite sewage sites in lieu of issuing onsite sewage system permits.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_15"/><heading><desig>15.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Performance requirements for nitrogen discharged from alternative onsite sewage systems that protect public health and ground and surface water quality.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c"/><heading><desig>C.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A fee of $ 75 shall be charged for filing an application for an onsite sewage system or an alternative discharging sewage system permit with the Department. Funds received in payment of such charges shall be transmitted to the Comptroller for deposit. The funds from the fees shall be credited to a special fund to be appropriated by the General Assembly, as it deems necessary, to the Department for the purpose of carrying out the provisions of this title. However, $ 10 of each fee shall be credited to the Onsite Sewage Indemnification Fund established pursuant to <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 32.1-164.1:01"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 32.1-164.1:01">§ 32.1-164.1:01.<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#958#0000000032#0000000001#     164.1#0000000001#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation></p><p>The Board, in its regulations, shall establish a procedure for the waiver of fees for persons whose incomes are below the federal poverty guidelines established by the United States Department of Health and Human Services or when the application is for a pit privy or the repair of a failing onsite sewage system. If the Department denies the permit for land on which the applicant seeks to construct his principal place of residence, then such fee shall be refunded to the applicant.</p><p>From such funds as are appropriated to the Department from the special fund, the Board shall apportion a share to local or district health departments to be allocated in the same ratios as provided for the operation of such health departments pursuant to <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 32.1-31"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 32.1-31">§ 32.1-31<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000032#     1#           31#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>. Such funds shall be transmitted to the local or district health departments on a quarterly basis.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d"/><heading><desig>D.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> In addition to factors related to the Board's responsibilities for the safe and sanitary treatment and disposal of sewage as they affect the public health and welfare, the Board shall, in establishing standards, give due consideration to economic costs of such standards in accordance with the applicable provisions of the Administrative Process Act (<citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 2.2-4000"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 2.2-4000">§ 2.2-4000<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000002#     2#         4000#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> et seq.).</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_e"/><heading><desig>E.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Further a fee of $ 75 shall be charged for such installation and monitoring inspections of alternative discharging sewage systems as may be required by the Board. The funds received in payment of such fees shall be credited to a special fund to be appropriated by the General Assembly, as it deems necessary, to the Department for the purpose of carrying out the provisions of this section. However, $ 10 of each fee shall be credited to the Onsite Sewage Indemnification Fund established pursuant to <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 32.1-164.1:01"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 32.1-164.1:01">§ 32.1-164.1:01.<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#958#0000000032#0000000001#     164.1#0000000001#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation></p><p>The Board, in its regulations, shall establish a procedure for the waiver of fees for persons whose incomes are below the federal poverty guidelines established by the United States Department of Health and Human Services.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_f"/><heading><desig>F.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Any owner who violates any provision of this section or any regulation of the Board of Health or the State Water Control Board relating to alternative discharging sewage systems or who fails to comply with any order of the Board of Health or any special final order of the State Water Control Board shall be subject to the penalties provided in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 32.1-27"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 32.1-27">§§ 32.1-27<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000032#     1#           27#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> and <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 62.1-44.32"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 62.1-44.32">62.1-44.32.<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000062#     1#        44.32#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation></p><p>In the event that a county, city, or town, or its agent, is the owner, the county, city, or town, or its agent may initiate a civil action against any user or users of an alternative discharging sewage system to recover that portion of any civil penalty imposed against the owner which directly resulted from violations by the user or users of any applicable federal, state, or local laws, regulations, or ordinances.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_g"/><heading><desig>G.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The Board shall establish and implement procedures for issuance of letters recognizing the appropriateness of onsite sewage site conditions in lieu of issuing onsite sewage system permits. The Board may require that a survey plat be included with an application for such letter. Such letters shall state, in language determined by the Office of the Attorney General and approved by the Board, the appropriateness of the soil for an onsite sewage system; no system design shall be required for issuance of such letter. The letter may be recorded in the land records of the clerk of the circuit court in the jurisdiction where all or part of the site or proposed site of the onsite sewage system is to be located so as to be a binding notice to the public, including subsequent purchases of the land in question. Upon the sale or transfer of the land which is the subject of any letter, the letter shall be transferred with the title to the property. A permit shall be issued on the basis of such letter unless, from the date of the letter's issuance, there has been a substantial, intervening change in the soil or site conditions where the onsite sewage system is to be located. The Board, Commissioner, and the Department shall accept evaluations from licensed onsite soil evaluators for the issuance of such letters, if they are produced in accordance with the Board's established procedures for issuance of letters. The Department shall issue such letters within 20 working days of the application filing date when evaluations produced by licensed onsite soil evaluators are submitted as supporting documentation. The Department shall not be required to do a field check of the evaluation prior to issuing such a letter or a permit based on such letter; however, the Department may conduct such field analyses as deemed necessary to protect the integrity of the Commonwealth's environment. Applicants for such letters in lieu of onsite sewage system permits shall pay the fee established by the Board for the letters' issuance and, upon application for an onsite sewage system permit, shall pay the permit application fee.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_h"/><heading><desig>H.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The Board shall establish a program for the operation and maintenance of alternative onsite systems. The program shall require:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_h_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The owner of an alternative onsite sewage system, as defined in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 32.1-163"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 32.1-163">§ 32.1-163<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000032#     1#          163#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, to have that system operated by a licensed operator, as defined in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 32.1-163"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 32.1-163">§ 32.1-163<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000032#     1#          163#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, and visited by the operator as specified in the operation permit;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_h_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The licensed operator to provide a report on the results of the site visit utilizing the web-based system required by this subsection. A fee of $ 1 shall be paid by the licensed operator at the time the report is filed. Such fees shall be credited to the Onsite Operation and Maintenance Fund established pursuant to <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 32.1-164.8"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 32.1-164.8">§ 32.1-164.8<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000032#     1#        164.8#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_h_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A statewide web-based reporting system to track the operation, monitoring, and maintenance requirements of each system, including its components. The system shall have the capability for pre-notification of operation, maintenance, or monitoring to the operator or owner. Licensed operators shall be required to enter their reports onto the system. The Department of Health shall utilize the system to provide for compliance monitoring of operation and maintenance requirements throughout the state. The Commissioner shall consider readily available commercial systems currently utilized within the Commonwealth; and</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_h_4"/><heading><desig>4.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Any additional requirements deemed necessary by the Board.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_i"/><heading><desig>I.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The Board shall promulgate regulations governing the requirements for maintaining alternative onsite sewage systems.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_j"/><heading><desig>J.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The Board shall establish a uniform schedule of civil penalties for violations of regulations promulgated pursuant to subsection B that are not remedied within 30 days after service of notice from the Department. Civil penalties collected pursuant to this chapter shall be credited to the Environmental Health Education and Training Fund established pursuant to <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 32.1-248.3"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 32.1-248.3">§ 32.1-248.3.<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000032#     1#        248.3#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation></p><p>This schedule of civil penalties shall be uniform for each type of specified violation, and the penalty for any one violation shall be not more than $ 100 for the initial violation and not more than $ 150 for each additional violation. Each day during which the violation is found to have existed shall constitute a separate offense. However, specified violations arising from the same operative set of facts shall not be charged more than once in any 10-day period, and a series of specified violations arising from the same operative set of facts shall not result in civil penalties exceeding a total of $ 3,000. Penalties shall not apply to unoccupied structures which do not contribute to the pollution of public or private water supplies or the contraction or spread of infectious, contagious, or dangerous diseases. The Department may pursue other remedies as provided by law; however, designation of a particular violation for a civil penalty pursuant to this section shall be in lieu of criminal penalties, except for any violation that contributes to or is likely to contribute to the pollution of public or private water supplies or the contraction or spread of infectious, contagious, or dangerous diseases.</p><p>The Department may issue a civil summons ticket as provided by law for a scheduled violation. Any person summoned or issued a ticket for a scheduled violation may make an appearance in person or in writing by mail to the Department prior to the date fixed for trial in court. Any person so appearing may enter a waiver of trial, admit liability, and pay the civil penalty established for the offense charged.</p><p>If a person charged with a scheduled violation does not elect to enter a waiver of trial and admit liability, the violation shall be tried in the general district court with jurisdiction in the same manner and with the same right of appeal as provided for by law. In any trial for a scheduled violation, the Department shall have the burden of proving by a preponderance of the evidence the liability of the alleged violator. An admission of liability or finding of liability under this section shall not be deemed an admission at a criminal proceeding.</p><p>This section shall not be interpreted to allow the imposition of civil penalties for activities related to land development.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_k"/><heading><desig>K.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The Department shall establish procedures for requiring a survey plat as part of an application for a permit or letter for any onsite sewage or alternative discharging sewage system, and for granting waivers for such requirements. In all cases, it shall be the landowner's responsibility to ensure that the system is properly located as permitted.</p></bodyText></level><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p>Code 1950, § 32-9; 1954, c. 646; 1964, c. 436; 1970, c. 645; 1972, c. 775; 1979, c. 711; 1986, c. 401; 1988, c. 203; <citation normalizedCite="1990 VA CH 438"><content><span normalizedCite="1990 Va. Ch. 438">1990, cc. 438<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1990#000438#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1990 VA CH 861"><content><span normalizedCite="1990 Va. Ch. 861">861<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1990#000861#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1990 VA CH 869"><content><span normalizedCite="1990 Va. Ch. 869">869<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1990#000869#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1994 VA CH 747"><content><span normalizedCite="1994 Va. Ch. 747">1994, c. 747<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1994#000747#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1999 VA CH 871"><content><span normalizedCite="1999 Va. Ch. 871">1999, c. 871<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1999#000871#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2003 VA CH 614"><content><span normalizedCite="2003 Va. Ch. 614">2003, c. 614<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2003#000614#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2007 VA CH 514"><content><span normalizedCite="2007 Va. Ch. 514">2007, cc. 514<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2007#000514#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2007 VA CH 892"><content><span normalizedCite="2007 Va. Ch. 892">892<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2007#000892#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2007 VA CH 924"><content><span normalizedCite="2007 Va. Ch. 924">924<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2007#000924#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2009 VA CH 695"><content><span normalizedCite="2009 Va. Ch. 695">2009, cc. 695<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2009#000695#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2009 VA CH 747"><content><span normalizedCite="2009 Va. Ch. 747">747<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2009#000747#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PVJ0-004G-K0YD-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 32.1.</desig><title>HEALTH</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 6.</desig><title>ENVIRONMENTAL HEALTH SERVICES</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="article"><heading><desig>ARTICLE 1.</desig><title>SEWAGE DISPOSAL</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Criminal Law &amp; Procedure</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NEU0RkE1OUQwNUQwNDgxODhEODZCMjkzOTg3NThBNzk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Admission of Evidence</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6ODE4QUJFNjFDNjIwNEQ3RjhCODQ2NUZEM0JFRTcwRDQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6N0U0NUI1RjY0RTQzNDI3MTlDRTYxQzk2NzkzQkU1N0M</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Environmental Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NzFDRDYyNkI2QjhBNDg3NTkyRjRDRkZEQjlCRkRBQzM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDU2MzVDODk3MEJDNDA2RDgyODRCNjg5NjExODVBOEM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QzJFQjdFQzcwMkM5NDQwMDg4ODU0RTMyODkxRDFFMzI</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Public Participation</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MzkwQTAyQTM0QjIzNDAzN0I2RjBBNDczNzA0N0I2NzE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjI3QUU4NUZEQzZFNEYzRThENkZBRTA1MkUyQTAwQTA</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Governments</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjdEQjE4OUJDMzQxNDNEMEI0RTI1QUFCMzJENjEwRTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Administrative Boards</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QTYwRUFCMDc5MzQ5NDEyREFEQkU2NkE2MjRGQTlCNzY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Njg1MkM3RkYyNzIxNEVFRkJFMTI2NUM4NUU1ODdEM0Q</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Clerks of Court</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6REVFMjkzRDI1MkU2NERDNjk3OEUxODY0REYwMUI1NjE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NURENzJGNTEyQzM0NEREQUI2RkVCRTM4RTc1RTZBREU</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Financing</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Q0QyN0IxRDI1MTE0NDQ3NkEzMzZCMTBCMkE2QkM3RTM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MEY3NUIxODI2RjU2NEY0NzgwMDQyNjFDMEQ1QUExRjM</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Sanitation &amp; Water</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NUJBQUJCRjYwQjU5NDg3RkI5RjBBMjZENTZDMkM2QzA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MEY3NUIxODI2RjU2NEY0NzgwMDQyNjFDMEQ1QUExRjM</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification><classificationGroup classificationScheme="indexing-terms"><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem score="90"><className>Environmental &amp; Natural Resources</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NzFDRDYyNkI2QjhBNDg3NTkyRjRDRkZEQjlCRkRBQzM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem score="90"><className>Healthcare</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NkUxMkVDQjJDOEY5NDVDQ0E5NTFEMTlDMjIwNzVERjc7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></classificationGroup></metadata></legislativeDoc>