<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#349#000016#     1#        345.2#">Va. Code Ann. § 16.1-345.2</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_16.1-345.2"/><heading><desig>§ 16.1-345.2.</desig><title>Mandatory outpatient treatment; criteria; orders</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a"/><heading><desig>A.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> After observing the minor and considering (i) the recommendations of any treating or examining physician or psychologist licensed in Virginia, if available, (ii) any past actions of the minor, (iii) any past mental health treatment of the minor, (iv) any evaluation of the minor, (v) any medical records available, (vi) the preadmission screening report, and (vii) any other relevant evidence that may have been admitted, the court shall order that the minor be admitted involuntarily to mandatory outpatient treatment for a period not to exceed 90 days if it finds, by clear and convincing evidence, that:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Because of mental illness, the minor (i) presents a serious danger to himself or others to the extent that severe or irremediable injury is likely to result, as evidenced by recent acts or threats or (ii) is experiencing a serious deterioration of his ability to care for himself in a developmentally age-appropriate manner, as evidenced by delusionary thinking or by a significant impairment of functioning in hydration, nutrition, self-protection, or self-control;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The minor is in need of compulsory treatment for a mental illness and is reasonably likely to benefit from the proposed treatment;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Less restrictive alternatives to involuntary inpatient treatment that would offer an opportunity for improvement of his condition have been investigated and are determined to be appropriate;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_4"/><heading><desig>4.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The minor, if 14 years of age or older, and his parents (i) have sufficient capacity to understand the stipulations of the minor's treatment, (ii) have expressed an interest in the minor's living in the community and have agreed to abide by the minor's treatment plan, and (iii) are deemed to have the capacity to comply with the treatment plan and understand and adhere to conditions and requirements of the treatment and services; and</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_5"/><heading><desig>5.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The ordered treatment can be delivered on an outpatient basis by the community services board or a designated provider.</p><p><pre/>Less restrictive alternatives shall not be determined to be appropriate unless the services are actually available in the community and providers of the services have actually agreed to deliver the services.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b"/><heading><desig>B.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Mandatory outpatient treatment may include day treatment in a hospital, night treatment in a hospital, or other appropriate course of treatment as may be necessary to meet the needs of the minor. The community services board serving the area in which the minor resides shall recommend a specific course of treatment and programs for the provision of mandatory outpatient treatment. Upon expiration of an order for mandatory outpatient treatment, the minor shall be released from the requirements of the order unless the order is continued in accordance with <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 16.1-345.5"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 16.1-345.5">§ 16.1-345.5.<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000016#     1#        345.5#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation></p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c"/><heading><desig>C.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Any order for mandatory outpatient treatment shall include an initial mandatory outpatient treatment plan developed by the community services board serving the area in which the minor resides. The plan shall, at a minimum, (i) identify the specific services to be provided, (ii) identify the provider who has agreed to provide each service, (iii) describe the arrangements made for the initial in-person appointment or contact with each service provider, and (iv) include any other relevant information that may be available regarding the mandatory outpatient treatment ordered. The order shall require the community services board to monitor the implementation of the mandatory outpatient treatment plan and report any material noncompliance to the court.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d"/><heading><desig>D.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> No later than five business days after an order for mandatory outpatient treatment has been entered pursuant to this section, the community services board that is responsible for monitoring compliance with the order shall file a comprehensive mandatory outpatient treatment plan. The comprehensive mandatory outpatient treatment plan shall (i) identify the specific type, amount, duration, and frequency of each service to be provided to the minor, (ii) identify the provider that has agreed to provide each service included in the plan, (iii) certify that the services are the most appropriate and least restrictive treatment available for the minor, (iv) certify that each provider has complied and continues to comply with applicable provisions of the Department of Behavioral Health and Developmental Services' licensing regulations, (v) be developed with the fullest involvement and participation of the minor and his parents and reflect their preferences to the greatest extent possible to support the minor's recovery and self-determination, (vi) specify the particular conditions with which the minor shall be required to comply, and (vii) describe how the community services board shall monitor the minor's compliance with the plan and report any material noncompliance with the plan. The minor shall be involved in the preparation of the plan to the maximum feasible extent consistent with his ability to understand and participate, and the minor's family shall be involved to the maximum extent consistent with the minor's treatment needs. The community services board shall submit the comprehensive mandatory outpatient treatment plan to the court for approval. Upon approval by the court, the comprehensive mandatory outpatient treatment plan shall be filed with the court and incorporated into the order of mandatory outpatient treatment. Any subsequent substantive modifications to the plan shall be filed with the court for review and attached to any order for mandatory outpatient treatment.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_e"/><heading><desig>E.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> If the community services board responsible for developing the comprehensive mandatory outpatient treatment plan determines that the services necessary for the treatment of the minor's mental illness are not available or cannot be provided to the minor in accordance with the order for mandatory outpatient treatment, it shall notify the court within five business days of the entry of the order for mandatory outpatient treatment. Within five business days of receiving such notice, the judge, after notice to the minor, the minor's attorney, and the community services board responsible for developing the comprehensive mandatory outpatient treatment plan, shall hold a hearing pursuant to <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 16.1-345.4"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 16.1-345.4">§ 16.1-345.4.<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000016#     1#        345.4#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation></p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_f"/><heading><desig>F.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Upon entry of any order for mandatory outpatient treatment, the clerk of the court shall provide a copy of the order to the minor who is the subject of the order, his parents, his attorney, his guardian ad litem, and the community services board required to monitor his compliance with the plan. The community services board shall acknowledge receipt of the order to the clerk of the court on a form established by the Office of the Executive Secretary of the Supreme Court and provided by the court for this purpose.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_g"/><heading><desig>G.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> After entry of any order for mandatory outpatient treatment if the court that entered the order is not the juvenile and domestic relations district court for the jurisdiction in which the minor resides, it shall transfer jurisdiction of the case to the court where the minor resides.</p></bodyText></level><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p><citation normalizedCite="2009 VA CH 455"><content><span normalizedCite="2009 Va. Ch. 455">2009, cc. 455<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2009#000455#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2009 VA CH 555"><content><span normalizedCite="2009 Va. Ch. 555">555<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2009#000555#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2010 VA CH 778"><content><span normalizedCite="2010 Va. Ch. 778">2010, cc. 778<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2010#000778#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2010 VA CH 825"><content><span normalizedCite="2010 Va. Ch. 825">825<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2010#000825#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PVN0-004G-K2TP-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 16.1.</desig><title>COURTS NOT OF RECORD</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 11.</desig><title>JUVENILE AND DOMESTIC RELATIONS DISTRICT COURTS</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="article"><heading><desig>ARTICLE 16.</desig><title>PSYCHIATRIC TREATMENT OF MINORS ACT</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Public Health &amp; Welfare Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDYwRTY1MDg3MTk5NDUyNkFFRDI1RjJBRERGQ0UxNzI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Treatment</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QTE3NDlDOUQ4Mzg1NDcxNzhCNzQwNDc2MkEzMTkwRUI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RTA2N0I2MjA4MEMwNEExNjlBQzkzRjBGOTAxODRCNkY</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification><classificationGroup classificationScheme="indexing-terms"><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem score="90"><className>Governments</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjdEQjE4OUJDMzQxNDNEMEI0RTI1QUFCMzJENjEwRTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></classificationGroup></metadata></legislativeDoc>