<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#349#000024#     2#          653#">Va. Code Ann. § 24.2-653</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_24.2-653"/><heading><desig>§ 24.2-653.</desig><title>Voter whose name does not appear on pollbook or who is marked as having voted; handling of provisional ballots; ballots cast after normal close of polls due to court order extending polling hours</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a"/><heading><desig>A.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> When a person offers to vote pursuant to <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 24.2-652"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 24.2-652">§ 24.2-652<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000024#     2#          652#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> and the general registrar is not available or cannot state that the person is registered to vote, then such person shall be allowed to vote by printed ballot in the manner provided in this section. This procedure shall also apply when required by <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 24.2-643"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 24.2-643">§ 24.2-643<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000024#     2#          643#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> or <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 24.2-651.1"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 24.2-651.1">24.2-651.1.<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000024#     2#        651.1#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation></p><p>Such person shall be given a printed ballot and provide, subject to the penalties for making false statements pursuant to <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 24.2-1016"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 24.2-1016">§ 24.2-1016<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000024#     2#         1016#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, on a green envelope supplied by the Department of Elections, the identifying information required on the envelope, including the last four digits of his social security number, if any, full name including the maiden or any other prior legal name, date of birth, complete address, and signature. Such person shall be asked to present one of the forms of identification specified in subsection B of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 24.2-643"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 24.2-643">§ 24.2-643<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000024#     2#          643#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>. The officers of election shall note on the green envelope whether or not the voter has presented one of the specified forms of identification. The officers of election shall enter the appropriate information for the person in the precinct provisional ballots log in accordance with the instructions of the State Board but shall not enter a consecutive number for the voter on the pollbook nor otherwise mark his name as having voted. The officers of election shall provide an application for registration to the person offering to vote in the manner provided in this section.</p><p>The voter shall then, in the presence of an officer of election, but in a secret manner, mark the printed ballot as provided in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 24.2-644"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 24.2-644">§ 24.2-644<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000024#     2#          644#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> and seal it in the green envelope. The envelope containing the ballot shall then promptly be placed in the ballot container by an officer of election.</p><p>An officer of election, by a written notice given to the voter, shall (i) inform him that a determination of his right to vote shall be made by the electoral board, (ii) advise the voter of the beginning time and place for the board's meeting and of the voter's right to be present at that meeting, and (iii) inform a voter voting provisionally when required by <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 24.2-643"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 24.2-643">§ 24.2-643<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000024#     2#          643#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> that he may submit a copy of one of the forms of identification specified in subsection B of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 24.2-643"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 24.2-643">§ 24.2-643<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000024#     2#          643#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> to the electoral board by facsimile, electronic mail, in-person submission, or timely United States Postal Service or commercial mail delivery, to be received by the electoral board no later than noon on the third day after the election. At the meeting, the voter may request an extension of the determination of the provisional vote in order to provide information to prove that the voter is entitled to vote in the precinct pursuant to <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 24.2-401"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 24.2-401">§ 24.2-401<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000024#     2#          401#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>. The electoral board shall have the authority to grant such extensions which it deems reasonable to determine the status of a provisional vote.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b"/><heading><desig>B.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The provisional votes submitted pursuant to subsection A, in their unopened envelopes, shall be sealed in a special envelope marked "Provisional Votes," inscribed with the number of envelopes contained therein, and signed by the officers of election who counted them. All provisional votes envelopes shall be delivered either (i) to the clerk of the circuit court who shall deliver all such envelopes to the secretary of the electoral board or (ii) to the general registrar in localities in which the electoral board has directed delivery of election materials to the general registrar pursuant to <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 24.2-668"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 24.2-668">§ 24.2-668<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000024#     2#          668#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p><p>The electoral board shall meet on the day following the election and determine whether each person having submitted such a provisional vote was entitled to do so as a qualified voter in the precinct in which he offered the provisional vote. If the board is unable to determine the validity of all the provisional ballots offered in the election, or has granted any voter who has offered a provisional ballot an extension as provided in subsection A, the meeting shall stand adjourned, not to exceed seven calendar days from the date of the election, until the board has determined the validity of all provisional ballots offered in the election.</p><p>One authorized representative of each political party or independent candidate in a general or special election or one authorized representative of each candidate in a primary election shall be permitted to remain in the room in which the determination is being made as an observer so long as he does not participate in the proceedings and does not impede the orderly conduct of the determination. Each authorized representative shall be a qualified voter of any jurisdiction of the Commonwealth. Each representative, who is not himself a candidate or party chairman, shall present to the electoral board a written statement designating him to be a representative of the party or candidate and signed by the county or city chairman of his political party, the independent candidate, or the primary candidate, as appropriate. If the county or city chairman is unavailable to sign such a written designation, such a designation may be made by the state or district chairman of the political party. However, no written designation made by a state or district chairman shall take precedence over a written designation made by the county or city chairman. Such statement, bearing the chairman's or candidate's original signature, may be photocopied and such photocopy shall be as valid as if the copy had been signed.</p><p>Notwithstanding the provisions of the Virginia Freedom of Information Act (<citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 2.2-3700"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 2.2-3700">§ 2.2-3700<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000002#     2#         3700#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> et seq.), attendance at meetings of the electoral board to determine the validity of provisional ballots shall be permitted only for the authorized representatives provided for in this subsection, for the persons whose provisional votes are being considered and their representative or legal counsel, and for appropriate staff and legal counsel for the electoral board.</p><p>If the electoral board determines that such person was not entitled to vote as a qualified voter in the precinct in which he offered the provisional vote, is unable to determine his right to vote, or has not been provided one of the forms of identification specified in subsection B of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 24.2-643"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 24.2-643">§ 24.2-643<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000024#     2#          643#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, the envelope containing his ballot shall not be opened and his vote shall not be counted. The provisional vote shall be counted if (a) such person is entitled to vote in the precinct pursuant to <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 24.2-401"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 24.2-401">§ 24.2-401<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000024#     2#          401#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> or (b) the Department of Elections or the voter presents proof that indicates the voter submitted an application for registration to the Department of Motor Vehicles or other state-designated voter registration agency prior to the close of registration pursuant to <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 24.2-416"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 24.2-416">§ 24.2-416<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000024#     2#          416#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> and the registrar determines that the person was qualified for registration based upon the application for registration submitted by the person pursuant to subsection A. The general registrar shall notify in writing pursuant to <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 24.2-114"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 24.2-114">§ 24.2-114<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000024#     2#          114#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> those persons found not properly registered or whose provisional vote was not counted.</p><p>If the electoral board determines that such person was entitled to vote, the name of the voter shall be entered in a provisional votes pollbook and marked as having voted, the envelope shall be opened, and the ballot placed in a ballot container without any inspection further than that provided for in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 24.2-646"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 24.2-646">§ 24.2-646<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000024#     2#          646#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p><p>On completion of its determination, the electoral board shall proceed to count such ballots and certify the results of its count. Its certified results shall be added to those found pursuant to <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 24.2-671"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 24.2-671">§ 24.2-671<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000024#     2#          671#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>. No adjustment shall be made to the statement of results for the precinct in which the person offered to vote. However, any voter who cast a provisional ballot and is determined by the electoral board to have been entitled to vote shall have his name included on the list of persons who voted that is submitted to the Department of Elections pursuant to <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 24.2-406"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 24.2-406">§ 24.2-406<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000024#     2#          406#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p><p>The certification of the results of the count together with all ballots and envelopes, whether open or unopened, and other related material shall be delivered by the electoral board to the clerk of the circuit court and retained by him as provided for in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 24.2-668"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 24.2-668">§§ 24.2-668<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000024#     2#          668#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> and <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 24.2-669"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 24.2-669">24.2-669<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000024#     2#          669#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c"/><heading><desig>C.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Whenever the polling hours are extended by an order of a court of competent jurisdiction, any ballots marked after the normal polling hours by persons who were not already in line at the time the polls would have closed, notwithstanding the court order, shall be treated as provisional ballots under this section. The officers of election shall mark the green envelope for each such provisional ballot to indicate that it was cast after normal polling hours due to the court order, and when preparing the materials to deliver to the registrar or electoral board, shall separate these provisional ballots from any provisional ballots used for any other reason. The electoral board shall treat these provisional ballots as provided in subsection B; however, the counted and uncounted provisional ballots marked after the normal polling hours shall be kept separate from all other ballots and recorded in a separate provisional ballots pollbook. The Department of Elections shall provide instructions to the electoral boards for the handling and counting of such provisional ballots pursuant to this section.</p></bodyText></level><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p>1975, c. 515, §§ 24.1-55.1, 24.1-55.2; 1982, c. 650; <citation normalizedCite="1993 VA CH 641"><content><span normalizedCite="1993 Va. Ch. 641">1993, c. 641<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1993#000641#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1996 VA CH 8"><content><span normalizedCite="1996 Va. Ch. 8">1996, c. 8<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1996#000008#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1997 VA CH 438"><content><span normalizedCite="1997 Va. Ch. 438">1997, cc. 438<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1997#000438#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1997 VA CH 456"><content><span normalizedCite="1997 Va. Ch. 456">456<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1997#000456#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2002 VA CH 24"><content><span normalizedCite="2002 Va. Ch. 24">2002, c. 24<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2002#000024#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2003 VA CH 984"><content><span normalizedCite="2003 Va. Ch. 984">2003, cc. 984<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2003#000984#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2003 VA CH 1015"><content><span normalizedCite="2003 Va. Ch. 1015">1015<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2003#001015#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2004 VA CH 410"><content><span normalizedCite="2004 Va. Ch. 410">2004, c. 410<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2004#000410#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2005 VA CH 824"><content><span normalizedCite="2005 Va. Ch. 824">2005, c. 824<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2005#000824#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2007 VA CH 692"><content><span normalizedCite="2007 Va. Ch. 692">2007, c. 692<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2007#000692#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2008 VA CH 110"><content><span normalizedCite="2008 Va. Ch. 110">2008, cc. 110<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2008#000110#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2008 VA CH 559"><content><span normalizedCite="2008 Va. Ch. 559">559<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2008#000559#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2010 VA CH 448"><content><span normalizedCite="2010 Va. Ch. 448">2010, c. 448<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2010#000448#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2012 VA CH 592"><content><span normalizedCite="2012 Va. Ch. 592">2012, cc. 592<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2012#000592#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2012 VA CH 838"><content><span normalizedCite="2012 Va. Ch. 838">838<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2012#000838#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2012 VA CH 839"><content><span normalizedCite="2012 Va. Ch. 839">839<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2012#000839#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2013 VA CH 503"><content><span normalizedCite="2013 Va. Ch. 503">2013, c. 503<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2013#000503#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2014 VA CH 486"><content><span normalizedCite="2014 Va. Ch. 486">2014, cc. 486<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2014#000486#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2014 VA CH 540"><content><span normalizedCite="2014 Va. Ch. 540">540<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2014#000540#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2014 VA CH 576"><content><span normalizedCite="2014 Va. Ch. 576">576<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2014#000576#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2015 VA CH 133"><content><span normalizedCite="2015 Va. Ch. 133">2015, cc. 133<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2015#000133#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2015 VA CH 712"><content><span normalizedCite="2015 Va. Ch. 712">712<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2015#000712#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PTY0-004G-K07J-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 24.2.</desig><title>ELECTIONS</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 6.</desig><title>THE ELECTION</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="article"><heading><desig>ARTICLE 4.</desig><title>CONDUCT OF ELECTION; ELECTION RESULTS</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Civil Rights Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NURDOUM5MEJFQUZGNEFBMDgzMkM0RTgwODdDNTMxREM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RjY5MjRCQzAyQjY0NDJFMThDNkJCNjdGQzMxNkY4RjY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6N0U1MEVBQUFGMjc2NDk4Qjg0QkY0OUM4N0QyNkNCNjU</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Provisional Ballots</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OTMzRDlEQ0VEQjY1NEU4MzkzNDVCNTczQUVBNzM0REM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDRDMjRGNDlCRkYxNDkzNEIwMzIzNTk0NEExQ0YzMTc</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Registration</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NjhGNUY0MjM2OUQ0NEE4NkE0RUJFODcwRDkyQjI2OUU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDRDMjRGNDlCRkYxNDkzNEIwMzIzNTk0NEExQ0YzMTc</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Governments</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjdEQjE4OUJDMzQxNDNEMEI0RTI1QUFCMzJENjEwRTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Administrative Boards</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QTYwRUFCMDc5MzQ5NDEyREFEQkU2NkE2MjRGQTlCNzY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Njg1MkM3RkYyNzIxNEVFRkJFMTI2NUM4NUU1ODdEM0Q</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Clerks of Court</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6REVFMjkzRDI1MkU2NERDNjk3OEUxODY0REYwMUI1NjE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NURENzJGNTEyQzM0NEREQUI2RkVCRTM4RTc1RTZBREU</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Elections</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RTlGMTIwRjY1ODQ4NDQyRUE1MkJFMUQwMTE1MDhGQjY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Njg1MkM3RkYyNzIxNEVFRkJFMTI2NUM4NUU1ODdEM0Q</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></metadata></legislativeDoc>