<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#349#000054#     1#         3482#">Va. Code Ann. § 54.1-3482</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_54.1-3482"/><heading><desig>§ 54.1-3482.</desig><title>Practice of physical therapy; certain experience and referrals required; physical therapist assistants</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a"/><heading><desig>A.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> It shall be unlawful for a person to engage in the practice of physical therapy except as a licensed physical therapist, upon the referral and direction of a licensed doctor of medicine, osteopathy, chiropractic, podiatry, or dental surgery, a licensed nurse practitioner practicing in accordance with his practice agreement, or a licensed physician assistant acting under the supervision of a licensed physician, except as provided in this section.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b"/><heading><desig>B.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A physical therapist who has completed a doctor of physical therapy program approved by the Commission on Accreditation of Physical Therapy Education or who has obtained a certificate of authorization pursuant to <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 54.1-3482.1"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 54.1-3482.1">§ 54.1-3482.1<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000054#     1#       3482.1#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> may evaluate and treat a patient for no more than 30 consecutive days after an initial evaluation without a referral under the following conditions: (i) the patient is not receiving care from any licensed doctor of medicine, osteopathy, chiropractic, podiatry, or dental surgery, a licensed nurse practitioner practicing in accordance with his practice agreement, or a licensed physician assistant acting under the supervision of a licensed physician for the symptoms giving rise to the presentation at the time of the presentation to the physical therapist for physical therapy services or (ii) the patient is receiving care from a licensed doctor of medicine, osteopathy, chiropractic, podiatry, or dental surgery, a licensed nurse practitioner practicing in accordance with his practice agreement, or a licensed physician assistant acting under the supervision of a licensed physician at the time of his presentation to the physical therapist for the symptoms giving rise to the presentation for physical therapy services and (a) the patient identifies a licensed doctor of medicine, osteopathy, chiropractic, podiatry, or dental surgery, a licensed nurse practitioner practicing in accordance with his practice agreement, or a licensed physician assistant acting under the supervision of a licensed physician from whom he is currently receiving care; (b) the patient gives written consent for the physical therapist to release all personal health information and treatment records to the identified practitioner; and (c) the physical therapist notifies the practitioner identified by the patient no later than 14 days after treatment commences and provides the practitioner with a copy of the initial evaluation along with a copy of the patient history obtained by the physical therapist. Treatment for more than 30 consecutive days after evaluation of such patient shall only be upon the referral and direction of a licensed doctor of medicine, osteopathy, chiropractic, podiatry, or dental surgery, a licensed nurse practitioner practicing in accordance with his practice agreement, or a licensed physician assistant acting under the supervision of a licensed physician. A physical therapist may contact the practitioner identified by the patient at the end of the 30-day period to determine if the practitioner will authorize additional physical therapy services until such time as the patient can be seen by the practitioner. A physical therapist shall not perform an initial evaluation of a patient under this subsection if the physical therapist has performed an initial evaluation of the patient under this subsection for the same condition within the immediately preceding 60 days.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c"/><heading><desig>C.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A physical therapist who has not completed a doctor of physical therapy program approved by the Commission on Accreditation of Physical Therapy Education or who has not obtained a certificate of authorization pursuant to <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 54.1-3482.1"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 54.1-3482.1">§ 54.1-3482.1<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000054#     1#       3482.1#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> may conduct a one-time evaluation that does not include treatment of a patient without the referral and direction of a licensed doctor of medicine, osteopathy, chiropractic, podiatry, or dental surgery, a licensed nurse practitioner practicing in accordance with his practice agreement, or a licensed physician assistant acting under the supervision of a licensed physician; if appropriate, the physical therapist shall immediately refer such patient to the appropriate practitioner.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d"/><heading><desig>D.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Invasive procedures within the scope of practice of physical therapy shall at all times be performed only under the referral and direction of a licensed doctor of medicine, osteopathy, chiropractic, podiatry, or dental surgery, a licensed nurse practitioner practicing in accordance with his practice agreement, or a licensed physician assistant acting under the supervision of a licensed physician.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_e"/><heading><desig>E.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> It shall be unlawful for any licensed physical therapist to fail to immediately refer any patient to a licensed doctor of medicine, osteopathy, chiropractic, podiatry, or dental surgery, or a licensed nurse practitioner practicing in accordance with his practice agreement when such patient's medical condition is determined, at the time of evaluation or treatment, to be beyond the physical therapist's scope of practice. Upon determining that the patient's medical condition is beyond the scope of practice of a physical therapist, a physical therapist shall immediately refer such patient to an appropriate practitioner.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_f"/><heading><desig>F.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Any person licensed as a physical therapist assistant shall perform his duties only under the direction and control of a licensed physical therapist.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_g"/><heading><desig>G.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> However, a licensed physical therapist may provide, without referral or supervision, physical therapy services to (i) a student athlete participating in a school-sponsored athletic activity while such student is at such activity in a public, private, or religious elementary, middle or high school, or public or private institution of higher education when such services are rendered by a licensed physical therapist who is certified as an athletic trainer by the National Athletic Trainers' Association Board of Certification or as a sports certified specialist by the American Board of Physical Therapy Specialties; (ii) employees solely for the purpose of evaluation and consultation related to workplace ergonomics; (iii) special education students who, by virtue of their individualized education plans (IEPs), need physical therapy services to fulfill the provisions of their IEPs; (iv) the public for the purpose of wellness, fitness, and health screenings; (v) the public for the purpose of health promotion and education; and (vi) the public for the purpose of prevention of impairments, functional limitations, and disabilities.</p></bodyText></level><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p><citation normalizedCite="2000 VA CH 688"><content><span normalizedCite="2000 Va. Ch. 688">2000, c. 688<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2000#000688#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2001 VA CH 858"><content><span normalizedCite="2001 Va. Ch. 858">2001, c. 858<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2001#000858#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2002 VA CH 434"><content><span normalizedCite="2002 Va. Ch. 434">2002, cc. 434<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2002#000434#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2002 VA CH 471"><content><span normalizedCite="2002 Va. Ch. 471">471<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2002#000471#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2003 VA CH 496"><content><span normalizedCite="2003 Va. Ch. 496">2003, c. 496<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2003#000496#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2005 VA CH 928"><content><span normalizedCite="2005 Va. Ch. 928">2005, c. 928<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2005#000928#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2007 VA CH 9"><content><span normalizedCite="2007 Va. Ch. 9">2007, cc. 9<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2007#000009#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2007 VA CH 18"><content><span normalizedCite="2007 Va. Ch. 18">18<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2007#000018#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2015 VA CH 724"><content><span normalizedCite="2015 Va. Ch. 724">2015, cc. 724<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2015#000724#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2015 VA CH 746"><content><span normalizedCite="2015 Va. Ch. 746">746<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2015#000746#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PVJ0-004G-K0X5-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 54.1.</desig><title>PROFESSIONS AND OCCUPATIONS</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="subtitle"><heading><desig>SUBTITLE III.</desig><title>PROFESSIONS AND OCCUPATIONS REGULATED BY BOARDS WITHIN THE DEPARTMENT OF HEALTH PROFESSIONS</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 34.1.</desig><title>PHYSICAL THERAPY</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Healthcare Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NkUxMkVDQjJDOEY5NDVDQ0E5NTFEMTlDMjIwNzVERjc7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6N0U1NEQ5NkFBQjhENEUyMjhDMjM2MjRFQkVBOTFDODI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MkIwM0E1RTM4NkY5NEU4QjhBM0RCNzc5QjE4RkIzOEI</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NTVDMzIyNkJCMTRBNDI0NUJBOTlBOTYyMjQ0MDkyODU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QTJGRDdFQzgwODczNDI0NDgwMzEyM0JBOEQ2MUVDNjg</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OTgwNUI4RTJENUI0NEIzOEJGNTUwMzZCODFEQjlGQjc7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OEQ4NDdDRTY1QTdDNEZFODhDREYxQTRGMDhGQURDMzU</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification><classificationGroup classificationScheme="indexing-terms"><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem score="90"><className>Businesses &amp; Corporations</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjA4OEVGODBENzY4NDcxM0IyQzA1OTEwQzVDODRBOUE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></classificationGroup></metadata></legislativeDoc>