<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#123#000055#       373#">Va. Code Ann. § 55-373</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_55-373"/><heading><desig>§ 55-373.</desig><title>Termination of certain time-shares</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a"/><heading><desig>A.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> This section applies to all time-share estate programs and, when provided by the time-share instrument, to time-share use programs.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b"/><heading><desig>B.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A time-share project may be terminated in whole by the developer at any time and for any reason if such developer is the sole owner of all time-shares within the time-share project. Such termination shall be accomplished by the developer executing and recording a termination document where the time-share instrument is recorded. Time-shares subject to this section also may be terminated by written agreement of the time-share owners having at least fifty-one percent of the time-shares, or by such larger percentage as may otherwise be provided in the time-share instrument. The termination agreement shall specify a date upon which it shall become void, unless it is recorded before that date in the clerk's office of the appropriate court where the time-share project is located.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c"/><heading><desig>C.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> If the termination agreement sets forth the material terms of a contract or proposed contract under which an estate or interest in each time-share unit equal to the sum of the time-shares therein is to be sold and designates a trustee to effect the sale, the termination agreement becomes effective upon recordation, and title to that estate or interest vests upon termination in the trustee for the benefit of the time-share owners, to be transferred pursuant to the contract. If the termination agreement does not set forth the material terms of a contract or proposed contract under which an estate or interest in each time-share unit equal to the sum of the time-shares therein is to be sold and designates a trustee to effect the sale, the termination agreement becomes effective upon recordation, and title to an estate or interest in each time-share unit equal to the sum of the time-shares therein vests upon termination in the time-share owners thereof in proportion to their respective interests as provided in subsection F, and liens on the time-shares shall accordingly encumber those interests; and in this instance, any co-owner of that estate or interest may thereafter maintain an action for partition or for allotment or sale in lieu of partition pursuant to the laws of the Commonwealth.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d"/><heading><desig>D.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Except as otherwise specified in the termination agreement, so long as the former time-share owners or their trustee holds title to the estate or interest equal to the sum of the time-shares, each former time-share owner and his successor in interest have the same rights with respect to the use, enjoyment and occupancy in the former time-share unit that he would have had if termination had not occurred, together with the same liabilities and other obligations imposed by this act or the time-share instrument.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_e"/><heading><desig>E.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> After termination of all time-shares in a time-share project and adequate provision for payment of the claims of the creditors for time-share expenses, distribution shall be made, in proportion to their respective interests as provided in subsection F, to the former time-share owners and their successors in interest of (i) the proceeds of any sale pursuant to this section, (ii) the proceeds of any personalty held for the use and benefit of the former time-share owners, and (iii) any other funds held for the use and benefit of the former time-share owners.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_f"/><heading><desig>F.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The time-share instrument may specify the respective fractional or percentage interest in the estate or interest in each unit equal to the sum of the time-share therein that will be owned by each former time-share owner. Otherwise, not more than 180 days prior to the termination, an appraisal shall be made of the fair market value of each time-share by 1 or more impartial qualified appraisers selected either by the trustee designated in the termination agreement, or by the managing entity if no trustee was so designated. The appraisal shall also state the corresponding fractional or percentage interests calculated in proportion to those values and in accordance with this subsection. A notice stating all of those values and corresponding interests and the return address of the sender shall be sent by certified or registered mail, by the managing entity or the trustee designated in the termination agreements, to all of the time-share owners. The appraisal governs the magnitude of each interest unless (i) at least twenty-five percent of the time-share owners deliver, within sixty days after the date the notices were mailed, written disapprovals to the return address of the sender of the notice, or (ii) the final judgment of a court of competent jurisdiction, entered during or after that period, holds that the appraisal should be set aside. The appraisal and the calculation of interests must be made in accordance with the following:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_f_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> If the termination agreement sets forth the material terms of a contract or proposed contract for the sale of the estate or interests equal to the sum of the time-shares, each time-share conferring a right of occupancy during a limited number of time periods must be appraised as if the time until the date specified for the conveyance of the property had already elapsed. Otherwise, each time-share of that kind must be appraised as if the time until the date specified pursuant to subsection B had already elapsed.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_f_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The interest of each time-share owner is the value of the time-share he owned divided by the sum of the values of all time-shares in the unit or units to which his time-share applies.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_g"/><heading><desig>G.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Foreclosure or enforcement of a lien or encumbrance against all of the time-shares in a time-share project does not of itself terminate those time-shares.</p></bodyText></level><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p>1981, c. 462; 1985, c. 517; <citation normalizedCite="2006 VA CH 653"><content><span normalizedCite="2006 Va. Ch. 653">2006, c. 653<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2006#000653#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PTD0-004G-K3BJ-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 55.</desig><title>PROPERTY AND CONVEYANCES</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 21.</desig><title>THE VIRGINIA REAL ESTATE TIME-SHARE ACT</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="article"><heading><desig>ARTICLE 2.</desig><title>CREATION, TERMINATION, AND MANAGEMENT</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Estate, Gift &amp; Trust Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OENGNTY0MEQ2RTU2NDA2NTk4QjcyNzI2NTBERUU3NUI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Q0VEQ0U4QTFCMzc1NDkyQjgzMjNBQUJFREFDOEJCOTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NUQ4NThEMTk0MTQ4NDM3N0FGOEM5RkU2QUQ4RjA1MkQ</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RkM5NEM1RTczNTEzNDMwREIzODZFNkU3MDk1RTcxMjI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RUEwMTQ5RDk2OTM4NEIyNDgwNTY2RTNBOUYyOTk1REQ</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Real Property Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QUUyRTcxRURBNEY2NEE2MDk3QzBCNzRDOEY0NTZDQzk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjJCOTVGQkMzRkQzNEQ2RjkzOEFGNzY4QUVBNEUzRTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjQxMkNBNkE1ODE5NDg0NUJDMTkzNzA1NTMwQzRFQ0M</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Partition Actions</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MTY1REU3NTUwRDI4NEIwQThEREM4QjgzOTFBMDJEN0U7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6M0QwNEZGNTU3OTQwNDAzNkE5NEMyOTg4NTEwRkUxQUQ</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Timeshares</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OTQ2MTA5RjlGODA0NDhFMEIzMEE2NDI4ODRBM0Y3MDU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjQxMkNBNkE1ODE5NDg0NUJDMTkzNzA1NTMwQzRFQ0M</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification><classificationGroup classificationScheme="indexing-terms"><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem score="90"><className>Real Property</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QUUyRTcxRURBNEY2NEE2MDk3QzBCNzRDOEY0NTZDQzk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></classificationGroup></metadata></legislativeDoc>