<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#349#000054#     1#       2021.1#">Va. Code Ann. § 54.1-2021.1</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_54.1-2021.1"/><heading><desig>§ 54.1-2021.1.</desig><title>Appraisal management companies; license required; posting of bond or letter of credit</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a"/><heading><desig>A.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> No person shall engage in business as an appraisal management company without a license issued by the Board.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b"/><heading><desig>B.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The Board may issue a license to do business as an appraisal management company in the Commonwealth to any applicant who has submitted a complete application and provides satisfactory evidence that he has successfully:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Completed all requirements established by the Board that are consistent with this chapter and are reasonably necessary to implement, administer, and enforce the provisions of this chapter; and</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Certified to the Board the following information, and such other information as may be reasonably required by the Board, regarding the person or entity seeking licensure:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_2_a"/><heading><desig>a.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The name of the person or entity;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_2_b"/><heading><desig>b.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The business address of the person or entity;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_2_c"/><heading><desig>c.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Phone contact information for the person or entity, and email address;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_2_d"/><heading><desig>d.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> If the entity is not an entity domiciled in the Commonwealth, the name and contact information for the entity's agent for service of process in the Commonwealth;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_2_e"/><heading><desig>e.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> If the entity is not an entity domiciled in the Commonwealth, proof that the entity is properly and currently registered with the Virginia State Corporation Commission;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_2_f"/><heading><desig>f.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The name, address, and contact information for any person or any entity that owns 10 percent or more of the appraisal management company;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_2_g"/><heading><desig>g.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The name, address, and contact information for a responsible person for the appraisal management company located in the Commonwealth, who shall be a person or entity licensed under Chapter 20.1 (<citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 54.1-2009"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 54.1-2009">§ 54.1-2009<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000054#     1#         2009#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> et seq.);</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_2_h"/><heading><desig>h.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> That any person or entity that owns 10 percent or more of the appraisal management company has never had a license to act as an appraiser refused, denied, canceled, or revoked by the Commonwealth or any other state;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_2_i"/><heading><desig>i.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> That the entity has a system in place to review the work of all appraisers that may perform appraisal services for the appraisal management company on a periodic basis to ensure that the appraisal services are being conducted in accordance with the Uniform Standards of Professional Appraisal Practice;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_2_j"/><heading><desig>j.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> That the entity maintains a detailed record of the following: (i) each request for an appraisal service that the appraisal management company receives; (ii) the name of each independent appraiser that performs the appraisal; (iii) the physical address or legal identification of the subject property; (iv) the name of the appraisal management company's client for the appraisal; (v) the amount paid to the appraiser; and (vi) the amount paid to the appraisal management company; and</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_2_k"/><heading><desig>k.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> That the entity has a system in place to ensure compliance with § 129E of the Truth in Lending Act <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="15 USC 1601"><content><span normalizedCite="15 U.S.C. 1601">(15 U.S.C. § 1601<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1828#123#000015#       1601#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> et seq.).</p></bodyText></level></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c"/><heading><desig>C.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Any person that owns 10 percent or more of an appraisal management company and any controlling person of an appraisal management company seeking to be licensed pursuant to this chapter shall be of good moral character, as determined by the Board, and shall submit to a background investigation, as determined by the Board.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d"/><heading><desig>D.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> In addition to the filing fee, each applicant for licensure shall post either a bond or a letter of credit as follows:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> If a bond is posted, the bond shall (i) be in the amount of $ 100,000 or any other amount as set by regulation of the Board, (ii) be in a form prescribed by regulation of the Board, and (iii) accrue to the Commonwealth for the benefit of (a) a claimant against the licensee to secure the faithful performance of the licensee's obligations under this chapter or (b) an appraiser who has performed an appraisal for the licensee for which the appraiser has not been paid. The aggregate liability of the surety shall not exceed the principal sum of the bond. A party having a claim against the licensee may bring suit directly on the surety bond. When a claimant or an appraiser is awarded a final judgment in a court of competent jurisdiction against a licensee of this section for the licensee's failure to faithfully perform its obligations under this chapter or failure to pay an appraiser who performed an appraisal, the claimant or the appraiser may file a claim with the Board for a directive ordering payment from the bond issuer of the amount of the judgment, court costs and reasonable attorney fees as awarded by the court. Such claim shall be filed with the Board no later than 12 months after the judgment becomes final. Upon receipt of the claim against the licensee, the Board may cause its own investigation to be conducted. The amount of the bond shall be restored by the licensee to the full amount required within 15 days after the payment of any claim on the bond. If the licensee fails to restore the full amount of the bond, the Board shall immediately revoke the license of the licensee whose conduct resulted in payment from the bond.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> If a letter of credit is posted, the letter of credit shall (i) be in the amount of $ 100,000 or any other amount as set by regulation of the Board, (ii) be irrevocable and in a form approved by the Board, payable to the Department of Professional Occupational Regulation, and (iii) be for the use and the benefit of (a) a claimant against the licensee to secure the faithful performance of the licensee's obligations under this chapter or (b) an appraiser who has performed an appraisal for the licensee for which the appraiser has not been paid. The aggregate liability on the letter of credit shall not exceed the principal sum of the letter of credit. When a claimant or an appraiser is awarded a final judgment in a court of competent jurisdiction against a licensee of this section for the licensee's failure to faithfully perform its obligations under this chapter or failure to pay an appraiser who performed an appraisal, the claimant or the appraiser may file a claim with the Board for a directive ordering payment from the issuer of the letter of credit of the amount of the judgment, court costs and reasonable attorney fees as awarded by the court. Such claim shall be filed with the Board no later than 12 months after the judgment becomes final. Upon receipt of the claim against the licensee, the Board may cause its own investigation to be conducted. Upon a draw against a letter of credit, the licensee shall provide a new letter of credit in the amount required by this subdivision within 15 days after payment of any claim on the letter of credit. If the licensee fails to restore the full amount of the letter of credit, the Board shall immediately revoke the license of the licensee whose conduct resulted in payment from the bond.</p></bodyText></level></level><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p><citation normalizedCite="2012 VA CH 405"><content><span normalizedCite="2012 Va. Ch. 405">2012, c. 405<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2012#000405#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2014 VA CH 210"><content><span normalizedCite="2014 Va. Ch. 210">2014, c. 210<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2014#000210#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PVX0-004G-K046-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 54.1.</desig><title>PROFESSIONS AND OCCUPATIONS</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="subtitle"><heading><desig>SUBTITLE II.</desig><title>PROFESSIONS AND OCCUPATIONS REGULATED BY THE DEPARTMENT OF PROFESSIONAL AND OCCUPATIONAL REGULATION AND BOARDS WITHIN THE DEPARTMENT</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 20.2.</desig><title>REAL ESTATE APPRAISAL MANAGEMENT COMPANIES</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Banking Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjQyMUFCOUJBNURBNEFDREE3MTNCNDk5QkQ4NUM3RjI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RTFFQkIyQzE4MzlBNEMxNjhGQTcyQzhEOTNFMTQ3MDY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NTkxREYzQzY2NDEyNEExMEIxNDc2QUZFRTY1RkNDRUM</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Civil Procedure</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MzUxNjJDMEQ5N0YwNDMzM0JDMjEzM0UzOTYzMzI3OTU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NUYzMzI4MDRCQ0JFNDczMzkyNkU1Mjk3OTRGOTE5QTM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDIwRkYyRkU2MUYwNDdFRkJCMzQwRDI3OUFERTQ0QUM</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Service on Agents</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MkYzMUQ5NDg3Njg5NEI4RkI1QjQ4QTdDMjZCNTMyNUU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MTI2NDJCMTgxOUQwNDFCOEJDQkMxREE1MTk2NEIzNzc</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Commercial Law (UCC)</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QUI5QjdCNzBDNjY0NEY3QzlGRTNCQTMzQ0IwQ0MzRUQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Amendments &amp; Cancellations</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NzYyNERFRDEyOEVENDMwNUJDODM3NkE0NjBGQ0QxNjE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MEYzRkYyRUI0MkI5NDgxNUIwNTI2MjQwNjE1MkExREY</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Costs &amp; Attorney Fees</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QkUxMDJDRDc1MkJENEI5MEFDOTdGODg5QTZBODVCNzU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDgyNUFFNDU3NTk2NERDQUJGODcwNzhEMDA1ODA0RjA</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Q0FDRjM3RDRFMTU2NEE1ODhCNDhGMUVERENGRDU4NzQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MEYzRkYyRUI0MkI5NDgxNUIwNTI2MjQwNjE1MkExREY</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NTUwMjQ5NkUzN0NBNDFFMDgyMEM0ODQ5NkVBRTE2QkI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MzVCNTFBNDk3REJCNEYyRUI0MkFCNURERUM0NzFEMjg</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Criminal Law &amp; Procedure</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NEU0RkE1OUQwNUQwNDgxODhEODZCMjkzOTg3NThBNzk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Revocation &amp; Remission</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NjI4Q0U3QjE5NEMzNEQyMzlEODdCQ0U0MjU2OTkzMDM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NUZCRUUyMDVEODIzNEY3Qjk0MTRBN0RDNzE3NEE1MjM</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Governments</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjdEQjE4OUJDMzQxNDNEMEI0RTI1QUFCMzJENjEwRTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Time Limitations</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDU5MENDQ0RCNEUyNEZBQjk1MkZGNTZGMzg1RTgyQjI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OUMyNDcyQTZEN0MxNDEzMEI0RDFFOTYwOTFFQjRDNzE</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification><classificationGroup classificationScheme="indexing-terms"><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem score="90"><className>Businesses &amp; Corporations</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjA4OEVGODBENzY4NDcxM0IyQzA1OTEwQzVDODRBOUE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></classificationGroup></metadata></legislativeDoc>