<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#349#000008#    01#          417#">Va. Code Ann. § 8.01-417</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_8.01-417"/><heading><desig>§ 8.01-417.</desig><title>Copies of written statements or transcriptions of verbal statements by injured person to be delivered to him; copies of subpoenaed documents to be provided to other party; disclosure of insurance policy limits</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a"/><heading><desig>A.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Any person who takes from a person who has sustained a personal injury a signed written statement or voice recording of any statement relative to such injury shall deliver to such injured person a copy of such written statement forthwith or a verified typed transcription of such recording within 30 days from the date such statement was given or recording made, when and if the statement or recording is transcribed or in all cases when requested by the injured person or his attorney.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b"/><heading><desig>B.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Unless otherwise ordered for good cause shown, when one party to a civil proceeding subpoenas documents, the subpoenaing party, upon receipt of the subpoenaed documents, shall, if requested in writing, provide true and full copies of the same to any other party or to the attorney for any other party, provided the other party or attorney for the other party pays the reasonable cost of copying or reproducing the subpoenaed documents. This provision does not apply where the subpoenaed documents are returnable to and maintained by the clerk of court in which the action is pending.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c"/><heading><desig>C.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> After he gives written notice that he represents an injured person, an attorney, or an individual injured in a motor vehicle accident if he is not represented by counsel, may, prior to the filing of a civil action for personal injuries sustained as a result of a motor vehicle accident, request in writing that the insurer disclose (i) the limits of liability of any motor vehicle liability or any personal injury liability insurance policy that may be applicable to the claim and (ii) the physical address, if known, of the alleged tortfeasor who is insured by the insurer, if not previously reported to the requesting party. The requesting party shall provide the insurer with the date of the motor vehicle accident, the name and last known address of the alleged tortfeasor if it has been reported to the requesting party, a copy of the accident report, if any, and the claim number, if available. The insurer shall provide the alleged tortfeasor's physical address within 30 days of the receipt of the request. When requesting the limits of liability, the requesting party shall also submit to the insurer the injured person's medical records, medical bills, and wage-loss documentation, if applicable, pertaining to the claimed injury. If the total of the medical bills and wage losses submitted equals or exceeds $ 12,500, the insurer shall respond in writing within 30 days of receipt of the request and shall disclose the limits of liability at the time of the accident of all such policies, regardless of whether the insurer contests the applicability of the policy to the injured person's claim, and the insured's address. Disclosure of the policy limits under this section shall not constitute an admission that the alleged injury or damage is subject to the policy. Information concerning the insurance policy is not by reason of disclosure pursuant to this subsection admissible as evidence at trial.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d"/><heading><desig>D.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> After he gives written notice that he represents the personal representative of the estate of a decedent who died as a result of a motor vehicle accident, an attorney, or the personal representative of the estate of the decedent who died as a result of a motor vehicle accident if he is not represented by counsel, may, prior to the filing of a civil action for wrongful death as a result of a motor vehicle accident, request in writing that the insurer disclose (i) the limits of liability of any motor vehicle liability insurance policy or any personal injury liability insurance policy that may be applicable to the claim and (ii) the physical address, if known, of the alleged tortfeasor who is insured by the insurer, if not previously reported to the requesting party. The requesting party shall provide the insurer with the date of the motor vehicle accident, the name and last known address of the alleged tortfeasor if it has been reported to the requesting party, a copy of the accident report, if any, and the claim number, if available. The insurer shall provide the alleged tortfeasor's physical address within 30 days of the receipt of the request. When requesting the limits of liability, the requesting party shall submit to the insurer the death certificate of the decedent; the certificate of qualification of the personal representative of the decedent's estate; the names and relationships of the statutory beneficiaries of the decedent; medical bills, if any, supporting a claim for damages under subdivision 3 of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 8.01-52"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 8.01-52">§ 8.01-52<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000008#    01#           52#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; and, if at the time the request is made a claim for damages under clause (i) of subdivision 2 of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 8.01-52"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 8.01-52">§ 8.01-52<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000008#    01#           52#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> is anticipated, a description of the source, amount, and payment history of the claimed income loss for each beneficiary. The insurer shall respond in writing within 30 days of receipt of the request and shall disclose the limits of liability at the time of the accident of all such policies, regardless of whether the insurer contests the applicability of the policy to the personal representative's claim, and the insured's address. Disclosure of the policy limits under this section shall not constitute an admission that the alleged death or other damage is subject to the policy. Information concerning the insurance policy is not by reason of disclosure pursuant to this subsection admissible as evidence at trial.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_e"/><heading><desig>E.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> For purposes of subsections C and D, if the alleged tortfeasor has insurance coverage from a self-insured locality for a motor vehicle accident, as described in this section, and the locality is authorized by the alleged tortfeasor to accept service of process on behalf of the alleged tortfeasor and agrees to do so, the locality, in its discretion and instead of disclosing the alleged tortfeasor's home address, may disclose the insured's work address and the name and address of the person who shall accept service of process on behalf of the alleged tortfeasor. If the locality makes such a disclosure, the locality shall not be required to disclose the alleged tortfeasor's home address.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_f"/><heading><desig>F.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> As used in subsections C and D, "insurer" does not include the insurance agency or the insurance agent representing the alleged tortfeasor as the authorized representative or agent with respect to the alleged tortfeasor's motor vehicle insurance policy.</p></bodyText></level><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p>Code 1950, § 8-628.2; 1954, c. 390; 1977, c. 617; <citation normalizedCite="2004 VA CH 345"><content><span normalizedCite="2004 Va. Ch. 345">2004, c. 345<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2004#000345#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2005 VA CH 211"><content><span normalizedCite="2005 Va. Ch. 211">2005, c. 211<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2005#000211#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2008 VA CH 819"><content><span normalizedCite="2008 Va. Ch. 819">2008, c. 819<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2008#000819#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2010 VA CH 354"><content><span normalizedCite="2010 Va. Ch. 354">2010, cc. 354<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2010#000354#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2010 VA CH 435"><content><span normalizedCite="2010 Va. Ch. 435">435<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2010#000435#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2015 VA CH 711"><content><span normalizedCite="2015 Va. Ch. 711">2015, c. 711<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2015#000711#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2016 VA CH 241"><content><span normalizedCite="2016 Va. Ch. 241">2016, cc. 241<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2016#000241#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2016 VA CH 267"><content><span normalizedCite="2016 Va. Ch. 267">267<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2016#000267#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PSD0-004G-K0SY-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 8.01.</desig><title>CIVIL REMEDIES AND PROCEDURE</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 14.</desig><title>EVIDENCE</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="article"><heading><desig>ARTICLE 9.</desig><title>MISCELLANEOUS PROVISIONS</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Civil Procedure</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MzUxNjJDMEQ5N0YwNDMzM0JDMjEzM0UzOTYzMzI3OTU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6ODA3NTUyMjE3RDA2NEU4NzkyRTc1QkNDQ0ZFOUE3Mzk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6M0NBREQ4NDMwMEVBNDk4QUE1QjNGNTc4RDkyRjUwOUY</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Governments</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjdEQjE4OUJDMzQxNDNEMEI0RTI1QUFCMzJENjEwRTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Clerks of Court</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6REVFMjkzRDI1MkU2NERDNjk3OEUxODY0REYwMUI1NjE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NURENzJGNTEyQzM0NEREQUI2RkVCRTM4RTc1RTZBREU</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Insurance Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDM4MzQ2QUYzMTY0NDQzQTkxRDQwRUUzRUM5RDg0OEM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6ODk1Qzg5MzA4MEQ2NDM4QUJGOTZBNkJDOEQ1MTUwNUQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RkE3MEM1QjNFMTFFNEY2MThGNDIwMzQzMzI4RTc4M0M</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RTFEMDYzQTAxQTZDNEYzQzkzODFBM0RBODNGNERDRDQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NzVCREFBMEI5RUMxNEVGNzhCNjRCRTNGODY5RTVBMTE</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RTJENUZEMkQzMzZGNDQ5MDkyNzZGQjk3QUFCNTZDRTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjVCQjlDMTYwQjlFNERDN0FFRTE0RjgxQkI4N0U3RjM</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Torts</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDAwOEM2NTEzQkVDNEI4NzlGMEZERUEyRjQwODM4Njg7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Medical Expenses</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RTMzMDRBNTIzQ0ZFNEVBRDhGQURCN0M1RjBDM0VBQjU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjE5NUQ0Nzc1RjExNDg2RDk3NTkxMjdBQ0M0OEFDMDI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification><classificationGroup classificationScheme="indexing-terms"><classification classificationScheme="legal"/></classificationGroup></metadata></legislativeDoc>