<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#958#0000000038#0000000002#   3407.15#0000000003#">Va. Code Ann. § 38.2-3407.15:3</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_38.2-3407.15_3"/><heading><desig>§ 38.2-3407.15:3.</desig><title>Carrier and intermediary contracts with pharmacy providers; disclosure and updating of maximum allowable cost of drugs; limit on termination or nonrenewal</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a"/><heading><desig>A.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> As used in this section, unless the context requires a different meaning:</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Carrier"</emphasis> has the same meaning ascribed thereto in subsection A of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 38.2-3407.15"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 38.2-3407.15">§ 38.2-3407.15.<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000038#     2#      3407.15#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation></p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Maximum allowable cost"</emphasis> means the maximum dollar amount that a carrier or its intermediary will reimburse a pharmacy provider for a group of drugs rated as "A", "AB", "NR", or "NA" in the most recent edition of the Approved Drug Products with Therapeutic Equivalence Evaluations, also known as the Orange Book, published by the U.S. Food and Drug Administration, or similarly rated by a nationally recognized reference.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Provider contract"</emphasis> has the same meaning ascribed thereto in subsection A of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 38.2-3407.15"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 38.2-3407.15">§ 38.2-3407.15.<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000038#     2#      3407.15#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation></p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b"/><heading><desig>B.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Any contract between a carrier and its intermediary, pursuant to which the intermediary has the right or obligation to establish a maximum allowable cost, and any provider contract between a carrier and a participating pharmacy provider or its contracting agent, pursuant to which the carrier has the right or obligation to establish a maximum allowable cost, shall contain specific provisions that require the intermediary or carrier to:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Update, not less frequently than once every seven days, the maximum allowable cost list, unless there has been no change to the maximum allowable cost of any drug on the list since the last update;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Verify, not less frequently than once every seven days, that the drugs on the maximum allowable cost list are available to participating pharmacy providers from at least one regional or national pharmacy wholesaler and that the amount for each drug is not obsolete and promptly revise the maximum allowable cost if necessary to comply with this subsection;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Provide a process for each participating pharmacy provider to readily access the maximum allowable cost list specific to that provider; and</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_4"/><heading><desig>4.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Prohibit the intermediary or carrier from terminating or failing to renew its contractual relationship with a participating pharmacy provider for invoking its rights under any contractual provision required by this section.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c"/><heading><desig>C.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Any contract between a carrier and its intermediary, pursuant to which the intermediary has the right or obligation to establish a maximum allowable cost, and any provider contract between a carrier and a participating pharmacy provider or its contracting agent, pursuant to which the carrier has the right or obligation to establish a maximum allowable cost, shall contain specific provisions that require the intermediary or carrier to provide a process for an appeal, investigation, and resolution of disputes regarding maximum allowable cost drug pricing that includes:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A time period of 14 days from the date of initial claim adjudication for the participating pharmacy provider to file its dispute request;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A requirement that the dispute request be investigated and resolved within 14 days of its initiation by the participating pharmacy provider;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A telephone number at which the participating pharmacy provider may contact the carrier or its intermediary to speak to a person responsible for processing dispute requests;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c_4"/><heading><desig>4.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A requirement that a carrier or its intermediary, if a dispute request is denied, provide (i) a reason for the denial, and (ii) the national drug code of the drug under dispute that the carrier or its intermediary contends may be purchased by the participating pharmacy provider for an amount that is equal to or less than the maximum allowable cost; and</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c_5"/><heading><desig>5.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A requirement that a carrier or its intermediary, if a dispute is successful, update the maximum allowable cost for the drug under dispute within five days of the determination of the dispute.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d"/><heading><desig>D.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The Commission shall have no jurisdiction to adjudicate individual controversies arising out of this section.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_e"/><heading><desig>E.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> This section shall apply with respect to contracts described in subsections B and C entered into, amended, extended, or renewed on or after January 1, 2016.</p></bodyText></level><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p><citation normalizedCite="2015 VA CH 518"><content><span normalizedCite="2015 Va. Ch. 518">2015, c. 518<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2015#000518#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PWC0-004G-K2YK-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 38.2.</desig><title>INSURANCE</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 34.</desig><title>PROVISIONS RELATING TO ACCIDENT AND SICKNESS INSURANCE</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="article"><heading><desig>ARTICLE 1.</desig><title>GENERAL PROVISIONS</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classificationGroup classificationScheme="indexing-terms"><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem score="90"><className>Insurance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDM4MzQ2QUYzMTY0NDQzQTkxRDQwRUUzRUM5RDg0OEM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Healthcare Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NkUxMkVDQjJDOEY5NDVDQ0E5NTFEMTlDMjIwNzVERjc7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem score="62"><className>Fiscal Intermediaries</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NTE0ODhFRjdBM0E1NDM3QjlEMkYyM0EzRTQ2MUY4NEY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RjE4MDdEODhDQzI4NEQ0NDhGMEI5NTI5OEUyRTUyRjk</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></classificationGroup></metadata></legislativeDoc>