<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#349#000002#     2#         5100#">Va. Code Ann. § 2.2-5100</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_2.2-5100"/><heading><desig>§ 2.2-5100.</desig><title>Short title; definitions</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a"/><heading><desig>A.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> This chapter shall be known and may be cited as the "Virginia Investment Partnership Act."</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b"/><heading><desig>B.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> As used in this chapter, unless the context requires a different meaning:</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Average manufacturing wage"</emphasis> means that amount determined by the Virginia Employment Commission to be the average wage paid manufacturing workers in a locality or region of the Commonwealth.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Average nonmanufacturing wage"</emphasis> means that amount determined by the Virginia Employment Commission to be the average wage paid nonmanufacturing workers in basic employment in a locality or region of the Commonwealth.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Basic employment"</emphasis> means employment that brings new or additional income into Virginia and adds to the gross state product.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Capital investment"</emphasis> means an investment in real property, personal property, or both, at a manufacturing or basic nonmanufacturing facility within the Commonwealth that is capitalized by the company and that increases the productivity of the manufacturing facility, results in the creation, development or utilization of a more advanced technology than is in use immediately prior to such investment, or both. In order to qualify as a capital investment, an investment in technology shall result in a measurable increase in capacity or productivity, a measurable decrease in the production of flawed product, or both. Expenditures for maintenance, replacement or repair of existing machinery, tools and real property shall not constitute a capital investment; however, expenditures for the replacement of property shall not be ineligible for designation as a capital investment if such replacement results in a measurable increase in productivity.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Eligible company"</emphasis> means, for companies located in a Metropolitan Statistical Area with a population of 300,000 or more in the most recently preceding decennial census, a Virginia employer that:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_a"/><heading><desig>a.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> (i) creates or causes to be created at least 400 jobs with average salaries at least 50 percent greater than the Prevailing Average Wage or (ii) creates or causes to be created at least 300 jobs with average salaries at least 100 percent greater than the Prevailing Average Wage, and</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_b"/><heading><desig>b.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> makes a capital investment of at least $ 5 million or $ 6,500 per job, whichever is greater.</p><p>For all companies located elsewhere in Virginia, "eligible company" shall mean a Virginia employer that creates or causes to be created at least 200 jobs with average salaries at least 50 percent greater than the Prevailing Average Wage, and making a capital investment of at least $ 6,500 per job.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Eligible manufacturer or research and development service"</emphasis> means an existing Virginia manufacturer or research and development service that makes a capital investment of at least $ 25 million that is announced on or after June 1, 1998, which investment does not result in any net reduction in employment within one year after the capital investment has been completed and verified. Any entity participating in any other production grant program in the Commonwealth shall not be an eligible manufacturer or research and development service.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Eligible research and development service"</emphasis> means an existing Virginia research and development service that supports manufacturing and that makes a capital investment of at least $ 25 million, which investment does not result in any net reduction in employment within one year after the capital investment has been completed and verified. Any entity participating in any other production grant program in the Commonwealth shall not be eligible.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Existing Virginia manufacturer"</emphasis> means a manufacturer that has a legal presence within the Commonwealth for at least three years prior to making the announcement of the capital investment that makes it an eligible manufacturer.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Flawed product"</emphasis> means an irregular unit of goods that cannot be sold to an end user.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Fund"</emphasis> means the Virginia Investment Partnership Grant Fund created pursuant to <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 2.2-5104"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 2.2-5104">§ 2.2-5104<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000002#     2#         5104#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, comprised of (i) the Major Eligible Employer Grant subfund, (ii) the Investment Performance Grant subfund, and (iii) the Economic Development Incentive Grant subfund.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Major eligible employer"</emphasis> means an existing Virginia manufacturer or any other nonmanufacturing basic employer that makes a capital investment of at least $ 100 million and creates at least 1,000 jobs, or corporate headquarters and other basic employers that make a capital investment of at least $ 100 million and create at least 400 jobs paying at least twice the prevailing average wage for the area.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Manufacturer"</emphasis> means a business firm owning or operating a manufacturing establishment as defined in the Standard Industrial Classification Manual issued by the U.S. Office of Management and Budget or the North American Industry Classification System Manual issued by the United States Census Bureau.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Net present value of benefits to Virginia"</emphasis> means the present value of the amount by which (i) the anticipated additional state tax revenue expected to accrue to the Commonwealth as a result of the capital investment and jobs created, over a period following the completion of the capital investment not to exceed 20 years, exceeds (ii) the value of all incentives provided by the Commonwealth, including any grant under this article, for such capital investment during that period.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"New job"</emphasis> means employment of an indefinite duration at the eligible facility, created as the direct result of the capital investment, for which the standard fringe benefits are paid by the firm for the employee, requiring a minimum of either (i) 35 hours of an employee's time a week for the entire normal year of the firm's operations, which "normal year" must consist of at least 48 weeks or (ii) 1,680 hours per year. Seasonal or temporary positions, positions created when a job function is shifted from an existing location in the Commonwealth to the facility, and positions with contractors, suppliers, and similar multiplier or spin-off jobs shall not qualify as new jobs under this article.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Partnership"</emphasis> means the Virginia Economic Development Partnership.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Prevailing Average Wage"</emphasis> means that amount determined by the Virginia Employment Commission to be the average wage paid workers in the city or county of the Commonwealth where the eligible company is located.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Productivity"</emphasis> means the number of hours of labor required to produce a unit of goods.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Research and development service"</emphasis> means a business firm owning or operating an establishment engaged in conducting research and experimental development that supports manufacturing in the physical, engineering and life sciences as defined in the North American Industry Classification System Manual issued by the United States Census Bureau.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Secretary"</emphasis> means the Secretary of Commerce and Trade.</p></bodyText></level></level><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p><citation normalizedCite="1999 VA CH 875"><content><span normalizedCite="1999 Va. Ch. 875">1999, cc. 875<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1999#000875#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1999 VA CH 961"><content><span normalizedCite="1999 Va. Ch. 961">961<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1999#000961#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, §§ 2.1-548.43:1, 2.1-548.43:2; <citation normalizedCite="2000 VA CH 571"><content><span normalizedCite="2000 Va. Ch. 571">2000, c. 571<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2000#000571#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2001 VA CH 844"><content><span normalizedCite="2001 Va. Ch. 844">2001, c. 844<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2001#000844#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2003 VA CH 17"><content><span normalizedCite="2003 Va. Ch. 17">2003, c. 17<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2003#000017#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2005 VA CH 431"><content><span normalizedCite="2005 Va. Ch. 431">2005, c. 431<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2005#000431#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2009 VA CH 151"><content><span normalizedCite="2009 Va. Ch. 151">2009, cc. 151<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2009#000151#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2009 VA CH 174"><content><span normalizedCite="2009 Va. Ch. 174">174<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2009#000174#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2012 VA CH 196"><content><span normalizedCite="2012 Va. Ch. 196">2012, cc. 196<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2012#000196#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2012 VA CH 407"><content><span normalizedCite="2012 Va. Ch. 407">407<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2012#000407#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PV90-004G-K1T2-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 2.2.</desig><title>ADMINISTRATION OF GOVERNMENT</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="subtitle"><heading><desig>SUBTITLE II.</desig><title>ADMINISTRATION OF STATE GOVERNMENT</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="part"><heading><desig>PART B.</desig><title>TRANSACTION OF PUBLIC BUSINESS</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 51.</desig><title>VIRGINIA INVESTMENT PARTNERSHIP ACT</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Governments</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjdEQjE4OUJDMzQxNDNEMEI0RTI1QUFCMzJENjEwRTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Metropolitan Statistical Areas</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MTBDMUFDMjJERTU0NEY4QUEyQTI2QkRGNjE0MjI0NTQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Njg1MkM3RkYyNzIxNEVFRkJFMTI2NUM4NUU1ODdEM0Q</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Labor &amp; Employment Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MTE3QUQwOTA0MUYzNDlCMEFFMjUwRUNDM0RDRkM5QzM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Definition of Employers</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6ODU0MDU3OTk2NjhCNDcxRUI0NkI2MTAwODczNUMyRjk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6M0Y4OTVEMTE3QTc3NDI5QTkwMjMwMkRBNjRBMUM2NkM</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification><classificationGroup classificationScheme="indexing-terms"><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem score="90"><className>Governments</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjdEQjE4OUJDMzQxNDNEMEI0RTI1QUFCMzJENjEwRTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></classificationGroup></metadata></legislativeDoc>