<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#123#000036#        47#">Va. Code Ann. § 36-47</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_36-47"/><heading><desig>§ 36-47.</desig><title>Consolidated housing authority</title></heading><bodyText><p>If the governing body of each of two or more municipalities (whether or not contiguous) by resolution declares that there is a need for one housing authority to be created for all of the municipalities to exercise in the municipalities the powers and other functions prescribed for a consolidated housing authority, a political subdivision of the Commonwealth to be known as a consolidated housing authority (with a corporate name it selects) shall thereupon exist for all of the municipalities and exercise its public and corporate powers and other functions within its area of operation (as herein defined), including the power to undertake projects therein. Thereupon, any housing authority created for each of the municipalities shall cease to exist except for the purpose of winding up its affairs and executing a deed of its real property to the consolidated housing authority. The creation of a consolidated housing authority and the finding of need therefor shall be subject to the same provisions and limitations of this chapter as are applicable to the creation of a regional housing authority. The provisions of this chapter applicable to regional housing authorities and the commissioners thereof shall be applicable to consolidated housing authorities and the commissioners thereof. The area of operation of a consolidated housing authority shall include all of the territory within the boundaries of each municipality joining in the creation of the authority, except that the area of operation may be changed to include or exclude any municipality or municipalities in the same manner and under the same provisions as provided in this chapter for changing the area of operation of a regional housing authority by including or excluding a county or counties. For all such purposes, the term "board of supervisors" shall be construed as meaning "governing body." The term "county" shall be construed as meaning "municipality" and the terms "county housing authority" and "regional housing authority" shall be construed as meaning "housing authority of the city" and "consolidated housing authority," respectively, unless a different meaning clearly appears from the context.</p><p>The governing body of a municipality for which a housing authority has not been created shall not adopt the above resolution unless it first declares that there is a need for a consolidated housing authority to function in the municipality, which declaration shall be made in the same manner and subject to the same conditions as the declaration of the governing body of a city required by <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 36-4"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 36 -4">§ 36-4<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#123#000036#         4#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> for the purpose of authorizing a housing authority created for a city to transact business and exercise its powers.</p><p>Except as otherwise provided herein, a consolidated housing authority and the commissioners thereof shall, within the area of operation of the consolidated housing authority, have the same functions, rights, powers, duties, privileges, immunities and limitations as those provided for housing authorities created for cities, counties, or groups of counties and the commissioners of such housing authorities, in the same manner as though all the provisions of law applicable to housing authorities created for cities, counties, or groups of counties were applicable to consolidated housing authorities.</p><p>The term "municipality" as used in this chapter shall mean any county, city or town in the Commonwealth.</p><p>The term "residential buildings" as used in this chapter shall include, but not be limited to, any multi-family residential property in which no less than twenty percent of the units will be occupied by persons of low income and the remainder therein by persons of moderate income, both as determined by the housing authority using the criteria set forth in the definition of "persons and families of low and moderate income" in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 36-55.26"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 36 -55.26">§ 36-55.26<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#123#000036#     55.26#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, and any nursing care facility, or any nursing home as defined in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 32.1-123"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 32.1-123">§ 32.1-123<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000032#     1#          123#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p>1942, p. 323; Michie Code 1942, § 3145(4k); 1958, c. 82; 1982, c. 330; 1983, c. 347; 1984, c. 350; 1987, c. 433; 1988, c. 217.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PT30-004G-K3TD-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 36.</desig><title>HOUSING</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 1.</desig><title>HOUSING AUTHORITIES LAW</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="article"><heading><desig>ARTICLE 6.</desig><title>REGIONAL AND CONSOLIDATED HOUSING AUTHORITIES</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Governments</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjdEQjE4OUJDMzQxNDNEMEI0RTI1QUFCMzJENjEwRTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Administrative Boards</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QTYwRUFCMDc5MzQ5NDEyREFEQkU2NkE2MjRGQTlCNzY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Njg1MkM3RkYyNzIxNEVFRkJFMTI2NUM4NUU1ODdEM0Q</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Duties &amp; Powers</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Njk1NTNGMzM0RTc3NDcyMUI4MENCQUQ1RDhEN0M1RUM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Njg1MkM3RkYyNzIxNEVFRkJFMTI2NUM4NUU1ODdEM0Q</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></metadata></legislativeDoc>