<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#349#000038#     2#         1330#">Va. Code Ann. § 38.2-1330</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_38.2-1330"/><heading><desig>§ 38.2-1330.</desig><title>Standards for transactions within an insurance holding company system; adequacy of surplus</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a"/><heading><desig>A.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Transactions within an insurance holding company system to which an insurer subject to registration is a party shall be subject to the following standards:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The terms shall be fair and reasonable;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Agreements for cost-sharing services and management shall include such provisions as required by rule or regulation promulgated by the Commission;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Charges or fees for services performed shall be reasonable;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_4"/><heading><desig>4.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Expenses incurred and payments received shall be allocated to the insurer in conformity with customary insurance accounting practices consistently applied;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_5"/><heading><desig>5.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The books, accounts, and records of each party shall disclose clearly and accurately the precise nature and details of the transactions, including such accounting information as is necessary to support the reasonableness of the charges or fees to the respective parties; and</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_6"/><heading><desig>6.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The insurer's surplus as regards policyholders following any dividends or distributions to shareholder affiliates shall be reasonable in relation to the insurer's outstanding liabilities and adequate to meet its financial needs.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b"/><heading><desig>B.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Transactions described in subdivisions 1 through 7 that involve a domestic insurer and any person in its insurance holding company system, including amendments or modifications of affiliate agreements previously filed pursuant to this section, that are subject to materiality standards contained in such subdivisions may not be entered into unless the insurer has notified the Commission in writing of its intention to enter into the transaction at least 30 days prior thereto, or such shorter period as the Commission may permit, and the Commission has not disapproved it within that period. The notice for amendments or modifications shall include the reasons for the change and the financial impact on the domestic insurer. Informal notice shall be reported, within 30 days after a termination of a previously filed agreement, to the Commission for determination of the type of filing required, if any. Transactions to which this subsection applies, with their materiality standards, are:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Sales, purchases, exchanges, loans, extensions of credit, or investments, provided the transactions are equal to or exceed:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_1_a"/><heading><desig>a.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> With respect to nonlife insurers, the lesser of three percent of the insurer's admitted assets or 25 percent of surplus as regards policyholders as of the immediately preceding December 31; or</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_1_b"/><heading><desig>b.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> With respect to life insurers, three percent of the insurer's admitted assets as of the immediately preceding December 31;</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Loans or extensions of credit to any person who is not an affiliate, where the insurer makes loans or extensions of credit with the agreement or understanding that the proceeds of the transactions, in whole or in substantial part, are to be used to make loans or extensions of credit to, to purchase assets of, or to make investments in, any affiliate of the insurer making the loans or extensions of credit, provided the transactions are equal to or exceed:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_2_a"/><heading><desig>a.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> With respect to nonlife insurers, the lesser of three percent of the insurer's admitted assets or 25 percent of surplus as regards policyholders as of the immediately preceding December 31; or</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_2_b"/><heading><desig>b.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> With respect to life insurers, three percent of the insurer's admitted assets as of the immediately preceding December 31;</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Reinsurance agreements or modifications thereto, including:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_3_a"/><heading><desig>a.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> All reinsurance pooling agreements; and</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_3_b"/><heading><desig>b.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Agreements in which the reinsurance premium or a change in the insurer's liabilities, or the projected reinsurance premium or a change in the insurer's liabilities in any of the next three years, equals or exceeds five percent of the insurer's surplus as regards policyholders, as of the immediately preceding December 31, including those agreements that may require as consideration the transfer of assets from an insurer to a nonaffiliate, if an agreement or understanding exists between the insurer and nonaffiliate that any portion of the assets will be transferred to one or more affiliates of the insurer;</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_4"/><heading><desig>4.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> All management agreements, service contracts, tax allocation agreements, guarantees, and cost-sharing arrangements;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_5"/><heading><desig>5.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Guarantees when made by a domestic insurer, provided, however, that a guarantee that is quantifiable as to amount is not subject to the notice requirements of this subdivision unless it exceeds the lesser of one-half of one percent of the insurer's admitted assets or 10 percent of surplus as regards policyholders as of the immediately preceding December 31. Further, all guarantees that are not quantifiable as to amount are subject to the notice requirements of this subdivision;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_6"/><heading><desig>6.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Direct or indirect acquisitions or investments in a person that controls the insurer or in an affiliate of the insurer in an amount that, together with its present holdings in such investments, exceeds two and one-half percent of the insurer's surplus to policyholders. The Commission may exempt such a transaction by regulation; and</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_7"/><heading><desig>7.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Any material transactions that the Commission determines may adversely affect the interests of the insurer's policyholders.</p><p><pre/>Nothing in this subsection shall be deemed to authorize or permit any transactions that, in the case of an insurer not a member of the same insurance holding company system, would be otherwise contrary to law.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c"/><heading><desig>C.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> In addition:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Notwithstanding the control of a domestic insurer by any person, the officers and directors of the insurer shall not thereby be relieved of any obligation or liability to which they would otherwise be subject by law, and the insurer shall be managed so as to assure its separate operating identity consistent with this article;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Nothing in this section shall preclude a domestic insurer from having or sharing a common management or cooperative or joint use of personnel, property, or services with one or more other persons under arrangements meeting the standards of subsection A;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Not less than one-third of the directors of a domestic insurer, and not less than one-third of the members of each committee of the board of directors of any domestic insurer, shall be persons who are not officers or employees of the insurer or of any entity controlling, controlled by, or under common control with the insurer and who are not beneficial owners of a controlling interest in the voting stock of the insurer or entity. At least one such person shall be included in any quorum for the transaction of business at any meeting of the board of directors or any committee thereof;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c_4"/><heading><desig>4.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The board of directors of a domestic insurer shall establish one or more committees composed solely of directors who are not officers or employees of the insurer or of any entity controlling, controlled by, or under common control with the insurer and who are not beneficial owners of a controlling interest in the voting stock of the insurer or any such entity. The committee or committees shall have responsibility for nominating candidates for director for election by shareholders or policyholders, evaluating the performance of officers deemed to be principal officers of the insurer, and recommending to the board of directors the selection and compensation of the principal officers;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c_5"/><heading><desig>5.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The provisions of subdivisions 3 and 4 shall not apply to a domestic insurer if the person controlling the insurer, such as an insurer, a mutual insurance holding company, or a publicly held corporation, has a board of directors and committees thereof that meet the requirements of subdivisions 3 and 4 with respect to such controlling entity; and</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c_6"/><heading><desig>6.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> An insurer may make application to the Commission for a waiver from the requirements of this subsection if the insurer's annual direct written and assumed premium, excluding premiums reinsured with the Federal Crop Insurance Corporation and National Flood Insurance Program, is less than $ 300 million. An insurer may also make application to the Commission for a waiver from the requirements of this subsection based upon unique circumstances. The Commission may consider various factors including the type of business entity, volume of business written, availability of qualified board members, or ownership or organizational structure of the entity.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d"/><heading><desig>D.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> For purposes of this article, in determining whether an insurer's surplus as regards policyholders is reasonable in relation to the insurer's outstanding liabilities and adequate to meet its financial needs, the following factors, among others, shall be considered:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The size of the insurer as measured by its assets, capital and surplus, reserves, premium writings, insurance in force, and other appropriate criteria;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The extent to which the insurer's business is diversified among different lines of insurance;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The number and size of risks insured in each line of business;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d_4"/><heading><desig>4.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The extent of the geographical dispersion of the insurer's insured risk;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d_5"/><heading><desig>5.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The nature and extent of the insurer's reinsurance program;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d_6"/><heading><desig>6.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The quality, diversification, and liquidity of the insurer's investment portfolio;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d_7"/><heading><desig>7.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The recent past and projected future trend in the size of the insurer's surplus to policyholders;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d_8"/><heading><desig>8.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The recent past and projected future trend in the size of the insurer's investment portfolio;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d_9"/><heading><desig>9.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The surplus as regards policyholders maintained by other comparable insurers;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d_10"/><heading><desig>10.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The adequacy of the insurer's reserves;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d_11"/><heading><desig>11.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The quality of the insurer's earnings and the extent to which the reported earnings of the insurer include extraordinary items; and</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d_12"/><heading><desig>12.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The quality and liquidity of investments in affiliates. The Commission in its judgment may classify any investment as a nonadmitted asset for the purpose of determining the adequacy of surplus as regards policyholders.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_e"/><heading><desig>E.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> No domestic insurer shall enter into transactions that are part of a plan or series of like transactions with persons within the insurance holding company system if the purpose of those separate transactions is to avoid the statutory threshold amount and thus avoid the review that otherwise would be required. If the Commission determines that separate transactions were entered into over any 12-month period for that purpose, the Commission may exercise its authority under <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 38.2-1334.2:2"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 38.2-1334.2:2">§ 38.2-1334.2:2.<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#958#0000000038#0000000002#    1334.2#0000000002#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation></p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_f"/><heading><desig>F.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The Commission, in reviewing transactions pursuant to subsection B, shall consider whether the transactions comply with the standards set forth in subsection A and whether they may adversely affect the interests of policyholders.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_g"/><heading><desig>G.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The Commission shall be notified in writing within 30 days of any investment of the domestic insurer in any one corporation if the total investment in such corporation by the insurance holding company system exceeds 10 percent of such corporation's voting securities.</p></bodyText></level><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p>1973, c. 505, § 38.1-178.3; 1986, c. 562; 1987, c. 417; <citation normalizedCite="1992 VA CH 588"><content><span normalizedCite="1992 Va. Ch. 588">1992, c. 588<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1992#000588#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2006 VA CH 577"><content><span normalizedCite="2006 Va. Ch. 577">2006, c. 577<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2006#000577#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2014 VA CH 309"><content><span normalizedCite="2014 Va. Ch. 309">2014, c. 309<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2014#000309#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PT40-004G-K4C6-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 38.2.</desig><title>INSURANCE</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 13.</desig><title>REPORTS, RESERVES AND EXAMINATIONS, INSURANCE HOLDING COMPANIES, REINSURANCE INTERMEDIARIES, AND MANAGING GENERAL AGENTS</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="article"><heading><desig>ARTICLE 5.</desig><title>INSURANCE HOLDING COMPANIES</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Banking Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjQyMUFCOUJBNURBNEFDREE3MTNCNDk5QkQ4NUM3RjI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>US National Flood Insurance Program</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MURFNzlFQzMzRjA5NDQ3NzhDNjA5RkE4RDVFQjU0RkM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MTEzMzQzODVBMzEzNDczMEE1ODM5N0REMTc3QzFDMkI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Reserves</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6N0ZGRjQ1NTA5NjAzNDY0MzlGNzZBM0MzNTczRTA5NEY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjA5REUyQzJFMEVCNDYzMjkxNDNGNDEwRDRENTA3OUQ</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>US National Flood Insurance Program</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MURFNzlFQzMzRjA5NDQ3NzhDNjA5RkE4RDVFQjU0RkM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MTEzMzQzODVBMzEzNDczMEE1ODM5N0REMTc3QzFDMkI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Contracts Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QzY0RTZFMzE0RjkwNDdFQUI5M0U5N0ZFMjYyREMyQzU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDIwM0RENTlDQjRGNDZBOEEzREMyRERCNjRGMjc5MzI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RjlEQ0Q0NzUyNTNENDYzMDg3ODVDNTIyNDIzOTdCNTQ</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Pooling Agreements</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MkU0MDk2OEU1NDEzNDdGQkIyQTRFQTg4M0M5REFCQ0Y7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Qjg1NzgyRDNGQzg1NEM5Nzg3RjA3MEUwRTA1QUI0NkU</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Insurance Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDM4MzQ2QUYzMTY0NDQzQTkxRDQwRUUzRUM5RDg0OEM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Cash Surrender Value</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NjFFMjY3OTFENUVBNDU4RTg3RDY3M0QyMEMwMTM0NzU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MzFEOTQ4RjM2RDk4NDJDNEJERDY1NjREOEVGMTRCOTA</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Crop Insurance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NkM0RThERjhDMDUxNEEyRjk3NDUzRThFRjAxRjNBMEI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDBDODI0OTUzNzQzNDA0MkExMkFBOTQ4NzcyREM1RjQ</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Flood Insurance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RkFFNEQyNDE4NUI1NEIwRDk5NTVFRkU2M0VBNkJGNjU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDBDODI0OTUzNzQzNDA0MkExMkFBOTQ4NzcyREM1RjQ</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NzA4NzhCMTQ4MTk0NDY3NDkzQjM5QjJDMEFGODk1RUM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDI3MjQ3NDBDODZENDNCNUJCNzgwNzgwQTBGNDkxRTQ</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Late Premiums &amp; Nonpayment</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RDhDM0RCNEFGRUU0NEVGNDg3QjQ4NThBOTdEQ0IyRDQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjVGMDBDMkY2QzA0NDYyOTg0MEU4QUQ1QzEwMTlFOEI</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Notice Requirements</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MkUwNjY2QUVERDA1NDJEMEE3NDRFREUzQUFEMkQ2QUQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RkE2MEIwQkEwRTExNDVGOUJCRDhBRUQ3QTRGNDdDNTI</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Reserves</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6N0ZGRjQ1NTA5NjAzNDY0MzlGNzZBM0MzNTczRTA5NEY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjA5REUyQzJFMEVCNDYzMjkxNDNGNDEwRDRENTA3OUQ</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Public Health &amp; Welfare Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDYwRTY1MDg3MTk5NDUyNkFFRDI1RjJBRERGQ0UxNzI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Emergency Services</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Q0E1M0VGRUVDNkJENDMyMkJGQjE5OThCMTVGNUMyREU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDZDNTZENUNCRjVBNEY4OEIyQzVBNjRDRTcyOEQ4NDQ</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification><classificationGroup classificationScheme="indexing-terms"><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem score="90"><className>Insurance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDM4MzQ2QUYzMTY0NDQzQTkxRDQwRUUzRUM5RDg0OEM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></classificationGroup></metadata></legislativeDoc>