<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#349#000008#    4a#          302#">Va. Code Ann. § 8.4A-302</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_8.4a-302"/><heading><desig>§ 8.4A-302.</desig><title>Obligations of receiving bank in execution of payment order</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a"/><heading><desig>(a)</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Except as provided in subsections (b) through (d) of this section, if the receiving bank accepts a payment order pursuant to subsection (a) of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 8.4A-209"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 8.4A-209">§ 8.4A-209<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000008#    4a#          209#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, the bank has the following obligations in executing the order:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_1"/><heading><desig>(1)</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The receiving bank is obliged to issue, on the execution date, a payment order complying with the sender's order and to follow the sender's instructions concerning (i) any intermediary bank or funds-transfer system to be used in carrying out the funds transfer, or (ii) the means by which payment orders are to be transmitted in the funds transfer. If the originator's bank issues a payment order to an intermediary bank, the originator's bank is obliged to instruct the intermediary bank according to the instruction of the originator.  An intermediary bank in the funds transfer is similarly bound by an instruction given to it by the sender of the payment order it accepts.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_2"/><heading><desig>(2)</desig></heading><bodyText><p> If the sender's instruction states that the funds transfer is to be carried out telephonically or by wire transfer or otherwise indicates that the funds transfer is to be carried out by the most expeditious means, the receiving bank is obliged to transmit its payment order by the most expeditious available means, and to instruct any intermediary bank accordingly.  If a sender's instruction states a payment date, the receiving bank is obliged to transmit its payment order at a time and by means reasonably necessary to allow payment to the beneficiary on the payment date or as soon thereafter as is feasible.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b"/><heading><desig>(b)</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Unless otherwise instructed, a receiving bank executing a payment order may (i) use any funds-transfer system if use of that system is reasonable in the circumstances, and (ii) issue a payment order to the beneficiary's bank or to an intermediary bank through which a payment order conforming to the sender's order can expeditiously be issued to the beneficiary's bank if the receiving bank exercises ordinary care in the selection of the intermediary bank.  A receiving bank is not required to follow an instruction of the sender designating a funds-transfer system to be used in carrying out the funds transfer if the receiving bank, in good faith, determines that it is not feasible to follow the instruction or that following the instruction would unduly delay completion of the funds transfer.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c"/><heading><desig>(c)</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Unless subdivision (a) (2) of this section applies or the receiving bank is otherwise instructed, the bank may execute a payment order by transmitting its payment order by first class mail or by any means reasonable in the circumstances.  If the receiving bank is instructed to execute the sender's order by transmitting its payment order by a particular means, the receiving bank may issue its payment order by the means stated or by any means as expeditious as the means stated.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d"/><heading><desig>(d)</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Unless instructed by the sender, (i) the receiving bank may not obtain payment of its charges for services and expenses in connection with the execution of the sender's order by issuing a payment order in an amount equal to the amount of the sender's order less the amount of the charges, and (ii) may not instruct a subsequent receiving bank to obtain payment of its charges in the same manner.</p></bodyText></level><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p><citation normalizedCite="1990 VA CH 9"><content><span normalizedCite="1990 Va. Ch. 9">1990, c. 9<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1990#000009#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PTS0-004G-K35X-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 8.4A.</desig><title>COMMERCIAL CODE--FUNDS TRANSFERS</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="part"><heading><desig>PART 3.</desig><title>EXECUTION OF SENDER'S PAYMENT ORDER BY RECEIVING BANK</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Commercial Law (UCC)</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QUI5QjdCNzBDNjY0NEY3QzlGRTNCQTMzQ0IwQ0MzRUQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Execution of Payment Orders</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDkyNzc0NDFGM0ZENEVBQkIwNUEyRUY1QzU0N0I2N0Y7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RTYyOEQ1QzBDQzA4NDQ1RDk4MTI5NzdCMUUxMjZBMDI</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NzdDRDRFMzY5MDJBNDgxQjhCNTEwMjNGMERFQUI5QTY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RTYyOEQ1QzBDQzA4NDQ1RDk4MTI5NzdCMUUxMjZBMDI</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Issuance &amp; Acceptance of Payment Orders</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NzNFQTVFODBCNDRBNDAzQkJBQzVCMUE0MTUwQTI0QjY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RTYyOEQ1QzBDQzA4NDQ1RDk4MTI5NzdCMUUxMjZBMDI</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Receipt of Payment Orders</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6REYzNDZGOTNDNEFDNDE4MUFGNDgzNzJBOEExNDc4QTY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RTYyOEQ1QzBDQzA4NDQ1RDk4MTI5NzdCMUUxMjZBMDI</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Types of Banks</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NjZCQzUyQ0VEM0M5NDNENkE0QTA1RDdDODQ3NkMxN0Q7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QUM0RDg5MTE2M0U4NDU2Rjg5QzI3NDhFRDQyRDVDNDA</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification><classificationGroup classificationScheme="indexing-terms"><classification classificationScheme="legal"/></classificationGroup></metadata></legislativeDoc>