<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#349#000046#     2#       2011.9#">Va. Code Ann. § 46.2-2011.9</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_46.2-2011.9"/><heading><desig>§ 46.2-2011.9.</desig><title>Bond and letter of credit requirements</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a"/><heading><desig>A.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Every applicant for an original certificate under this chapter shall obtain and file with the Department, along with the application, a surety bond or an irrevocable letter of credit, in addition to any other bond or letter of credit required by law, in the amount of $ 25,000, which shall remain in effect for the first three years of licensure. The bond or letter of credit shall be in a form and content acceptable to the Department. The bond or letter of credit shall be conditioned on a statement by the applicant that the applicant will not practice fraud, make any fraudulent representation, or violate any provision of this chapter in the conduct of the applicant's business. The Department may, without holding a hearing, suspend the certificate during the period that the certificate holder does not have a sufficient bond or letter of credit on file.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b"/><heading><desig>B.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Every applicant for an original license pursuant to this chapter shall obtain and file with the Department, along with the application, a surety bond or an irrevocable letter of credit, in addition to any other bond or letter of credit required by law, in the amount of $ 25,000. The bond or letter of credit shall be in a form and content acceptable to the Department. The bond or letter of credit shall be conditioned on a statement by the applicant that the applicant will not practice fraud, make any fraudulent representation, or violate any provision of this chapter in the conduct of the applicant's business. The Department may, without holding a hearing, suspend the license during the period that the licensee does not have a sufficient bond or letter of credit on file.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c"/><heading><desig>C.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> If a person suffers any of the following: (i) loss or damage in connection with the transportation service by reason of fraud practiced on him or fraudulent representation made to him by a licensee or certificate holder or his agent or employee acting within the scope of employment; (ii) loss or damage by reason of a violation by a licensee or certificate holder or his agent or employee of any provision of this chapter in connection with the transportation service; or (iii) loss or damage resulting from a breach of a contract entered into on or after the effective date of this act, that person shall have a claim against the licensee or certificate holder's bond or letter of credit, and may recover from such bond or letter of credit the amount awarded to such person by final judgment of a court of competent jurisdiction against the licensee or certificate holder as a result of such loss or damage up to, but not exceeding, the amount of the bond or letter of credit.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d"/><heading><desig>D.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The licensee or certificate holder's surety shall notify the Department when a claim is made against a licensee or certificate holder's bond, when a claim is paid and when the bond is canceled. Such notification shall include the amount of a claim and the circumstances surrounding the claim. Notification of cancellation shall include the effective date and reason for cancellation.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_e"/><heading><desig>E.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The surety on any bond filed by a licensee or certificate holder shall be released and discharged from all liability accruing on such bond after the expiration of 60 days from the date on which the surety files with the Department a written request to be released and discharged. Such request shall not operate to relieve, release or discharge the surety from any liability already accrued or which shall accrue before the expiration of the 60-day period.</p></bodyText></level><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p><citation normalizedCite="2001 VA CH 596"><content><span normalizedCite="2001 Va. Ch. 596">2001, c. 596<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2001#000596#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2013 VA CH 165"><content><span normalizedCite="2013 Va. Ch. 165">2013, cc. 165<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2013#000165#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2013 VA CH 582"><content><span normalizedCite="2013 Va. Ch. 582">582<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2013#000582#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PV70-004G-K0JD-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 46.2.</desig><title>MOTOR VEHICLES</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="subtitle"><heading><desig>SUBTITLE V.</desig><title>MOTOR CARRIERS</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 20.</desig><title>REGULATION OF PASSENGER CARRIERS</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="article"><heading><desig>ARTICLE 1.</desig><title>MOTOR CARRIERS OF PASSENGERS -- GENERALLY</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Civil Procedure</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MzUxNjJDMEQ5N0YwNDMzM0JDMjEzM0UzOTYzMzI3OTU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Execution of Bonds</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RTM5MjlDQ0NDNzM0NDFCNjkwODUxNTI0MUU2MUE4NjI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RTJEQTFGMDU2MUNGNEY1MTg0NjcyRUM0OEMzMTVDNDE</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Procedural Matters</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RUM1REM4OEVENDc1NDA3RDk0MjZCOTU0MDJGM0MzMTM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MkEwMEQ0M0JCOTA1NEQ1NUFCOTAzQURBOThGRjEwOTc</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Commercial Law (UCC)</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QUI5QjdCNzBDNjY0NEY3QzlGRTNCQTMzQ0IwQ0MzRUQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Forgeries &amp; Fraud</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUE3Q0ExQjEwNjc1NDdGM0EwM0I0QzU0QjAyQjI1OTY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MzQ4RUVFMjkwRjNCNDU0REEzNEVFNjUyNDlBRTA4NTk</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification><classificationGroup classificationScheme="indexing-terms"><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem score="90"><className>Transportation</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RTYzRTk5RDVBQkQ2NDcwQzk2NTU3ODQ5OEE3NDlBNzk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></classificationGroup></metadata></legislativeDoc>