<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#349#000008#    01#        407.1#">Va. Code Ann. § 8.01-407.1</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_8.01-407.1"/><heading><desig>§ 8.01-407.1.</desig><title>Identity of persons communicating anonymously over the Internet</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a"/><heading><desig>A.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> In civil proceedings where it is alleged that an anonymous individual has engaged in Internet communications that are tortious, any subpoena seeking information held by a nongovernmental person or entity that would identify the tortfeasor shall be governed by the following procedure unless more expedited scheduling directions have been ordered by the court upon consideration of the interests of each person affected thereby:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> At least thirty days prior to the date on which disclosure is sought, a party seeking information identifying an anonymous communicator shall file with the appropriate circuit court a complete copy of the subpoena and all items annexed or incorporated therein, along with supporting material showing:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_1_a"/><heading><desig>a.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> That one or more communications that are or may be tortious or illegal have been made by the anonymous communicator, or that the party requesting the subpoena has a legitimate, good faith basis to contend that such party is the victim of conduct actionable in the jurisdiction where the suit was filed. A copy of the communications that are the subject of the action or subpoena shall be submitted.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_1_b"/><heading><desig>b.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> That other reasonable efforts to identify the anonymous communicator have proven fruitless.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_1_c"/><heading><desig>c.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> That the identity of the anonymous communicator is important, is centrally needed to advance the claim, relates to a core claim or defense, or is directly and materially relevant to that claim or defense.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_1_d"/><heading><desig>d.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> That no motion to dismiss, motion for judgment on the pleadings, or judgment as a matter of law, demurrer or summary judgment-type motion challenging the viability of the lawsuit of the underlying plaintiff is pending. The pendency of such a motion may be considered by the court in determining whether to enforce, suspend or strike the proposed disclosure obligation under the subpoena.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_1_e"/><heading><desig>e.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> That the individuals or entities to whom the subpoena is addressed are likely to have responsive information.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_1_f"/><heading><desig>f.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> If the subpoena sought relates to an action pending in another jurisdiction, the application shall contain a copy of the pleadings in such action, along with the mandate, writ or commission of the court where the action is pending that authorizes the discovery of the information sought in the Commonwealth.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Two copies of the subpoena and supporting materials set forth in subdivision A. 1. a. through f. shall be served upon the person to whom it is addressed along with payment sufficient to cover postage for mailing one copy of the application within the United States by registered mail, return receipt requested.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Except where the anonymous communicator has consented to disclosure in advance, within five business days after receipt of a subpoena and supporting materials calling for disclosure of identifying information concerning an anonymous communicator, the individual or entity to whom the subpoena is addressed shall (i) send an electronic mail notification to the anonymous communicator reporting that the subpoena has been received if an e-mail address is available and (ii) dispatch one copy thereof, by registered mail or commercial delivery service, return receipt requested, to the anonymous communicator at his last known address, if any is on file with the person to whom the subpoena is addressed.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_4"/><heading><desig>4.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> At least seven business days prior to the date on which disclosure is sought under the subpoena, any interested person may file a detailed written objection, motion to quash, or motion for protective order. Any such papers filed by the anonymous communicator shall be served on or before the date of filing upon the party seeking the subpoena and the party to whom the subpoena is addressed. Any such papers filed by the party to whom the subpoena is addressed shall be served on or before the date of filing upon the party seeking the subpoena and the anonymous communicator whose identifying information is sought. Service is effective when it has been mailed, dispatched by commercial delivery service, transmitted by facsimile, or delivered to counsel of record and to parties having no counsel.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_5"/><heading><desig>5.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Any written objection, motion to quash, or motion for protective order shall set forth all grounds relied upon for denying the disclosure sought in the subpoena and shall also address to the extent feasible (i) whether the identity of the anonymous communicator has been disclosed in any way beyond its recordation in the account records of the party to whom the subpoena is addressed, (ii) whether the subpoena fails to allow a reasonable time for compliance, (iii) whether it requires disclosure of privileged or other protected matter and no exception or waiver applies, or (iv) whether it subjects a person to undue burden.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_6"/><heading><desig>6.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The party to whom the subpoena is addressed shall not comply with the subpoena earlier than three business days before the date on which disclosure is due, to allow the anonymous communicator the opportunity to object. If any person files a written objection, motion to quash, or motion for protective order, compliance with the subpoena shall be deferred until the appropriate court rules on the obligation to comply. If an objection or motion is made, the party serving the subpoena shall not be entitled to inspect or copy the materials except pursuant to an order of the court on behalf of which the subpoena was issued. If an objection or motion has been filed, any interested person may notice the matter for a hearing. Two copies of any such notice shall be served upon the subpoenaed party, who shall mail one copy thereof, by registered mail or commercial delivery service, return receipt requested, to the anonymous communicator whose identifying information is the subject of the subpoena at that person's last known address.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b"/><heading><desig>B.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The party requesting or issuing a subpoena for information identifying an anonymous Internet communicator shall serve along with each copy of such subpoena notices in boldface capital letters in substantially this form:</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it"> NOTICE TO INTERNET SERVICE PROVIDER</emphasis></p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it"> WITHIN FIVE BUSINESS DAYS AFTER RECEIPT OF THIS SUBPOENA CALLING FOR IDENTIFYING INFORMATION CONCERNING YOUR CLIENT, SUBSCRIBER OR CUSTOMER, EXCEPT WHERE CONSENT TO DISCLOSURE HAS BEEN GIVEN IN ADVANCE, YOU ARE REQUIRED BY <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 8.01-407.1"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 8.01-407.1">§ 8.01-407.1 OF THE CODE OF VIRGINIA<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000008#    01#        407.1#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> TO MAIL ONE COPY THEREOF, BY REGISTERED MAIL OR COMMERCIAL DELIVERY SERVICE, RETURN RECEIPT REQUESTED, TO THE CLIENT, SUBSCRIBER OR CUSTOMER WHOSE IDENTIFYING INFORMATION IS THE SUBJECT OF THE SUBPOENA. AT LEAST SEVEN BUSINESS DAYS PRIOR TO THE DATE ON WHICH DISCLOSURE IS SOUGHT YOU MAY, BUT ARE NOT REQUIRED TO, FILE A DETAILED WRITTEN OBJECTION, MOTION TO QUASH OR MOTION FOR PROTECTIVE ORDER. ANY SUCH OBJECTION OR MOTION SHALL BE SERVED UPON THE PARTY INITIATING THE SUBPOENA AND UPON THE CLIENT, SUBSCRIBER OR CUSTOMER WHOSE IDENTIFYING INFORMATION IS SOUGHT.</emphasis></p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it"> IF YOU CHOOSE NOT TO OBJECT TO THE SUBPOENA, YOU MUST ALLOW TIME FOR YOUR CLIENT, SUBSCRIBER OR CUSTOMER TO FILE HIS OWN OBJECTION, THEREFORE YOU MUST NOT RESPOND TO THE SUBPOENA ANY EARLIER THAN THREE BUSINESS DAYS BEFORE THE DISCLOSURE IS DUE.</emphasis></p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it"> IF YOU RECEIVE NOTICE THAT YOUR CLIENT, SUBSCRIBER OR CUSTOMER HAS FILED A WRITTEN OBJECTION, MOTION TO QUASH OR MOTION FOR PROTECTIVE ORDER REGARDING THIS SUBPOENA, OR IF YOU FILE A MOTION TO QUASH THIS SUBPOENA, NO DISCLOSURE PURSUANT TO THE SUBPOENA SHALL BE MADE EXCEPT PURSUANT TO AN ORDER OF THE COURT ON BEHALF OF WHICH THE SUBPOENA WAS ISSUED. </emphasis></p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it"> NOTICE TO INTERNET USER</emphasis></p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it"> THE ATTACHED PAPERS MEAN THAT<emphasis typeStyle="un"><pre/></emphasis></emphasis></p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it"> (INSERT NAME OF PARTY REQUESTING OR CAUSING ISSUANCE OF THE SUBPOENA) HAS </emphasis><br/><emphasis typeStyle="it">EITHER ASKED THE COURT TO ISSUE A SUBPOENA, OR A SUBPOENA HAS BEEN ISSUED, TO </emphasis><br/><emphasis typeStyle="it">YOUR INTERNET SERVICE PROVIDER<emphasis typeStyle="un"><pre/></emphasis></emphasis></p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it"> (INSERT NAME OF INTERNET SERVICE PROVIDER) REQUIRING PRODUCTION OF INFORMATION REGARDING YOUR IDENTITY. UNLESS A DETAILED WRITTEN OBJECTION IS FILED WITH THE COURT, THE SERVICE PROVIDER WILL BE REQUIRED BY LAW TO RESPOND BY PROVIDING THE REQUIRED INFORMATION. IF YOU BELIEVE YOUR IDENTIFYING INFORMATION SHOULD NOT BE DISCLOSED AND OBJECT TO SUCH DISCLOSURE, YOU HAVE THE RIGHT TO FILE WITH THE CLERK OF COURT A DETAILED WRITTEN OBJECTION, MOTION TO QUASH THE SUBPOENA OR MOTION TO OBTAIN A PROTECTIVE ORDER. YOU MAY ELECT TO CONTACT AN ATTORNEY TO REPRESENT YOUR INTERESTS. IF YOU ELECT TO FILE A WRITTEN OBJECTION, MOTION TO QUASH, OR MOTION FOR PROTECTIVE ORDER, IT SHOULD BE FILED AS SOON AS POSSIBLE, AND MUST IN ALL INSTANCES BE FILED NO LESS THAN SEVEN BUSINESS DAYS BEFORE THE DATE ON WHICH DISCLOSURE IS DUE (LISTED IN THE SUBPOENA). IF YOU ELECT TO FILE A WRITTEN OBJECTION OR MOTION AGAINST THIS SUBPOENA, YOU MUST AT THE SAME TIME SEND A COPY OF THAT OBJECTION OR MOTION TO BOTH YOUR INTERNET SERVICE PROVIDER AND THE PARTY WHO REQUESTED THE SUBPOENA. IF YOU WISH TO OPPOSE THE ATTACHED SUBPOENA, IN WHOLE OR IN PART, YOU OR YOUR ATTORNEY MAY FILE A WRITTEN OBJECTION, A MOTION TO QUASH THE SUBPOENA, OR A MOTION FOR A PROTECTIVE ORDER OR YOU MAY USE THE FORM BELOW, WHICH MUST BE FILED WITH THE COURT AND SERVED UPON THE PARTY REQUESTING THE SUBPOENA AND THE INTERNET SERVICE PROVIDER BY MAILING AT LEAST SEVEN BUSINESS DAYS PRIOR TO THE DATE SET IN THE SUBPOENA FOR DISCLOSURE: </emphasis></p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it"><emphasis typeStyle="un"><pre/></emphasis></emphasis></p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it"> Name of Court Listed on Subpoena</emphasis></p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it"><emphasis typeStyle="un"><pre/></emphasis></emphasis></p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it"> Name of Party Seeking Information</emphasis></p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it"> Case No. <emphasis typeStyle="un"><pre/></emphasis></emphasis></p><p>OBJECTION TO SUBPOENA DUCES TECUM </p><p>I object to the Subpoena Duces Tecum addressed to<emphasis typeStyle="un"><pre/></emphasis></p><p>for the following reasons:</p><p>[Name of Internet Service Provider to Whom the Subpoena is Addressed]</p><p>(Please PRINT. Set forth, in detail, all reasons why the subpoena should not be complied with, and in addition, state (i) whether the identity of the anonymous communicator has been disclosed in any fashion, (ii) whether the subpoena fails to allow a reasonable time for compliance, (iii) whether it requires disclosure of privileged or other protected matter and no exception or waiver applies, or (iv) whether it subjects a person to undue burden.)</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="un"><pre/></emphasis></p><p><emphasis typeStyle="un"><pre/></emphasis></p><p><emphasis typeStyle="un"><pre/></emphasis></p><p><emphasis typeStyle="un"><pre/></emphasis></p><p><emphasis typeStyle="un"><pre/></emphasis></p><p><emphasis typeStyle="un"><pre/></emphasis></p><p><emphasis typeStyle="un"><pre/></emphasis></p><p><emphasis typeStyle="un"><pre/></emphasis></p><p>(attach additional sheets if needed)</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="un"><pre/></emphasis></p><p>Respectfully Submitted,</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="un"><pre/></emphasis></p><p>John Doe<emphasis typeStyle="un"><pre/></emphasis></p><p><emphasis typeStyle="un"><pre/></emphasis></p><p>Enter e-mail nickname or other<emphasis typeStyle="un"><pre/></emphasis></p><p>alias used in communicating via<emphasis typeStyle="un"><pre/></emphasis></p><p>the Internet service provider to<emphasis typeStyle="un"><pre/></emphasis></p><p>whom the subpoena is addressed.<emphasis typeStyle="un"><pre/></emphasis></p><p>CERTIFICATE </p><p>I hereby certify that a true copy of the above Objection to Subpoena Duces Tecum was mailed this <emphasis typeStyle="un"><pre/></emphasis> day of <emphasis typeStyle="un"><pre/></emphasis>, (month, year), to</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="un"><pre/></emphasis></p><p>(Name and address of party seeking information) and</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="un"><pre/></emphasis></p><p>(Name and address of Internet Service Provider)</p><p>John Doe<emphasis typeStyle="un"><pre/></emphasis></p><p>Enter e-mail nickname or other<emphasis typeStyle="un"><pre/></emphasis></p><p>alias used in communicating via<emphasis typeStyle="un"><pre/></emphasis></p><p>the Internet service provider to<emphasis typeStyle="un"><pre/></emphasis></p><p>whom the subpoena is addressed.<emphasis typeStyle="un"><pre/></emphasis></p></bodyText></level><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p><citation normalizedCite="2002 VA CH 875"><content><span normalizedCite="2002 Va. Ch. 875">2002, c. 875<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2002#000875#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PV90-004G-K1XK-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 8.01.</desig><title>CIVIL REMEDIES AND PROCEDURE</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 14.</desig><title>EVIDENCE</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="article"><heading><desig>ARTICLE 5.</desig><title>COMPELLING ATTENDANCE OF WITNESSES, ETC</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Civil Procedure</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MzUxNjJDMEQ5N0YwNDMzM0JDMjEzM0UzOTYzMzI3OTU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Demurrers</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NzIyQzA1QUE2QTJENDY5NEIyNTJGMEVGMzcwQ0M3NUQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MkE4NUJDOTQ4MURENDYwOUIyQUE4NEM5RUFDMzQ1MTU</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OTA4OTc1RTI1OEMzNDIzQkE3OEM1NkU3REI1RDk0NjM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUQ0ODlENjkzQ0I1NDVFRTkyMjBCNkY0NEYzQTdFQzI</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Judgment on Pleadings</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RDc1OUFCODhBQjNENDI4MUJDN0Q3ODk1OEIzNjdCNDY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUQ5QkE1Nzk0MEM2NDJEQzgyNTlEQzZFMDY1MzIyQkU</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Mandamus</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6REI5QTYzQjJCNUIzNDQzMzlFODI1RThGMjg2NDNEQUI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6M0IwQkRFNEU3QTlBNDc1Q0E1MzdCMUZGQkYyNkMwNzM</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Protective Orders</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NTlGNUE2M0Q1RjI5NEFCNEI0QjM2QTkxQUExOEVENUM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6N0U4MkI2QTY1RDhFNEVBRjk4ODdGNjUwQ0RERjU0NjU</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Subpoenas</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NUUwMEFDNDQyNkMyNDU2QzhBRDVDRTRBMUE5NzI3Q0Y7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6N0U4MkI2QTY1RDhFNEVBRjk4ODdGNjUwQ0RERjU0NjU</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Communications Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MEQxMkU0NzE2OEE2NDIxNEE3QzU0NjU2MDRERUNGNDE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Internet Services</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6M0RBNjIwOTBBREExNDE1Q0ExQUYwMDE4MjI2MTkyQTc7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MzNFQTlENUZGNUIyNEUyMzhEOEZFNUEzNzYzNEE4Qzg</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Computer &amp; Internet Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Qzk0QUJBRENDQzhBNDc2MDk5OTAyQzI3QkRFMkU0OUU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QUI1MzMxMzgxRDEwNDMxNkI2MUIwRTBDRjk5QUY3OEY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6N0U2OEYyMDlBMThBNDQxRjg4NkFGM0I4REVDODE1QTE</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Q0MxOEZFQjREMEU0NDJDRDg2QjlGQ0Y3QjEzNTZBREE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDIyOTIwOUI5NTQ0NDMzREFBMUQ4ODBBMzEwNzAyQjU</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Service Providers</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QTdDMERDMEEwRTAxNEQ2Njk4OTk4QzRGNzkxN0M0OTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDIyOTIwOUI5NTQ0NDMzREFBMUQ4ODBBMzEwNzAyQjU</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Criminal Law &amp; Procedure</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NEU0RkE1OUQwNUQwNDgxODhEODZCMjkzOTg3NThBNzk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Application &amp; Issuance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QzRFRTU0NkVFQTkzNDZFMEEyODNFODM4ODFDMjRCNkQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6REVEMDZCMjVGNTNGNDlDN0E1QjBCRDJCMjNBQzdGNDg</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NUIxQTE2NTMyRENCNDdFOUFBRTAyMEJGODFCQzA5RDA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6REVEMDZCMjVGNTNGNDlDN0E1QjBCRDJCMjNBQzdGNDg</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Governments</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjdEQjE4OUJDMzQxNDNEMEI0RTI1QUFCMzJENjEwRTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Clerks of Court</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6REVFMjkzRDI1MkU2NERDNjk3OEUxODY0REYwMUI1NjE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NURENzJGNTEyQzM0NEREQUI2RkVCRTM4RTc1RTZBREU</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification><classificationGroup classificationScheme="indexing-terms"><classification classificationScheme="legal"/></classificationGroup></metadata></legislativeDoc>