<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#123#000030#       133#">Va. Code Ann. § 30-133</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_30-133"/><heading><desig>§ 30-133.</desig><title>Duties and powers generally</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a"/><heading><desig>A.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The Auditor of Public Accounts shall audit all the accounts of every state department, officer, board, commission, institution or other agency handling any state funds. In the performance of such duties and the exercise of such powers he may employ the services of certified public accountants, provided the cost thereof shall not exceed such sums as may be available out of the appropriation provided by law for the conduct of his office.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b"/><heading><desig>B.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The Auditor of Public Accounts shall review the information required in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 2.2-1501"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 2.2-1501">§ 2.2-1501<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000002#     2#         1501#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> to determine that state agencies are providing and reporting appropriate information on financial and performance measures, and the Auditor shall review the accuracy of the management systems used to accumulate and report the results. The Auditor shall report annually to the General Assembly the results of such audits and make recommendations, if indicated, for new or revised accountability or performance measures to be implemented for the agencies audited.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c"/><heading><desig>C.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The Auditor of Public Accounts shall prepare, by November 1, a summary of the results of all of the audits and other oversight responsibilities performed for the most recently ended fiscal year. The Auditor of Public Accounts shall present this summary to the Senate Finance, House Appropriations and House Finance Committees on the day the Governor presents to the General Assembly the Executive Budget in accordance with <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 2.2-1508"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 2.2-1508">§§ 2.2-1508<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000002#     2#         1508#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> and <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 2.2-1509"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 2.2-1509">2.2-1509<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000002#     2#         1509#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> or at the direction of the respective Chairman of the Senate Finance, House Appropriations or House Finance Committees at one of their committee meetings prior to the meeting above.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d"/><heading><desig>D.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> As part of his normal oversight responsibilities, the Auditor of Public Accounts shall incorporate into his audit procedures and processes a review process to ensure that the Commonwealth's payments to counties, cities, and towns under Chapter 35.1 (<citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 58.1-3523"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 58.1-3523">§ 58.1-3523<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000058#     1#         3523#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> et seq.) of Title 58.1 are consistent with the provisions of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 58.1-3524"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 58.1-3524">§ 58.1-3524<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000058#     1#         3524#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>. The Auditor of Public Accounts shall report to the Governor and the Chairman of the Senate Finance Committee annually any material failure by a locality or the Commonwealth to comply with the provisions of Chapter 35.1 of Title 58.1.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_e"/><heading><desig>E.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The Auditor of Public Accounts when called upon by the Governor shall examine the accounts of any institution maintained in whole or in part by the Commonwealth and, upon the direction of the Comptroller, shall examine the accounts of any officer required to settle his accounts with him; and upon the direction of any other state officer at the seat of government he shall examine the accounts of any person required to settle his accounts with such officer.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_f"/><heading><desig>F.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Upon the written request of any member of the General Assembly, the Auditor of Public Accounts shall furnish the requested information and provide technical assistance upon any matter requested by such member.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_g"/><heading><desig>G.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> In compliance with the provisions of the federal Single Audit Act Amendments of 1996, Public Law 104-156, the Joint Legislative Audit and Review Commission may authorize the Auditor of Public Accounts to audit biennially the accounts pertaining to federal funds received by state departments, officers, boards, commissions, institutions or other agencies.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_h"/><heading><desig>H.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> 1. <emphasis typeStyle="it"> (Effective until October 1, 2016)</emphasis> The Auditor of Public Accounts shall compile and maintain on its Internet website a searchable database providing certain state expenditure, revenue, and demographic information as described in this subsection. In maintaining the database, the Auditor of Public Accounts shall work with and coordinate his efforts with the Joint Legislative Audit and Review Commission in obtaining, summarizing, and compiling the information to avoid duplication of efforts. The database shall be updated each year by October 15 to provide the information required in this subsection for the 10 most recently ended fiscal years of the Commonwealth.</p><p><pre/>The online database shall be made available to citizens of the Commonwealth to allow public access to historical revenue collections and appropriations with related demographic information, to the extent that the information is available and provided to the Auditor of Public Accounts. All state departments, courts officers, boards, commissions, institutions, or other agencies of the Commonwealth shall furnish all information requested by the Auditor of Public Accounts and shall cooperate with him to the fullest extent.</p><p><pre/>For purposes of reporting information and implementing the database pursuant to this subsection, the Auditor of Public Accounts shall include all appropriated funds and other sources under the control of state-supported institutions of higher education, except for the activity of private gifts, including endowment funds and unrestricted gifts referenced in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 23-9.2"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 23 -9.2">§ 23-9.2.<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#123#000023#       9.2#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> The exclusion of this activity does not affect the public access to these records unless otherwise specifically exempted by law.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_h_seq_2"/><heading><desig>H.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> 1. <emphasis typeStyle="it"> (Effective October 1, 2016)</emphasis> The Auditor of Public Accounts shall compile and maintain on its Internet website a searchable database providing certain state expenditure, revenue, and demographic information as described in this subsection. In maintaining the database, the Auditor of Public Accounts shall work with and coordinate his efforts with the Joint Legislative Audit and Review Commission in obtaining, summarizing, and compiling the information to avoid duplication of efforts. The database shall be updated each year by October 15 to provide the information required in this subsection for the 10 most recently ended fiscal years of the Commonwealth.</p><p><pre/>The online database shall be made available to citizens of the Commonwealth to allow public access to historical revenue collections and appropriations with related demographic information, to the extent that the information is available and provided to the Auditor of Public Accounts. All state departments, courts officers, boards, commissions, institutions, or other agencies of the Commonwealth shall furnish all information requested by the Auditor of Public Accounts and shall cooperate with him to the fullest extent.</p><p><pre/>For purposes of reporting information and implementing the database pursuant to this subsection, the Auditor of Public Accounts shall include all appropriated funds and other sources under the control of state-supported institutions of higher education, except for the activity of private gifts, including endowment funds and unrestricted gifts referenced in § 23.1-101. The exclusion of this activity does not affect the public access to these records unless otherwise specifically exempted by law.</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_h_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The database shall contain the following for each of the 10 most recently ended fiscal years of the Commonwealth:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_h_2_a"/><heading><desig>a.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Major categories of spending by each secretariat and for major agencies, to include for each agency and institution a register of all funds expended, showing vendor name, date of payment, amount, and a description of the type of expense, including also credit card purchases with the same information to the extent that the information exists;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_h_2_b"/><heading><desig>b.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The number of full-time state employees and a listing of the positions and salary of each such position, organized by agency;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_h_2_c"/><heading><desig>c.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Total fiscal year revenues from state taxes, fees, and other charges, and total fiscal year revenues from state taxes, fees, and other charges computed on a per capita basis and as a percentage of personal income in the Commonwealth;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_h_2_d"/><heading><desig>d.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> With regard to state taxes, fees, and other charges computed on a per capita basis and as a percentage of personal income, a comparison of such statistics for Virginia with the same statistics for other states;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_h_2_e"/><heading><desig>e.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Total fiscal year revenues from federal sources, including the major categories of spending for such revenues;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_h_2_f"/><heading><desig>f.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Total population and total population by various age groups including, but not limited to, school-age population and the population of persons 65 years of age and older;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_h_2_g"/><heading><desig>g.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Student enrollment in grades K through 12;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_h_2_h"/><heading><desig>h.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Enrollment in public institutions of higher education of the Commonwealth;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_h_2_i"/><heading><desig>i.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Enrollment in private institutions of higher education in the Commonwealth;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_h_2_j"/><heading><desig>j.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The annual prison population;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_h_2_k"/><heading><desig>k.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Virginia adjusted gross income and Virginia taxable income by various age groups;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_h_2_l"/><heading><desig>l.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The number of citizens in the Commonwealth receiving food stamps;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_h_2_m"/><heading><desig>m.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The number of driver's licenses issued;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_h_2_n"/><heading><desig>n.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The number of registered motor vehicles;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_h_2_o"/><heading><desig>o.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The number of full-time private sector employees;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_h_2_p"/><heading><desig>p.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The number of households;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_h_2_q"/><heading><desig>q.</desig><title><emphasis typeStyle="it"> (Effective until October 1, 2016)</emphasis></title></heading><bodyText><p> The number of prepaid tuition contracts outstanding pursuant to Chapter 4.9 (<citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 23-38.75"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 23 -38.75">§ 23-38.75<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#123#000023#     38.75#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> et seq.) of Title 23 and the estimated total liability under such contracts;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_h_2_q_seq_2"/><heading><desig>q.</desig><title><emphasis typeStyle="it"> (Effective October 1, 2016)</emphasis></title></heading><bodyText><p> The number of prepaid tuition contracts outstanding pursuant to Chapter 7 (§ 23.1-700 et seq.) of Title 23.1 and the estimated total liability under such contracts;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_h_2_r"/><heading><desig>r.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Any state audit or report relating to the programs or activities of an agency;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_h_2_s"/><heading><desig>s.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Information on capital outlay payments including, but not limited to, project title, funding date, completion date, appropriations, year-to-date expenditures, and unexpended appropriations;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_h_2_t"/><heading><desig>t.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Annual bonded indebtedness that shall include, but not be limited to, the amount of the total original obligation stated in terms of principal and interest, the term of the obligation, the amounts of principal and interest previously paid to reduce the obligation, the balance remaining of the obligation, and any refinancing of the obligation; and</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_h_2_u"/><heading><desig>u.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Other data as the Auditor deems appropriate relating to the Commonwealth of Virginia.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_h_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The Auditor of Public Accounts shall incorporate into the database the following additional elements as they become available through improved enterprise applications or other systems:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_h_3_a"/><heading><desig>a.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Commodities including, but not limited to, line item expenditures;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_h_3_b"/><heading><desig>b.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Virginia Performs data as it directly relates to funding actions or expenditures;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_h_3_c"/><heading><desig>c.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Descriptive purpose for funding action or expenditure;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_h_3_d"/><heading><desig>d.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Statute or act of General Assembly authorizing the issuance of bonds; and</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_h_3_e"/><heading><desig>e.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Copies of actual grants and contracts.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_h_4"/><heading><desig>4.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The Auditor of Public Accounts shall incorporate in the database the following enhancements:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_h_4_a"/><heading><desig>a.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Graphs, charts, or other visual displays of aggregated data showing (i) current state spending by expense category, (ii) year-to-year state spending, and (iii) other data deemed appropriate by the Auditor, including display of available line item expenditures; and</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_h_4_b"/><heading><desig>b.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Frequently asked questions and their responses.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_h_5"/><heading><desig>5.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> By October 15 of each year, the Auditor shall also produce a paper copy or a computer file containing the information described in this subsection and shall distribute the copy or file to newspapers of general circulation in the Commonwealth. The distribution shall include the address of the Internet website for the searchable database.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_i"/><heading><desig>I.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> As a part of audits conducted pursuant to subsection A, the Auditor of Public Accounts shall review compliance with requirements established pursuant to the provisions of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 2.2-519"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 2.2-519">§ 2.2-519<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000002#     2#          519#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> and the requirements of the Virginia Debt Collection Act (<citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 2.2-4800"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 2.2-4800">§ 2.2-4800<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000002#     2#         4800#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> et seq.).</p></bodyText></level><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p>Code 1950, §§ 2-127, 2-132, 2-135; 1950, p. 664; 1966, c. 677, §§ 2.1-155, 2.1-160, 2.1-163; 1972, c. 582; 1973, c. 507; 1985, c. 315; 1998, Sp. Sess., c. 2; <citation normalizedCite="2001 VA CH 844"><content><span normalizedCite="2001 Va. Ch. 844">2001, c. 844<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2001#000844#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2002 VA CH 727"><content><span normalizedCite="2002 Va. Ch. 727">2002, c. 727<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2002#000727#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2003 VA CH 270"><content><span normalizedCite="2003 Va. Ch. 270">2003, c. 270<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2003#000270#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2004 VA CH 1"><content><span normalizedCite="2004 Va. Ch. 1">2004, Sp. Sess. I, c. 1<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2004#000001#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2005 VA CH 494"><content><span normalizedCite="2005 Va. Ch. 494">2005, c. 494<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2005#000494#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2007 VA CH 577"><content><span normalizedCite="2007 Va. Ch. 577">2007, c. 577<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2007#000577#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2008 VA CH 637"><content><span normalizedCite="2008 Va. Ch. 637">2008, c. 637<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2008#000637#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2009 VA CH 758"><content><span normalizedCite="2009 Va. Ch. 758">2009, cc. 758<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2009#000758#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2009 VA CH 812"><content><span normalizedCite="2009 Va. Ch. 812">812<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2009#000812#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2010 VA CH 671"><content><span normalizedCite="2010 Va. Ch. 671">2010, c. 671<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2010#000671#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2016 VA CH 547"><content><span normalizedCite="2016 Va. Ch. 547">2016, c. 547<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2016#000547#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PV70-004G-K09S-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 30.</desig><title>GENERAL ASSEMBLY</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 14.</desig><title>AUDITOR OF PUBLIC ACCOUNTS</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Criminal Law &amp; Procedure</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NEU0RkE1OUQwNUQwNDgxODhEODZCMjkzOTg3NThBNzk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Imprisonment</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NURCMTExOEEzNDJBNDk4RjhFQTQ0NzEwMzc0OTg3RTE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QTFGRjg4NjA3RTg1NDA2RkIzMDk4QzdGREIyQzVGMDk</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Evidence</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUVGQkU0QjJFMTIzNDNBM0FCNTVEQjAxQTM3RDcwOTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Summaries</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDJDMTlCN0FBOEM4NDA4MzlCMTlBMzE0RjQwNzRBMUE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RjNBNTI3MkNCN0VCNDk1Qjk5QTQ4RjEzMkM5NDVEQzA</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Governments</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjdEQjE4OUJDMzQxNDNEMEI0RTI1QUFCMzJENjEwRTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Employees &amp; Officials</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OTU3RThFMjRDRjdGNDRFNTg0NEYyMUM1NEU3MzdCQTU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QURCRDNBRjBGRTE0NEFBRUEzNUU1MzFGQjg3MTM4MDI</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Finance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjMzOTBBRTg2MUVDNDdDNUE1M0QxNDk1RERCNjNCN0I7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Njg1MkM3RkYyNzIxNEVFRkJFMTI2NUM4NUU1ODdEM0Q</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Tax Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OTNEM0E2OEE0RkQyNEY1MDhBQzdGMkQ4ODI4QTJDODE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Adjusted Gross Income</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6N0U5MEZFRjQ4RDAyNEY5RUEyMDMxMUMzQzRBQzk5MzA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NzI4OUU5MkIwMjUxNDgyREI4RkY4NDQ0RDVEQzk2Nzg</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjMzNUY4MTdCNEQyNDg5NkE2RUVFRjI2REMzN0YxOUM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjlBMzhERjhEMTlFNEQwOEI5Q0I4MkIwMUExRTdBNTk</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RjAxQTY3MUE4MUNCNDg3MEE1RERCOUNDRTBERjk0NUE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NzI4OUU5MkIwMjUxNDgyREI4RkY4NDQ0RDVEQzk2Nzg</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification><classificationGroup classificationScheme="indexing-terms"><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem score="90"><className>Governments</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjdEQjE4OUJDMzQxNDNEMEI0RTI1QUFCMzJENjEwRTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></classificationGroup></metadata></legislativeDoc>