<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#349#000033#     2#         1200#">Va. Code Ann. § 33.2-1200</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_33.2-1200"/><heading><desig>§ 33.2-1200.</desig><title>Policy; definitions</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a"/><heading><desig>A.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> In order to promote the safety, convenience, and enjoyment of travel on and protection of the public investment in highways within the Commonwealth, attract tourists and promote the prosperity, economic well-being, and general welfare of the Commonwealth, and preserve and enhance the natural scenic beauty or aesthetic features of the highways and adjacent areas, the General Assembly declares it to be the policy of the Commonwealth that the erection and maintenance of outdoor advertising in areas adjacent to the rights-of-way of the highways within the Commonwealth shall be regulated in accordance with the terms of this article and regulations promulgated by the Board pursuant thereto.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b"/><heading><desig>B.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> As used in this article, unless the context requires a different meaning:</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Advertisement"</emphasis> means any writing, printing, picture, painting, display, emblem, drawing, sign, or similar device that is posted or displayed outdoors on real property and is intended to invite or to draw the attention of or solicit the patronage or support of the public to any goods, merchandise, real or personal property, business, services, entertainment, or amusement manufactured, produced, bought, sold, conducted, furnished, or dealt in by any person. "Advertisement" includes any part of an advertisement recognizable as such.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Advertising structure"</emphasis> means any rigid or semirigid material, with or without any advertisement displayed thereon, situated upon or attached to real property outdoors, primarily or principally for the purpose of furnishing a background or base or support upon which an advertisement may be posted or displayed.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Area of an advertising structure"</emphasis> means the area determined from its outside measurements, excluding as a part thereof the height and overall width of supports and supporting structure and any other portion or portions thereof beneath the normal area upon which an advertisement is posted or intended to be posted.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Billboard sign"</emphasis> means any sign, advertisement, or advertising structure as defined in this section owned by a person, firm, or corporation in the business of outdoor advertising.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Business of outdoor advertising"</emphasis> means the erection, use, or maintenance of advertising structures or the posting or display of outdoor advertisements by any person who receives profit gained from rentals or any other compensation from any other person for the use or maintenance of such advertising structures or the posting or display of such advertisements, except reasonable compensation for materials and labor used or furnished in the actual erection of advertising structures or the actual posting of advertisements. "Business of outdoor advertising" does not include the leasing or rental of advertising structures or advertisements used to advertise products, services, or entertainment sold or provided on the premises where the advertising structures or advertisement is located.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Centerline of the highway"</emphasis> means a line equidistant from the edges of the median separating the main traveled ways of a divided highway or the centerline of the main traveled way of a nondivided highway.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Distance from edge of a right-of-way"</emphasis> means the horizontal distance measured along a line normal or perpendicular to the centerline of the highway.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Federal-aid primary highway"</emphasis> means any highway within that portion of the primary state highway system as established and maintained under Article 2 (<citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 33.2-310"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 33.2-310">§ 33.2-310<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000033#     2#          310#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> et seq.) of Chapter 3, including extensions of such system within municipalities, that has been approved by the Secretary of Transportation pursuant to <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="23 USC 103"><content><span normalizedCite="23 U.S.C. 103">23 U.S.C. § 103<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1828#123#000023#        103#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>(b), as that system existed on June 1, 1991.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Highway"</emphasis> means every way or place of whatever nature open to the use of the public for purposes of vehicular travel in the Commonwealth.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Historic place, museum, or shrine"</emphasis> includes only places that are maintained wholly at public expense or by a nonprofit organization.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Information center"</emphasis> means an area or site established and maintained at rest areas for the purpose of informing the public of places of interest within the Commonwealth and providing such other information as the Commonwealth may consider desirable.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Interchange"</emphasis> means a grade separated intersection with one or more turning roadways for travel between intersection legs, or an intersection at grade, where two or more highways join or cross.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Lawfully erected"</emphasis> means any sign that was erected pursuant to the issuance of a permit from the Commissioner of Highways under <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 33.2-1208"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 33.2-1208">§ 33.2-1208<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000033#     2#         1208#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, unless the local governing body has evidence of noncompliance with ordinances in effect at the time the sign was erected.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Legible"</emphasis> means capable of being read without visual aid by a person of normal visual acuity.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Maintain"</emphasis> means to allow to exist.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Main traveled way"</emphasis> means the traveled way of a highway on which through traffic is carried. In the case of a divided highway, the traveled way of each of the separated roadways for traffic in opposite directions is a main traveled way. "Main traveled way" does not include such facilities as frontage roads, turning roadways, or parking areas.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"National Highway System"</emphasis> means the federal-aid highway system referenced in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="23 USC 103"><content><span normalizedCite="23 U.S.C. 103">23 U.S.C. § 103<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1828#123#000023#        103#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>(b), and regulations adopted pursuant thereto. For the purpose of this article, outdoor advertising controls on the National Highway System shall be implemented as those highways are designated and approved by congressional action or designation by the U.S. Secretary of Transportation and such designation and approval shall be kept on file in the central office of the Department of Transportation and placed in the minutes of the Commonwealth Transportation Board by the Commissioner of Highways. Prior to congressional approval or designation by the U.S. Secretary of Transportation, highways classified as National System of Interstate and Defense Highways, Dwight D. Eisenhower National System of Interstate and Defense Highways, Interstate System, or federal-aid primary highway as defined in this section shall be considered as the National Highway System.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Nonconforming sign," "nonconforming advertisement,"</emphasis> or <emphasis typeStyle="it">"nonconforming advertising structure"</emphasis> means one that was lawfully erected adjacent to any highway in the Commonwealth but that does not comply with the provisions of state law, state regulations, or ordinances adopted by local governing bodies passed at a later date or that later fails to comply with state law, state regulations, or ordinances adopted by local governing bodies due to changed conditions.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Person"</emphasis> includes an individual, partnership, association, or corporation.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Post"</emphasis> means post, display, print, paint, burn, nail, paste, or otherwise attach.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Real property"</emphasis> includes any property physically attached or annexed to real property in any manner whatsoever.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Rest area"</emphasis> means an area or site established and maintained within or adjacent to the right-of-way or under public supervision or control for the convenience of the traveling public.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Scenic area"</emphasis> means any public park or area of particular scenic beauty or historical significance designated as a scenic area by the Board.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Sign"</emphasis> means any outdoor sign, display, device, figure, painting, drawing, message, placard, poster, billboard, or other thing that is designed, intended, or used to advertise or inform, any part of the advertising or informative contents of which is visible from any highway.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Trade name"</emphasis> includes a brand name, trademark, distinctive symbol, or other similar device or thing used to identify particular products or services.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Traveled way"</emphasis> means the portion of a roadway for the movement of vehicles, exclusive of shoulders.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Turning roadway"</emphasis> means a connecting roadway for traffic turning between two intersection legs of an interchange.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Urban area"</emphasis> means an urbanized area or, in the case of an urbanized area encompassing more than one state, that part of the urbanized area within the Commonwealth, or an urban place.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Urbanized area"</emphasis> means an area so designated by the U.S. Census Bureau, within boundaries fixed by the Commissioner of Highways, in his discretion, in cooperation with the governing bodies of the localities affected and the appropriate federal authority. Such boundaries shall, at a minimum, encompass the entire urbanized area within a state as designated by the U.S. Census Bureau.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Urban place"</emphasis> means an area so designated by the U.S. Census Bureau having a population of 5,000 or more and not within any urbanized area, within boundaries fixed by the Commissioner of Highways, in his discretion, in cooperation with the governing bodies of the localities affected and the appropriate federal authority. Such boundaries shall, at a minimum, encompass the entire urban place designated by the U.S. Census Bureau.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Virginia byway"</emphasis> and <emphasis typeStyle="it">"scenic highway"</emphasis> means those highways designated by the Board pursuant to <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 33.2-405"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 33.2-405">§ 33.2-405<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000033#     2#          405#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>. For the purposes of this article, a Virginia byway means a scenic byway as referenced in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="23 USC 131"><content><span normalizedCite="23 U.S.C. 131">23 U.S.C. § 131<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1828#123#000023#        131#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>(s).</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Visible"</emphasis> means capable of being seen (whether or not legible) without visual aid by a person of normal visual acuity.</p></bodyText></level><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p>Code 1950, §§ 33-298, 33-310; 1954, c. 588; 1960, c. 406; 1962, c.  176; 1966, c. 663; 1970, c. 322, §§ 33.1-351, 33.1-363; 1976, c. 14; 1980, c. 275; 1984, c. 750; <citation normalizedCite="1993 VA CH 538"><content><span normalizedCite="1993 Va. Ch. 538">1993, c. 538<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1993#000538#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1996 VA CH 777"><content><span normalizedCite="1996 Va. Ch. 777">1996, c. 777<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1996#000777#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2000 VA CH 432"><content><span normalizedCite="2000 Va. Ch. 432">2000, cc. 432<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2000#000432#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2000 VA CH 449"><content><span normalizedCite="2000 Va. Ch. 449">449<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2000#000449#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2002 VA CH 672"><content><span normalizedCite="2002 Va. Ch. 672">2002, c. 672<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2002#000672#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2012 VA CH 145"><content><span normalizedCite="2012 Va. Ch. 145">2012, c. 145<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2012#000145#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2013 VA CH 127"><content><span normalizedCite="2013 Va. Ch. 127">2013, c. 127<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2013#000127#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2014 VA CH 805"><content><span normalizedCite="2014 Va. Ch. 805">2014, c. 805<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2014#000805#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PWB0-004G-K29J-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 33.2.</desig><title>HIGHWAYS AND OTHER SURFACE TRANSPORTATION SYSTEMS</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="subtitle"><heading><desig>SUBTITLE II.</desig><title>MODES OF TRANSPORTATION: HIGHWAYS, BRIDGES, FERRIES, RAIL, AND PUBLIC TRANSPORTATION</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 12.</desig><title>OUTDOOR ADVERTISING IN SIGHT OF PUBLIC HIGHWAYS</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="article"><heading><desig>ARTICLE 1.</desig><title>GENERAL POLICIES AND REGULATIONS</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Governments</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjdEQjE4OUJDMzQxNDNEMEI0RTI1QUFCMzJENjEwRTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Boundaries</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDEyQzA0NjVBQjA3NDRDOUJDNkExQkIzRkEzNzE2MTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Njg1MkM3RkYyNzIxNEVFRkJFMTI2NUM4NUU1ODdEM0Q</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Bridges &amp; Roads</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RTBBOTc0NTk5Nzg4NEM4MEI5REUxMTc4OEY4RDIwQzA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MEY3NUIxODI2RjU2NEY0NzgwMDQyNjFDMEQ1QUExRjM</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Real Property Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QUUyRTcxRURBNEY2NEE2MDk3QzBCNzRDOEY0NTZDQzk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Nonconforming Uses</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OTI5M0I4MUYyMEQ3NDNDOEFFRkVFMEI4QjlCNDVCOUQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NjcyQTdEMEUxODYyNDY0OThFQTg1NUNGMjFBMTkxQ0M</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Trademark Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QUY4QzQ2QTdDQjY1NEFGMjlGQjMwMTYzM0FDN0IxRTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NzM5MjE1NjcxRDA2NEJGREJDQUI5MkMwNkJEOUVGODA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6ODNCNDg3MzU3NkEyNEQzMDhDRjhGRDM0RUU4QjU5QkU</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QTUzRTNENDYwNjJDNDVGNDk3QTY0QkZEMjc4MUEzNTc7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RDVDM0Y3MDdEOTE5NEVCNDgxMDNDMjU0MjcxMzUyMTg</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjI0NDg2MzBERDBDNDYxQ0I4OTVENUI1MDJGN0FFRUU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QkYzRTA5MzU2N0YwNDVGQTg2NUExNjFBMjkxQzcyNzE</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Transportation Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RTYzRTk5RDVBQkQ2NDcwQzk2NTU3ODQ5OEE3NDlBNzk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Funding</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QTFFNkIxMEVFQTA2NERDMDhDRUUwNUY2NEQ4MTYyOUM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjVCODE3RDNEMENDNDkxRjg5MzBBNTJFQkNCRDlFOEU</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NTkyRUE5REJENDMwNDE4OTg3OTg5NTg0OEVEOUE3M0E7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjVCODE3RDNEMENDNDkxRjg5MzBBNTJFQkNCRDlFOEU</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification><classificationGroup classificationScheme="indexing-terms"><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem score="90"><className>Transportation</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RTYzRTk5RDVBQkQ2NDcwQzk2NTU3ODQ5OEE3NDlBNzk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></classificationGroup></metadata></legislativeDoc>