<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#349#000059#     1#          318#">Va. Code Ann. § 59.1-318</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_59.1-318"/><heading><desig>§ 59.1-318.</desig><title>Application for registration of membership camping operator</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a"/><heading><desig>A.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The application for registration shall be on a form prescribed by the Commissioner and shall include, to the extent applicable, the following:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The applicant's name, address, and the organizational form of his business, including the date, and jurisdiction under which the business was organized; the address of each of its offices in this Commonwealth; and the name and address of each campground located in this Commonwealth, which is owned or operated, in whole or in part, by the applicant;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The name, address, and principal occupation for the past five years of every officer of the applicant, including its principal managers, and the extent and nature of the interest of each such person at the time the application is filed;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A list of all owners of ten percent or more of the capital stock of the applicant, except that this list is not required if the applicant is a company required to report under the Securities and Exchange Act of 1934;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_4"/><heading><desig>4.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A brief description of and a certified copy of the instrument which creates the applicant's ownership of, or other right to use the campground and the facilities at the campground which are to be available for use by purchasers, together with a copy of any lease, license, franchise, reciprocal agreement or other agreement entitling the applicant to use such campground and facilities, and any material provision of the agreement which restricts a purchaser's use of such campground or facilities;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_5"/><heading><desig>5.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A sample copy of each instrument which will be delivered to a purchaser to evidence his membership in the campground and a sample copy of each agreement which a purchaser will be required to execute;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_6"/><heading><desig>6.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A statement of the zoning and other governmental regulations affecting the use of the campground including the site plans and building permits and their status;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_7"/><heading><desig>7.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A list of special taxes or assessments, whether current or proposed, which affect the campground;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_8"/><heading><desig>8.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Financial statements of the applicant prepared in accordance with generally accepted accounting principles, which shall include a financial statement for the most recent fiscal year audited by an independent certified public accountant and an unaudited financial statement for the most recent fiscal quarter;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_9"/><heading><desig>9.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A copy of the disclosure statement required by <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 59.1-326"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 59.1-326">§ 59.1-326<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000059#     1#          326#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_10"/><heading><desig>10.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> An irrevocable appointment of the Commissioner or his designees to receive service of any lawful process in any proceeding arising under this chapter against the applicant or his agents, except one issued by the Commissioner. The Commissioner shall forward any such process by registered or certified mail addressed to any of the principals, officers, directors, partners, or trustees of the applicant who are listed on the application for registration pursuant to this chapter, or to any other person designated in the application to receive such process, and shall keep a record of it. Any process, notice, order, or demand issued by the Commissioner shall be served by registered mail addressed to any principal, officer, director, partner, or trustee of the applicant listed on the application for registration pursuant to this chapter or to any person designated in the application to receive such process. Nothing in this section shall be construed to limit or prohibit the lawful service of process on individual principals as allowed by the laws of the Commonwealth.  The names and addresses of the principals, officers, directors, partners, or trustees of the membership camping operator as last filed with the Commissioner pursuant to the provisions of this chapter shall be conclusive for the purposes of services of process;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_11"/><heading><desig>11.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A narrative description of the promotional plan for the sale of the membership camping contracts;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_12"/><heading><desig>12.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Any bonds required to be posted pursuant to the provisions of this chapter;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_13"/><heading><desig>13.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A copy of the agreement, if any, between the applicant and any person owning, controlling, or managing the campground and the applicant;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_14"/><heading><desig>14.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A complete list of locations and addresses of any and all sales offices located within the Commonwealth, together with a roster of all salespersons who are employed in this Commonwealth by the applicant whether as employees or as independent contractors;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_15"/><heading><desig>15.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The names of any other states or foreign countries in which an application for registration of the membership camping operator or the membership camping contract or any similar document has been filed; and</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_16"/><heading><desig>16.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Complete information concerning any adverse order, judgment, or decree which has been entered by any court or administrative agency in connection with a campground or other project operated by the applicant or in which the applicant has or had an interest at the time.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b"/><heading><desig>B.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The application shall be signed by the membership camping operator, an officer or general partner thereof or by another person holding a power of attorney for this purpose from the membership camping operator. If the application is signed pursuant to a power of attorney, a copy of the power of attorney shall be included with the application.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c"/><heading><desig>C.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The application shall be submitted with a facing page as might be prescribed by the Commissioner if then in effect, along with the appropriate fees.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d"/><heading><desig>D.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> An application for registration shall be amended within twenty-five days if there is a material change in the information included in the application. A material change includes any change which significantly reduces or terminates either the applicant's or the purchaser's right to use the campground or any of the facilities described in the membership camping contract, but does not include minor changes covering the use of the campground, its facilities or the reciprocal program.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_e"/><heading><desig>E.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The review of the application for registration of the membership camping operator shall occur pursuant to the provisions of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 59.1-320.1"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 59.1-320.1">§ 59.1-320.1.<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000059#     1#        320.1#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation></p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_f"/><heading><desig>F.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Registration with the Commissioner shall not be deemed to be an approval or endorsement by the Commissioner of the membership camping operator, his membership camping contract, or his campground, and any attempt by the membership camping operator to indicate that registration constitutes such approval or endorsement shall be unlawful.</p></bodyText></level><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p>1985, c. 409; <citation normalizedCite="1992 VA CH 545"><content><span normalizedCite="1992 Va. Ch. 545">1992, c. 545<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1992#000545#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PTM0-004G-K0GG-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 59.1.</desig><title>TRADE AND COMMERCE</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 25.</desig><title>VIRGINIA MEMBERSHIP CAMPING ACT</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="article"><heading><desig>ARTICLE 2.</desig><title>REGISTRATION</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjA4OEVGODBENzY4NDcxM0IyQzA1OTEwQzVDODRBOUE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QkUzMkQ5REVCNDgyNEE4OTlGNjZGRTQxRUY2MjNCNjU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RDY4QTA4MkI3NURDNDA1MEEyOTY1RDM4MTVGOTQ0Mjk</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NzQwNjJBMUVBRDAwNEVFNUIwNjE0M0JFQ0IwNjk5MDU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NTBBOERFMzlGNEE5NDI2OUEwMUFDNkNFOURENTQ5MDQ</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>International Trade Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RTRDNDkyQ0UwRkRGNEQ0MjgwNzM2NzI3NjlGODE0ODk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDYzN0EyREIxMDk0NENCNjlDMzhEQjFFRDlDOTIzNDc7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RTRDNDkyQ0UwRkRGNEQ0MjgwNzM2NzI3NjlGODE0ODk</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Securities Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RkFFMTQ3ODhCRDYyNDkyN0IwQkEyQzRCRDlFMEM5ODc7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MkNCNjFDQjNCQzRFNDM3QkJFQjYwQjREMEYyMERBMjI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Njk1MERGMzk2ODkwNENCMUFCRjhGOUIxMjk2OTUyMUU</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification><classificationGroup classificationScheme="indexing-terms"><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem score="90"><className>Antitrust</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6REEyRTNDM0JGQzYyNEMyOEFGNTAwNUJEOUU1MDg4NjU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></classificationGroup></metadata></legislativeDoc>