<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#123#000020#     124.2#">Va. Code Ann. § 20-124.2</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_20-124.2"/><heading><desig>§ 20-124.2.</desig><title>Court-ordered custody and visitation arrangements</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a"/><heading><desig>A.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> In any case in which custody or visitation of minor children is at issue, whether in a circuit or district court, the court shall provide prompt adjudication, upon due consideration of all the facts, of custody and visitation arrangements, including support and maintenance for the children, prior to other considerations arising in the matter. The court may enter an order pending the suit as provided in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 20-103"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 20 -103">§ 20-103<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#123#000020#       103#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>. The procedures for determining custody and visitation arrangements shall insofar as practical, and consistent with the ends of justice, preserve the dignity and resources of family members. Mediation shall be used as an alternative to litigation where appropriate. When mediation is used in custody and visitation matters, the goals may include development of a proposal addressing the child's residential schedule and care arrangements, and how disputes between the parents will be handled in the future.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b"/><heading><desig>B.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> In determining custody, the court shall give primary consideration to the best interests of the child. The court shall assure minor children of frequent and continuing contact with both parents, when appropriate, and encourage parents to share in the responsibilities of rearing their children. As between the parents, there shall be no presumption or inference of law in favor of either. The court shall give due regard to the primacy of the parent-child relationship but may upon a showing by clear and convincing evidence that the best interest of the child would be served thereby award custody or visitation to any other person with a legitimate interest. The court may award joint custody or sole custody.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c"/><heading><desig>C.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The court may order that support be paid for any child of the parties. The court shall also order that support will continue to be paid for any child over the age of 18 who is (i) a full-time high school student, (ii) not self-supporting, and (iii) living in the home of the party seeking or receiving child support until such child reaches the age of 19 or graduates from high school, whichever first occurs. The court may also order that support be paid or continue to be paid for any child over the age of 18 who is (a) severely and permanently mentally or physically disabled, and such disability existed prior to the child reaching the age of 18 or the age of 19 if the child met the requirements of clauses (i), (ii), and (iii); (b) unable to live independently and support himself; and (c) residing in the home of the parent seeking or receiving child support. In addition, the court may confirm a stipulation or agreement of the parties which extends a support obligation beyond when it would otherwise terminate as provided by law. The court shall have no authority to decree support of children payable by the estate of a deceased party. The court may make such further decree as it shall deem expedient concerning support of the minor children, including an order that either party or both parties provide health care coverage or cash medical support, or both.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d"/><heading><desig>D.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> In any case in which custody or visitation of minor children is at issue, whether in a circuit or district court, the court may order an independent mental health or psychological evaluation to assist the court in its determination of the best interests of the child. The court may enter such order as it deems appropriate for the payment of the costs of the evaluation by the parties.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_e"/><heading><desig>E.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The court shall have the continuing authority and jurisdiction to make any additional orders necessary to effectuate and enforce any order entered pursuant to this section or <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 20-103"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 20 -103">§ 20-103<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#123#000020#       103#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> including the authority to punish as contempt of court any willful failure of a party to comply with the provisions of the order. A parent or other person having legal custody of a child may petition the court to enjoin and the court may enter an order to enjoin a parent of the child from filing a petition relating to custody and visitation of that child for any period of time up to 10 years if doing so is in the best interests of the child and such parent has been convicted of an offense under the laws of the Commonwealth or a substantially similar law of another state, the United States, or any foreign jurisdiction which constitutes (i) murder or voluntary manslaughter, or a felony attempt, conspiracy or solicitation to commit any such offense, if the victim of the offense was a child of the parent, a child with whom the parent resided at the time the offense occurred, or the other parent of the child, or (ii) felony assault resulting in serious bodily injury, felony bodily wounding resulting in serious bodily injury, or felony sexual assault, if the victim of the offense was a child of the parent or a child with whom the parent resided at the time of the offense. When such a petition to enjoin the filing of a petition for custody and visitation is filed, the court shall appoint a guardian ad litem for the child pursuant to § 16.1-266.</p></bodyText></level><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p><citation normalizedCite="1994 VA CH 769"><content><span normalizedCite="1994 Va. Ch. 769">1994, c. 769<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1994#000769#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1996 VA CH 767"><content><span normalizedCite="1996 Va. Ch. 767">1996, cc. 767<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1996#000767#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1996 VA CH 879"><content><span normalizedCite="1996 Va. Ch. 879">879<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1996#000879#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1996 VA CH 884"><content><span normalizedCite="1996 Va. Ch. 884">884<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1996#000884#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1999 VA CH 574"><content><span normalizedCite="1999 Va. Ch. 574">1999, c. 574<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1999#000574#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2003 VA CH 520"><content><span normalizedCite="2003 Va. Ch. 520">2003, c. 520<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2003#000520#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2006 VA CH 665"><content><span normalizedCite="2006 Va. Ch. 665">2006, c. 665<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2006#000665#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2009 VA CH 713"><content><span normalizedCite="2009 Va. Ch. 713">2009, c. 713<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2009#000713#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2015 VA CH 653"><content><span normalizedCite="2015 Va. Ch. 653">2015, cc. 653<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2015#000653#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2015 VA CH 654"><content><span normalizedCite="2015 Va. Ch. 654">654<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2015#000654#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PV00-004G-K0W0-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 20.</desig><title>DOMESTIC RELATIONS</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 6.1.</desig><title>CUSTODY AND VISITATION ARRANGEMENTS FOR MINOR CHILDREN</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Family Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NEI4M0U5Qzg3RTk0NDdBRUJGNDRGNkZEQkU3RDdFNDU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Appointment</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RkFERUQxQTg2MjBCNEQ5OTg4NEE2MDEzQjk4QTg1RTM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDkyNkUxNzIzNzZFNDI3OUI1MTI2NTBEOUMyNERGNTE</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Best Interests of Child</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6REFFNzMzRUNGMEE4NDI0Njg5REM0RTRDQzA0ODRDOTk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjhEMEQ1Qjc2MUIwNEE2RkE4MEY4MDU5NjQ2ODg0NjI</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RTkwM0NDOUJFQUMzNEY2MjgwOTc3QUFGRUIxQkY3MTQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QTcwM0ZEODVFNjlFNDZCNDlGNDUxMkRFNEU1NDAwMTA</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDQzMkMzRDlBNTIyNDk4RUE0QTE1MTQ4N0E0RDdEN0E7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QzczNzBDMkVEM0IzNDczOUJCRjE1RUZDODEzMkQ1NjE</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Mediation</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NUM3QkQ5QUZBNUFBNEYyMUIyOTEwMENDRjI1NDc4NEM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QThBNjRBREYzQ0VCNEEwNkE4QjhEMjk0MzIyRDQ2RTQ</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification><classificationGroup classificationScheme="indexing-terms"><classification classificationScheme="legal"/></classificationGroup></metadata></legislativeDoc>