<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#349#000046#     2#       1573.8#">Va. Code Ann. § 46.2-1573.8</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_46.2-1573.8"/><heading><desig>§ 46.2-1573.8.</desig><title>Warranty obligations</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a"/><heading><desig>A.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Each recreational vehicle manufacturer, factory branch, distributor, or distributor branch shall (i) specify in writing to each of its recreational vehicle dealers licensed in the Commonwealth the dealer's obligations for preparation, delivery, and warranty service on its products and (ii) compensate the dealer for warranty parts, service, and diagnostic work required of the dealer by the manufacturer or distributor as follows:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Compensation of a dealer for warranty parts, service, and diagnostic work shall not be less than the amounts charged by the dealer for the manufacturer's or distributor's original parts, service, and diagnostic work to retail customers for nonwarranty service, parts, and diagnostic work installed or performed in the dealer's service department unless the amounts are not reasonable;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> For purposes of determining warranty parts and service compensation, menu-priced parts or services, group discounts, special event discounts, and special event promotions shall not be considered in determining amounts charged by the dealer to retail customers;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Increases in dealer warranty parts and service compensation and diagnostic work compensation, pursuant to this section, shall be requested by the dealer in writing, shall be based on 100 consecutive repair orders or all repair orders over a 90-day period, whichever occurs first, and, in the case of parts, shall be stated as a percentage of markup that shall be uniformly applied to all the manufacturer's or distributor's parts;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_4"/><heading><desig>4.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> In the case of warranty parts compensation, the provisions of this subsection shall be effective only for model year 1992 and succeeding model years;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_5"/><heading><desig>5.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> If a manufacturer or distributor furnishes a part to a dealer at no cost for use by the dealer in performing work for which the manufacturer or distributor is required to compensate the dealer under this section, the manufacturer or distributor shall compensate the dealer for the part in the same manner as warranty parts compensation, less the wholesale costs, for such part as listed in the manufacturer's current price schedules. A manufacturer or distributor may pay the dealer a reasonable handling fee instead of the compensation otherwise required by this subsection for special high-performance complete engine assemblies in limited production recreational vehicles that constitute less than five percent of model production furnished to the dealer at no cost, if the manufacturer or distributor excludes such special high-performance complete engine assemblies in determining whether the amounts requested by the dealer for warranty compensation are consistent with the amounts that the dealer charges its other retail service customers for parts used by the dealer to perform similar work; or</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_6"/><heading><desig>6.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> In the case of service work, manufacturer original parts or parts otherwise specified by the manufacturer or distributor, and parts provided by a dealer either pursuant to an adjustment program as defined in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 59.1-207.34"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 59.1-207.34">§ 59.1-207.34<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000059#     1#       207.34#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> or as otherwise requested by the manufacturer or distributor, the dealer shall be compensated in the same manner as for warranty service or parts.</p><p><pre/>This section does not apply to compensation for parts such as components, systems, fixtures, appliances, furnishings, accessories, and features that are designed, used, and maintained primarily for nonvehicular, residential purposes. Warranty audits of dealer records may be conducted by the manufacturer, factory branch, distributor, or distributor branch on a reasonable basis, and dealer claims for warranty compensation shall not be denied except for good cause, such as performance of nonwarranty repairs, lack of material documentation, fraud, or misrepresentation. Claims for dealer compensation shall be paid within 30 days of dealer submission or within 30 days of the end of an incentive program or rejected in writing for stated reasons. The manufacturer, factory branch, distributor, or distributor branch shall reserve the right to reasonable periodic audits to determine the validity of all such paid claims for dealer compensation. Any chargebacks for warranty parts or service compensation and service incentives shall only be for the 12-month period immediately following the date of the claim and, in the case of chargebacks for sales compensation only, for the 18-month period immediately following the date of claim. However, such limitations shall not be effective in the case of intentionally false or fraudulent claims.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b"/><heading><desig>B.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> It shall be unlawful for any recreational vehicle manufacturer, factory branch, distributor, or distributor branch to:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Fail to perform any of its warranty obligations, including tires, with respect to a recreational vehicle;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Fail to assume all responsibility for any liability resulting from structural or production defects;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Fail to include in written notices of factory recalls to recreational vehicle owners and dealers the expected date by which necessary parts and equipment will be available to dealers for the correction of defects;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_4"/><heading><desig>4.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Fail to compensate any of the recreational vehicle dealers licensed in the Commonwealth for repairs effected by the dealer of merchandise damaged in manufacture or transit to the dealer where the carrier is designated by the manufacturer, factory branch, distributor, or distributor branch;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_5"/><heading><desig>5.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Fail to compensate its recreational vehicle dealers licensed in the Commonwealth for warranty parts, work, and service pursuant to subsection A or for legal costs and expenses incurred by such dealers in connection with warranty obligations for which the manufacturer, factory branch, distributor, or distributor branch is legally responsible or that the manufacturer, factory branch, distributor, or distributor branch imposes upon the dealer;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_6"/><heading><desig>6.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Misrepresent in any way to purchasers of recreational vehicles that warranties with respect to the manufacture, performance, or design of the recreational vehicle are made by the dealer, either as warrantor or co-warrantor;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_7"/><heading><desig>7.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Require the dealer to make warranties to customers in any manner related to the manufacture, performance, or design of the recreational vehicle; or</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_8"/><heading><desig>8.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Shift or attempt to shift to the recreational vehicle dealer, directly or indirectly, any liabilities of the manufacturer, factory branch, distributor, or distributor branch under the Virginia Motor Vehicle Warranty Enforcement Act (<citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 59.1-207.9"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 59.1-207.9">§ 59.1-207.9<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000059#     1#        207.9#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> et seq.), unless such liability results from the act or omission by the dealer.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c"/><heading><desig>C.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Notwithstanding the terms of any franchise, it shall be unlawful for any recreational vehicle manufacturer, factory branch, distributor, or distributor branch to fail to indemnify and hold harmless its recreational vehicle dealers against any losses or damages arising out of complaints, claims, or suits relating to the manufacture, assembly, or design of recreational vehicles, parts, or accessories, or other functions by the manufacturer, factory branch, distributor, or distributor branch beyond the control of the dealer, including, without limitation, the selection by the manufacturer, factory branch, distributor, or distributor branch of parts or components for the recreational vehicle or any damages to merchandise occurring in transit to the dealer where the carrier is designated by the manufacturer, factory branch, distributor, or distributor branch. The dealer shall notify the manufacturer of pending suits in which allegations are made that come within this subsection whenever reasonably practicable to do so. Every recreational vehicle dealer franchise issued to, amended, or renewed for recreational vehicle dealers in the Commonwealth shall be construed to incorporate provisions consistent with the requirements of this subsection.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d"/><heading><desig>D.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> On any new recreational vehicle, any uncorrected damage or any corrected damage exceeding three percent of the manufacturer's or distributor's suggested retail price as defined in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="15 USC 1231"><content><span normalizedCite="15 U.S.C. 1231">15 U.S.C. §§ 1231<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1828#123#000015#       1231#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>-1233, as measured by retail repair costs, must be disclosed to the dealer in writing prior to delivery. Factory mechanical repair and damage to glass, tires, and bumpers are excluded from the three percent rule when properly replaced by identical manufacturer's or distributor's original equipment or parts. Whenever a new recreational vehicle is damaged in transit, when the carrier or means of transportation is determined by the manufacturer or distributor, or whenever a recreational vehicle is otherwise damaged prior to delivery to the new recreational vehicle dealer, the new recreational vehicle dealer shall:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Notify the manufacturer or distributor of the damage within three business days from the date of delivery of the new recreational vehicle to the new recreational vehicle dealership or within the additional time specified in the franchise; and</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Request from the manufacturer or distributor authorization to replace the components, parts, and accessories damaged or otherwise correct the damage, unless the damage to the recreational vehicle exceeds the three percent rule, in which case the dealer may reject the vehicle within three business days.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_e"/><heading><desig>E.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> If the manufacturer or distributor refuses or fails to authorize correction of such damage within 10 days after receipt of notification, or if the dealer rejects the recreational vehicle because damage exceeds the three percent rule, ownership of the new recreational vehicle shall revert to the manufacturer or distributor, and the new recreational vehicle dealer shall have no obligation, financial or otherwise, with respect to such recreational vehicle. Should either the manufacturer, distributor, or the dealer elect to correct the damage or any other damage exceeding the three percent rule, full disclosure shall be made by the dealer in writing to the buyer and an acknowledgment by the buyer is required. If there is less than three percent damage, no disclosure is required, provided that the damage has been corrected. Predelivery mechanical work shall not require a disclosure. Failure to disclose any corrected damage within the knowledge of the selling dealer to a new recreational vehicle in excess of the three percent rule shall constitute grounds for revocation of the buyer order, provided that, within 30 days of purchase, the recreational vehicle is returned to the dealer with an accompanying written notice of the grounds for revocation. In case of revocation pursuant to this section, the dealer shall accept the recreational vehicle and refund any payments made to the dealer in connection with the transaction, less a reasonable allowance for the consumer's use of the vehicle as defined in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 59.1-207.11"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 59.1-207.11">§ 59.1-207.11.<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000059#     1#       207.11#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation></p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_f"/><heading><desig>F.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> If there is a dispute between the manufacturer, factory branch, distributor, or distributor branch and the dealer with respect to any matter referred to in subsection A, B, or C, either party may petition the Commissioner in writing, within 30 days after either party has given written notice of the dispute to the other, for a hearing. The decision of the Commissioner shall be binding on the parties, subject to rights of judicial review and appeal as provided in the Administrative Process Act (<citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 2.2-4000"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 2.2-4000">§ 2.2-4000<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000002#     2#         4000#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> et seq.). However, nothing contained in this section shall give the Commissioner any authority as to the content or interpretation of any manufacturer's or distributor's warranty.</p></bodyText></level><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p><citation normalizedCite="1995 VA CH 767"><content><span normalizedCite="1995 Va. Ch. 767">1995, cc. 767<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1995#000767#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1995 VA CH 816"><content><span normalizedCite="1995 Va. Ch. 816">816<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1995#000816#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, § 46.2-1979; <citation normalizedCite="1996 VA CH 453"><content><span normalizedCite="1996 Va. Ch. 453">1996, cc. 453<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1996#000453#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1996 VA CH 1043"><content><span normalizedCite="1996 Va. Ch. 1043">1043<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1996#001043#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1996 VA CH 1052"><content><span normalizedCite="1996 Va. Ch. 1052">1052<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1996#001052#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2015 VA CH 615"><content><span normalizedCite="2015 Va. Ch. 615">2015, c. 615<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2015#000615#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PWC0-004G-K324-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 46.2.</desig><title>MOTOR VEHICLES</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="subtitle"><heading><desig>SUBTITLE IV.</desig><title>DEALERS AND DRIVER TRAINING SCHOOLS</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 15.</desig><title>MOTOR VEHICLE DEALERS</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="article"><heading><desig>ARTICLE 7.2.</desig><title>RECREATIONAL VEHICLE FRANCHISES.</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Antitrust &amp; Trade Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6REEyRTNDM0JGQzYyNEMyOEFGNTAwNUJEOUU1MDg4NjU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QzNBOTBENDBCNzk2NDRFQ0E1MUY4ODU3MzYyNUVBMkE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MURDQjFBMDIyNEVDNENFREJFNEIzOUVERUE4MjE0OEM</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjA4OEVGODBENzY4NDcxM0IyQzA1OTEwQzVDODRBOUE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Franchise Agreements</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NThGOTdFNEFBNDk1NEVGQ0FGMjRCMjg5RDNCQ0Y3RUY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6M0VDOEM1M0IxQThBNEQ4MEJGRDI4QjQ2NDYxNTA4MEE</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Fraud &amp; Misrepresentation</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NTU0NEQyODVBNjIwNEQ3MkI5RjNEQjRCQTM4RkMxMzI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6REU3MzM2MzI1RDdFNEU1QkIyRjJFOTkxMzk4QjMzODQ</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Mjg0NjVFNDA0MkI0NEY5RkI0MTQwMzI2MEM2MTQzMTE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6REU3MzM2MzI1RDdFNEU1QkIyRjJFOTkxMzk4QjMzODQ</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MzMwNEJCOTIyMjNCNEM2MjkxRTQ3RDE2RUNCREQzRDc7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RUFBNTg1NUM0MEI3NEJGM0EyRkI3RkNBNTUyQjhCMkE</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Qzc2Q0Q3QkMwNEU3NDJFN0FENzQ0MjEyNDNEQUU5RUQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QkFDNzQ1NkIxQkJENEYxRkEyRTVEN0VDODQ5MDRBQ0E</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Contracts Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QzY0RTZFMzE0RjkwNDdFQUI5M0U5N0ZFMjYyREMyQzU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NEREREIyNjFBM0ZFNDI3REFFRjUwQkUxNUYyNjczRjU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OUY4QjU3NUExRDY1NEIwQjlDODhBODYxQ0U5QTU4NDk</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Torts</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDAwOEM2NTEzQkVDNEI4NzlGMEZERUEyRjQwODM4Njg7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjMzNEI4MDMxNzE2NDE0Qjg2M0RCRTI5QkFBREFENkM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OUU0QUYxRTRCRERCNEQyNTgwQzdFMzA1NThBMDlFQkY</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Transportation Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RTYzRTk5RDVBQkQ2NDcwQzk2NTU3ODQ5OEE3NDlBNzk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Damages</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MEI2NTlDNDY2MkEzNDIzMjg5ODJERUIxMDREQ0JDQ0Y7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QzczQ0MwNDEzMjhGNDIxQ0FEM0ExM0EwQjk0QjI0RTk</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Workers' Compensation &amp; SSDI</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NTNGOEUzQTYwRUQ1NEFCN0FGMjg0Rjc5MjI3NjBDMEI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NUEzN0Y3RjczMEZENEVDMkE1MzBCNUY2OUJFQTRENjE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjA5MTVEOEFCRUE3NEEzMThGN0M3QzZFQ0RFQkI1MzU</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification><classificationGroup classificationScheme="indexing-terms"><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem score="90"><className>Transportation</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RTYzRTk5RDVBQkQ2NDcwQzk2NTU3ODQ5OEE3NDlBNzk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></classificationGroup></metadata></legislativeDoc>