<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#349#000038#     2#         1324#">Va. Code Ann. § 38.2-1324</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_38.2-1324"/><heading><desig>§ 38.2-1324.</desig><title>Contents of application</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a"/><heading><desig>A.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The application filed with the Commission under <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 38.2-1323"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 38.2-1323">§ 38.2-1323<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000038#     2#         1323#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> shall be made under oath or affirmation and shall contain the following information:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The name and address of each acquiring person including:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_1_a"/><heading><desig>a.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> If the acquiring person is a natural person, his principal occupation, all offices and positions held during the past five years, and any conviction of crimes other than minor traffic violations during the past 10 years; and</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_1_b"/><heading><desig>b.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> If the acquiring person is not a natural person, (i) a report of the nature of its business operations during the existence of the acquiring person and any of its predecessors, not to exceed five years; (ii) an informative description of the business intended to be done by the person and the person's subsidiaries; and (iii) a list of all individuals who are or who have been selected to become directors or executive officers of the person or who perform or will perform functions appropriate to those positions. The report shall include the information required by subdivision 1 a.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The source, nature, and amount of the consideration used or to be used in effecting the acquisition of control, a description of any transaction in which funds were or are to be obtained for that purpose, and the identity of persons furnishing the consideration. However, where a source of the consideration is a loan made in the lender's ordinary course of business, the identity of the lender shall remain confidential if requested by the person filing the application;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Fully audited financial information regarding the earnings and financial condition of each acquiring person during the existence of the acquiring person or the predecessors, not to exceed five years, and similar unaudited information as of a date not earlier than 90 days prior to the filing of the application;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_4"/><heading><desig>4.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Any plans or proposals that each acquiring person may have to liquidate the insurer, to sell its assets or merge or consolidate it with any person, or to make any other material change in its business or corporate structure or management;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_5"/><heading><desig>5.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The number of shares of any security of the insurer that each acquiring person proposes to acquire and the terms of the acquisition;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_6"/><heading><desig>6.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The amount of each class of any such security that each acquiring person beneficially owns or has a right to acquire beneficial ownership of;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_7"/><heading><desig>7.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A full description of any contracts, arrangements, or understandings with respect to any security in which an acquiring person is involved, including but not limited to transfer of any of the securities, joint ventures, loan or option arrangements, puts or calls, guarantees of loans, guarantees against loss or guarantees of profits, division of losses or profits, or the giving or withholding of proxies. The description shall identify the persons with whom the contracts, arrangements, or understandings have been made;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_8"/><heading><desig>8.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A description of any acquiring person's purchase of any such security during the 12 calendar months preceding the filing of the application, including the dates of purchases, names of the purchasers, and consideration paid or agreed to be paid for the security;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_9"/><heading><desig>9.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A description of any recommendations to purchase any such security made by any acquiring person or by any person based upon interviews or at the suggestion of any acquiring person during the 12 calendar months preceding the filing of the application;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_10"/><heading><desig>10.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Copies of all tender offers, requests or invitations for tenders of exchange offers and agreements to acquire or exchange any such security and of additional related soliciting material which has been distributed;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_11"/><heading><desig>11.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The terms of any agreement, contract, or understanding made with any broker-dealer as to solicitation of these securities for tender and the amount of any associated fees, commissions, or other compensation to be paid to broker-dealers;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_12"/><heading><desig>12.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> An agreement by the person required to file the statement referred to in subsection A of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 38.2-1323"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 38.2-1323">§ 38.2-1323<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000038#     2#         1323#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> that it will provide the annual enterprise risk report specified in subsection L of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 38.2-1329"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 38.2-1329">§ 38.2-1329<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000038#     2#         1329#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, for so long as control exists;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_13"/><heading><desig>13.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> An acknowledgment by the person required to file the statement referred to in subsection A of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 38.2-1323"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 38.2-1323">§ 38.2-1323<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000038#     2#         1323#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> that the person and all subsidiaries within its control in the insurance holding company system will provide information to the Commission upon request as necessary to evaluate enterprise risk to the insurer; and</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_14"/><heading><desig>14.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Any additional information the Commission may prescribe as necessary or appropriate for the protection of the policyholders or the public.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b"/><heading><desig>B.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> If the person required to file the application referred to in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 38.2-1323"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 38.2-1323">§ 38.2-1323<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000038#     2#         1323#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> is a partnership, limited partnership, syndicate, or other group, the Commission may require that the information called for by subsection A be given with respect to (i) each partner of the partnership or limited partnership, (ii) each member of the syndicate or group, and (iii) each person who controls any partner or member. If any partner, member, or person is a corporation, or if the person required to file the application referred to in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 38.2-1323"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 38.2-1323">§ 38.2-1323<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000038#     2#         1323#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> is a corporation, the Commission may require that information be given for the corporation, each officer and director of the corporation, and each person who is directly or indirectly the beneficial owner of more than 10 percent of the outstanding voting securities of the corporation as required by subsection A.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c"/><heading><desig>C.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> If any material change occurs in the facts set forth in the application filed with the Commission and sent to an insurer pursuant to <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 38.2-1323"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 38.2-1323">§ 38.2-1323<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000038#     2#         1323#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, an amendment setting forth the change, together with copies of all documents and other material relevant to the change, shall be filed with the Commission and sent to the insurer within two business days after the person filing the application learns of the change.</p></bodyText></level><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p>1977, c. 414, § 38.1-178.1:2; 1986, c. 562; <citation normalizedCite="2014 VA CH 309"><content><span normalizedCite="2014 Va. Ch. 309">2014, c. 309<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2014#000309#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PT40-004G-K4C1-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 38.2.</desig><title>INSURANCE</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 13.</desig><title>REPORTS, RESERVES AND EXAMINATIONS, INSURANCE HOLDING COMPANIES, REINSURANCE INTERMEDIARIES, AND MANAGING GENERAL AGENTS</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="article"><heading><desig>ARTICLE 5.</desig><title>INSURANCE HOLDING COMPANIES</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjA4OEVGODBENzY4NDcxM0IyQzA1OTEwQzVDODRBOUE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RDVCRkUzRjg3NUFFNDMwNjhGMDc3MkNENDMxNzhFOEM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDFEQjUyNDAyMzQ0NDQyNUE5RjNGOEZEMzNBRDA1RUY</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Insurance Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDM4MzQ2QUYzMTY0NDQzQTkxRDQwRUUzRUM5RDg0OEM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Brokers</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NjA1OTZGMjY0MkIyNEE3NEI1NDc3QjhGNjYzRjkyQjk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NzVCREFBMEI5RUMxNEVGNzhCNjRCRTNGODY5RTVBMTE</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Mergers &amp; Acquisitions Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjRDRTUzQzBCMEIyNDU5QkE4QjFDMEE2Qjg2MUZDOTk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RUY4N0JCOTk2OTJENDI1RjhGMjZDRjI3RDE1MjZGMkY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NkE4OEIzNzhFMEUxNEMwRkFENkZBNzlCRDcyNUEyRkI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification><classificationGroup classificationScheme="indexing-terms"><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem score="90"><className>Insurance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDM4MzQ2QUYzMTY0NDQzQTkxRDQwRUUzRUM5RDg0OEM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></classificationGroup></metadata></legislativeDoc>