<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#349#000018#     2#      308.016#">Va. Code Ann. § 18.2-308.016</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><note><bodyText><p>This section has more than one version with varying effective dates.  To view a complete list of the versions of this section see Table of Contents.</p></bodyText></note><anchor id="_18.2-308.016"/><heading><desig>§ 18.2-308.016.</desig><title>(Effective July 1, 2018) Retired law-enforcement officers; carrying a concealed handgun</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a"/><heading><desig>A.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Except as provided in subsection A of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 18.2-308.012"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 18.2-308.012">§ 18.2-308.012<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000018#     2#      308.012#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 18.2-308"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 18.2-308">§ 18.2-308<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000018#     2#          308#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> shall not apply to:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Any State Police officer retired from the Department of State Police, any officer retired from the Division of Capitol Police, any local law-enforcement officer, auxiliary police officer or animal control officer retired from a police department or sheriff's office within the Commonwealth, any special agent retired from the State Corporation Commission or the Virginia Alcoholic Beverage Control Authority, any employee with internal investigations authority designated by the Department of Corrections pursuant to subdivision 11 of § 53.1-10 retired from the Department of Corrections, any conservation police officer retired from the Department of Game and Inland Fisheries, any Virginia Marine Police officer retired from the Law Enforcement Division of the Virginia Marine Resources Commission, any campus police officer appointed under Article 3 (§ 23.1-809 et seq.) of Chapter 8 of Title 23.1 retired from a campus police department, any retired member of the enforcement division of the Department of Motor Vehicles appointed pursuant to <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 46.2-217"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 46.2-217">§ 46.2-217<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000046#     2#          217#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, and any retired investigator of the security division of the Virginia Lottery, other than an officer or agent terminated for cause, (i) with a service-related disability; (ii) following at least 10 years of service with any such law-enforcement agency, commission, board, or any combination thereof; (iii) who has reached 55 years of age; or (iv) who is on long-term leave from such law-enforcement agency or board due to a service-related injury, provided such officer carries with him written proof of consultation with and favorable review of the need to carry a concealed handgun issued by the chief law-enforcement officer of the last such agency from which the officer retired or the agency that employs the officer or, in the case of special agents, issued by the State Corporation Commission or the Virginia Alcoholic Beverage Control Authority. A copy of the proof of consultation and favorable review shall be forwarded by the chief, Commission, or Board to the Department of State Police for entry into the Virginia Criminal Information Network. The chief law-enforcement officer shall not without cause withhold such written proof if the retired law-enforcement officer otherwise meets the requirements of this section. An officer set forth in clause (iv) who receives written proof of consultation to carry a concealed handgun shall surrender such proof of consultation upon return to work or upon termination of employment with the law-enforcement agency. Notice of the surrender shall be forwarded to the Department of State Police for entry into the Virginia Criminal Information Network. However, if such officer retires on disability because of the service-related injury, and would be eligible under clause (i) for written proof of consultation to carry a concealed handgun, he may retain the previously issued written proof of consultation.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Any person who is eligible for retirement with at least 20 years of service with a law-enforcement agency, commission, or board mentioned in subdivision 1 who has resigned in good standing from such law-enforcement agency, commission, or board to accept a position covered by a retirement system that is authorized under Title 51.1, provided such person carries with him written proof of consultation with and favorable review of the need to carry a concealed handgun issued by the chief law-enforcement officer of the agency from which he resigned or, in the case of special agents, issued by the State Corporation Commission or the Virginia Alcoholic Beverage Control Authority. A copy of the proof of consultation and favorable review shall be forwarded by the chief, Commission, or Board to the Department of State Police for entry into the Virginia Criminal Information Network. The chief law-enforcement officer shall not without cause withhold such written proof if the law-enforcement officer otherwise meets the requirements of this section.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Any State Police officer who is a member of the organized reserve forces of any of the Armed Services of the United States or National Guard, while such officer is called to active military duty, provided such officer carries with him written proof of consultation with and favorable review of the need to carry a concealed handgun issued by the Superintendent of State Police. The proof of consultation and favorable review shall be valid as long as the officer is on active military duty and shall expire when the officer returns to active law-enforcement duty. The issuance of the proof of consultation and favorable review shall be entered into the Virginia Criminal Information Network. The Superintendent of State Police shall not without cause withhold such written proof if the officer is in good standing and is qualified to carry a weapon while on active law-enforcement duty.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b"/><heading><desig>B.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> For purposes of complying with the federal Law Enforcement Officers Safety Act of 2004, a retired or resigned law-enforcement officer who receives proof of consultation and review pursuant to this section shall have the opportunity to annually participate, at the retired or resigned law-enforcement officer's expense, in the same training and testing to carry firearms as is required of active law-enforcement officers in the Commonwealth. If such retired or resigned law-enforcement officer meets the training and qualification standards, the chief law-enforcement officer shall issue the retired or resigned officer certification, valid one year from the date of issuance, indicating that the retired or resigned officer has met the standards of the agency to carry a firearm.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c"/><heading><desig>C.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A retired or resigned law-enforcement officer who receives proof of consultation and review pursuant to this section may annually participate and meet the training and qualification standards to carry firearms as is required of active law-enforcement officers in the Commonwealth. If such retired or resigned law-enforcement officer meets the training and qualification standards, the chief law-enforcement officer shall issue the retired or resigned officer certification, valid one year from the date of issuance, indicating that the retired or resigned officer has met the standards of the Commonwealth to carry a firearm. A copy of the certification indicating that the retired or resigned officer has met the standards of the Commonwealth to carry a firearm shall be forwarded by the chief, Commission, or Board to the Department of State Police for entry into the Virginia Criminal Information Network.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d"/><heading><desig>D.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> For all purposes, including for the purpose of applying the reciprocity provisions of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 18.2-308.014"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 18.2-308.014">§ 18.2-308.014<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000018#     2#      308.014#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, any person granted the privilege to carry a concealed handgun pursuant to this section, while carrying the proof of consultation and favorable review required, shall be deemed to have been issued a concealed handgun permit.</p></bodyText></level><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p><citation normalizedCite="2016 VA CH 209"><content><span normalizedCite="2016 Va. Ch. 209">2016, cc. 209<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2016#000209#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2016 VA CH 257"><content><span normalizedCite="2016 Va. Ch. 257">257<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2016#000257#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2016 VA CH 421"><content><span normalizedCite="2016 Va. Ch. 421">421<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2016#000421#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PWD0-004G-K3D4-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 18.2.</desig><title>CRIMES AND OFFENSES GENERALLY</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 7.</desig><title>CRIMES INVOLVING HEALTH AND SAFETY</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="article"><heading><desig>ARTICLE 6.1.</desig><title>CONCEALED WEAPONS AND CONCEALED HANDGUN PERMITS</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjA4OEVGODBENzY4NDcxM0IyQzA1OTEwQzVDODRBOUE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Q0I0MEM0NzQwMjFGNEU3MzgxMUVEN0IyNzI0RjNGNEE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MkE1OTExQkYxN0UyNDU0NkIxRjRCOTVFM0UwQ0MxMTk</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MTY4NjRCRjcwODE2NDNGMEJGOTcwM0MzNEJERkZCNzQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NjcxMDAyODc5OTA1NDBEMjhFMEVEQUM2NzI1NkM2NTA</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Operation of Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RDMzRUIzMkY4QzFDNEI4Qjg0MERBM0MxMjQwMTQ2NUY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NjcxMDAyODc5OTA1NDBEMjhFMEVEQUM2NzI1NkM2NTA</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Special Agents</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6ODQ2NTAwQkMzOTA0NDNDMUI4OTcxRjEzRTNCNTlEODE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MkE1OTExQkYxN0UyNDU0NkIxRjRCOTVFM0UwQ0MxMTk</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Criminal Law &amp; Procedure</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NEU0RkE1OUQwNUQwNDgxODhEODZCMjkzOTg3NThBNzk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Applications</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Q0E0OTA2NEZGOTdGNDdGM0E3RDUxOUZDRjA2NzMwNkI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MzZEODM5NDNBMDJCNDIzMEI0RkQyOEMzM0U2MUE5QzI</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Carrying &amp; Concealed Permits</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDhDMzU1NTY1MUE1NDQ3NTg3QTRFNDIxNzAwNzM3RTQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MzZEODM5NDNBMDJCNDIzMEI0RkQyOEMzM0U2MUE5QzI</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MEU1MzkwRjgyRjdENEMyREJEMDZFNDQxNjYzODdBMjk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUI3NjYzN0UxRTI4NEE2MEE2NzlCQTkxRkM1NUEwRDc</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RjczMDYwMkI2NjFENDQxOTkxMENCOUY4N0RFNDBGQUY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RUZDNkZFODQ3QUExNEU1MzlBRTQ5OUY2MTM3QjQ3Nzk</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDVCNjQzRTU0Q0MzNDQ1RjkyM0M5QjI2QzY5OTc1MEM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MzZEODM5NDNBMDJCNDIzMEI0RkQyOEMzM0U2MUE5QzI</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6N0Y3MEEyMEY2NTE1NDcyOThBNTAyMDJEQjQ3NDEwOUQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDNBRjM1MzY2MkNBNDJDOEI0RURGOEE0QzExOUQ2NkM</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Governments</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjdEQjE4OUJDMzQxNDNEMEI0RTI1QUFCMzJENjEwRTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Employees &amp; Officials</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NzhCNTkxRUNENDI5NDQxMDk3NkNGOTI5REE1RjI0QjM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MkM1MTYwRDE0NkJBNEVFMEIxQjM3RUE2NDRFQUFEODY</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Labor &amp; Employment Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MTE3QUQwOTA0MUYzNDlCMEFFMjUwRUNDM0RDRkM5QzM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RDY5MEREQjZCQzFBNDk5NUE1NTU1QTBDMjYwNUJGMjA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MzBEMkJFMTg2NTJDNEVGRjlGREQ2Nzg2ODkzMzkwQTQ</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Military &amp; Veterans Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NzM1OUEyRDNERTdENEU2MTk3RTlCNEJCRUY0NjRGRjQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>US National Guard</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NTkwM0VGNDEwNEJENEExOEJGMzY1NUQxM0MwNzVGQjQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MEZGOTk3QzJDQUY1NDk5MDlDOTI5MDI4NDYxRDU5NjE</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Weapons</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NjNGNDBBOEIxMEJFNEU3MkJDNkY2QzJFRDJDMTdCMUE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjkyNTQ4NzRBQzdFNDk0RUI0REMxNEY0RDNGM0MyNzg</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Torts</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDAwOEM2NTEzQkVDNEI4NzlGMEZERUEyRjQwODM4Njg7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MkQwMTc0MUU5MzkxNEMwQzhEQkU0QjA2REQzQzNGMTc7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RjMzQjNFQ0U1MDdFNEQzMjg0MTA0MTY4MUZCQTZBM0U</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification><classificationGroup classificationScheme="indexing-terms"><classification classificationScheme="legal"/></classificationGroup></metadata></legislativeDoc>