<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#123#000030#       111#">Va. Code Ann. § 30-111</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><note><bodyText><p>This section has more than one version with varying effective dates.  To view a complete list of the versions of this section see Table of Contents.</p></bodyText></note><anchor id="_30-111"/><heading><desig>§ 30-111.</desig><title>(Effective until January 1, 2017) Disclosure form</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a"/><heading><desig>A.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The disclosure form to be used for filings required by subsections A and B of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 30-110"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 30 -110">§ 30-110<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#123#000030#       110#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> shall be substantially similar to the following. All completed forms shall be filed electronically with the Council in accordance with the standards approved by it pursuant to <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 30-356"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 30 -356">§ 30-356<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#123#000030#       356#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p><p>STATEMENT OF ECONOMIC INTERESTS. </p><p>Name.....................................................................…</p><p>Office or position held or sought........................................…</p><p>Address..................................................................…</p><p>Names of members of immediate family.....................................…</p><p>DEFINITIONS AND EXPLANATORY MATERIAL. </p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Business"</emphasis> means a corporation, partnership, sole proprietorship, firm, enterprise, franchise, association, trust or foundation, or any other individual or entity carrying on a business or profession, whether or not for profit.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Close financial association"</emphasis> means an association in which the filer shares significant financial involvement with an individual and the filer would reasonably be expected to be aware of the individual's business activities and would have access to the necessary records either directly or through the individual. "Close financial association" does not mean an association based on (i) the receipt of retirement benefits or deferred compensation from a business by which the legislator is no longer employed, or (ii) the receipt of compensation for work performed by the legislator as an independent contractor of a business that represents an entity before any state governmental agency when the legislator has had no communications with the state governmental agency.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Contingent liability"</emphasis> means a liability that is not presently fixed or determined, but may become fixed or determined in the future with the occurrence of some certain event.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Gift"</emphasis> means any gratuity, favor, discount, entertainment, hospitality, loan, forbearance, or other item having monetary value. It includes services as well as gifts of transportation, lodgings and meals, whether provided in-kind, by purchase of a ticket, payment in advance or reimbursement after the expense has been incurred. "Gift" does not include (i) any offer of a ticket, coupon, or other admission or pass unless the ticket, coupon, admission, or pass is used; (ii) honorary degrees; (iii) any athletic, merit, or need-based scholarship or any other financial aid awarded by a public or private school, institution of higher education, or other educational program pursuant to such school, institution, or program's financial aid standards and procedures applicable to the general public; (iv) a campaign contribution properly received and reported pursuant to Chapter 9.3 (<citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 24.2-945"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 24.2-945">§ 24.2-945<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000024#     2#          945#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> et seq.) of Title 24.2; (v) any gift related to the private profession or occupation of a legislator or of a member of his immediate family; (vi) food or beverages consumed while attending an event at which the filer is performing official duties related to his public service; (vii) food and beverages received at or registration or attendance fees waived for any event at which the filer is a featured speaker, presenter, or lecturer; (viii) unsolicited awards of appreciation or recognition in the form of a plaque, trophy, wall memento, or similar item that is given in recognition of public, civic, charitable, or professional service; (ix) a devise or inheritance; (x) travel disclosed pursuant to the Campaign Finance Disclosure Act (<citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 24.2-945"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 24.2-945">§ 24.2-945<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000024#     2#          945#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> et seq.); (xi) travel paid for or provided by the government of the United States, any of its territories, or any state or any political subdivision of such state; (xii) travel provided to facilitate attendance by a legislator at a regular or special session of the General Assembly, a meeting of a legislative committee or commission, or a national conference where attendance is approved by the House or Senate Committee on Rules; (xiii) travel related to an official meeting of the Commonwealth, its political subdivisions, or any board, commission, authority, or other entity, or any charitable organization established pursuant to <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="26 USC 501"><content><span normalizedCite="26 U.S.C. 501">§ 501(c)(3) of the Internal Revenue Code<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#29854#1127#00000000501#1#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> affiliated with such entity, to which such person has been appointed or elected or is a member by virtue of his office or employment; or (xiv) gifts from relatives or personal friends. "Relative" means the donee's spouse, child, uncle, aunt, niece, nephew, or first cousin; a person to whom the donee is engaged to be married; the donee's or his spouse's parent, grandparent, grandchild, brother, sister, step-parent, step-grandparent, step-grandchild, step-brother, or step-sister; or the donee's brother's or sister's spouse. "Personal friend" does not include any person that the filer knows or has reason to know is (a) a lobbyist registered pursuant to Article 3 (<citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 2.2-418"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 2.2-418">§ 2.2-418<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000002#     2#          418#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> et seq.) of Chapter 4 of Title 2.2 or (b) a lobbyist's principal as defined in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 2.2-419"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 2.2-419">§ 2.2-419<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000002#     2#          419#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Immediate family"</emphasis> means (i) a spouse and (ii) any other person who resides in the same household as the legislator and who is a dependent of the legislator.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Lobbyist relationship"</emphasis> means (i) an engagement, agreement, or representation that relates to legal services, consulting services, or public relations services, whether gratuitous or for compensation, between a member or member-elect and any person who is, or has been within the prior calendar year, registered as a lobbyist with the Secretary of the Commonwealth or (ii) a greater than three percent ownership interest by a member or member-elect in a business that employs, or engages as an independent contractor, any person who is, or has been within the prior calendar year, registered as a lobbyist with the Secretary of the Commonwealth. The disclosure of a lobbyist relationship shall not (a) constitute a waiver of any attorney-client or other privilege, (b) require a waiver of any attorney-client or other privilege for a third party, or (c) be required where a member or member-elect is employed or engaged by a person and such person also employs or engages a person in a lobbyist relationship so long as the member or member-elect has no financial interest in the lobbyist relationship.</p><p>TRUST. If you or your immediate family, separately or together, are the only beneficiaries of a trust, treat the trust's assets as if you own them directly. If you or your immediate family has a proportional interest in a trust, treat that proportion of the trust's assets as if you own them directly. For example, if you and your immediate family have a one-third interest in a trust, complete your Statement as if you own one-third of each of the trust's assets. If you or a member of your immediate family created a trust and can revoke it without the beneficiaries' consent, treat its assets as if you own them directly.</p><p>REPORT TO THE BEST OF INFORMATION AND BELIEF. Information required on this Statement must be provided on the basis of the best knowledge, information, and belief of the individual filing the Statement as of the date of this report unless otherwise stated.</p><p>COMPLETE ITEMS 1 THROUGH 11. REFER TO SCHEDULES ONLY IF DIRECTED.</p><p>You may attach additional explanatory information.</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Offices and Directorships.</p><p><pre/>Are you or a member of your immediate family a paid officer or paid director of a business?</p><p><pre/>EITHER check NO /  /  OR check YES /  /  and complete Schedule A.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Personal Liabilities.</p><p><pre/>Do you or a member of your immediate family owe more than $ 5,000 to any one creditor including contingent liabilities? (Exclude debts to any government and loans secured by recorded liens on property at least equal in value to the loan.)</p><p><pre/>EITHER check NO /  /  OR check YES /  /  and complete Schedule B.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Securities.</p><p><pre/>Do you or a member of your immediate family, directly or indirectly, separately or together, own securities valued in excess of $ 5,000 invested in one business? Account for mutual funds, limited partnerships and trusts.</p><p><pre/>EITHER check NO /  /  OR check YES /  /  and complete Schedule C.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_4"/><heading><desig>4.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Payments for Talks, Meetings, and Publications.</p><p><pre/>During the past six months did you receive in your capacity as a legislator lodging, transportation, money, or anything else of value with a combined value exceeding $ 100 (i) for a single talk, meeting, or published work or (ii) for a meeting, conference, or event where your attendance at the meeting, conference, or event was designed to (a) educate you on issues relevant to your duties as a legislator, including issues faced by your constituents, or (b) enhance your knowledge and skills relative to your duties as a legislator? Do not include payments and reimbursements from the Commonwealth for meetings attended in your capacity as a legislator; see Question 11 and Schedule D2 to report such meetings.</p><p><pre/>EITHER check NO /  /  OR check YES /  /  and complete Schedule D.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_5"/><heading><desig>5.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Gifts.</p><p><pre/>During the past six months did a business, government, or individual other than a relative or personal friend (i) furnish you or a member of your immediate family with any gift or entertainment at a single event, and the value received exceeded $ 50 or (ii) furnish you or a member of your immediate family with gifts or entertainment in any combination and the total value received exceeded $ 50, and for which you or the member of your immediate family neither paid nor rendered services in exchange? Account for entertainment events only if the average value per person attending the event exceeded $ 50. Account for all business entertainment (except if related to the private profession or occupation of you or the member of your immediate family who received such business entertainment) even if unrelated to your official duties.</p><p><pre/>EITHER check NO /  /  OR check YES /  /  and complete Schedule E.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_6"/><heading><desig>6.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Salary and Wages.</p><p><pre/>List each employer that pays you or a member of your immediate family salary or wages in excess of $ 5,000 annually. (Exclude any salary received as a member of the General Assembly pursuant to <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 30-19.11"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 30 -19.11">§ 30-19.11.<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#123#000030#     19.11#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>)</p><p><pre/>If no reportable salary or wages, check here /  /.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="un"><pre/></emphasis></p><p><emphasis typeStyle="un"><pre/></emphasis></p><p><emphasis typeStyle="un"><pre/></emphasis></p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_7"/><heading><desig>7.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Business Interests and Lobbyist Relationships.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_7a"/><heading><desig>7A.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Do you or a member of your immediate family, separately or together, operate your own business, or own or control an interest in excess of $ 5,000 in a business?</p><p><pre/>EITHER check NO /  /  OR check YES /  /  and complete Schedule F-1.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_7b"/><heading><desig>7B.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Do you have a lobbyist relationship as that term is defined above?</p><p><pre/>EITHER check NO /  /  OR check YES /  /  and complete Schedule F-2.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_8"/><heading><desig>8.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Payments for Representation and Other Services.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_8a"/><heading><desig>8A.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Did you represent any businesses before any state governmental agencies, excluding courts or judges, for which you received total compensation during the past six months in excess of $ 1,000, excluding compensation for other services to such businesses and representation consisting solely of the filing of mandatory papers and subsequent representation regarding the mandatory papers?</p><p><pre/>EITHER check NO /  /  OR check YES /  /  and complete Schedule G-1.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_8b"/><heading><desig>8B.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Subject to the same exceptions as in 8A, did persons with whom you have a close financial association (partners, associates or others) represent any businesses before any state governmental agency for which total compensation was received during the past six months in excess of $ 1,000?</p><p><pre/>EITHER check NO /  /  OR check YES /  /  and complete Schedule G-2.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_8c"/><heading><desig>8C.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Did you or persons with whom you have a close financial association furnish services to businesses operating in Virginia, pursuant to an agreement between you and such businesses, or between persons with whom you have a close financial association and such businesses for which total compensation in excess of $ 1,000 was received during the past six months? Services reported under this provision shall not include services involving the representation of businesses that are reported under question 8A or 8B above.</p><p><pre/>EITHER check NO /  /  OR check YES /  /  and complete Schedule G-3.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_9"/><heading><desig>9.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Real Estate.</p><p><pre/>Do you or a member of your immediate family hold an interest, including a partnership interest, valued at more than $ 5,000 in real property (other than your principal residence) for which you have not already listed the full address on Schedule F? Account for real estate held in trust.</p><p><pre/>EITHER check NO /  /  OR check YES /  /  and complete Schedule H.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_10"/><heading><desig>10.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Real Estate Contracts with State Governmental Agencies.</p><p><pre/>Do you or a member of your immediate family hold an interest valued at more than $ 5,000 in real estate, including a corporate, partnership, or trust interest, option, easement, or land contract, which real estate is the subject of a contract, whether pending or completed within the past six months, with a state governmental agency?</p><p><pre/>If the real estate contract provides for the leasing of the property to a state governmental agency, do you or a member of your immediate family hold an interest in the real estate, including a corporate, partnership, or trust interest, option, easement, or land contract valued at more than $ 1,000? Account for all such contracts whether or not your interest is reported in Schedule F or H. This requirement to disclose an interest in a lease does not apply to an interest derived through an ownership interest in a business unless the ownership interest exceeds three percent of the total equity of the business.</p><p><pre/>EITHER check NO /  /  OR check YES /  /  and complete Schedule I.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_11"/><heading><desig>11.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Payments by the Commonwealth for Meetings.</p><p><pre/>During the past six months did you receive lodging, transportation, money, or anything else of value with a combined value exceeding $ 100 from the Commonwealth for a single meeting attended out-of-state in your capacity as a legislator? Do not include reimbursements from the Commonwealth for meetings attended in the Commonwealth.</p><p><pre/>EITHER check NO /  /  OR check YES /  /  and complete Schedule D-2.</p><p><pre/>For Statements filed in June 2016 and each two years thereafter, complete the following statement indicating whether you completed the ethics orientation sessions provided pursuant to law:</p><p><pre/>I certify that I completed ethics training as required by <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 30-129.1"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 30 -129.1">§ 30-129.1.<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#123#000030#     129.1#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> YES /  /  or NO /  /  .</p><p><pre/>Statements of Economic Interests are open for public inspection.</p><p>AFFIRMATION. </p><p><pre/>In accordance with the rules of the house in which I serve, if I receive a request that this disclosure statement be corrected, augmented, or revised in any respect, I hereby pledge that I shall respond promptly to the request. I understand that if a determination is made that the statement is insufficient, I will satisfy such request or be subjected to disciplinary action of my house.</p><p><pre/>I swear or affirm that the foregoing information is full, true and correct to the best of my knowledge.</p><p><pre/>Signature <emphasis typeStyle="un"><pre/></emphasis></p><p><pre/>(Return only if needed to complete Statement.)</p><p>SCHEDULES<br/>to<br/>STATEMENT OF ECONOMIC INTERESTS. </p><p><pre/>NAME <emphasis typeStyle="un"><pre/></emphasis></p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_11_a"/><heading><desig>SCHEDULE A --</desig><title> OFFICES AND DIRECTORSHIPS.</title></heading><bodyText><p>Identify each business of which you or a member of your immediate family is a paid officer or paid director.</p><p>--------------------------------------------------------------- ------------- <br/>--------------------------------------------------------------- ------------- </p><p>Name of Business<pre/>Address of Business<pre/>Position Held<pre/><br/><pre/>and by Whom<pre/><br/>-----------------<pre/>------------------<pre/>------------------<pre/><br/>-----------------<pre/>------------------<pre/>------------------<pre/><br/>-----------------<pre/>------------------<pre/>------------------<pre/><br/>-----------------<pre/>------------------<pre/>------------------<pre/><br/>--------------------------------------------------------------- ------------- <br/>--------------------------------------------------------------- ------------- </p><p><pre/>RETURN TO ITEM 2</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_11_b"/><heading><desig>SCHEDULE B --</desig><title> PERSONAL LIABILITIES.</title></heading><bodyText><p>Report personal liability by checking each category. Report only debts in excess of $ 5,000. Do not report debts to any government. Do not report loans secured by recorded liens on property at least equal in value to the loan.</p><p><pre/>Report contingent liabilities below and indicate which debts are contingent.</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_11_b_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> My personal debts are as follows:</p><p>--------------------------------------------------------------- ------------- <br/>--------------------------------------------------------------- ------------- </p><p><pre/>Check<pre/>Check one<pre/><br/><pre/>appropriate<pre/>$ 5,001 to<pre/>More than <br/><pre/>categories<pre/>$ 50,000<pre/>$ 50,000<pre/><br/>Banks<pre/><br/>Savings institutions<pre/><br/>Other loan or finance companies<pre/><br/>Insurance companies<pre/><br/>Stock, commodity or other brokerage<pre/><br/><pre/>companies<pre/><br/>Other businesses:<pre/><br/>(State principal business activity for each<pre/><br/><pre/>creditor and its name.)<pre/><br/><emphasis typeStyle="un"><pre/></emphasis><pre/><br/><emphasis typeStyle="un"><pre/></emphasis><pre/><br/>Individual creditors:<pre/><br/>(State principal business or occupation of<pre/><br/><pre/>each creditor and its name.)<pre/><br/><emphasis typeStyle="un"><pre/></emphasis><pre/><br/><emphasis typeStyle="un"><pre/></emphasis></p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_11_b_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The personal debts of the members of my immediate family are as follows:</p><p>--------------------------------------------------------------- ------------- <br/>--------------------------------------------------------------- ------------- </p><p><pre/>Check<pre/>Check one<pre/><br/><pre/>appropriate<pre/>$ 5,001 to<pre/>More than <br/><pre/>categories<pre/>$ 50,000<pre/>$ 50,000<pre/><br/>Banks<pre/><br/>Savings institutions<pre/><br/>Other loan or finance companies<pre/><br/>Insurance companies<pre/><br/>Stock, commodity or other brokerage<pre/><br/><pre/>companies<pre/><br/>Other businesses:<pre/><br/>(State principal business activity for each<pre/><br/><pre/>creditor and its name.)<pre/><br/><emphasis typeStyle="un"><pre/></emphasis><pre/><br/><emphasis typeStyle="un"><pre/></emphasis><pre/><br/>Individual creditors:<pre/><br/>(State principal business or occupation of<pre/><br/><pre/>each creditor and its name.)<pre/><br/><emphasis typeStyle="un"><pre/></emphasis><pre/><br/><emphasis typeStyle="un"><pre/></emphasis></p><p><pre/>RETURN TO ITEM 3</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_11_c"/><heading><desig>SCHEDULE C --</desig><title> SECURITIES.</title></heading><bodyText><p>"Securities" INCLUDES stocks, bonds, "Securities" EXCLUDES</p><p>mutual funds, limited partnerships, certificates of deposit,</p><p>and commodity futures contracts. money market funds, annuity</p><p>contracts, and insurance policies.</p><p><pre/>Identify each business or Virginia governmental entity in which you or a member of your immediate family, directly or indirectly, separately or together, own securities valued in excess of $ 5,000. Name each issuer and type of security individually.</p><p><pre/>Do not list U.S. Bonds or other government securities not issued by the Commonwealth of Virginia or its authorities, agencies, or local governments. Do not list organizations that do not do business in this Commonwealth, but most major businesses conduct business in Virginia. Account for securities held in trust.</p><p><pre/>If no reportable securities, check here /  / .</p><p>----------------------------------------------------------------------------- <br/>----------------------------------------------------------------------------- <br/><pre/>Check one<pre/><br/><pre/>Type of Security<pre/>$ 5,001<pre/>$ 50,001<pre/>More<pre/><br/><pre/>(stocks, bonds, mutual<pre/>to<pre/>to<pre/>than<pre/><br/>Name of Issuer<pre/>funds, etc.)<pre/>$ <pre/>$ 250,000<pre/>$ <pre/><br/><pre/>50,000<pre/>250,000<br/>--------------<pre/>------------------------ ------- ---------<pre/>-------<br/><pre/>---<pre/><br/>--------------<pre/>------------------------ ------- ---------<pre/>-------<br/><pre/>---<pre/><br/>--------------<pre/>------------------------ ------- ---------<pre/>-------<br/><pre/>---<pre/><br/>--------------<pre/>------------------------ ------- ---------<pre/>-------<br/><pre/>---<pre/><br/>----------------------------------------------------------------------------- <br/>----------------------------------------------------------------------------- </p><p><pre/>RETURN TO ITEM 4</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_11_d-1"/><heading><desig>SCHEDULE D-1 --</desig><title> PAYMENTS FOR TALKS, MEETINGS, AND PUBLICATIONS.</title></heading><bodyText><p>List each source from which you received during the past six months in your capacity as a legislator lodging, transportation, money, or any other thing of value with a combined value exceeding $ 100 (i) for your presentation of a single talk, participation in one meeting, or publication of a work or (ii) for your attendance at a meeting, conference, or event where your attendance at the meeting, conference, or event was designed to (a) educate you on issues relevant to your duties as a legislator, including issues faced by your constituents, or (b) enhance your knowledge and skills relative to your duties as a legislator. Any lodging, transportation, money, or other thing of value received by a legislator that does not satisfy the criteria of clause (i), (ii)(a), or (ii)(b) shall be listed as a gift on Schedule E. Do not list payments or reimbursements by the Commonwealth. (See Schedule D-2 for such payments or reimbursements.) List a payment even if you donated it to charity. Do not list information about a payment if you returned it within 60 days or if you received it from an employer already listed under Item 6 or from a source of income listed on Schedule F.</p><p><pre/>If no payment must be listed, check here / /.</p><p>--------------------------------------------------------------- ------------- <br/>--------------------------------------------------------------- ------------- <br/><pre/>Type of Payment<pre/><br/><pre/>(e.g.Honoraria<pre/><br/><pre/>Travel reimburse-<pre/><br/>Payer<pre/>Approximate Value<pre/>Circumstances<pre/>ment, etc.)<pre/><br/>----------<pre/>---------------------<pre/>--------------<pre/>---------------<pre/><br/>----------<pre/>---------------------<pre/>--------------<pre/>---------------<pre/><br/>----------<pre/>---------------------<pre/>--------------<pre/>---------------<pre/><br/>----------<pre/>---------------------<pre/>--------------<pre/>---------------<pre/><br/>--------------------------------------------------------------- ------------- <br/>--------------------------------------------------------------- ------------- </p><p><pre/>RETURN TO ITEM 5</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_11_d-2"/><heading><desig>SCHEDULE D-2 --</desig><title> PAYMENTS BY THE COMMONWEALTH FOR MEETINGS.</title></heading><bodyText><p>List each meeting for which the Commonwealth provided payments or reimbursements during the past six months to you for lodging, transportation, money, or any other thing of value with a combined value exceeding $ 100 for your participation in your capacity as a legislator. Do not list payments or reimbursements by the Commonwealth for meetings or travel within the Commonwealth.</p><p><pre/>If no payment must be listed, check here /  /.</p><p>--------------------------------------------------------------- ------------- <br/>--------------------------------------------------------------- ------------- <br/><pre/>Type of Payment<pre/><br/><pre/>(e.g. Honoraria,<pre/><br/><pre/>travel reimburse-<pre/><br/>Payer<pre/>Approximate Value<pre/>Circumstances<pre/>ment, etc.)<pre/><br/>----------<pre/>---------------------<pre/>--------------<pre/>---------------<pre/><br/>----------<pre/>---------------------<pre/>--------------<pre/>---------------<pre/><br/>----------<pre/>---------------------<pre/>--------------<pre/>---------------<pre/><br/>----------<pre/>---------------------<pre/>--------------<pre/>---------------<pre/><br/>--------------------------------------------------------------- ------------- <br/>--------------------------------------------------------------- ------------- </p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_11_e"/><heading><desig>SCHEDULE E --</desig><title> GIFTS.</title></heading><bodyText><p>List each business, governmental entity, or individual that, during the past six months, (i) furnished you or a member of your immediate family with any gift or entertainment at a single event, and the value received exceeded $ 50 or (ii) furnished you or a member of your immediate family with gifts or entertainment in any combination and the total value received exceeded $ 50, and for which you or the member of your immediate family neither paid nor rendered services in exchange. List each such gift or event.</p><p><pre/>Do not list entertainment events unless the average value per person attending the event exceeded $ 50. Do not list business entertainment related to the private profession or occupation of you or the member of your immediate family who received such business entertainment. Do not list gifts or other things of value given by a relative or personal friend for reasons clearly unrelated to your public position. Do not list campaign contributions publicly reported as required by Chapter 9.3 (<citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 24.2-945"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 24.2-945">§ 24.2-945<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000024#     2#          945#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> et seq.) of Title 24.2 of the Code of Virginia.</p><p> --------------------------------------------------------------- ------------ <br/> --------------------------------------------------------------- ------------ <br/><pre/>Name of Business,<pre/>City or<pre/>Exact<pre/><br/>Name of<pre/>Organization, or<pre/>County<pre/>Gift or<pre/>Approximate<br/>Recipient<pre/>Individual<pre/>and State<pre/>Event<pre/>Value</p><p><pre/>RETURN TO ITEM 6</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_11_f-1"/><heading><desig>SCHEDULE F-1 --</desig><title> BUSINESS INTERESTS.</title></heading><bodyText><p>Complete this Schedule for each self-owned or family-owned business (including rental property, a farm, or consulting work), partnership, or corporation in which you or a member of your immediate family, separately or together, own an interest having a value in excess of $ 5,000.</p><p><pre/>If the enterprise is owned or operated under a trade, partnership, or corporate name, list that name; otherwise, merely explain the nature of the enterprise. If rental property is owned or operated under a trade, partnership, or corporate name, list the name only; otherwise, give the address of each property. Account for business interests held in trust.</p><p>--------------------------------------------------------------- ------------- <br/>--------------------------------------------------------------- ------------- <br/>Name of<pre/>Gross<pre/>income<pre/><br/>Business<pre/>Nature of<pre/><br/>Corporation<pre/>Enterprise<pre/><br/>Partnership,<pre/>(farming,<pre/><br/>Farm;<pre/>law,<pre/><br/>Address of<pre/>City or<pre/>rental<pre/>$ 50,000<pre/>$ 50,001<pre/>More<pre/><br/>Rental<pre/>County<pre/>property,<pre/>or less<pre/>to<pre/>than<pre/><br/>Property<pre/>and State etc.)<pre/>$ 250,000<pre/>$ 250,000<pre/><br/>------------<pre/>--------- -----------<pre/>-------<pre/>---------<pre/>---------<pre/><br/>-----<pre/>-----<pre/>---------<pre/><br/>------------<pre/>--------- -----------<pre/>-------<pre/>---------<pre/>---------<pre/><br/>-----<pre/>-----<pre/>---------<pre/><br/>------------<pre/>--------- -----------<pre/>-------<pre/>---------<pre/>---------<pre/><br/>-----<pre/>-----<pre/>---------<pre/><br/>------------<pre/>--------- -----------<pre/>-------<pre/>---------<pre/>---------<pre/><br/>-----<pre/>-----<pre/>---------<pre/><br/>--------------------------------------------------------------- ------------- <br/>--------------------------------------------------------------- ------------- </p><p><pre/>RETURN TO ITEM 8</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_11_f-2"/><heading><desig>SCHEDULE F-2 --</desig><title> LOBBYIST RELATIONSHIPS AND PAYMENTS.</title></heading><bodyText><p>Complete this Schedule for each lobbyist relationship with the following:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_11_f-2_i"/><heading><desig>(i)</desig></heading><bodyText><p> any person who is, or has been within the prior calendar year, registered as a lobbyist with the Secretary of the Commonwealth, or</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_11_f-2_ii"/><heading><desig>(ii)</desig></heading><bodyText><p> any business in which you have a greater than three percent ownership interest and that business employs, or engages as an independent contractor, any person who is, or has been within the prior calendar year, registered as a lobbyist with the Secretary of the Commonwealth.</p><p>--------------------------------------------------------------- ------------- <br/>--------------------------------------------------------------- ------------- <br/>List of each person<pre/>Describe each<pre/>Dates of<pre/>Payments to<pre/><br/>or business<pre/>relationship<pre/>relationship<pre/>Lobbyist<pre/><br/><pre/>$ <pre/>More than<pre/><br/><pre/>10,000<pre/><br/><pre/>or less<pre/>$ 10,000<pre/><br/>-----------------<pre/>---------------- -------------<pre/>-------<pre/>-----------<br/><pre/>--<pre/>-----<pre/>-------<pre/>-------<pre/><br/><pre/>---<pre/><br/>-----------------<pre/>---------------- -------------<pre/>-------<pre/>-----------<br/><pre/>--<pre/>-----<pre/>-------<pre/>-------<pre/><br/><pre/>---<pre/><br/>-----------------<pre/>---------------- -------------<pre/>-------<pre/>-----------<br/><pre/>--<pre/>-----<pre/>-------<pre/>-------<pre/><br/><pre/>---<pre/><br/>-----------------<pre/>---------------- -------------<pre/>-------<pre/>-----------<br/><pre/>--<pre/>-----<pre/>-------<pre/>-------<pre/><br/><pre/>---<pre/><br/>-----------------<pre/>---------------- -------------<pre/>-------<pre/>-----------<br/><pre/>--<pre/>-----<pre/>-------<pre/>-------<pre/><br/><pre/>---<pre/><br/>--------------------------------------------------------------- ------------- <br/>--------------------------------------------------------------- ------------- </p><p><pre/>THE DISCLOSURE OF A LOBBYIST RELATIONSHIP SHALL NOT (I) CONSTITUTE A WAIVER OF ANY ATTORNEY-CLIENT OR OTHER PRIVILEGE, (II) REQUIRE A WAIVER OF ANY ATTORNEY-CLIENT OR OTHER PRIVILEGE FOR A THIRD PARTY, OR (III) BE REQUIRED WHERE A MEMBER OR MEMBER-ELECT IS EMPLOYED OR ENGAGED BY A PERSON AND SUCH PERSON ALSO EMPLOYS OR ENGAGES A PERSON IN A LOBBYIST RELATIONSHIP SO LONG AS THE MEMBER OR MEMBER-ELECT HAS NO FINANCIAL INTEREST IN THE LOBBYIST RELATIONSHIP.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_11_g-1"/><heading><desig>SCHEDULE G-1 --</desig><title> PAYMENTS FOR REPRESENTATION BY YOU.</title></heading><bodyText><p>List the businesses you represented before any state governmental agency, excluding any court or judge, for which you received total compensation during the past six months in excess of $ 1,000, excluding compensation for other services to such businesses and representation consisting solely of the filing of mandatory papers and subsequent representation regarding the mandatory papers filed by you.</p><p><pre/>Identify each business, the nature of the representation and the amount received by dollar category from each such business. You may state the type, rather than name, of the business if you are required by law not to reveal the name of the business represented by you.</p><p> --------------------------------------------------------------- ------------ <br/> --------------------------------------------------------------- ------------ <br/><pre/>Amount Received<pre/><br/>Name<pre/>Type<pre/>Pur-<pre/>Name<pre/><br/>of<pre/>of<pre/>pose<pre/>of<pre/><br/>Busi- Busi- of<pre/>Agen-<pre/><br/>ness<pre/>ness<pre/>Repre- cy<pre/><br/><pre/>senta-<pre/><br/><pre/>tion<pre/>$ 1,001<pre/>$ 10,001<pre/>$ 50,001<pre/>$ 100,001<pre/>$ 250,001<br/><pre/>to<pre/>to<pre/>to<pre/>to<pre/>and<pre/><br/><pre/>$ 10,000<pre/>$ 50,000<pre/>$ 100,000<pre/>$ 250,000<pre/>over<pre/><br/>----- ----- ------ ------<pre/>--------<pre/>--------<pre/>--------<pre/>--------<pre/>-------- <br/>----- ----- ------ ------<pre/>--------<pre/>--------<pre/>--------<pre/>--------<pre/>-------- <br/>----- ----- ------ ------<pre/>--------<pre/>--------<pre/>--------<pre/>--------<pre/>-------- <br/>----- ----- ------ ------<pre/>--------<pre/>--------<pre/>--------<pre/>--------<pre/>-------- <br/> --------------------------------------------------------------- ------------ <br/> --------------------------------------------------------------- ------------ </p><p><pre/>If you have received $ 250,001 or more from a single business within the <br/>reporting period, indicate the amount received, rounded to the nearest $<br/>10,000.<pre/>Amount Received: <emphasis typeStyle="un"><pre/></emphasis> .</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_11_g-2"/><heading><desig>SCHEDULE G-2 --</desig><title> PAYMENTS FOR REPRESENTATION BY ASSOCIATES.</title></heading><bodyText><p>List the businesses that have been represented before any state governmental agency, excluding any court or judge, by persons who are your partners, associates or others with whom you have a close financial association and who received total compensation in excess of $ 1,000 for such representation during the past six months, excluding representation consisting solely of the filing of mandatory papers and subsequent representation regarding the mandatory papers filed by your partners, associates or others with whom you have a close financial association.</p><p><pre/>Identify such businesses by type and also name the state governmental agencies before which such person appeared on behalf of such businesses.</p><p>--------------------------------------------------------------- ------------- <br/>--------------------------------------------------------------- ------------- <br/>Type of Business<pre/>Name of State Governmental Agency<pre/><br/>-------------------<pre/>--------------------------------------<pre/><br/>--------------------<pre/>--------------------------------------<pre/><br/>--------------------<pre/>--------------------------------------<pre/><br/>--------------------<pre/>--------------------------------------<pre/><br/> --------------------------------------------------------------- ------------ <br/> --------------------------------------------------------------- ------------ </p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_11_g-3"/><heading><desig>SCHEDULE G-3 --</desig><title> PAYMENTS FOR OTHER SERVICES GENERALLY.</title></heading><bodyText><p>Indicate below types of businesses that operate in Virginia to which services were furnished by you or persons with whom you have a close financial association pursuant to an agreement between you and such businesses, or between persons with whom you have a close financial association and such businesses and for which total compensation in excess of $ 1,000 was received during the past six months. Services reported in this Schedule shall not include services involving the representation of businesses that are reported in Schedule G-1 or G-2 above.</p><p><pre/>Identify opposite each category of businesses listed below (i) the type of business, (ii) the type of service rendered and (iii) the value by dollar category of the compensation received for all businesses falling within each category.</p><p>--------------------------------------------------------------- ------------- <br/>--------------------------------------------------------------- ------------- <br/><pre/>Value of Compensation<pre/><br/><pre/>Check<pre/>Type<pre/><br/><pre/>if<pre/>of<pre/><br/><pre/>ser-<pre/>ser-<pre/><br/><pre/>vices<pre/>vice<pre/><br/><pre/>were<pre/>ren-<pre/><br/><pre/>ren-<pre/>dered<pre/><br/><pre/>dered<pre/>$ 1,001 $ 10,001 $ 50,001$ 100,001$ 250,001<br/><pre/>to<pre/>to<pre/>to<pre/>to<pre/>and<pre/><br/><pre/>$ 10,000$ 50,000$ 100,000$ 250,000<pre/>over<pre/><br/>Electric utilities<pre/><br/>Gas utilities<pre/><br/>Telephone utilities<pre/><br/>Water utilities<pre/><br/>Cable television<pre/><br/>companies<pre/><br/>Interstate<pre/><br/>transportation<pre/><br/>companies<pre/><br/>Intrastate<pre/><br/>transportation<pre/><br/>companies<pre/><br/>Oil or gas retail<pre/><br/>companies<pre/><br/>Banks<pre/><br/>Savings institutions<pre/><br/>Loan or finance<pre/><br/>companies<pre/><br/>Manufacturing<pre/><br/>companies<pre/>(state<pre/><br/>type of product,<pre/><br/>e.g., textile,<pre/><br/>furniture, etc.)<pre/><br/>Mining companies<pre/><br/>Life insurance<pre/><br/>companies<pre/><br/>Casualty insurance<pre/><br/>companies<pre/><br/>Other insurance<pre/><br/>companies<pre/><br/>Retail companies<pre/><br/>Beer, wine or liquor<pre/><br/>companies or<pre/><br/>distributors<pre/><br/>Trade associations<pre/><br/>Professional<pre/><br/>associations<pre/><br/>Associations of<pre/><br/>public employees or<pre/><br/>officials<pre/><br/>Counties, cities or<pre/><br/>towns<pre/><br/>Labor organizations<pre/><br/>Other</p><p><pre/>RETURN TO ITEM 9</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_11_h"/><heading><desig>SCHEDULE H --</desig><title> REAL ESTATE.</title></heading><bodyText><p>List real estate other than your principal residence in which you or a member of your immediate family holds an interest, including a partnership interest, option, easement, or land contract, valued at $ 5,000 or more. Each parcel shall be listed individually.</p><p>--------------------------------------------------------------- ------------- <br/>--------------------------------------------------------------- ------------- <br/>List the location<pre/>Describe the type of real<pre/>If the real estate is<pre/><br/>(state, and county<pre/>estate you own in each<pre/>owned or recorded in<pre/><br/>or city where you<pre/>location (business,<pre/>a name other than your <br/>own real estate<pre/>recreational, apartment,<pre/>own, list that name<pre/><br/><pre/>commercial, open land,<pre/><br/><pre/>etc.)<pre/><br/>----------------------<pre/>-------------------------<pre/>---------------------- <br/>----------------------<pre/>-------------------------<pre/>---------------------- <br/>----------------------<pre/>-------------------------<pre/>---------------------- <br/>----------------------<pre/>-------------------------<pre/>---------------------- <br/>----------------------<pre/>-------------------------<pre/>---------------------- <br/>--------------------------------------------------------------- ------------- <br/>--------------------------------------------------------------- ------------- </p><p><pre/>RETURN TO ITEM 10</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_11_i"/><heading><desig>SCHEDULE I --</desig><title> REAL ESTATE CONTRACTS WITH STATE GOVERNMENTAL AGENCIES.</title></heading><bodyText><p>List all contracts, whether pending or completed within the past six months, with a state governmental agency for the sale or exchange of real estate in which you or a member of your immediate family holds an interest, including a corporate, partnership or trust interest, option, easement, or land contract, valued at more than $ 10,000. List all contracts with a state governmental agency for the lease of real estate in which you or a member of your immediate family holds such an interest valued at more than $ 1,000. This requirement to disclose an interest in a lease does not apply to an interest derived through an ownership interest in a business unless the ownership interest exceeds three percent of the total equity of the business.</p><p>--------------------------------------------------------------- ------------- <br/>--------------------------------------------------------------- ------------- <br/>List your real<pre/>List each<pre/>State the annual<pre/><br/>estate interest and<pre/>governmental agency<pre/>income from the<pre/><br/>the person or entity,<pre/>which is a party to<pre/>contract, and the<pre/><br/>including the type of<pre/>the contract and<pre/>amount, if any, of<pre/><br/>entity, which is<pre/>indicate the county<pre/>income you or any<pre/><br/>party to the contract.<pre/>or city where the<pre/>immediate family<pre/><br/>Describe any<pre/>real estate is<pre/>member derives<pre/><br/>management<pre/><br/>role and the<pre/>located.<pre/>annually from<pre/><br/>percentage<pre/><br/>ownership interest<pre/>the contract.<pre/><br/>you or your immediate<pre/><br/>family member has in<pre/><br/>the real estate<pre/><br/>or entity.<pre/><br/>----------------------<pre/>-------------------------<pre/>---------------------- <br/>----------------------<pre/>-------------------------<pre/>---------------------- <br/>----------------------<pre/>-------------------------<pre/>---------------------- <br/>----------------------<pre/>-------------------------<pre/>---------------------- <br/>----------------------<pre/>-------------------------<pre/>---------------------- <br/>--------------------------------------------------------------- ------------- <br/>--------------------------------------------------------------- ------------- </p></bodyText></level></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b"/><heading><desig>B.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Any legislator who knowingly and intentionally makes a false statement of a material fact on the Statement of Economic Interests is guilty of a Class 5 felony and shall be subject to disciplinary action for such violations by the house in which the legislator sits.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c"/><heading><desig>C.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The Statement of Economic Interests of all members of each house shall be reviewed by the Council. If a legislator's Statement is found to be inadequate as filed, the legislator shall be notified in writing and directed to file an amended Statement correcting the indicated deficiencies, and a time shall be set within which such amendment shall be filed. If the Statement of Economic Interests, in either its original or amended form, is found to be adequate as filed, the legislator's filing shall be deemed in full compliance with this section as to the information disclosed thereon.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d"/><heading><desig>D.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Ten percent of the membership of a house, on the basis of newly discovered facts, may in writing request the house in which those members sit, in accordance with the rules of that house, to review the Statement of Economic Interests of another member of that house in order to determine the adequacy of his filing. In accordance with the rules of each house, each Statement of Economic Interests shall be promptly reviewed, the adequacy of the filing determined, and notice given in writing to the legislator whose Statement is in issue. Should it be determined that the Statement requires correction, augmentation or revision, the legislator involved shall be directed to make the changes required within such time as shall be set under the rules of each house.</p><p>If a legislator, after having been notified in writing in accordance with the rules of the house in which he sits that his Statement is inadequate as filed, fails to amend his Statement so as to come into compliance within the time limit set, he shall be subject to disciplinary action by the house in which he sits. No legislator shall vote on any question relating to his own Statement.</p></bodyText></level><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p>1987, Sp. Sess., c. 1, § 2.1-639.41; 1988, c. 849; <citation normalizedCite="1994 VA CH 724"><content><span normalizedCite="1994 Va. Ch. 724">1994, cc. 724<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1994#000724#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1994 VA CH 733"><content><span normalizedCite="1994 Va. Ch. 733">733<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1994#000733#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1994 VA CH 735"><content><span normalizedCite="1994 Va. Ch. 735">735<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1994#000735#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1994 VA CH 777"><content><span normalizedCite="1994 Va. Ch. 777">777<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1994#000777#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1994 VA CH 793"><content><span normalizedCite="1994 Va. Ch. 793">793<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1994#000793#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1995 VA CH 763"><content><span normalizedCite="1995 Va. Ch. 763">1995, c. 763<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1995#000763#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1996 VA CH 77"><content><span normalizedCite="1996 Va. Ch. 77">1996, c. 77<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1996#000077#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1997 VA CH 577"><content><span normalizedCite="1997 Va. Ch. 577">1997, cc. 577<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1997#000577#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1997 VA CH 844"><content><span normalizedCite="1997 Va. Ch. 844">844<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1997#000844#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1998 VA CH 732"><content><span normalizedCite="1998 Va. Ch. 732">1998, c. 732<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1998#000732#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2001 VA CH 844"><content><span normalizedCite="2001 Va. Ch. 844">2001, c. 844<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2001#000844#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2003 VA CH 610"><content><span normalizedCite="2003 Va. Ch. 610">2003, c. 610<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2003#000610#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2006 VA CH 779"><content><span normalizedCite="2006 Va. Ch. 779">2006, cc. 779<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2006#000779#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2006 VA CH 787"><content><span normalizedCite="2006 Va. Ch. 787">787<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2006#000787#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2006 VA CH 892"><content><span normalizedCite="2006 Va. Ch. 892">892<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2006#000892#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2007 VA CH 620"><content><span normalizedCite="2007 Va. Ch. 620">2007, cc. 620<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2007#000620#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2007 VA CH 627"><content><span normalizedCite="2007 Va. Ch. 627">627<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2007#000627#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2010 VA CH 418"><content><span normalizedCite="2010 Va. Ch. 418">2010, cc. 418<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2010#000418#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2010 VA CH 474"><content><span normalizedCite="2010 Va. Ch. 474">474<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2010#000474#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2010 VA CH 670"><content><span normalizedCite="2010 Va. Ch. 670">670<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2010#000670#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2014 VA CH 792"><content><span normalizedCite="2014 Va. Ch. 792">2014, cc. 792<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2014#000792#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2014 VA CH 804"><content><span normalizedCite="2014 Va. Ch. 804">804<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2014#000804#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2015 VA CH 763"><content><span normalizedCite="2015 Va. Ch. 763">2015, cc. 763<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2015#000763#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2015 VA CH 777"><content><span normalizedCite="2015 Va. Ch. 777">777<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2015#000777#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PWD0-004G-K36Y-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 30.</desig><title>GENERAL ASSEMBLY</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 13.</desig><title>GENERAL ASSEMBLY CONFLICTS OF INTERESTS ACT</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="article"><heading><desig>ARTICLE 5.</desig><title>DISCLOSURE STATEMENTS REQUIRED TO BE FILED</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Distribution, Processing &amp; Storage of Food &amp; Agricultural Products</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NENGNzZCMDU5RjcyNEM0NEFFOUU4ODFCQkZCOThBRkI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NkVDMzM4QkJENTg3NDQ0RDg3NTA5OEM3RkMyQTlENDI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjA4OEVGODBENzY4NDcxM0IyQzA1OTEwQzVDODRBOUE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NzQwNjJBMUVBRDAwNEVFNUIwNjE0M0JFQ0IwNjk5MDU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NTBBOERFMzlGNEE5NDI2OUEwMUFDNkNFOURENTQ5MDQ</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RkE2ODg4Mjk1MTE2NDgzOTk1NTVERDRBRUJFRUUxMjk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NjMzQjkyNzZDOUQ4NEQ2NEIyOEYxNkJCNzBGNTk1OEY</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Contracts Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QzY0RTZFMzE0RjkwNDdFQUI5M0U5N0ZFMjYyREMyQzU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Creditors &amp; Debtors</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6ODZDNjdDMUIxNjdGNERDRkFDNzAwRTI4NDhCNTBGNTk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OTdCODg3NEVGQTY5NENDQ0EzRkEwMzNGOTVBQTE0NEY</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Futures</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RUUzNDUzQTZERTFBNDI5RDhFOEM2QzA1RDIxMjQ2RkQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Qjg1NzgyRDNGQzg1NEM5Nzg3RjA3MEUwRTA1QUI0NkU</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Q0YyRjY1NkZBQjkzNDA0RUFCQzA0RjJEMjhGNTYwN0M7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDMzOTAwOUFFMTFCNEE3Njg4QUEzQTJFOUE1NzE5MkM</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6REM4OThDMTQwNjI4NDVBRTg2OUJBRjlFNUY1MTk4MTQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MkUyQjY4NDMwRDBFNDVEQ0E4N0Y3M0Y0QkU2MzI3Rjc</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RjUzRDFFQkQ2OEM0NEM5RDhGM0MwQkNBNkYwMjRENzM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6ODBDRDNDNDk3QjM0NDZGRjhDOUFGQkE2QUY4MUUwOTg</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Copyright Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MzM3NEE0Qjk0NzRCNDhFM0E0NjM2RTE4M0QzNTczMTU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Copyright Act of 1976</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Nzc0RjdGMjlFNUQ2NEM4RTgyOEY2MzlEQTYwMDc4Qjg7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NjIzNEZERTQ3N0MwNDg3Njg4MTE4NzZGMDYxQ0NENzI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Education Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDkzNUEzQzFBNEZBNEFBREIxNDM5MTc1MUU5QjI4MTY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Athletic Scholarships</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RDJBRTc3QTBFOUJBNDBENTg5MEY5MjBFMDU5NDEyOTY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Njk4RUMyMDg4ODMwNDIwNUI1NEQwMDE0OUU3REYyOTM</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Estate, Gift &amp; Trust Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OENGNTY0MEQ2RTU2NDA2NTk4QjcyNzI2NTBERUU3NUI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NTM0MTFFRkQ3M0E2NEQwREFFMzc3QjBDQjhEQjZEOTM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RkJCNEFGNEQyOEM1NEZBQ0ExREJFNUQyMDM5N0U2Rjg</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Q0VEQ0U4QTFCMzc1NDkyQjgzMjNBQUJFREFDOEJCOTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NUQ4NThEMTk0MTQ4NDM3N0FGOEM5RkU2QUQ4RjA1MkQ</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Evidence</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUVGQkU0QjJFMTIzNDNBM0FCNTVEQjAxQTM3RDcwOTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Waiver</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RDdBRDY4ODJBNzMwNDA4Q0E3Njc0MDVGMkE3OTMzODg7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OUJCNkIwOENDMTA3NEI0NkI2MDEyMkYxNzk1Mjk0MDg</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Governments</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjdEQjE4OUJDMzQxNDNEMEI0RTI1QUFCMzJENjEwRTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Distribution, Processing &amp; Storage</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NENGNzZCMDU5RjcyNEM0NEFFOUU4ODFCQkZCOThBRkI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NkVDMzM4QkJENTg3NDQ0RDg3NTA5OEM3RkMyQTlENDI</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Finance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjMzOTBBRTg2MUVDNDdDNUE1M0QxNDk1RERCNjNCN0I7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Njg1MkM3RkYyNzIxNEVFRkJFMTI2NUM4NUU1ODdEM0Q</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OTI0MkYyMDU1OEFCNDczQTgxNTc1NTczREYzMUQ3MzI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QURCRDNBRjBGRTE0NEFBRUEzNUU1MzFGQjg3MTM4MDI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Pensions &amp; Benefits Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QzNEOEE3NjhDNTJBNDhCOTgxRkQzNzc1Q0JCMkU4Q0I7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>State Pensions</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OTlBNTkwQTdCMDczNEQ3Q0I0OTREMEFERkU5QkIzQUE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NzUzMDgwRDk4QjFDNDBFQUExMUVGQzBCMkNGQzYyNzk</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Real Property Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QUUyRTcxRURBNEY2NEE2MDk3QzBCNzRDOEY0NTZDQzk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Holding Trusts</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjAyRkY5RjIzM0Q0NDFBMEI4NEVFRjEwREY5MDE3QjQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDA0QjAwN0E3NDgwNDhBRjgxMDIzRUFDQkNERDc0ODQ</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Securities Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RkFFMTQ3ODhCRDYyNDkyN0IwQkEyQzRCRDlFMEM5ODc7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Futures Contracts</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDc2N0M2MDhBREJFNDE3MEIxRkQ0Q0E2OTk2QUNGNDY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QUE5REYwNEVDOTM1NDI1MUI4MzI5RkQzQzcyRDYzRjM</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Tax Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OTNEM0E2OEE0RkQyNEY1MDhBQzdGMkQ4ODI4QTJDODE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Income &amp; Credits</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RkVDQkY3QkI5NTM2NDYxRDg2NkFGMUU0MEM3QzgzRDQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NEE1NzkyQkYxNDg5NEU3Mjk1NkRCNUJFMERDRDQxRkM</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification><classificationGroup classificationScheme="indexing-terms"><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem score="90"><className>Governments</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjdEQjE4OUJDMzQxNDNEMEI0RTI1QUFCMzJENjEwRTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></classificationGroup></metadata></legislativeDoc>