<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#142#        36#     55.33#         2#">Va. Code Ann. § 36-55.33:2</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_36-55.33_2"/><heading><desig>§ 36-55.33:2.</desig><title>Powers relative to acquisition, development and ownership by HDA of multi-family residential housing</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a"/><heading><desig>A.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> HDA shall have all the powers necessary or convenient to purchase, acquire, construct, rehabilitate, own, operate, improve, repair, maintain, encumber, mortgage, lease, sell and transfer or otherwise dispose of multi-family residential housing or any part or interest therein for occupancy by persons and families of low and moderate income. For the purposes of this section, HDA may form corporations, joint ventures, partnerships, trusts or other legal entities or any combination thereof, on its own behalf or in conjunction with individuals or other public or private entities, to serve as housing sponsors for multi-family residential housing developments; may acquire, own, encumber, pledge, sell, transfer or otherwise dispose of interests in such housing sponsors; may provide financing and other funding to such housing sponsors; and may exercise all necessary or convenient rights and powers and perform all requisite duties and obligations relating thereto. HDA shall not exercise the powers granted under this section with respect to any multi-family residential housing development, unless HDA makes the following findings:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> That there exists a shortage of decent, safe and sanitary housing at rentals or prices which persons and families of low income or moderate income can afford within the general housing market area to be served by the proposed housing development.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> That private enterprise and investment have been unable, without assistance, to provide the needed decent, safe and sanitary housing at rentals or prices which persons or families of low and moderate income can afford.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> That private sponsors would not be willing, without assistance, to undertake the proposed housing development upon substantially similar terms and conditions.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_4"/><heading><desig>4.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> That HDA has not received notification from both the local housing authority having jurisdiction over the area in which the housing development would be located and the sponsor of such development that it is the preference of both parties that the local housing authority undertake the proposed housing development.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_5"/><heading><desig>5.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> That the proposed housing development will provide well-planned, well-designed housing for persons or families of low and moderate income.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_6"/><heading><desig>6.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> That the housing development will be of public use and will provide a public benefit.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_7"/><heading><desig>7.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> That the housing development will be undertaken within the authority conferred by this chapter upon HDA.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b"/><heading><desig>B.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> HDA shall also find, in connection with the new construction or substantial rehabilitation by HDA of any proposed multi-family residential housing development, that the governing body of the locality in which such housing development is to be located has not, within sixty days after written notification of such proposed construction or substantial rehabilitation has been sent by HDA to such governing body and to any local housing authority having jurisdiction in such locality, certified to HDA in writing its disapproval of the proposed multi-family residential housing development. The foregoing notwithstanding, no such finding need be made if HDA has received from the governing body its certified resolution approving the proposed housing development.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c"/><heading><desig>C.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> At least sixty days prior to purchasing, acquiring, constructing or rehabilitating any multi-family residential housing development pursuant to this section, HDA shall publish a notice in a newspaper of general circulation in the locality in which such development is to be located. Such notice (i) shall state that HDA intends to purchase, acquire, construct or rehabilitate a multi-family residential housing development or developments in such locality and shall solicit proposals from interested parties for such purchase, acquisition, construction or rehabilitation or (ii) shall identify the multi-family residential housing development or developments to be purchased, acquired, constructed or rehabilitated and shall request comments from the general public with respect to such proposed purchase, acquisition, construction or rehabilitation.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d"/><heading><desig>D.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> In the event HDA or any legal entity formed by HDA is to construct or rehabilitate a multi-family residential housing development pursuant to this section, HDA or such legal entity shall contract with a private firm for the performance of such construction and rehabilitation, unless HDA determines that no responsible private firm would be willing and able to contract for such construction or rehabilitation at a price necessary for the financial feasibility of such development. HDA or any legal entity formed by HDA shall contract with a private firm or public body for the performance of management services for any multi-family residential housing development owned by HDA or such legal entity pursuant to this section, unless HDA determines that no responsible private firm and no public body would be willing and able to contract for the performance of such management services at a price necessary for the financial feasibility of such development. For the purpose of this subsection, the term "private firm" shall include an individual, joint venture, partnership, stock corporation, trust or other similar business entity legally authorized to perform the construction, rehabilitation or management, as may be applicable, of the proposed multi-family residential housing development.</p></bodyText></level><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p>1987, c. 254; <citation normalizedCite="1991 VA CH 206"><content><span normalizedCite="1991 Va. Ch. 206">1991, c. 206<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1991#000206#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1996 VA CH 298"><content><span normalizedCite="1996 Va. Ch. 298">1996, c. 298<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1996#000298#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PT30-004G-K3VP-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 36.</desig><title>HOUSING</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 1.2.</desig><title>VIRGINIA HOUSING DEVELOPMENT AUTHORITY ACT</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Contracts Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QzY0RTZFMzE0RjkwNDdFQUI5M0U5N0ZFMjYyREMyQzU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Joint Contracts</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Q0ZDM0VENzI0QTZGNDIxOTlGNzU4NDhERTA1MTEzMEQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Qjg1NzgyRDNGQzg1NEM5Nzg3RjA3MEUwRTA1QUI0NkU</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Mergers &amp; Acquisitions Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjRDRTUzQzBCMEIyNDU5QkE4QjFDMEE2Qjg2MUZDOTk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RUY4N0JCOTk2OTJENDI1RjhGMjZDRjI3RDE1MjZGMkY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NkE4OEIzNzhFMEUxNEMwRkFENkZBNzlCRDcyNUEyRkI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Real Property Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QUUyRTcxRURBNEY2NEE2MDk3QzBCNzRDOEY0NTZDQzk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDc3NDJDNEMzOUVCNDBGRTkyQjA1RENENzcwRUFFRDg7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjdCOTA2RjU5MzlBNEMyQkJCMDg3RTZCMkRFNTIzRjE</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RkY0OTA5NjA2MDc1NDk5OUFGMERGOUFFOTE1MDg0Mzc7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NzNFRkY2MkZBNjVCNDE1NEE4NEE5NUU4NTlCNTFCQjM</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Merger of Legal Entities</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUUwMjcxQ0I5N0EwNDlGOTkzRDQyNTZDRDJGQTY0ODM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Q0I1MjUzRkFDMDE4NDdFMTkwRTAyMzQzQjlGNjZCNDY</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></metadata></legislativeDoc>