<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#349#000003#     2#         3104#">Va. Code Ann. § 3.2-3104</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_3.2-3104"/><heading><desig>§ 3.2-3104.</desig><title>Tobacco Indemnification and Community Revitalization Endowment</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a"/><heading><desig>A.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> There is hereby established in the state treasury a special fund to be designated the "Tobacco Indemnification and Community Revitalization Endowment." The Endowment shall receive any proceeds from any sale of all or any portion of the Commission Allocation, and any gifts, grants and contributions that are specifically designated for inclusion in such Endowment. No part of the Endowment, neither corpus nor income, or interest thereon, shall revert to the general fund of the state treasury. The Endowment shall be under the management and control of the Treasury Board, and the Treasury Board shall have such powers and authority as may be necessary to exercise such management and control consistent with the provisions of this section. The income of the Endowment shall be paid out, not less than annually, to the Fund. In addition, up to six percent of the corpus of the Endowment shall be paid to the Fund annually upon request of the Commission, by majority vote, to the Treasury Board. Upon two-thirds vote of the Commission, up to 10 percent of the corpus of the Endowment shall be so paid. Upon three-fourths vote of the Commission, up to 15 percent of the corpus of the Endowment shall be so paid. No use of proceeds shall be made that would cause bonds issued on a tax-exempt basis to be deemed taxable. For purposes of this section, "income" of the Endowment means at the time of determination the lesser of the available cash in, or the realized investment income for the applicable period of, the Endowment, and "corpus" of the Endowment means at the time of determination the sum of the proceeds from the sale of all or any portion of the Commission Allocation, any gifts, grants, and contributions that have been credited to such Endowment, and any income not appropriated and withdrawn from the Endowment prior to June 30 of each year, less withdrawals from the corpus. Determinations by the Treasury Board, or the State Treasurer on behalf of the Treasury Board, as to the amount of income or the amount of the corpus shall be conclusive.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b"/><heading><desig>B.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The Treasury Board shall serve as trustee of the Endowment and the corpus and income of the Endowment shall be withdrawn and credited to the Fund by order of the Treasury Board as provided in subsection A. The State Treasurer shall be custodian of the funds credited to the Endowment. The Treasury Board shall have full power to invest and reinvest funds credited to the Endowment in accordance with the provisions of the Uniform Prudent Management of Institutional Funds Act (<citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 64.2-1100"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 64.2-1100">§ 64.2-1100<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000064#     2#         1100#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> et seq.) and, in addition, as otherwise provided by law. The Treasury Board may borrow money in such amounts as may be necessary whenever in its judgment it would be more advantageous to borrow money than to sell securities held for the Fund. Any debt so incurred may be evidenced by notes duly authorized by resolution of the Treasury Board, such notes to be retired no later than the end of the biennium in which such debt is incurred. The Treasury Board may commingle, for purposes of investment, the corpus of the Endowment provided that it shall appropriately account for the investments credited to the Endowment. The Treasury Board may hire independent investment advisors and managers as it deems appropriate to assist with investing the Endowment. The expenses of making and disposing of investments, such as brokerage commissions, legal expenses related to a particular transaction, investment advisory and management fees and expenses, transfer taxes, and other customary transactional expenses shall be payable out of the income of the Endowment.</p><p>Not less than annually and more frequently if so desired by the Commission or requested by the Treasury Board, the Commission shall provide to the Treasury Board schedules of anticipated disbursements from the Fund for the current and succeeding fiscal year, and the Treasury Board shall, to the extent practicable, take into account such schedules and changes thereto in scheduling maturities and redemptions of its investments of the Endowment.</p></bodyText></level><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p><citation normalizedCite="2002 VA CH 482"><content><span normalizedCite="2002 Va. Ch. 482">2002, cc. 482<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2002#000482#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2002 VA CH 488"><content><span normalizedCite="2002 Va. Ch. 488">488<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2002#000488#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, § 3.1-1109.1; <citation normalizedCite="2008 VA CH 184"><content><span normalizedCite="2008 Va. Ch. 184">2008, cc. 184<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2008#000184#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2008 VA CH 860"><content><span normalizedCite="2008 Va. Ch. 860">860<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2008#000860#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2015 VA CH 399"><content><span normalizedCite="2015 Va. Ch. 399">2015, cc. 399<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2015#000399#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2015 VA CH 433"><content><span normalizedCite="2015 Va. Ch. 433">433<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2015#000433#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PVK0-004G-K1PW-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 3.2.</desig><title>AGRICULTURE, ANIMAL CARE, AND FOOD</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="subtitle"><heading><desig>SUBTITLE II.</desig><title>BOARDS, COUNCILS, FOUNDATIONS, AND COMMISSIONS</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="part"><heading><desig>PART D.</desig><title>TOBACCO REGION REVITALIZATION COMMISSION AND VIRGINIA TOBACCO REGION REVOLVING FUND</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 31.</desig><title>TOBACCO REGION REVITALIZATION COMMISSION</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Governments</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjdEQjE4OUJDMzQxNDNEMEI0RTI1QUFCMzJENjEwRTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Finance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RkM1MUYxRDBGNjIwNDhDRjkxOTdFODhEMjJCQjcxOUI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QURCRDNBRjBGRTE0NEFBRUEzNUU1MzFGQjg3MTM4MDI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Securities Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RkFFMTQ3ODhCRDYyNDkyN0IwQkEyQzRCRDlFMEM5ODc7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Compensation</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6ODlDOEU5OEE1Rjk2NDJCRThCNkREMUFBN0RFOTVENUE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6ODQ2M0Q5NUExRUZENEY2NDkzMzlDMDVFNjFCNTY3MTQ</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification><classificationGroup classificationScheme="indexing-terms"><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem score="90"><className>Governments</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjdEQjE4OUJDMzQxNDNEMEI0RTI1QUFCMzJENjEwRTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></classificationGroup></metadata></legislativeDoc>