<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#958#0000000032#0000000001#     102.3#0000000002#">Va. Code Ann. § 32.1-102.3:2</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_32.1-102.3_2"/><heading><desig>§ 32.1-102.3:2.</desig><title>Certificates of public need; applications to be filed in response to Requests for Applications (RFAs)</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a"/><heading><desig>A.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Except for applications for continuing care retirement community nursing home bed projects filed by continuing care providers registered with the State Corporation Commission pursuant to Chapter 49 (<citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 38.2-4900"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 38.2-4900">§ 38.2-4900<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000038#     2#         4900#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> et seq.) of Title 38.2 which comply with the requirements established in this section, the Commissioner shall approve, authorize or accept applications for the issuance of any certificate of public need pursuant to this article only in response to Requests for Applications (RFAs) for any project which would result in an increase in the number of beds in a planning district in which nursing facility or extended care services are provided, except as provided in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 32.1-102.3:7"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 32.1-102.3:7">§ 32.1-102.3:7.<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#958#0000000032#0000000001#     102.3#0000000007#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation></p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b"/><heading><desig>B.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The Board shall adopt regulations establishing standards for the approval and issuance of Requests for Applications by the Commissioner. The standards shall include, but shall not be limited to, a requirement that determinations of need take into account any limitations on access to existing nursing home beds in the planning districts. The RFAs, which shall be published at least annually, shall be jointly developed by the Department and the Department of Medical Assistance Services. RFAs shall be based on analyses of the need, or lack thereof, for increases in the nursing home bed supply in each of the Commonwealth's planning districts in accordance with standards adopted by the Board by regulation. The Commissioner shall only accept for review applications in response to such RFAs which conform with the geographic and bed need determinations of the specific RFA.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c"/><heading><desig>C.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Sixty days prior to the Commissioner's approval and issuance of any RFA, the Board shall publish the proposed RFA in the Virginia Register for public comment together with an explanation of (i) the regulatory basis for the planning district bed needs set forth in the RFA and (ii) the rationale for the RFA's planning district designations. Any person objecting to the contents of the proposed RFA may notify, within 14 days of the publication, the Board and the Commissioner of his objection and the objection's regulatory basis. The Commissioner shall prepare, and deliver by registered mail, a written response to each such objection within two weeks of the date of receiving the objection. The objector may file a rebuttal to the Commissioner's response in writing within five days of receiving the Commissioner's response. If objections are received, the Board may, after considering the provisions of the RFA, any objections, the Commissioner's responses, and if filed, any written rebuttals of the Commissioner's responses, hold a public hearing to receive comments on the specific RFA. Prior to making a decision on the RFA, the Commissioner shall consider any recommendations made by the Board.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d"/><heading><desig>D.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Except for a continuing care retirement community applying for a certificate of public need pursuant to provisions of subsections A, B, and C, applications for continuing care retirement community nursing home bed projects shall be accepted by the Commissioner only if the following criteria are met: (i) the facility is registered with the State Corporation Commission as a continuing care provider pursuant to Chapter 49 (<citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 38.2-4900"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 38.2-4900">§ 38.2-4900<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000038#     2#         4900#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> et seq.) of Title 38.2, (ii) the number of new nursing home beds requested in the initial application does not exceed the lesser of 20 percent of the continuing care retirement community's total number of beds that are not nursing home beds or 60 beds, (iii) the number of new nursing home beds requested in any subsequent application does not cause the continuing care retirement community's total number of nursing home beds to exceed 20 percent of its total number of beds that are not nursing home beds, and (iv) the continuing care retirement community has established a qualified resident assistance policy.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_e"/><heading><desig>E.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The Commissioner may approve an initial certificate of public need for nursing home beds in a continuing care retirement community not to exceed the lesser of 60 beds or 20 percent of the total number of beds that are not nursing home beds which authorizes an initial one-time, three-year open admission period during which the continuing care retirement community may accept direct admissions into its nursing home beds. The Commissioner may approve a certificate of public need for nursing home beds in a continuing care retirement community in addition to those nursing home beds requested for the initial one-time, three-year open admission period if (i) the number of new nursing home beds requested in any subsequent application does not cause the continuing care retirement community's total number of nursing home beds to exceed 20 percent of its total number of beds that are not nursing beds, (ii) the number of licensed nursing home beds within the continuing care retirement community does not and will not exceed 20 percent of the number of occupied beds that are not nursing beds, and (iii) no open-admission period is allowed for these nursing home beds. Upon the expiration of any initial one-time, three-year open admission period, a continuing care retirement community which has obtained a certificate of public need for a nursing facility project pursuant to subsection D may admit into its nursing home beds (a) a standard contract holder who has been a bona fide resident of the non-nursing home portion of the continuing care retirement community for at least 30 days, (b) a person who is a standard contract holder who has lived in the non-nursing home portion of the continuing care retirement community for less than 30 days but who requires nursing home care due to change in health status since admission to the continuing care retirement community, (c) a person who is a family member of a standard contract holder residing in a non-nursing home portion of the continuing care retirement community, (d) a person who is an employee or a member of the board of trustees or board of directors of the continuing care retirement community, (e) a person who is a family member of an employee or a member of the board of trustees or board of directors of the continuing care retirement community, or (f) a person who is an accredited practitioner of the religious organization or denomination with which the continuing care retirement community is affiliated.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_f"/><heading><desig>F.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Any continuing care retirement community applicant for a certificate of public need to increase the number of nursing home beds shall authorize the State Corporation Commission to disclose such information to the Commissioner as may be in the State Corporation Commission's possession concerning such continuing care retirement community in order to allow the Commissioner to enforce the provisions of this section. The State Corporation Commission shall provide the Commissioner with the requested information when so authorized.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_g"/><heading><desig>G.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> For the purposes of this section:</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Family member"</emphasis> means spouse, mother, father, son, daughter, brother, sister, aunt, uncle, or cousin by blood, marriage, or adoption.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"One-time, three-year open admission period"</emphasis> means the three years after the initial licensure of nursing home beds during which the continuing care retirement community may take admissions directly into its nursing home beds without the signing of a standard contract. The facility or a related facility on the same campus shall not be granted any open admissions period for any subsequent application or authorization for nursing home beds.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Qualified resident assistance policy"</emphasis> means a procedure, consistently followed by a facility, pursuant to which the facility endeavors to avoid requiring a resident to leave the facility because of inability to pay regular charges and which complies with the requirements of the Internal Revenue Service for maintenance of status as a tax exempt charitable organization under <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="26 USC 501"><content><span normalizedCite="26 U.S.C. 501">§ 501(c)(3) of the Internal Revenue Code<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#29854#1127#00000000501#1#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>. This policy shall be (i) generally made known to residents through the resident contract and (ii) supported by reasonable and consistent efforts to promote the availability of funds, either through a special fund, separate foundation or access to other available funds, to assist residents who are unable to pay regular charges in whole or in part.</p><p>This policy may (a) take into account the sound financial management of the facility, including existing reserves, and the reasonable requirements of lenders and (b) include requirements that residents seeking such assistance provide all requested financial information and abide by reasonable conditions, including seeking to qualify for other assistance and restrictions on the transfer of assets to third parties.</p><p>A qualified resident assistance policy shall not constitute the business of insurance as defined in Chapter 1 (<citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 38.2-100"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 38.2-100">§ 38.2-100<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000038#     2#          100#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> et seq.) of Title 38.2.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Standard contract"</emphasis> means a contract requiring the same entrance fee, terms, and conditions as contracts executed with residents of the non-nursing home portion of the facility, if the entrance fee is no less than the amount defined in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 38.2-4900"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 38.2-4900">§ 38.2-4900<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000038#     2#         4900#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_h"/><heading><desig>H.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> This section shall not be construed to prohibit or prevent a continuing care retirement community from discharging a resident (i) for breach of nonfinancial contract provisions, (ii) if medically appropriate care can no longer be provided to the resident, or (iii) if the resident is a danger to himself or others while in the facility.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_i"/><heading><desig>I.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The provisions of subsections D, E, and H shall not affect any certificate of public need issued prior to July 1, 1998; however, any certificate of public need application for additional nursing home beds shall be subject to the provisions of this act.</p></bodyText></level><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p><citation normalizedCite="1989 VA CH 517"><content><span normalizedCite="1989 Va. Ch. 517">1989, c. 517<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1989#000517#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1990 VA CH 191"><content><span normalizedCite="1990 Va. Ch. 191">1990, cc. 191<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1990#000191#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1990 VA CH 478"><content><span normalizedCite="1990 Va. Ch. 478">478<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1990#000478#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1990 VA CH 753"><content><span normalizedCite="1990 Va. Ch. 753">753<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1990#000753#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1990 VA CH 845"><content><span normalizedCite="1990 Va. Ch. 845">845<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1990#000845#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1991 VA CH 561"><content><span normalizedCite="1991 Va. Ch. 561">1991, c. 561<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1991#000561#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1992 VA CH 612"><content><span normalizedCite="1992 Va. Ch. 612">1992, cc. 612<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1992#000612#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1992 VA CH 682"><content><span normalizedCite="1992 Va. Ch. 682">682<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1992#000682#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1993 VA CH 347"><content><span normalizedCite="1993 Va. Ch. 347">1993, cc. 347<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1993#000347#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1993 VA CH 474"><content><span normalizedCite="1993 Va. Ch. 474">474<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1993#000474#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1993 VA CH 540"><content><span normalizedCite="1993 Va. Ch. 540">540<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1993#000540#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1993 VA CH 564"><content><span normalizedCite="1993 Va. Ch. 564">564<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1993#000564#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1993 VA CH 704"><content><span normalizedCite="1993 Va. Ch. 704">704<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1993#000704#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1993 VA CH 762"><content><span normalizedCite="1993 Va. Ch. 762">762<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1993#000762#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1993 VA CH 957"><content><span normalizedCite="1993 Va. Ch. 957">957<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1993#000957#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1993 VA CH 993"><content><span normalizedCite="1993 Va. Ch. 993">993<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1993#000993#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1994 VA CH 57"><content><span normalizedCite="1994 Va. Ch. 57">1994, cc. 57<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1994#000057#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1994 VA CH 680"><content><span normalizedCite="1994 Va. Ch. 680">680<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1994#000680#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1994 VA CH 711"><content><span normalizedCite="1994 Va. Ch. 711">711<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1994#000711#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1994 VA CH 726"><content><span normalizedCite="1994 Va. Ch. 726">726<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1994#000726#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1994 VA CH 797"><content><span normalizedCite="1994 Va. Ch. 797">797<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1994#000797#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1995 VA CH 505"><content><span normalizedCite="1995 Va. Ch. 505">1995, cc. 505<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1995#000505#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1995 VA CH 632"><content><span normalizedCite="1995 Va. Ch. 632">632<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1995#000632#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1995 VA CH 641"><content><span normalizedCite="1995 Va. Ch. 641">641<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1995#000641#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1995 VA CH 695"><content><span normalizedCite="1995 Va. Ch. 695">695<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1995#000695#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1995 VA CH 753"><content><span normalizedCite="1995 Va. Ch. 753">753<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1995#000753#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1996 VA CH 531"><content><span normalizedCite="1996 Va. Ch. 531">1996, cc. 531<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1996#000531#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1996 VA CH 849"><content><span normalizedCite="1996 Va. Ch. 849">849<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1996#000849#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1996 VA CH 901"><content><span normalizedCite="1996 Va. Ch. 901">901<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1996#000901#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1998 VA CH 794"><content><span normalizedCite="1998 Va. Ch. 794">1998, c. 794<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1998#000794#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2009 VA CH 175"><content><span normalizedCite="2009 Va. Ch. 175">2009, c. 175<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2009#000175#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2012 VA CH 492"><content><span normalizedCite="2012 Va. Ch. 492">2012, c. 492<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2012#000492#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2013 VA CH 433"><content><span normalizedCite="2013 Va. Ch. 433">2013, cc. 433<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2013#000433#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2013 VA CH 515"><content><span normalizedCite="2013 Va. Ch. 515">515<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2013#000515#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PTP0-004G-K1J4-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 32.1.</desig><title>HEALTH</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 4.</desig><title>HEALTH CARE PLANNING</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="article"><heading><desig>ARTICLE 1.1.</desig><title>MEDICAL CARE FACILITIES CERTIFICATE OF PUBLIC NEED</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Regulation of Nursing Facilities for Disabled &amp; Elderly Persons</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QkI5RTc4N0U1MjU1NDQwMEI1MzhDOThGRTIyNDU1NDU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MTlCM0Q3MTlFNUQ0NDA5OTgwQTEwQjE1M0ZGMTlFQjc</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Healthcare Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NkUxMkVDQjJDOEY5NDVDQ0E5NTFEMTlDMjIwNzVERjc7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NTVDMzIyNkJCMTRBNDI0NUJBOTlBOTYyMjQ0MDkyODU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QTJGRDdFQzgwODczNDI0NDgwMzEyM0JBOEQ2MUVDNjg</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Nursing Facilities</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OTk0NDgxMUUxM0MzNDI5QzhDNEVGNzkwODVFN0MxRDg7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QUVDOEU4Qjg3REQzNEYxNDhCMUNGNzQ5NzNBRTVGNDk</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Public Health &amp; Welfare Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDYwRTY1MDg3MTk5NDUyNkFFRDI1RjJBRERGQ0UxNzI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MTJEMUIzNEFBMEE0NDUwMTgyOTk5Q0Q5MUQ3NTNDNTM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NjVGRUIzQkI1QTg1NDUxNkJFM0UwN0IxRTVENDlBNTM</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Nursing Facilities</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QkI5RTc4N0U1MjU1NDQwMEI1MzhDOThGRTIyNDU1NDU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NjVGRUIzQkI1QTg1NDUxNkJFM0UwN0IxRTVENDlBNTM</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Real Property Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QUUyRTcxRURBNEY2NEE2MDk3QzBCNzRDOEY0NTZDQzk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Mortgagee's Interests</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MzQwOUI5Qjk2Qzg5NEJDNUFBODI4M0NFNjE0MzYwNzI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDhDNTc4RkY3N0RDNDhDRkI1ODk3RjI2RkEyRTMwNEI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification><classificationGroup classificationScheme="indexing-terms"><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem score="90"><className>Healthcare</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NkUxMkVDQjJDOEY5NDVDQ0E5NTFEMTlDMjIwNzVERjc7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></classificationGroup></metadata></legislativeDoc>