<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#349#000032#     1#        102.1#">Va. Code Ann. § 32.1-102.1</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_32.1-102.1"/><heading><desig>§ 32.1-102.1.</desig><title>Definitions</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><bodyText><p>As used in this article, unless the context indicates otherwise:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><bodyText><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Certificate"</emphasis> means a certificate of public need for a project required by this article.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Clinical health service"</emphasis> means a single diagnostic, therapeutic, rehabilitative, preventive or palliative procedure or a series of such procedures that may be separately identified for billing and accounting purposes.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Health planning region"</emphasis> means a contiguous geographical area of the Commonwealth with a population base of at least 500,000 persons which is characterized by the availability of multiple levels of medical care services, reasonable travel time for tertiary care, and congruence with planning districts.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><bodyText><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Medical care facility,"</emphasis> as used in this title, means any institution, place, building or agency, whether or not licensed or required to be licensed by the Board or the Department of Behavioral Health and Developmental Services, whether operated for profit or nonprofit and whether privately owned or privately operated or owned or operated by a local governmental unit, (i) by or in which health services are furnished, conducted, operated or offered for the prevention, diagnosis or treatment of human disease, pain, injury, deformity or physical condition, whether medical or surgical, of two or more nonrelated persons who are injured or physically sick or have mental illness, or for the care of two or more nonrelated persons requiring or receiving medical, surgical or nursing attention or services as acute, chronic, convalescent, aged, physically disabled or crippled or (ii) which is the recipient of reimbursements from third-party health insurance programs or prepaid medical service plans. For purposes of this article, only the following medical care facilities shall be subject to review:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> General hospitals.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Sanitariums.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Nursing homes.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_4"/><heading><desig>4.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Intermediate care facilities, except those intermediate care facilities established for individuals with intellectual disability (ICF/MR) that have no more than 12 beds and are in an area identified as in need of residential services for individuals with intellectual disability in any plan of the Department of Behavioral Health and Developmental Services.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_5"/><heading><desig>5.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Extended care facilities.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_6"/><heading><desig>6.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Mental hospitals.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_7"/><heading><desig>7.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Facilities for individuals with intellectual disability.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_8"/><heading><desig>8.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Psychiatric hospitals and intermediate care facilities established primarily for the medical, psychiatric or psychological treatment and rehabilitation of individuals with substance abuse.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_9"/><heading><desig>9.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Specialized centers or clinics or that portion of a physician's office developed for the provision of outpatient or ambulatory surgery, cardiac catheterization, computed tomographic (CT) scanning, stereotactic radiosurgery, lithotripsy, magnetic resonance imaging (MRI), magnetic source imaging (MSI), positron emission tomographic (PET) scanning, radiation therapy, stereotactic radiotherapy, proton beam therapy, nuclear medicine imaging, except for the purpose of nuclear cardiac imaging, or such other specialty services as may be designated by the Board by regulation.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_10"/><heading><desig>10.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Rehabilitation hospitals.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_11"/><heading><desig>11.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Any facility licensed as a hospital.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><bodyText><p><pre/>The term "medical care facility" does not include any facility of (i) the Department of Behavioral Health and Developmental Services; (ii) any nonhospital substance abuse residential treatment program operated by or contracted primarily for the use of a community services board under the Department of Behavioral Health and Developmental Services' Comprehensive State Plan; (iii) an intermediate care facility for individuals with intellectual disability (ICF/MR) that has no more than 12 beds and is in an area identified as in need of residential services for individuals with intellectual disability in any plan of the Department of Behavioral Health and Developmental Services; (iv) a physician's office, except that portion of a physician's office described in subdivision 9 of the definition of "medical care facility"; (v) the Wilson Workforce and Rehabilitation Center of the Department for Aging and Rehabilitative Services; (vi) the Department of Corrections; or (vii) the Department of Veterans Services. "Medical care facility" shall also not include that portion of a physician's office dedicated to providing nuclear cardiac imaging.</p><p><pre/><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Project"</emphasis> means:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_1_seq_2"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Establishment of a medical care facility;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_2_seq_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> An increase in the total number of beds or operating rooms in an existing medical care facility;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_3_seq_2"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Relocation of beds from one existing facility to another, provided that "project" does not include the relocation of up to 10 beds or 10 percent of the beds, whichever is less, (i) from one existing facility to another existing facility at the same site in any two-year period, or (ii) in any three-year period, from one existing nursing home facility to any other existing nursing home facility owned or controlled by the same person that is located either within the same planning district, or within another planning district out of which, during or prior to that three-year period, at least 10 times that number of beds have been authorized by statute to be relocated from one or more facilities located in that other planning district and at least half of those beds have not been replaced, provided further that, however, a hospital shall not be required to obtain a certificate for the use of 10 percent of its beds as nursing home beds as provided in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 32.1-132"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 32.1-132">§ 32.1-132<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000032#     1#          132#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_4_seq_2"/><heading><desig>4.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Introduction into an existing medical care facility of any new nursing home service, such as intermediate care facility services, extended care facility services, or skilled nursing facility services, regardless of the type of medical care facility in which those services are provided;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_5_seq_2"/><heading><desig>5.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Introduction into an existing medical care facility of any new cardiac catheterization, computed tomographic (CT) scanning, stereotactic radiosurgery, lithotripsy, magnetic resonance imaging (MRI), magnetic source imaging (MSI), medical rehabilitation, neonatal special care, obstetrical, open heart surgery, positron emission tomographic (PET) scanning, psychiatric, organ or tissue transplant service, radiation therapy, stereotactic radiotherapy, proton beam therapy, nuclear medicine imaging, except for the purpose of nuclear cardiac imaging, substance abuse treatment, or such other specialty clinical services as may be designated by the Board by regulation, which the facility has never provided or has not provided in the previous 12 months;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_6_seq_2"/><heading><desig>6.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Conversion of beds in an existing medical care facility to medical rehabilitation beds or psychiatric beds;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_7_seq_2"/><heading><desig>7.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The addition by an existing medical care facility of any medical equipment for the provision of cardiac catheterization, computed tomographic (CT) scanning, stereotactic radiosurgery, lithotripsy, magnetic resonance imaging (MRI), magnetic source imaging (MSI), open heart surgery, positron emission tomographic (PET) scanning, radiation therapy, stereotactic radiotherapy, proton beam therapy, or other specialized service designated by the Board by regulation. Replacement of existing equipment shall not require a certificate of public need;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_8_seq_2"/><heading><desig>8.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Any capital expenditure of $ 15 million or more, not defined as reviewable in subdivisions 1 through 7 of this definition, by or on behalf of a medical care facility other than a general hospital. Capital expenditures of $ 5 million or more by a general hospital and capital expenditures between $ 5 and $ 15 million by a medical care facility other than a general hospital shall be registered with the Commissioner pursuant to regulations developed by the Board. The amounts specified in this subdivision shall be revised effective July 1, 2008, and annually thereafter to reflect inflation using appropriate measures incorporating construction costs and medical inflation. Nothing in this subdivision shall be construed to modify or eliminate the reviewability of any project described in subdivisions 1 through 7 of this definition when undertaken by or on behalf of a general hospital; or</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_9_seq_2"/><heading><desig>9.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Conversion in an existing medical care facility of psychiatric inpatient beds approved pursuant to a Request for Applications (RFA) to nonpsychiatric inpatient beds.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><bodyText><p><pre/><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Regional health planning agency"</emphasis> means the regional agency, including the regional health planning board, its staff and any component thereof, designated by the Virginia Health Planning Board to perform the health planning activities set forth in this chapter within a health planning region.</p><p><pre/><emphasis typeStyle="it">"State Medical Facilities Plan"</emphasis> means the planning document adopted by the Board of Health which shall include, but not be limited to, (i) methodologies for projecting need for medical care facility beds and services; (ii) statistical information on the availability of medical care facilities and services; and (iii) procedures, criteria and standards for review of applications for projects for medical care facilities and services.</p></bodyText></level><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p>1982, c. 388; 1983, c. 533; 1984, c. 740; 1985, c. 513; <citation normalizedCite="1989 VA CH 517"><content><span normalizedCite="1989 Va. Ch. 517">1989, c. 517<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1989#000517#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1991 VA CH 561"><content><span normalizedCite="1991 Va. Ch. 561">1991, c. 561<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1991#000561#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1992 VA CH 612"><content><span normalizedCite="1992 Va. Ch. 612">1992, c. 612<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1992#000612#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1993 VA CH 704"><content><span normalizedCite="1993 Va. Ch. 704">1993, c. 704<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1993#000704#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1995 VA CH 524"><content><span normalizedCite="1995 Va. Ch. 524">1995, c. 524<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1995#000524#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1996 VA CH 1050"><content><span normalizedCite="1996 Va. Ch. 1050">1996, c. 1050<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1996#001050#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1997 VA CH 600"><content><span normalizedCite="1997 Va. Ch. 600">1997, c. 600<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1997#000600#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1998 VA CH 289"><content><span normalizedCite="1998 Va. Ch. 289">1998, c. 289<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1998#000289#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1999 VA CH 899"><content><span normalizedCite="1999 Va. Ch. 899">1999, cc. 899<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1999#000899#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1999 VA CH 920"><content><span normalizedCite="1999 Va. Ch. 920">920<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1999#000920#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1999 VA CH 922"><content><span normalizedCite="1999 Va. Ch. 922">922<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1999#000922#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2000 VA CH 850"><content><span normalizedCite="2000 Va. Ch. 850">2000, cc. 850<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2000#000850#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2000 VA CH 920"><content><span normalizedCite="2000 Va. Ch. 920">920<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2000#000920#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2004 VA CH 75"><content><span normalizedCite="2004 Va. Ch. 75">2004, c. 75<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2004#000075#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2007 VA CH 502"><content><span normalizedCite="2007 Va. Ch. 502">2007, c. 502<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2007#000502#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2008 VA CH 664"><content><span normalizedCite="2008 Va. Ch. 664">2008, c. 664<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2008#000664#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2009 VA CH 67"><content><span normalizedCite="2009 Va. Ch. 67">2009, cc. 67<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2009#000067#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2009 VA CH 175"><content><span normalizedCite="2009 Va. Ch. 175">175<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2009#000175#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2009 VA CH 813"><content><span normalizedCite="2009 Va. Ch. 813">813<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2009#000813#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2009 VA CH 840"><content><span normalizedCite="2009 Va. Ch. 840">840<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2009#000840#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2011 VA CH 92"><content><span normalizedCite="2011 Va. Ch. 92">2011, cc. 92<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2011#000092#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2011 VA CH 150"><content><span normalizedCite="2011 Va. Ch. 150">150<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2011#000150#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2012 VA CH 476"><content><span normalizedCite="2012 Va. Ch. 476">2012, cc. 476<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2012#000476#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2012 VA CH 492"><content><span normalizedCite="2012 Va. Ch. 492">492<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2012#000492#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2012 VA CH 507"><content><span normalizedCite="2012 Va. Ch. 507">507<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2012#000507#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2012 VA CH 803"><content><span normalizedCite="2012 Va. Ch. 803">803<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2012#000803#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2012 VA CH 835"><content><span normalizedCite="2012 Va. Ch. 835">835<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2012#000835#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2015 VA CH 541"><content><span normalizedCite="2015 Va. Ch. 541">2015, cc. 541<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2015#000541#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2015 VA CH 542"><content><span normalizedCite="2015 Va. Ch. 542">542<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2015#000542#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2015 VA CH 651"><content><span normalizedCite="2015 Va. Ch. 651">651<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2015#000651#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PT20-004G-K3BB-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 32.1.</desig><title>HEALTH</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 4.</desig><title>HEALTH CARE PLANNING</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="article"><heading><desig>ARTICLE 1.1.</desig><title>MEDICAL CARE FACILITIES CERTIFICATE OF PUBLIC NEED</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Regulation of Nursing Facilities for Disabled &amp; Elderly Persons</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QkI5RTc4N0U1MjU1NDQwMEI1MzhDOThGRTIyNDU1NDU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MTlCM0Q3MTlFNUQ0NDA5OTgwQTEwQjE1M0ZGMTlFQjc</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Public Health &amp; Welfare Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDYwRTY1MDg3MTk5NDUyNkFFRDI1RjJBRERGQ0UxNzI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NUVCNTZERDE5OTI4NDJDRUEzMDVFNjQ3NkEyMjI5QUI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MTlCM0Q3MTlFNUQ0NDA5OTgwQTEwQjE1M0ZGMTlFQjc</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MTJEMUIzNEFBMEE0NDUwMTgyOTk5Q0Q5MUQ3NTNDNTM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NjVGRUIzQkI1QTg1NDUxNkJFM0UwN0IxRTVENDlBNTM</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Nursing Facilities</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QkI5RTc4N0U1MjU1NDQwMEI1MzhDOThGRTIyNDU1NDU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NjVGRUIzQkI1QTg1NDUxNkJFM0UwN0IxRTVENDlBNTM</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Rehabilitation</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NkY3QTlDNUZFOTFDNENGNzlDRUQ0MTNGNjk2MzU2NDY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NjhBRDBBMTY1RjVDNEI5Q0E5QjNDOTcyNDY2NjU3MUM</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Treatment</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QTE3NDlDOUQ4Mzg1NDcxNzhCNzQwNDc2MkEzMTkwRUI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RTA2N0I2MjA4MEMwNEExNjlBQzkzRjBGOTAxODRCNkY</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification><classificationGroup classificationScheme="indexing-terms"><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem score="90"><className>Healthcare</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NkUxMkVDQjJDOEY5NDVDQ0E5NTFEMTlDMjIwNzVERjc7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></classificationGroup></metadata></legislativeDoc>