<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#349#000060#     2#          219#">Va. Code Ann. § 60.2-219</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_60.2-219"/><heading><desig>§ 60.2-219.</desig><title>Services not included in term "employment."</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><bodyText><p>The term "employment" shall not include:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Service performed in the employ of the United States government or of any instrumentality of the United States which is wholly or partially owned by the United States or which is exempt from the tax imposed by <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="26 USC 3301"><content><span normalizedCite="26 U.S.C. 3301">§ 3301 of the Federal Internal Revenue Code<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#29854#1127#00000003301#1#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> by virtue of any provision of law which specifically refers to such section (or the corresponding section of prior law) in granting such exemption;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Service with respect to which unemployment compensation is payable under an unemployment compensation system established by an act of Congress, including service performed after June 30, 1939, for an employer determined to be subject to the Railroad Unemployment Insurance Act <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="45 USC 351"><content><span normalizedCite="45 U.S.C. 351">(45 U.S.C. § 351<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1828#123#000045#        351#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> et seq.) by the agency or agencies empowered to make such determination by an act of Congress, and service as an employer representative determined to be subject to such act by such agency or agencies. The Commission is hereby authorized and directed to enter into agreements with the proper agencies under such act of Congress, which agreements shall become effective 10 days after publication thereof, in the manner provided in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 60.2-111"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 60.2-111">§ 60.2-111<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000060#     2#          111#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> for general rules, to provide reciprocal treatment to individuals who have, after acquiring potential rights to benefits under this title, acquired rights to unemployment compensation under such act of Congress, or who have, after acquiring potential rights to unemployment compensation under such act of Congress, acquired rights to benefits under this title;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Agricultural labor as defined in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 60.2-201"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 60.2-201">§ 60.2-201<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000060#     2#          201#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> except as provided for in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 60.2-214"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 60.2-214">§ 60.2-214<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000060#     2#          214#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_4"/><heading><desig>4.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Domestic service in a private home, local college club or local chapter of a college fraternity or sorority except as provided for in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 60.2-215"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 60.2-215">§ 60.2-215<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000060#     2#          215#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_5"/><heading><desig>5.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Service performed on or in connection with a vessel or aircraft not an American vessel or American aircraft by an employee, if the employee is employed on and in connection with such vessel or aircraft when outside the United States;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_6"/><heading><desig>6.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Service performed by an individual in, or as an officer or member of the crew of, a vessel while it is engaged in the catching, taking, harvesting, cultivating or farming of any kind of fish, shellfish, crustacea, sponges, seaweeds or other aquatic forms of animal and vegetable life, including service performed by any such individual as an ordinary incident to any such activity, except (i) service performed in connection with the catching or taking of salmon or halibut for commercial purposes and (ii) service performed on or in connection with a vessel of more than 10 net tons, determined in the manner provided for determining the register tonnage of merchant vessels under the laws of the United States;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_6a"/><heading><desig>6a.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Service performed by an individual on a boat engaged in catching fish or other forms of aquatic life under an arrangement with the owner or operator of such boat pursuant to which:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_6a_a"/><heading><desig>a.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Such individual does not receive any cash remuneration, other than as provided in subdivision b of subsection 6a;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_6a_b"/><heading><desig>b.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Such individual receives a share of the boat's, or the boats' in the case of a fishing operation involving more than one boat, catch of fish or other forms of aquatic animal life, or a share of the proceeds from the sale of such catch; and</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_6a_c"/><heading><desig>c.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The amount of such individual's share depends on the amount of the boat's, or the boats' in the case of a fishing operation involving more than one boat, catch of fish or other forms of aquatic animal life, but only if the operating crew of such boat, or each boat from which the individual receives a share in the case of a fishing operation involving more than one boat is normally made up of fewer than 10 individuals;</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_7"/><heading><desig>7.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Service performed by an individual in the employ of his son, daughter, or spouse and service performed by a child under the age of 21 in the employ of his father or mother;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_8"/><heading><desig>8.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Service performed in any calendar quarter in the employ of any organization exempt from income tax (i) under <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="26 USC 501"><content><span normalizedCite="26 U.S.C. 501">§ 501 (a) of the Federal Internal Revenue Code<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#29854#1127#00000000501#1#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> (26 U.S.C.), other than an organization described in § 401 (a) of such Code, or (ii) under <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="26 USC 521"><content><span normalizedCite="26 U.S.C. 521">§ 521 of the Federal Internal Revenue Code<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#29854#1127#00000000521#1#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, if the remuneration for such service is less than $ 50;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_9"/><heading><desig>9.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Service performed in the employ of a school, college or university, if such service is performed by a student who is enrolled and is regularly attending classes at such school, college or university;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_10"/><heading><desig>10.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Service performed as a student nurse in the employ of a hospital or a nurses' training school by an individual who is enrolled and is regularly attending classes in a nurses' training school chartered or approved pursuant to state law;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_11"/><heading><desig>11.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Service performed as an intern in the employ of a hospital by an individual who has completed a four-year course in a medical school chartered or approved pursuant to state law;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_12"/><heading><desig>12.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Service performed by an individual for an employing unit as an insurance agent or as an insurance solicitor, if all such service performed by such individual for such employing unit is performed for remuneration solely by way of commission;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_13"/><heading><desig>13.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Service performed by an individual for an employing unit as a real estate salesman, if all such service performed by such individual for such employing unit is performed for remuneration solely by way of commission;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_14"/><heading><desig>14.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Service covered by an arrangement between the Commission and the agency charged with the administration of any other state or federal unemployment compensation law pursuant to which all services performed by an individual for an employing unit during the period covered by such employing unit's duly approved election are deemed to be performed entirely within such agency's state or under such federal law;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_15"/><heading><desig>15.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Service performed by an individual for an employing unit as an agent in the wholesale distribution and sale of gasoline and other petroleum products, if all such service performed by such individual for such employing unit is performed for remuneration solely by way of commission;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_16"/><heading><desig>16.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Service not in the course of the employer's trade or business performed in any calendar quarter by an employee, unless the cash remuneration paid for such service is $ 50 or more and such service is performed by an individual who is regularly employed by such employer to perform such service. For the purposes of this subdivision, an individual shall be deemed to be regularly employed by an employer during a calendar quarter only if (i) on each of some 24 days during such quarter such individual performs for such employer for some portion of the day service not in the course of the employer's trade or business, or (ii) such individual was regularly employed, as determined under clause (i) of this subdivision, by such employer in the performance of such service during the preceding calendar quarter;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_17"/><heading><desig>17.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> a. Service performed by an individual who is enrolled at a nonprofit or public educational institution which normally maintains a regular faculty and curriculum and normally has a regularly organized body of students in attendance at the place where its educational activities are carried on. In order for such services to be excluded from "employment":</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_17_1"/><heading><desig>(1)</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The individual shall be enrolled as a student in a full-time program,</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_17_2"/><heading><desig>(2)</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The program shall be taken for credit at such institution,</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_17_3"/><heading><desig>(3)</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The program combines academic instruction with work experience, and</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_17_4"/><heading><desig>(4)</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Such service shall be an integral part of such program.</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_17_4_b"/><heading><desig>b.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Such institution shall certify to the employer that subdivisions 17 a (1) through 17 a (4) of this section have been met.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_17_4_c"/><heading><desig>c.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> This subdivision shall not apply to service performed in a program established for or on behalf of an employer or group of employers;</p></bodyText></level></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_18"/><heading><desig>18.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Service performed in the employ of a hospital, if such service is performed by a patient of the hospital, as defined in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 60.2-221"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 60.2-221">§ 60.2-221<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000060#     2#          221#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_19"/><heading><desig>19.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Services provided by an individual pursuant to an agreement among the service recipient, a public human services agency as defined in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 15.2-2811"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 15.2-2811">§ 15.2-2811<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000015#     2#         2811#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, and such individual to an eligible service recipient in his own home or the home of the service provider, unless coverage of such services is required by the provisions of § 3304 (a) (6) (A) of the Federal Unemployment Tax Act;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_20"/><heading><desig>20.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Services performed by an individual as a "direct seller" provided that:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_20_a"/><heading><desig>a.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Such person:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_20_a_1"/><heading><desig>(1)</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Is engaged in the trade or business of selling, or soliciting the sale of, consumer products to any buyer on a buy-sell basis, a deposit-commission basis, or any similar basis which the Secretary of the Treasury prescribes by regulations for resale by the buyer or any other person in the home or otherwise than in a permanent retail establishment;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_20_a_2"/><heading><desig>(2)</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Is engaged in the trade or business of selling, or soliciting the sale of, consumer products to a consumer in the home or otherwise than in a permanent retail establishment; or</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_20_a_3"/><heading><desig>(3)</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Is engaged in the trade or business of the delivery or distribution of newspapers or shopping news (including any delivery services directly related to such trade or business).</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_20_b"/><heading><desig>b.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Substantially all of the remuneration for the services performed as a direct seller, whether or not paid in cash, is directly related to sales or output, including the performances of services, rather than to the number of hours worked;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_20_c"/><heading><desig>c.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The services performed by the person are performed pursuant to a written contract between such person and the person for whom the services are performed and such contract provides that the person will not be treated as an employee with respect to such services for federal tax purposes;</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_21"/><heading><desig>21.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Service performed after July 1, 1984, by an individual as a taxicab driver, or as a driver of an executive sedan as defined in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 46.2-2000"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 46.2-2000">§ 46.2-2000<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000046#     2#         2000#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, provided the Commission is furnished evidence that such individual is excluded from taxation by the Federal Unemployment Tax Act;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_22"/><heading><desig>22.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Services performed by an individual as a "contract carrier courier driver" provided the Commission is furnished evidence that such individual is excluded from taxation by the Federal Unemployment Tax Act;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_23"/><heading><desig>23.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Services performed by a full-time student in the employ of an organized camp if:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_23_a"/><heading><desig>a.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Such camp:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_23_a_1"/><heading><desig>(1)</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Did not operate for more than seven months in the calendar year and did not operate for more than seven months in the preceding calendar year; or</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_23_a_2"/><heading><desig>(2)</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Had average gross receipts for any six months in the preceding calendar year which were not more than 33 1/3 percent of its average gross receipts for the other six months in the preceding calendar year; and</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_23_b"/><heading><desig>b.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Such full-time student performed services in the employ of such camp for less than 13 calendar weeks in such calendar year;</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_24"/><heading><desig>24.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Services performed by an individual as a court reporter for an employing unit if all such service performed by the individual for the employing unit is performed for remuneration solely by way of commission;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_25"/><heading><desig>25.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Services performed by an individual as a cosmetologist or as a barber provided the Commission is furnished evidence that such individual is excluded from taxation by the Federal Unemployment Tax Act;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_26"/><heading><desig>26.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Services performed by a licensed clinical social worker as defined in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 54.1-3700"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 54.1-3700">§ 54.1-3700<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000054#     1#         3700#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, licensed psychologist as defined in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 54.1-3600"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 54.1-3600">§ 54.1-3600<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000054#     1#         3600#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, licensed professional counselor as defined in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 54.1-3500"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 54.1-3500">§ 54.1-3500<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000054#     1#         3500#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, licensed psychiatrist, or licensed marriage and family therapist as defined in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 54.1-3500"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 54.1-3500">§ 54.1-3500<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000054#     1#         3500#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, if such individual:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_26_a"/><heading><desig>a.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Operates under a contract specifying that the individual is free from control or direction over the performance of such services;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_26_b"/><heading><desig>b.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Is licensed in the Commonwealth to perform independent clinical services;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_26_c"/><heading><desig>c.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Is compensated solely by way of fees charged for services rendered by such individual; and</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_26_d"/><heading><desig>d.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Has a valid business license issued by the locality in which such individual performs such services; and</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_27"/><heading><desig>27.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Services performed by an inmate for a penal or custodial institution or while participating in the Diversion Center Incarceration Program pursuant to <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 19.2-316.3"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 19.2-316.3">§ 19.2-316.3.<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000019#     2#        316.3#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation></p></bodyText></level></level><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p>Code 1950, § 60-14; 1952, cc. 30, 184; 1956, c. 440; 1962, c. 71; 1968, c. 738, § 60.1-14; 1971, Ex. Sess., c. 235; 1972, c. 824; 1974, cc. 466, 660; 1976, c. 304; 1977, c. 330; 1979, c. 637; 1980, cc. 520, 522; 1981, cc. 28, 369, 374, 375; 1982, c. 25; 1983, c. 14; 1984, cc. 120, 139, 204; 1985, cc. 152, 254; 1986, c. 480; 1987, c. 113; 1988, c. 678; <citation normalizedCite="1989 VA CH 339"><content><span normalizedCite="1989 Va. Ch. 339">1989, c. 339<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1989#000339#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1992 VA CH 4"><content><span normalizedCite="1992 Va. Ch. 4">1992, c. 4<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1992#000004#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1997 VA CH 171"><content><span normalizedCite="1997 Va. Ch. 171">1997, cc. 171<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1997#000171#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1997 VA CH 189"><content><span normalizedCite="1997 Va. Ch. 189">189<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1997#000189#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2000 VA CH 438"><content><span normalizedCite="2000 Va. Ch. 438">2000, c. 438<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2000#000438#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2003 VA CH 609"><content><span normalizedCite="2003 Va. Ch. 609">2003, c. 609<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2003#000609#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2004 VA CH 977"><content><span normalizedCite="2004 Va. Ch. 977">2004, c. 977<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2004#000977#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2005 VA CH 110"><content><span normalizedCite="2005 Va. Ch. 110">2005, c. 110<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2005#000110#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PTM0-004G-K0MX-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 60.2.</desig><title>UNEMPLOYMENT COMPENSATION</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 2.</desig><title>DEFINITIONS</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Admiralty &amp; Maritime Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QzRDNDVDOTdGRUQ1NDE1M0I1RjRBRDFBRTI3ODFGMDk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Licensing &amp; Registration</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QkQ2NzAwOTIzNjIwNDJCQTkyRTYwQzM3RkY2NUJFNDk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NUNBQjc0Q0M5OTI5NEU1RUFCODY4OTgyODhCNkM0OTg</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Scope &amp; Definitions</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDhGQ0ZDREVCRTkzNDcxNTlBQUIzOUM5QTA2QUY2Njk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MEUyNDQ5RTc4RDI2NDc3Q0I3MUE0OEE2NTA3QjYzRkM</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Vessel Licensing &amp; Registration</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QkQ2NzAwOTIzNjIwNDJCQTkyRTYwQzM3RkY2NUJFNDk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QzRDNDVDOTdGRUQ1NDE1M0I1RjRBRDFBRTI3ODFGMDk</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Energy &amp; Utilities Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OUUzODAyRDk1QzVFNEZGMEJDM0RGMDYxOTlEMEEzRDA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Gasoline Dealers &amp; Distributors</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6ODhGNkRGMUNGNkU1NEJFRTgyNzc5MUY4MUFCMDNBRUI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NTc1NEQ0MUJEMTkwNDhEQTgyMzI0MTJFREYzQkE2M0I</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Family Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NEI4M0U5Qzg3RTk0NDdBRUJGNDRGNkZEQkU3RDdFNDU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6REJGM0U3ODNBRTVGNDJGRUI3NENBMkVBNDQyRDhBODU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDlEQ0FFMTZDRDFGNEI0RTlFOTY4ODUwNDVDMjFCQUE</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Governments</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjdEQjE4OUJDMzQxNDNEMEI0RTI1QUFCMzJENjEwRTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Court Personnel</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6ODYzN0QyMzhDNDkyNDJDNTlGNkZBQzQzQTkzRjI0NzQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NURENzJGNTEyQzM0NEREQUI2RkVCRTM4RTc1RTZBREU</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Property</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDhDNkM0Q0Y5QTIwNDlCODhEMkJFMUY4QzQxQTA2QkI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MkM1MTYwRDE0NkJBNEVFMEIxQjM3RUE2NDRFQUFEODY</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Healthcare Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NkUxMkVDQjJDOEY5NDVDQ0E5NTFEMTlDMjIwNzVERjc7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NTVDMzIyNkJCMTRBNDI0NUJBOTlBOTYyMjQ0MDkyODU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QTJGRDdFQzgwODczNDI0NDgwMzEyM0JBOEQ2MUVDNjg</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Labor &amp; Employment Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MTE3QUQwOTA0MUYzNDlCMEFFMjUwRUNDM0RDRkM5QzM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NkQ3NTU4M0UyNTk2NDZCQzhEOTg1MUE5RkY2NzcxRTQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NTc1ODA5RTExMjE1NDRFNThBOTc4RkYyNkM3ODQyMzI</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Scope &amp; Definitions</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDhGQ0ZDREVCRTkzNDcxNTlBQUIzOUM5QTA2QUY2Njk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MEUyNDQ5RTc4RDI2NDc3Q0I3MUE0OEE2NTA3QjYzRkM</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Real Property Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QUUyRTcxRURBNEY2NEE2MDk3QzBCNzRDOEY0NTZDQzk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Right to Commissions</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6REZDMTdEMUM4RjA1NDg3Nzk0RDRCRkI4MzEwNTEzNTE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Q0Y4NEU1ODkzRTlENEQ5MEI1NTRFRTI0RTIzNDcxRkI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Torts</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDAwOEM2NTEzQkVDNEI4NzlGMEZERUEyRjQwODM4Njg7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MkQwMTc0MUU5MzkxNEMwQzhEQkU0QjA2REQzQzNGMTc7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RjMzQjNFQ0U1MDdFNEQzMjg0MTA0MTY4MUZCQTZBM0U</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Transportation Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RTYzRTk5RDVBQkQ2NDcwQzk2NTU3ODQ5OEE3NDlBNzk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Security Interests</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OUJBQjVENTkzNEM2NDFDRUJBRTUwNDM1ODFBRkJCRTY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NkEyRTREQTdBRjkzNDE5OTk4ODAzMEY5MDkzRjlGRTE</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></metadata></legislativeDoc>