<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#349#000002#     2#         2204#">Va. Code Ann. § 2.2-2204</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_2.2-2204"/><heading><desig>§ 2.2-2204.</desig><title>Powers of the Authority</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><bodyText><p>The Authority is granted all powers necessary or convenient for the carrying out of its statutory purposes, including, but not limited to, the power to:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Sue and be sued, implead and be impleaded, complain and defend in all courts;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Adopt, use, and alter at will a common seal;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Acquire any project and property, real, personal or mixed, tangible or intangible, or any interest therein, by purchase, gift or devise and to sell, lease (whether as lessor or lessee), transfer, convey or dispose of any project or property, real, personal or mixed, tangible or intangible or any interest therein, at any time acquired or held by the Authority on such terms and conditions as may be determined by the Board;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_4"/><heading><desig>4.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Plan, develop, undertake, carry out, construct, equip, improve, rehabilitate, repair, furnish, maintain and operate projects;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_5"/><heading><desig>5.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Adopt an annual budget for the Authority's capital improvements and operations;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_6"/><heading><desig>6.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Adopt, alter, and repeal bylaws, rules, and regulations governing the manner in which its business shall be transacted and the manner in which the power of the Authority shall be exercised and its duties performed. Such bylaws, rules, and regulations may provide for such committees and their functions as the Authority may deem necessary and expedient. Such bylaws, rules, and regulations shall be exempt from the Administrative Process Act (<citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 2.2-4000"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 2.2-4000">§ 2.2-4000<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000002#     2#         4000#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> et seq.);</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_7"/><heading><desig>7.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Fix, alter, charge, and collect rates, rentals, fees, and other charges for the use of projects of, the sale of products of, or services rendered by the Authority at rates to be determined by it for the purpose of providing for the payment of the expenses of the Authority; the planning, development, construction, improvement, rehabilitation, repair, furnishing, maintenance, and operation of its projects and properties; the payment of the costs accomplishing its purposes set forth in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 2.2-2202"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 2.2-2202">§ 2.2-2202<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000002#     2#         2202#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; the payment of the principal of and interest on its obligations; and the creation of reserves for such purposes, for other purposes of the Authority and to pay the cost of maintaining, repairing and operating any project and fulfilling the terms and provisions of any agreements made with the purchasers or holders of any such obligations and any other purposes as set forth in this article;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_8"/><heading><desig>8.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Borrow money, make and issue bonds including bonds as the Authority may determine to issue for the purpose of accomplishing the purposes set forth in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 2.2-2202"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 2.2-2202">§ 2.2-2202<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000002#     2#         2202#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> or for refunding bonds previously issued by the Authority, whether such outstanding bonds have matured or are then subject to redemption, or any combination of such purposes; secure the payment of all bonds, or any part thereof, by pledge, assignment or deed of trust of all or any of its revenues, rentals, and receipts or of any project or property, real, personal or mixed, tangible or intangible, or any rights and interest therein; make such agreements with the purchasers or holders of such bonds or with others in connection with any such bonds, whether issued or to be issued, as the Authority shall deem advisable; and in general to provide for the security for said bonds and the rights of holders thereof. However, the total principal amount of bonds, including refunding bonds, outstanding at any time shall not exceed $ 50 million, excluding from such limit any revenue bonds. The Authority shall not issue any bonds, other than revenue bonds, that are not specifically authorized by a bill or resolution passed by a majority vote of those elected to each house of the General Assembly;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_9"/><heading><desig>9.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Make and enter into all contracts and agreements necessary or incidental to the performance of its duties, the furtherance of its purposes, and the execution of its powers under this article, including interstate compacts that have been authorized by the General Assembly and where necessary consented to by the United States Congress and agreements with any person or federal agency;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_10"/><heading><desig>10.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Employ, in its discretion, consultants, attorneys, architects, engineers, accountants, financial experts, investment bankers, superintendents, managers and such other employees and agents as may be necessary, and to fix their compensation to be payable from funds made available to the Authority;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_11"/><heading><desig>11.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Receive and accept from any federal or private agency, foundation, corporation, association or person grants, donations of money, real or personal property for the benefit of the Authority, and to receive and accept from the Commonwealth or any state, and any municipality, county or other political subdivision thereof and from any other source, aid or contributions of either money, property, or other things of value, to be held, used and applied for the purposes for which such grants and contributions may be made;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_12"/><heading><desig>12.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Render advice and assistance, and to provide services, to institutions of higher education and to other persons providing services or facilities for scientific and technological research or graduate education, provided that credit toward a degree, certificate or diploma shall be granted only if such education is provided in conjunction with an institution of higher education authorized to operate in Virginia;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_13"/><heading><desig>13.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Develop, undertake and provide programs, alone or in conjunction with any person or federal agency, for scientific and technological research, technology management, continuing education and in-service training; however, credit towards a degree, certificate or diploma shall be granted only if such education is provided in conjunction with an institution of higher education authorized to operate in Virginia; foster the utilization of scientific and technological research, information discoveries and data and obtain patents, copyrights and trademarks thereon; coordinate the scientific and technological research efforts of public institutions and private industry and collect and maintain data on the development and utilization of scientific and technological research capabilities;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_14"/><heading><desig>14.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Pledge or otherwise encumber all or any of the revenues or receipts of the Authority as security for all or any of the obligations of the Authority; and</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_15"/><heading><desig>15.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Do all acts and things necessary or convenient to carry out the powers granted to it by law.</p></bodyText></level></level><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p><citation normalizedCite="1995 VA CH 758"><content><span normalizedCite="1995 Va. Ch. 758">1995, c. 758<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1995#000758#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, § 9-266.5; <citation normalizedCite="1996 VA CH 111"><content><span normalizedCite="1996 Va. Ch. 111">1996, c. 111<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1996#000111#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2001 VA CH 844"><content><span normalizedCite="2001 Va. Ch. 844">2001, c. 844<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2001#000844#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2012 VA CH 779"><content><span normalizedCite="2012 Va. Ch. 779">2012, cc. 779<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2012#000779#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2012 VA CH 817"><content><span normalizedCite="2012 Va. Ch. 817">817<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2012#000817#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PV80-004G-K15C-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 2.2.</desig><title>ADMINISTRATION OF GOVERNMENT</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="subtitle"><heading><desig>SUBTITLE I.</desig><title>ORGANIZATION OF STATE GOVERNMENT</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="part"><heading><desig>PART D.</desig><title>STATE AUTHORITIES, BOARDS, COMMISSIONS, COUNCILS, FOUNDATIONS AND OTHER COLLEGIAL BODIES</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 22.</desig><title>AUTHORITIES</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="article"><heading><desig>ARTICLE 2.</desig><title>COMMERCIAL SPACE FLIGHT AUTHORITY</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Governments</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjdEQjE4OUJDMzQxNDNEMEI0RTI1QUFCMzJENjEwRTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Employees &amp; Officials</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NzhCNTkxRUNENDI5NDQxMDk3NkNGOTI5REE1RjI0QjM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MkM1MTYwRDE0NkJBNEVFMEIxQjM3RUE2NDRFQUFEODY</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification><classificationGroup classificationScheme="indexing-terms"><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem score="90"><className>Governments</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjdEQjE4OUJDMzQxNDNEMEI0RTI1QUFCMzJENjEwRTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></classificationGroup></metadata></legislativeDoc>