<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#123#000023#        19#">Va. Code Ann. § 23-19</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_23-19"/><heading><desig>§ 23-19.</desig><title>(Repealed effective October 1, 2016) Amount of bonds; purposes; resolutions; Treasury Board to be paying agent and to approve terms and structure; payment or purchase by institution; no personal liability</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a"/><heading><desig>(a)</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Every institution shall have power and is hereby authorized and empowered from time to time to execute its bonds in such aggregate principal amount as may be determined upon by its board and approved by the Governor. All such bonds shall be approved by the Treasury Board pursuant to <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 2.2-2416"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 2.2-2416">§ 2.2-2416<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000002#     2#         2416#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, and the Treasury Board is hereby designated the paying agent of such institutions under this chapter. The Treasury Board's duties shall include the approval of the terms and structure of such bonds. Such aggregate principal amount may include without limitation any costs associated with the development and management of the project or legal or accounting expenses incurred by the institution in connection with the project for the erection of which such bonds are issued, and the cost of issuance of the bonds, including printing, engraving, advertising, legal and other similar expenses.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b"/><heading><desig>(b)</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Such bonds shall be authorized by resolution of the board, approved by the Governor, and may be issued in one or more series, shall bear such date or dates, mature at such time or times, bear interest at such rate not exceeding the rate specified in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 23-30.03"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 23 -30.03">§ 23-30.03<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#123#000023#     30.03#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> payable at such time or times, be in such denominations, be in such form, either coupon or registered, carry such registration privileges, be executed in such manner, be payable in such medium of payment, at such place or places, be subject to such terms of redemption, with or without premium, as such resolution or resolutions may provide. Such bonds may be sold at public or private sale for such price or prices as the board with the approval of the Governor shall determine, provided that the interest cost to maturity of the money received for any issue of such bonds shall not exceed the rate specified in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 23-30.03"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 23 -30.03">§ 23-30.03<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#123#000023#     30.03#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; however, prior to the issuance of bonds to finance any "project," the approval of the General Assembly must be obtained; and provided further, that biennially on or before the first day of September in the odd-numbered years, each educational institution shall submit to the Governor any project or projects and the estimated cost of each separate project such educational institution desires to have financed under the provisions of this chapter, and the Governor shall consider such projects and make his recommendation to the General Assembly in the budget submitted in accordance with the provisions of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 2.2-1508"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 2.2-1508">§ 2.2-1508<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000002#     2#         1508#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>. Each educational institution is authorized to finance only those projects approved by the General Assembly in the appropriations act for the biennium covered by such appropriations act, which projects need not be limited to the projects recommended by the Governor.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c"/><heading><desig>(c)</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Such bonds may be issued to finance all or a portion of the cost of any project plus amounts to fund issuance costs, reserve funds, capitalized interest for a period not to exceed one year following completion of the project and for the corporate purpose or purposes of the institution specified by <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 23-17"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 23 -17">§ 23-17<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#123#000023#        17#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> hereof or to carry out the powers conferred on the institution by <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 23-18"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 23 -18">§ 23-18<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#123#000023#        18#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> hereof.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d"/><heading><desig>(d)</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Any resolution or resolutions authorizing such bonds may contain a provision or provisions which shall be part of the contract with the holders of such bonds as to:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d_1"/><heading><desig>(1)</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Fixing, revising, charging and collecting fees, rents and charges for or in connection with the use, occupation or services of the project and pledging the same and any increases in revenues to be derived from any existing facilities at such institution resulting from any increase in the fees, rents or charges for or in connection with the use, occupation or services of any such existing facilities to the payment of the principal of and the interest on such bonds;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d_2"/><heading><desig>(2)</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Fixing, revising, charging and collecting fees, rents and charges for or in connection with the use, occupation or services of any existing facilities at such institution and pledging the same to the payment of the principal of and the interest on such bonds;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d_3"/><heading><desig>(3)</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Fixing, revising, charging and collecting student building fees and other student fees from students enrolled at such institution and pledging the same in whole or in part to the payment of the principal of and the interest on such bonds;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d_4"/><heading><desig>(4)</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Pledging to the payment of the principal of and the interest on such bonds any moneys available for the use of such institution, including, but not limited to, and subject to Treasury Board guidelines and approval pursuant to <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 2.2-2416"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 2.2-2416">§ 2.2-2416<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000002#     2#         2416#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, moneys appropriated to such institution from the general fund of the Commonwealth or from nongeneral funds, without regard to the source of such moneys, and which are not required by law or by previous binding contract to be devoted to some other purpose;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d_5"/><heading><desig>(5)</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Paying the cost of operating and maintaining any project and any such existing facilities from any one or more of the revenue sources mentioned in subdivisions (1), (2), (3) and (4) of this subsection creating reserves for such purposes and providing for the use and application thereof;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d_6"/><heading><desig>(6)</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Creating sinking funds for the payment of the principal of and the interest on such bonds, creating reserves for such purposes and providing for the use and application thereof;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d_7"/><heading><desig>(7)</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Limiting the right of the institution to restrict and regulate the use, occupation and services of the project and such other existing facilities or the services rendered therein;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d_8"/><heading><desig>(8)</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Limiting the purposes to which the proceeds of sale of any issue of bonds then or thereafter to be issued may be applied;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d_9"/><heading><desig>(9)</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Limiting the issuance of additional bonds;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d_10"/><heading><desig>(10)</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Setting forth the procedure, if any, by which the terms of any contract with the holders of such bonds may be amended or abrogated and the manner in which such consent of such holders to any such amendment or abrogation may be given; and</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d_11"/><heading><desig>(11)</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Setting forth such other condition or conditions as may be required by the United States of America or any federal agency as a condition precedent to or a requirement in connection with the obtaining of a direct grant or grants of money for or in aid of the erection of any project, or to defray or to partially defray the cost of labor and material employed in the erection of any project, or to obtain a loan or loans of money for or in aid of the erection of any project from the United States of America or any federal agency, provided that such other condition or conditions are approved by the Governor.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_e"/><heading><desig>(e)</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The power and obligation of an institution to pay any bonds issued under this chapter shall be limited. Such bonds shall be payable only from any one or more of the revenue sources mentioned in subdivisions (1), (2), (3) and (4) of subsection (d) of this section and pledged therefor pursuant to a resolution adopted under said subsection (d). Such bonds shall in no event constitute an indebtedness of the institution, except to the extent of the collection of such revenues and such institution shall not be liable to pay such bonds or the interest thereon from any other funds; and no contract entered into by the institution pursuant to subsection (b) of this section shall be construed to require the costs or expenses of operation and maintenance of the project for the erection of which the bonds are issued and any such other existing facilities to be paid out of any funds other than the revenues derived from the sources mentioned in subdivisions (1), (2), (3) and (4) of subsection (d) of this section and pledged therefor. Any provision of the general laws to the contrary notwithstanding, any bonds issued pursuant to the authority of this chapter shall be fully negotiable within the meaning and for all the purposes of Title 8.3A.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_f"/><heading><desig>(f)</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Neither the Governor nor the members of the board nor any person executing such bonds shall be liable personally on the bonds or be subject to any personal liability or accountability by reason of the issuance thereof.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_g"/><heading><desig>(g)</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The institution shall have power out of any funds available therefor to purchase any bonds issued by it at a price not more than the principal amount thereof and the accrued interest. All bonds so purchased shall be cancelled unless purchased as an endowment fund investment. This paragraph shall not apply to the redemption of bonds.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_h"/><heading><desig>(h)</desig></heading><bodyText><p> In any case in which an institution shall have obtained a loan for or in aid of the erection of any project from the United States of America or any federal agency, which loan requires the establishment of a debt service reserve, the institution, with the consent of the Governor, may deposit securities in a separate collateral account in an amount equal to the required debt service reserve, which securities shall be pledged to meet the debt service requirements only if the revenues derived from any one or more of the sources mentioned in subdivisions (1), (2), (3) and (4) of subsection (d) of this section and pledged for the payment of such loan become insufficient for such purpose. The face value of United States government securities and the market value of all other securities shall be deemed to be the value of any securities so deposited. Nothing herein shall be construed as prohibiting repayment of any portion of such loan from income derived from the securities so deposited. No securities shall be deposited in any such collateral account unless the same shall have been purchased with funds, the use of which is in nowise limited or restricted or shall have been donated to such institution for the purpose of establishing such debt service reserve.</p></bodyText></level><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p>1933, p. 85; 1936-7, p. 28; 1946, p. 184; 1950, p. 366; 1954, c. 397; 1958, cc. 17, 486; 1959, Ex. Sess., c. 61; 1962, c. 373; 1964, c. 635; 1970, c. 609; <citation normalizedCite="1990 VA CH 54"><content><span normalizedCite="1990 Va. Ch. 54">1990, cc. 54<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1990#000054#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1990 VA CH 856"><content><span normalizedCite="1990 Va. Ch. 856">856<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1990#000856#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1996 VA CH 636"><content><span normalizedCite="1996 Va. Ch. 636">1996, cc. 636<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1996#000636#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1996 VA CH 656"><content><span normalizedCite="1996 Va. Ch. 656">656<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1996#000656#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1996 VA CH 672"><content><span normalizedCite="1996 Va. Ch. 672">672<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1996#000672#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1996 VA CH 689"><content><span normalizedCite="1996 Va. Ch. 689">689<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1996#000689#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PT00-004G-K1SJ-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 23.</desig><title>EDUCATIONAL INSTITUTIONS</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 3.</desig><title>BONDS AND OTHER OBLIGATIONS</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjA4OEVGODBENzY4NDcxM0IyQzA1OTEwQzVDODRBOUE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjQ1NzI5NzRGQUEwNDg1RThBNDE0NTE2MkYzODc3NUQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RUZBNTgwODk0QkRCNDUwQkExNzBFRkU0NkI4MkE5OTU</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Civil Procedure</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MzUxNjJDMEQ5N0YwNDMzM0JDMjEzM0UzOTYzMzI3OTU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Execution of Bonds</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RTM5MjlDQ0NDNzM0NDFCNjkwODUxNTI0MUU2MUE4NjI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RTJEQTFGMDU2MUNGNEY1MTg0NjcyRUM0OEMzMTVDNDE</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Contracts Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QzY0RTZFMzE0RjkwNDdFQUI5M0U5N0ZFMjYyREMyQzU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Conditions Precedent</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDBDQzk1QjVEQjg3NDA1QTgzRTlCNEEwODJENjkxM0E7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QUQwMUEyNUE3Nzg0NEJGNTg0MkJBNkRBNDUwNjRGRTI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Education Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDkzNUEzQzFBNEZBNEFBREIxNDM5MTc1MUU5QjI4MTY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NUJBMkUxQjc0M0QyNEJFQkEwQjQ4MDMzMEUxNTBGQTE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjZBQUM2RjM4QkI4NDlFMkFCNTBDMzJGNDg0MTgxOUU</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Governments</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjdEQjE4OUJDMzQxNDNEMEI0RTI1QUFCMzJENjEwRTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Claims By &amp; Against</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QzMzOUFCQTMxMDM3NDREMkJBMUFCNzlBQjY4Mjk2M0E7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MkM1MTYwRDE0NkJBNEVFMEIxQjM3RUE2NDRFQUFEODY</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification><classificationGroup classificationScheme="indexing-terms"><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem score="90"><className>Education</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDkzNUEzQzFBNEZBNEFBREIxNDM5MTc1MUU5QjI4MTY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></classificationGroup></metadata></legislativeDoc>