<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#349#000038#     2#         6106#">Va. Code Ann. § 38.2-6106</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_38.2-6106"/><heading><desig>§ 38.2-6106.</desig><title>Optional provisions</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><bodyText><p>Dental benefit contracts may contain the following provisions:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A provision including the dental plan organization's intention to charge a specified missed appointment fee. The fee shall be reasonable in relation to the nature of the procedure for which the missed appointment had been made. Neither the plan dentist nor the dental plan organization may charge a missed appointment fee unless this provision appears in the dental benefit contract. For purposes of this section, the term <emphasis typeStyle="it">"missed appointment"</emphasis> means an appointment for which advance cancellation of at least 24 hours was not provided.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A provision including the dental plan organization's ability to increase premiums or subscription fees, with this provision indicating that these fees may not be increased unless:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_2_a"/><heading><desig>a.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The contract holder has been given written notice at least 60 days before the effective date of the increase; and</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_2_b"/><heading><desig>b.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> In the case of:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_2_b_1"/><heading><desig>(1)</desig></heading><bodyText><p> An individual contract, present rates under the contract have not been changed for at least 12 months, or</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_2_b_2"/><heading><desig>(2)</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A group contract, present rates under the contract have been in effect for at least 12 months.</p></bodyText></level></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A provision including the dental plan organization's intention to impose a financial penalty on an enrollee for voluntarily withdrawing from the dental plan during the first year of coverage, which penalty may not:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_3_a"/><heading><desig>a.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Be charged if the enrollee withdraws from the dental plan after being covered for at least 12 months; or</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_3_b"/><heading><desig>b.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Exceed the usual, customary, and reasonable charge for services received reduced by the sum of the subscription fees paid by or for the enrollee and any copayments paid by or for the enrollee.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_4"/><heading><desig>4.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A provision including the dental plan organization's ability to increase the patient charge schedule, with the provision indicating that the increase may not be effective unless the:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_4_a"/><heading><desig>a.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Present schedule under the contract has been in effect for at least 12 months; and</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_4_b"/><heading><desig>b.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Contract holder has been given written notice of the increase at least 60 days before the effective date of the increase.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_5"/><heading><desig>5.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A provision including the dental plan organization's rights if an enrollee refuses to follow a particular course of treatment. The dental plan organization may not terminate the membership of an enrollee for refusal to follow a recommended course of treatment for a particular condition. The provision may indicate that the dental plan organization may refuse to provide any further benefits for the particular condition if the enrollee refuses to accept a recommended course of treatment.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_6"/><heading><desig>6.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A provision including the dental plan organization's rights if an enrollee fraudulently uses his membership card or knowingly permits his membership card to be used by others. The dental plan organization may terminate an enrollee's coverage if the enrollee fraudulently uses his membership card or knowingly permits his membership card to be used by others. The dental plan organization may not terminate coverage for an entire family because a dependent fraudulently uses the membership card. In this instance, only the dependent's coverage may terminate.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_7"/><heading><desig>7.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A provision specifying that the dental plan organization may terminate an enrollee's coverage if the enrollee is unable to maintain a satisfactory dentist-patient relationship with a plan dentist, provided, however:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_7_a"/><heading><desig>a.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Before terminating the enrollee's coverage, the dental plan organization shall permit the enrollee to change primary dentists at least once;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_7_b"/><heading><desig>b.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The enrollee shall be given written notice of the termination at least 30 days before the termination of the enrollee's membership.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_8"/><heading><desig>8.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> If the contract provides coverage for dependent children, the contract shall also contain the following provision:</p><excerpt><level levelType="paragraph"><bodyText><p><pre/>"Notwithstanding any limiting age stated in the contract, any unmarried child covered under the contract as a dependent of an enrollee who is chiefly dependent for support upon the enrollee, and who, at the time of reaching the limiting age, is incapable of self-support because of mental or physical incapacity that commenced prior to the child's attaining the limiting age, shall continue to be covered under the contract while remaining so dependent, unmarried, and mentally or physically incapacitated, until the coverage on the enrollee upon whom the child is dependent terminates."</p></bodyText></level></excerpt></bodyText></level></level><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p><citation normalizedCite="2004 VA CH 668"><content><span normalizedCite="2004 Va. Ch. 668">2004, c. 668<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2004#000668#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PVD0-004G-K3VY-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 38.2.</desig><title>INSURANCE</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 61.</desig><title>DENTAL PLAN ORGANIZATIONS</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Contracts Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QzY0RTZFMzE0RjkwNDdFQUI5M0U5N0ZFMjYyREMyQzU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Discharge &amp; Termination</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MkYzNDBBRjgzQjhENDZBRjg1MkNGNzc4NTE0Mzg0NDQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OTdCODg3NEVGQTY5NENDQ0EzRkEwMzNGOTVBQTE0NEY</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Minors</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Q0EzMkU3MUM2REE1NDMxQUFBRjFDMjZDREY3NTQwOEI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QzRENDc0OTlENDE3NDUzRDlERUU2QUM1MTQyRUMzRTM</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Insurance Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDM4MzQ2QUYzMTY0NDQzQTkxRDQwRUUzRUM5RDg0OEM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Notice Requirements</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MkUwNjY2QUVERDA1NDJEMEE3NDRFREUzQUFEMkQ2QUQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RkE2MEIwQkEwRTExNDVGOUJCRDhBRUQ3QTRGNDdDNTI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification><classificationGroup classificationScheme="indexing-terms"><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem score="90"><className>Insurance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDM4MzQ2QUYzMTY0NDQzQTkxRDQwRUUzRUM5RDg0OEM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></classificationGroup></metadata></legislativeDoc>