<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#349#000037#     2#          809#">Va. Code Ann. § 37.2-809</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_37.2-809"/><heading><desig>§ 37.2-809.</desig><title>Involuntary temporary detention; issuance and execution of order</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a"/><heading><desig>A.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> For the purposes of this section:</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Designee of the local community services board"</emphasis> means an examiner designated by the local community services board who (i) is skilled in the assessment and treatment of mental illness, (ii) has completed a certification program approved by the Department, (iii) is able to provide an independent examination of the person, (iv) is not related by blood or marriage to the person being evaluated, (v) has no financial interest in the admission or treatment of the person being evaluated, (vi) has no investment interest in the facility detaining or admitting the person under this article, and (vii) except for employees of state hospitals and of the U.S. Department of Veterans Affairs, is not employed by the facility.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Employee"</emphasis> means an employee of the local community services board who is skilled in the assessment and treatment of mental illness and has completed a certification program approved by the Department.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Investment interest"</emphasis> means the ownership or holding of an equity or debt security, including shares of stock in a corporation, interests or units of a partnership, bonds, debentures, notes, or other equity or debt instruments.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b"/><heading><desig>B.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A magistrate shall issue, upon the sworn petition of any responsible person, treating physician, or upon his own motion and only after an evaluation conducted in-person or by means of a two-way electronic video and audio communication system as authorized in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 37.2-804.1"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 37.2-804.1">§ 37.2-804.1<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000037#     2#        804.1#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> by an employee or a designee of the local community services board to determine whether the person meets the criteria for temporary detention, a temporary detention order if it appears from all evidence readily available, including any recommendation from a physician or clinical psychologist treating the person, that the person (i) has a mental illness and that there exists a substantial likelihood that, as a result of mental illness, the person will, in the near future, (a) cause serious physical harm to himself or others as evidenced by recent behavior causing, attempting, or threatening harm and other relevant information, if any, or (b) suffer serious harm due to his lack of capacity to protect himself from harm or to provide for his basic human needs; (ii) is in need of hospitalization or treatment; and (iii) is unwilling to volunteer or incapable of volunteering for hospitalization or treatment. The magistrate shall also consider, if available, (a) information provided by the person who initiated emergency custody and (b) the recommendations of any treating or examining physician licensed in Virginia either verbally or in writing prior to rendering a decision. Any temporary detention order entered pursuant to this section shall provide for the disclosure of medical records pursuant to <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 37.2-804.2"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 37.2-804.2">§ 37.2-804.2.<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000037#     2#        804.2#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> This subsection shall not preclude any other disclosures as required or permitted by law.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c"/><heading><desig>C.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> When considering whether there is probable cause to issue a temporary detention order, the magistrate may, in addition to the petition, consider (i) the recommendations of any treating or examining physician or psychologist licensed in Virginia, if available, (ii) any past actions of the person, (iii) any past mental health treatment of the person, (iv) any relevant hearsay evidence, (v) any medical records available, (vi) any affidavits submitted, if the witness is unavailable and it so states in the affidavit, and (vii) any other information available that the magistrate considers relevant to the determination of whether probable cause exists to issue a temporary detention order.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d"/><heading><desig>D.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A magistrate may issue a temporary detention order without an emergency custody order proceeding. A magistrate may issue a temporary detention order without a prior evaluation pursuant to subsection B if (i) the person has been personally examined within the previous 72 hours by an employee or a designee of the local community services board or (ii) there is a significant physical, psychological, or medical risk to the person or to others associated with conducting such evaluation.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_e"/><heading><desig>E.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> An employee or a designee of the local community services board shall determine the facility of temporary detention in accordance with the provisions of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 37.2-809.1"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 37.2-809.1">§ 37.2-809.1<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000037#     2#        809.1#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> for all individuals detained pursuant to this section. An employee or designee of the local community services board may change the facility of temporary detention and may designate an alternative facility for temporary detention at any point during the period of temporary detention if it is determined that the alternative facility is a more appropriate facility for temporary detention of the individual given the specific security, medical, or behavioral health needs of the person. In cases in which the facility of temporary detention is changed following transfer of custody to an initial facility of temporary custody, transportation of the individual to the alternative facility of temporary detention shall be provided in accordance with the provisions of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 37.2-810"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 37.2-810">§ 37.2-810<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000037#     2#          810#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>. The initial facility of temporary detention shall be identified on the preadmission screening report and indicated on the temporary detention order; however, if an employee or designee of the local community services board designates an alternative facility, that employee or designee shall provide written notice forthwith, on a form developed by the Executive Secretary of the Supreme Court of Virginia, to the clerk of the issuing court of the name and address of the alternative facility. Subject to the provisions of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 37.2-809.1"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 37.2-809.1">§ 37.2-809.1<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000037#     2#        809.1#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, if a facility of temporary detention cannot be identified by the time of the expiration of the period of emergency custody pursuant to <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 37.2-808"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 37.2-808">§ 37.2-808<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000037#     2#          808#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, the individual shall be detained in a state facility for the treatment of individuals with mental illness and such facility shall be indicated on the temporary detention order. Except as provided in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 37.2-811"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 37.2-811">§ 37.2-811<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000037#     2#          811#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> for inmates requiring hospitalization in accordance with subdivision A 2 of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 19.2-169.6"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 19.2-169.6">§ 19.2-169.6<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000019#     2#        169.6#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, the person shall not be detained in a jail or other place of confinement for persons charged with criminal offenses and shall remain in the custody of law enforcement until the person is either detained within a secure facility or custody has been accepted by the appropriate personnel designated by either the initial facility of temporary detention identified in the temporary detention order or by the alternative facility of temporary detention designated by the employee or designee of the local community services board pursuant to this subsection. The person detained or in custody pursuant to this section shall be given a written summary of the temporary detention procedures and the statutory protections associated with those procedures.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_f"/><heading><desig>F.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Any facility caring for a person placed with it pursuant to a temporary detention order is authorized to provide emergency medical and psychiatric services within its capabilities when the facility determines that the services are in the best interests of the person within its care. The costs incurred as a result of the hearings and by the facility in providing services during the period of temporary detention shall be paid and recovered pursuant to <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 37.2-804"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 37.2-804">§ 37.2-804<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000037#     2#          804#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>. The maximum costs reimbursable by the Commonwealth pursuant to this section shall be established by the State Board of Medical Assistance Services based on reasonable criteria. The State Board of Medical Assistance Services shall, by regulation, establish a reasonable rate per day of inpatient care for temporary detention.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_g"/><heading><desig>G.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The employee or the designee of the local community services board who is conducting the evaluation pursuant to this section shall determine, prior to the issuance of the temporary detention order, the insurance status of the person. Where coverage by a third party payor exists, the facility seeking reimbursement under this section shall first seek reimbursement from the third party payor. The Commonwealth shall reimburse the facility only for the balance of costs remaining after the allowances covered by the third party payor have been received.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_h"/><heading><desig>H.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The duration of temporary detention shall be sufficient to allow for completion of the examination required by <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 37.2-815"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 37.2-815">§ 37.2-815<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000037#     2#          815#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, preparation of the preadmission screening report required by <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 37.2-816"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 37.2-816">§ 37.2-816<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000037#     2#          816#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, and initiation of mental health treatment to stabilize the person's psychiatric condition to avoid involuntary commitment where possible, but shall not exceed 72 hours prior to a hearing. If the 72-hour period herein specified terminates on a Saturday, Sunday, legal holiday, or day on which the court is lawfully closed, the person may be detained, as herein provided, until the close of business on the next day that is not a Saturday, Sunday, legal holiday, or day on which the court is lawfully closed. The person may be released, pursuant to § 37.2-813, before the 72-hour period herein specified has run.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_i"/><heading><desig>I.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> If a temporary detention order is not executed within 24 hours of its issuance, or within a shorter period as is specified in the order, the order shall be void and shall be returned unexecuted to the office of the clerk of the issuing court or, if the office is not open, to any magistrate serving the jurisdiction of the issuing court. Subsequent orders may be issued upon the original petition within 96 hours after the petition is filed. However, a magistrate must again obtain the advice of an employee or a designee of the local community services board prior to issuing a subsequent order upon the original petition. Any petition for which no temporary detention order or other process in connection therewith is served on the subject of the petition within 96 hours after the petition is filed shall be void and shall be returned to the office of the clerk of the issuing court.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_j"/><heading><desig>J.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The Executive Secretary of the Supreme Court of Virginia shall establish and require that a magistrate, as provided by this section, be available seven days a week, 24 hours a day, for the purpose of performing the duties established by this section. Each community services board shall provide to each general district court and magistrate's office within its service area a list of its employees and designees who are available to perform the evaluations required herein.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_k"/><heading><desig>K.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> For purposes of this section, a health care provider or designee of a local community services board or behavioral health authority shall not be required to encrypt any email containing information or medical records provided to a magistrate unless there is reason to believe that a third party will attempt to intercept the email.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_l"/><heading><desig>L.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> If the employee or designee of the community services board who is conducting the evaluation pursuant to this section recommends that the person should not be subject to a temporary detention order, such employee or designee shall (i) inform the petitioner, the person who initiated emergency custody if such person is present, and an onsite treating physician of his recommendation; (ii) promptly inform such person who initiated emergency custody that the community services board will facilitate communication between the person and the magistrate if the person disagrees with recommendations of the employee or designee of the community services board who conducted the evaluation and the person who initiated emergency custody so requests; and (iii) upon prompt request made by the person who initiated emergency custody, arrange for such person who initiated emergency custody to communicate with the magistrate as soon as is practicable and prior to the expiration of the period of emergency custody. The magistrate shall consider any information provided by the person who initiated emergency custody and any recommendations of the treating or examining physician and the employee or designee of the community services board who conducted the evaluation and consider such information and recommendations in accordance with subsection B in making his determination to issue a temporary detention order. The individual who is the subject of emergency custody shall remain in the custody of law enforcement or a designee of law enforcement and shall not be released from emergency custody until communication with the magistrate pursuant to this subsection has concluded and the magistrate has made a determination regarding issuance of a temporary detention order.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_m"/><heading><desig>M.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> For purposes of this section, "person who initiated emergency custody" means any person who initiated the issuance of an emergency custody order pursuant to <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 37.2-808"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 37.2-808">§ 37.2-808<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000037#     2#          808#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> or a law-enforcement officer who takes a person into custody pursuant to subsection G of § 37.2-808.</p></bodyText></level><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p>1974, c. 351, § 37.1-67.1; 1975, cc. 237, 433; 1976, c. 671, § 37.1-67.4; 1980, c. 582; 1981, cc. 233, 463; 1982, c. 435; 1986, cc. 134, 478, 629; 1987, c. 96; 1988, c. 98; <citation normalizedCite="1989 VA CH 716"><content><span normalizedCite="1989 Va. Ch. 716">1989, c. 716<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1989#000716#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1990 VA CH 429"><content><span normalizedCite="1990 Va. Ch. 429">1990, cc. 429<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1990#000429#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1990 VA CH 728"><content><span normalizedCite="1990 Va. Ch. 728">728<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1990#000728#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1991 VA CH 159"><content><span normalizedCite="1991 Va. Ch. 159">1991, c. 159<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1991#000159#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1992 VA CH 566"><content><span normalizedCite="1992 Va. Ch. 566">1992, c. 566<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1992#000566#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1995 VA CH 844"><content><span normalizedCite="1995 Va. Ch. 844">1995, c. 844<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1995#000844#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1996 VA CH 343"><content><span normalizedCite="1996 Va. Ch. 343">1996, cc. 343<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1996#000343#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1996 VA CH 893"><content><span normalizedCite="1996 Va. Ch. 893">893<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1996#000893#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1998 VA CH 37"><content><span normalizedCite="1998 Va. Ch. 37">1998, cc. 37<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1998#000037#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1998 VA CH 594"><content><span normalizedCite="1998 Va. Ch. 594">594<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1998#000594#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1998 VA CH 611"><content><span normalizedCite="1998 Va. Ch. 611">611<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1998#000611#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2004 VA CH 737"><content><span normalizedCite="2004 Va. Ch. 737">2004, c. 737<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2004#000737#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2005 VA CH 716"><content><span normalizedCite="2005 Va. Ch. 716">2005, c. 716<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2005#000716#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2007 VA CH 526"><content><span normalizedCite="2007 Va. Ch. 526">2007, c. 526<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2007#000526#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2008 VA CH 331"><content><span normalizedCite="2008 Va. Ch. 331">2008, cc. 331<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2008#000331#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2008 VA CH 551"><content><span normalizedCite="2008 Va. Ch. 551">551<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2008#000551#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2008 VA CH 691"><content><span normalizedCite="2008 Va. Ch. 691">691<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2008#000691#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2008 VA CH 728"><content><span normalizedCite="2008 Va. Ch. 728">728<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2008#000728#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2008 VA CH 779"><content><span normalizedCite="2008 Va. Ch. 779">779<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2008#000779#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2008 VA CH 782"><content><span normalizedCite="2008 Va. Ch. 782">782<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2008#000782#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2008 VA CH 793"><content><span normalizedCite="2008 Va. Ch. 793">793<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2008#000793#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2008 VA CH 828"><content><span normalizedCite="2008 Va. Ch. 828">828<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2008#000828#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2008 VA CH 850"><content><span normalizedCite="2008 Va. Ch. 850">850<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2008#000850#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2008 VA CH 870"><content><span normalizedCite="2008 Va. Ch. 870">870<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2008#000870#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2009 VA CH 455"><content><span normalizedCite="2009 Va. Ch. 455">2009, cc. 455<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2009#000455#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2009 VA CH 555"><content><span normalizedCite="2009 Va. Ch. 555">555<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2009#000555#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2010 VA CH 340"><content><span normalizedCite="2010 Va. Ch. 340">2010, cc. 340<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2010#000340#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2010 VA CH 406"><content><span normalizedCite="2010 Va. Ch. 406">406<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2010#000406#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2010 VA CH 778"><content><span normalizedCite="2010 Va. Ch. 778">778<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2010#000778#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2010 VA CH 825"><content><span normalizedCite="2010 Va. Ch. 825">825<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2010#000825#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2013 VA CH 87"><content><span normalizedCite="2013 Va. Ch. 87">2013, cc. 87<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2013#000087#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2013 VA CH 321"><content><span normalizedCite="2013 Va. Ch. 321">321<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2013#000321#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2014 VA CH 499"><content><span normalizedCite="2014 Va. Ch. 499">2014, cc. 499<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2014#000499#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2014 VA CH 538"><content><span normalizedCite="2014 Va. Ch. 538">538<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2014#000538#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2014 VA CH 675"><content><span normalizedCite="2014 Va. Ch. 675">675<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2014#000675#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2014 VA CH 691"><content><span normalizedCite="2014 Va. Ch. 691">691<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2014#000691#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2014 VA CH 761"><content><span normalizedCite="2014 Va. Ch. 761">761<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2014#000761#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2014 VA CH 773"><content><span normalizedCite="2014 Va. Ch. 773">773<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2014#000773#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2016 VA CH 569"><content><span normalizedCite="2016 Va. Ch. 569">2016, cc. 569<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2016#000569#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2016 VA CH 693"><content><span normalizedCite="2016 Va. Ch. 693">693<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2016#000693#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PVG0-004G-K55P-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 37.2.</desig><title>BEHAVIORAL HEALTH AND DEVELOPMENTAL SERVICES</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="subtitle"><heading><desig>SUBTITLE 3.</desig><title>ADMISSIONS AND DISPOSITIONS</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 8.</desig><title>EMERGENCY CUSTODY AND VOLUNTARY AND INVOLUNTARY CIVIL ADMISSIONS</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="article"><heading><desig>ARTICLE 4.</desig><title>EMERGENCY CUSTODY AND INVOLUNTARY TEMPORARY DETENTION</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Criminal Law &amp; Procedure</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NEU0RkE1OUQwNUQwNDgxODhEODZCMjkzOTg3NThBNzk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Imprisonment</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NURCMTExOEEzNDJBNDk4RjhFQTQ0NzEwMzc0OTg3RTE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QTFGRjg4NjA3RTg1NDA2RkIzMDk4QzdGREIyQzVGMDk</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Governments</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjdEQjE4OUJDMzQxNDNEMEI0RTI1QUFCMzJENjEwRTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Administrative Boards</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QTYwRUFCMDc5MzQ5NDEyREFEQkU2NkE2MjRGQTlCNzY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Njg1MkM3RkYyNzIxNEVFRkJFMTI2NUM4NUU1ODdEM0Q</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Judges</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OTg1QUIzNkIwNzk5NDQ4NzhGMDdDQjVGNEYyRjY5OTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NURENzJGNTEyQzM0NEREQUI2RkVCRTM4RTc1RTZBREU</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Sunday Closing Laws</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NjE1QTMyMzg5RjAyNDA1QUE4RkFFREQ1MjgzRUFGMzM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6ODM0MTQxODNGMEIyNDI0QkE5NTYzMEJBM0E4NTJBM0U</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Healthcare Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NkUxMkVDQjJDOEY5NDVDQ0E5NTFEMTlDMjIwNzVERjc7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6REIzOUJERjYzNEE1NEI2QUFENjZDQTBERkIzNTk0RjY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NjM2NTg4ODQ2MEU0NENDOUE4NzlDN0E2QjM5MjJFQjg</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MTE1QUJDMEU3QTA4NDJGN0I0NkFFQjdEMTg2NEI1RDI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QzA5NjIyOEJGMkZDNEUwMUJFODFENUUxRTQxOUY5NDg</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Labor &amp; Employment Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MTE3QUQwOTA0MUYzNDlCMEFFMjUwRUNDM0RDRkM5QzM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Definition of Employees</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QUIyNDcxQkExREQ4NDBEMkE1MkRERTE3QkI2RTkzNEY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6M0Y4OTVEMTE3QTc3NDI5QTkwMjMwMkRBNjRBMUM2NkM</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Invasion of Privacy</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDg2RkJDNTA4NjM2NEQwNEE3RDU4MEU0RUZBNDI5NjY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6M0YxREQzODhGODFBNDUyODkzQ0Y1NTk1M0ExMUUxRkQ</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Public Health &amp; Welfare Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDYwRTY1MDg3MTk5NDUyNkFFRDI1RjJBRERGQ0UxNzI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RjM3NDdEQTcwRDVENDFENEI4QUJFMzQ5NzVGMTE1RDA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6REY3QUUxQ0YxMDFENEE3MTg3QTU4QTdBNkRGMEVCMDc</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></metadata></legislativeDoc>