<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#958#0000000062#0000000001#     44.15#0000000027#">Va. Code Ann. § 62.1-44.15:27</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><note><bodyText><p>This section has more than one version with varying effective dates.  To view a complete list of the versions of this section see Table of Contents.</p></bodyText></note><anchor id="_62.1-44.15_27"/><heading><desig>§ 62.1-44.15:27.</desig><title>(For effective date -- see notes) Virginia Programs for Erosion Control and Stormwater Management</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a"/><heading><desig>A.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Any locality that operates a regulated MS4 or that administers a Virginia Stormwater Management Program (VSMP) as of July 1, 2017, shall be required to adopt and administer a VESMP consistent with the provisions of this article that regulates any land-disturbing activity that (i) disturbs 10,000 square feet or more or (ii) disturbs 2,500 square feet or more in an area of a locality designated as a Chesapeake Bay Preservation Area pursuant to the Chesapeake Bay Preservation Act (<citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 62.1-44.15:67"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 62.1-44.15:67">§ 62.1-44.15:67<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#958#0000000062#0000000001#     44.15#0000000067#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> et seq.). The VESMP shall be adopted according to a process established by the Department.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b"/><heading><desig>B.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Any locality that does not operate a regulated MS4 and for which the Department administers a VSMP as of July 1, 2017, shall choose one of the following options and shall notify the Department of its choice according to a process established by the Department:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Adopt and administer a VESMP consistent with the provisions of this article that regulates any land-disturbing activity that (i) disturbs 10,000 square feet or more or (ii) disturbs 2,500 square feet or more in an area of a locality designated as a Chesapeake Bay Preservation Area pursuant to the Chesapeake Bay Preservation Act (<citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 62.1-44.15:67"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 62.1-44.15:67">§ 62.1-44.15:67<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#958#0000000062#0000000001#     44.15#0000000067#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> et seq.);</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Adopt and administer a VESMP consistent with the provisions of this article that regulates any land-disturbing activity that (i) disturbs 10,000 square feet or more or (ii) disturbs 2,500 square feet or more in an area of a locality designated as a Chesapeake Bay Preservation Area pursuant to the Chesapeake Bay Preservation Act (<citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 62.1-44.15:67"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 62.1-44.15:67">§ 62.1-44.15:67<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#958#0000000062#0000000001#     44.15#0000000067#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> et seq.), except that the Department shall provide the locality with review of the plan required by <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 62.1-44.15:34"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 62.1-44.15:34">§ 62.1-44.15:34<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#958#0000000062#0000000001#     44.15#0000000034#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> and provide a recommendation to the locality on the plan's compliance with the water quality and water quantity technical criteria; or</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Adopt and administer a VESCP pursuant to Article 2.4 (<citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 62.1-44.15:51"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 62.1-44.15:51">§ 62.1-44.15:51<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#958#0000000062#0000000001#     44.15#0000000051#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> et seq.) that regulates any land-disturbing activity that (i) disturbs 10,000 square feet or more or (ii) disturbs 2,500 square feet or more in an area of a locality designated as a Chesapeake Bay Preservation Area pursuant to the Chesapeake Bay Preservation Act (<citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 62.1-44.15:67"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 62.1-44.15:67">§ 62.1-44.15:67<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#958#0000000062#0000000001#     44.15#0000000067#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> et seq.). For such a land-disturbing activity in a Chesapeake Bay Preservation Area, the VESCP authority also shall adopt requirements set forth in this article and attendant regulations as required to regulate those activities in accordance with <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 62.1-44.15:28"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 62.1-44.15:28">§§ 62.1-44.15:28<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#958#0000000062#0000000001#     44.15#0000000028#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> and <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 62.1-44.15:34"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 62.1-44.15:34">62.1-44.15:34.<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#958#0000000062#0000000001#     44.15#0000000034#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation></p><p><pre/>The Board shall administer a VSMP on behalf of each VESCP authority for any land-disturbing activity that (a) disturbs one acre or more of land or (b) disturbs less than one acre of land and is part of a larger common plan of development or sale that results in one acre or greater of land disturbance.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c"/><heading><desig>C.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Any town that is required to or elects to adopt and administer a VESMP or VESCP, as applicable, may choose one of the following options and shall notify the Department of its choice according to a process established by the Department:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Any town, including a town that operates a regulated MS4, lying within a county may enter into an agreement with the county to become subject to the county's VESMP. If a town lies within the boundaries of more than one county, it may enter into an agreement with any of those counties that operates a VESMP.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Any town that chooses not to adopt and administer a VESMP pursuant to subdivision B 3 and that lies within a county may enter into an agreement with the county to become subject to the county's VESMP or VESCP, as applicable. If a town lies within the boundaries of more than one county, it may enter into an agreement with any of those counties.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Any town that is subject to the provisions of the Chesapeake Bay Preservation Act (<citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 62.1-44.15:67"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 62.1-44.15:67">§ 62.1-44.15:67<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#958#0000000062#0000000001#     44.15#0000000067#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> et seq.) may enter into an agreement with a county pursuant to subdivision C 1 or 2 only if the county administers a VESMP for land-disturbing activities that disturb 2,500 square feet or more.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d"/><heading><desig>D.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Any locality that chooses not to implement a VESMP pursuant to subdivision B 3 may notify the Department at any time that it has chosen to implement a VESMP pursuant to subdivision B 1 or 2. Any locality that chooses to implement a VESMP pursuant to subdivision B 2 may notify the Department at any time that it has chosen to implement a VESMP pursuant to subdivision B 1. A locality may petition the Board at any time for approval to change from fully administering a VESMP pursuant to subdivision B 1 to administering a VESMP in coordination with the Department pursuant to subdivision B 2 due to a significant change in economic conditions or other fiscal emergency in the locality. The provisions of the Administrative Process Act (<citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 2.2-4000"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 2.2-4000">§ 2.2-4000<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000002#     2#         4000#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> et seq.) shall govern any appeal of the Board's decision.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_e"/><heading><desig>E.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> In support of VESMP authorities, the Department shall provide technical assistance and training and general assistance to localities in the establishment and administration of their individual or regional programs.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_f"/><heading><desig>F.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The Department shall develop a model ordinance for establishing a VESMP consistent with this article.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_g"/><heading><desig>G.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Each locality that operates a regulated MS4 or that chooses to administer a VESMP shall, by ordinance, establish a VESMP that shall be administered in conjunction with a local MS4 management program, if applicable, and which shall include the following:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_g_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Ordinances, policies, and technical materials consistent with regulations adopted in accordance with this article;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_g_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Requirements for land-disturbance approvals;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_g_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Requirements for plan review, inspection, and enforcement consistent with the requirements of this article, including provisions requiring periodic inspections of the installation of stormwater management measures. A VESMP authority may require monitoring and reports from the person responsible for meeting the permit conditions to ensure compliance with the permit and to determine whether the measures required in the permit provide effective stormwater management;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_g_4"/><heading><desig>4.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Provisions charging each applicant a reasonable fee to defray the cost of program administration for a regulated land-disturbing activity that does not require permit coverage. Such fee may be in addition to any fee charged pursuant to the statewide fee schedule established in accordance with subdivision 9 of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 62.1-44.15:28"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 62.1-44.15:28">§ 62.1-44.15:28<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#958#0000000062#0000000001#     44.15#0000000028#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, although payment of fees may be consolidated in order to provide greater convenience and efficiency for those responsible for compliance with the program. A VESMP authority shall hold a public hearing prior to establishing such fees. The fee shall not exceed an amount commensurate with the services rendered, taking into consideration the time, skill, and the VESMP authority's expense involved;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_g_5"/><heading><desig>5.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Provisions for long-term responsibility for and maintenance of stormwater management control devices and other techniques specified to manage the quality and quantity of runoff; and</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_g_6"/><heading><desig>6.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Provisions for the coordination of the VESMP with flood insurance, flood plain management, and other programs requiring compliance prior to authorizing land disturbance in order to make the submission and approval of plans, issuance of land-disturbance approvals, payment of fees, and coordination of inspection and enforcement activities more convenient and efficient both for the local governments and those responsible for compliance with the programs.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_h"/><heading><desig>H.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The Board shall approve a VESMP when it deems a program consistent with this article and associated regulations.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_i"/><heading><desig>I.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A VESMP authority may enter into agreements or contracts with the Department, soil and water conservation districts, adjacent localities, planning district commissions, or other public or private entities to carry out or assist with plan review and inspections.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_j"/><heading><desig>J.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A VESMP authority shall be required to obtain evidence of permit coverage from the Department's online reporting system, where such coverage is required, prior to providing land-disturbance approval.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_k"/><heading><desig>K.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The VESMP authority responsible for regulating the land-disturbing activity shall require compliance with its applicable ordinances and the conditions of its land-disturbance approval and plan specifications. The Board shall enforce permits and require compliance with its applicable regulations, including when serving as a VSMP authority in a locality that chose not to adopt a VESMP in accordance with subdivision B 3.</p></bodyText></level><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p><citation normalizedCite="1989 VA CH 467"><content><span normalizedCite="1989 Va. Ch. 467">1989, cc. 467<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1989#000467#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1989 VA CH 499"><content><span normalizedCite="1989 Va. Ch. 499">499<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1989#000499#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, § 10.1-603.3; <citation normalizedCite="2004 VA CH 372"><content><span normalizedCite="2004 Va. Ch. 372">2004, c. 372<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2004#000372#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2006 VA CH 171"><content><span normalizedCite="2006 Va. Ch. 171">2006, c. 171<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2006#000171#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2009 VA CH 18"><content><span normalizedCite="2009 Va. Ch. 18">2009, c. 18<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2009#000018#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2012 VA CH 785"><content><span normalizedCite="2012 Va. Ch. 785">2012, cc. 785<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2012#000785#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2012 VA CH 819"><content><span normalizedCite="2012 Va. Ch. 819">819<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2012#000819#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2013 VA CH 756"><content><span normalizedCite="2013 Va. Ch. 756">2013, cc. 756<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2013#000756#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2013 VA CH 793"><content><span normalizedCite="2013 Va. Ch. 793">793<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2013#000793#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2014 VA CH 303"><content><span normalizedCite="2014 Va. Ch. 303">2014, cc. 303<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2014#000303#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2014 VA CH 598"><content><span normalizedCite="2014 Va. Ch. 598">598<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2014#000598#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2016 VA CH 68"><content><span normalizedCite="2016 Va. Ch. 68">2016, cc. 68<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2016#000068#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2016 VA CH 758"><content><span normalizedCite="2016 Va. Ch. 758">758<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2016#000758#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PWF0-004G-K4BV-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 62.1.</desig><title>WATERS OF THE STATE, PORTS AND HARBORS</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 3.1.</desig><title>STATE WATER CONTROL LAW</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="article"><heading><desig>ARTICLE 2.3.</desig><title>STORMWATER MANAGEMENT ACT</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Governments</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjdEQjE4OUJDMzQxNDNEMEI0RTI1QUFCMzJENjEwRTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUYzRDgzNzg0MTBGNEYyN0FFMzFCRTY5MjA1MTc2Q0Q7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MEY3NUIxODI2RjU2NEY0NzgwMDQyNjFDMEQ1QUExRjM</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Insurance Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDM4MzQ2QUYzMTY0NDQzQTkxRDQwRUUzRUM5RDg0OEM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Flood Insurance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RkFFNEQyNDE4NUI1NEIwRDk5NTVFRkU2M0VBNkJGNjU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDBDODI0OTUzNzQzNDA0MkExMkFBOTQ4NzcyREM1RjQ</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MTFDNEI4Q0Y0MTk0NDgyRTkzOEY5NDY2ODM1MkJFRUY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QzZFRUM3RDQ3M0Y1NDc1RUE2N0E4M0ZGQjY0MDk1MTY</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Real Property Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QUUyRTcxRURBNEY2NEE2MDk3QzBCNzRDOEY0NTZDQzk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NzIxOUEwNTk5MTZCNEM3ODgxNjAzMkQ3MzIxMzQ1OUE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Nzg5NTlBMjdCREU3NDE1OTg1QjFCODExQkZENkM1Nzk</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification><classificationGroup classificationScheme="indexing-terms"><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem score="90"><className>Admiralty &amp; Maritime</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QzRDNDVDOTdGRUQ1NDE1M0I1RjRBRDFBRTI3ODFGMDk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem score="90"><className>Transportation</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RTYzRTk5RDVBQkQ2NDcwQzk2NTU3ODQ5OEE3NDlBNzk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></classificationGroup></metadata></legislativeDoc>