<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#349#000051#     1#        142.2#">Va. Code Ann. § 51.1-142.2</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><note><bodyText><p>This section has more than one version with varying effective dates.  To view a complete list of the versions of this section see Table of Contents.</p></bodyText></note><anchor id="_51.1-142.2"/><heading><desig>§ 51.1-142.2.</desig><title>(Effective January 1, 2017) Prior service or membership credit for certain members; service credit for accumulated sick leave</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><bodyText><p>Certain members may purchase credit for service as provided in this section.</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a"/><heading><desig>A.</desig></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Any member in service may purchase service credit from the following categories of service or leave: (i) leave of absence for educational purposes that was previously approved by the member's employer; (ii) leave of absence for a serious health condition of the member or of an immediate family member, all as defined in the Family and Medical Leave Act of 1993, <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="29 USC 2601"><content><span normalizedCite="29 U.S.C. 2601">29 U.S.C. § 2601<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1828#123#000029#       2601#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> et seq., as amended, and previously certified by the member's employer; (iii) up to one year of service credit per occurrence of leave for any unpaid leave of absence due to the birth, adoption, or death of a qualifying child, as defined in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 51.1-500"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 51.1-500">§ 51.1-500<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000051#     1#          500#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; (iv) service as a full-time employee of another state, a public school system of another state, or a political subdivision of the Commonwealth or another state, as certified by such state, public school system, or political subdivision; (v) full-time service of a political subdivision of this state not credited to the member under an agreement as provided for in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 51.1-143.1"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 51.1-143.1">§ 51.1-143.1<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000051#     1#        143.1#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, as certified by such political subdivision; (vi) civilian service of the United States; (vii) full-time service at a private institution of higher education if the private institution is merged with a public institution of higher education and graduates of the private institution are then issued new degrees from the public institution; or (viii) any period of time when the member was employed part time or in a wage position by a participating employer and not otherwise eligible to participate in the retirement system because the member was not an employee as defined in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 51.1-124.3"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 51.1-124.3">§ 51.1-124.3.<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000051#     1#        124.3#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> However, no member in service shall be allowed to purchase more than a total of four years of service credit pursuant to this subdivision.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> In addition to the service credit that may be purchased under subdivision 1, any member in service may purchase up to four years of service credit for prior active duty military service in the armed forces of the United States, provided that the discharge from a period of active duty status with the armed forces was not dishonorable.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The service credit to be credited to a member under this subsection shall be calculated at the ratio of one year, or portion thereof, of service credit to one year, or portion thereof, of service purchased, except for employment service purchased under clause (viii) of subdivision 1, which shall be calculated at the ratio of one month of service credit for each 173 hours of service as certified by the employer.</p><p><pre/>For each year or portion thereof to be credited at the time of purchase under this subsection, the member shall pay the approximate normal cost of the retirement plan under which the member is covered at the time of such purchase, as determined by the Board in its sole discretion. If the member does not purchase, or enter into a purchase of service credit contract for, the service made available in this subsection within the first 24 months of the member's active service following his first date of hire or the final day of any applicable leave of absence, as applicable, then, for each year or portion thereof to be credited at the time of purchase, the member shall pay the actuarial equivalent cost. To the extent the member becomes inactive during the 24 months following his first date of hire or the final day of any applicable leave of absence, such periods shall not be included in the 24 months of active service.</p><p><pre/>Except as otherwise required by Chapter 1223 of Title 10 of the United States Code, as amended, no service credit may be purchased under this section if it is included in the calculation of any retirement allowance received or to be received by the member from this or another retirement system, or if there is a balance in a defined contribution account that serves as a primary retirement account related to such service.</p><p><pre/>For purposes of this subsection, "active duty military service" means full-time service of at least 180 consecutive days in the United States Army, Navy, Air Force, Marines, Coast Guard, or reserve components thereof.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b"/><heading><desig>B.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Any member in service may purchase all prior service credit for creditable service lost from ceasing to be a member under this chapter, as provided in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 51.1-128"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 51.1-128">§ 51.1-128<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000051#     1#          128#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, because of the withdrawal of his accumulated contributions. For each year or portion thereof to be credited at the time of purchase under this subsection, the member shall pay the withdrawn amount to be purchased plus interest accrued daily and compounded annually from the date of withdrawal to the date of payment at the assumed rate of return established by the Board for the actuarial valuation of the retirement system that is in effect at the time of the purchase. The Board shall develop guidelines and procedures for administering this subsection.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c"/><heading><desig>C.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Any member in service may purchase service credit for accumulated sick leave on his effective date of retirement based upon such sums as the employer may provide as payment for any unused sick leave balances. The cost of service credit purchased under this subsection shall be the actuarial equivalent cost of such service.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d"/><heading><desig>D.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Any member receiving benefits under the Virginia Workers' Compensation Act (<citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 65.2-100"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 65.2-100">§ 65.2-100<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000065#     2#          100#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> et seq.) may, in a manner prescribed by the Board and prior to the effective date of retirement, purchase service that is not reported to the retirement system by the member's employer while the member is receiving such benefits.</p><p><pre/>For each year or portion thereof to be credited at the time of purchase under this subsection, the member shall pay the approximate normal cost of the retirement plan under which the member is covered, as determined by the Board in its sole discretion. If the member does not purchase, or enter into a purchase of service credit contract for, any service made available in this subsection within the first 24 months of the member's active service following his first date of hire or the final day of any applicable leave of absence, then, for each year or portion thereof to be credited at the time of purchase, the member shall pay the actuarial equivalent cost. To the extent the member becomes inactive during the 24 months following his first date of hire or the final day of any applicable leave of absence, such periods shall not be included in the 24 months of active service.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_e"/><heading><desig>E.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Payment may be made in a lump sum at the time of purchase or by payroll deduction. Any number of additional deductions may be permitted at any time. Should any deduction be terminated before the member purchases the entire period contracted for, the member shall be credited with the number of full or partial months of service for which full payment has been made. If any deduction is continued after the entire period has been purchased, the member shall be credited with no more than the amount of service for which he was eligible and for which he paid, and the excess amount deducted shall be refunded to the member.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_f"/><heading><desig>F.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Any employer may elect to pay an equivalent amount in lieu of all member contributions required of its employees for the purchase of service credit pursuant to this section. These contributions shall not be considered wages for purposes of Chapter 7 (<citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 51.1-700"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 51.1-700">§ 51.1-700<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000051#     1#          700#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> et seq.), nor shall they be considered salary for purposes of this chapter.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_g"/><heading><desig>G.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> In any case where member and employer contributions, as required under this chapter, were not made because of an error in the payroll, personnel, or other classification system of an employer participating in the retirement system, service that has not been credited because of such error may be purchased on the following basis:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_g_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The most recent three years of service credit shall be purchased, using applicable member and employer contribution rates and creditable compensation in effect for such period, in a manner and at the cost prescribed by the Board; and</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_g_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> All other years of service credit shall be purchased by the employer at an actuarial equivalent cost.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_h"/><heading><desig>H.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Any member may receive credit at no cost for service rendered in the armed forces of the United States provided (i) the member was on leave of absence from a covered position, (ii) the discharge from a period of active duty with the armed forces was not dishonorable, (iii) the member has not withdrawn his accumulated contributions, (iv) the member is not disabled or killed while on leave without pay while performing active duty military service in the armed forces of the United States, and (v) the member reenters service in a covered position within one year after discharge from the armed forces. In order to receive such service, the member must complete such forms and other requirements as are required by the Board and the retirement system.</p></bodyText></level></level><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p><citation normalizedCite="2001 VA CH 686"><content><span normalizedCite="2001 Va. Ch. 686">2001, cc. 686<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2001#000686#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2001 VA CH 697"><content><span normalizedCite="2001 Va. Ch. 697">697<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2001#000697#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2003 VA CH 7"><content><span normalizedCite="2003 Va. Ch. 7">2003, c. 7<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2003#000007#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2005 VA CH 292"><content><span normalizedCite="2005 Va. Ch. 292">2005, c. 292<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2005#000292#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2006 VA CH 635"><content><span normalizedCite="2006 Va. Ch. 635">2006, c. 635<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2006#000635#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2007 VA CH 89"><content><span normalizedCite="2007 Va. Ch. 89">2007, c. 89<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2007#000089#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2008 VA CH 27"><content><span normalizedCite="2008 Va. Ch. 27">2008, c. 27<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2008#000027#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2009 VA CH 362"><content><span normalizedCite="2009 Va. Ch. 362">2009, c. 362<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2009#000362#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2010 VA CH 737"><content><span normalizedCite="2010 Va. Ch. 737">2010, cc. 737<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2010#000737#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2010 VA CH 738"><content><span normalizedCite="2010 Va. Ch. 738">738<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2010#000738#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2011 VA CH 722"><content><span normalizedCite="2011 Va. Ch. 722">2011, cc. 722<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2011#000722#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2011 VA CH 880"><content><span normalizedCite="2011 Va. Ch. 880">880<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2011#000880#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2012 VA CH 696"><content><span normalizedCite="2012 Va. Ch. 696">2012, cc. 696<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2012#000696#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2012 VA CH 701"><content><span normalizedCite="2012 Va. Ch. 701">701<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2012#000701#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2012 VA CH 823"><content><span normalizedCite="2012 Va. Ch. 823">823<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2012#000823#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2014 VA CH 356"><content><span normalizedCite="2014 Va. Ch. 356">2014, c. 356<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2014#000356#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2015 VA CH 508"><content><span normalizedCite="2015 Va. Ch. 508">2015, cc. 508<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2015#000508#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2015 VA CH 536"><content><span normalizedCite="2015 Va. Ch. 536">536<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2015#000536#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2016 VA CH 263"><content><span normalizedCite="2016 Va. Ch. 263">2016, cc. 263<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2016#000263#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2016 VA CH 280"><content><span normalizedCite="2016 Va. Ch. 280">280<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2016#000280#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PWC0-004G-K2XH-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 51.1.</desig><title>PENSIONS, BENEFITS, AND RETIREMENT</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 1.</desig><title>VIRGINIA RETIREMENT SYSTEM</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="article"><heading><desig>ARTICLE 6.</desig><title>CREDITABLE SERVICE</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Labor &amp; Employment Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MTE3QUQwOTA0MUYzNDlCMEFFMjUwRUNDM0RDRkM5QzM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Adoption &amp; Childbirth</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NzM3NzI0MDZFRDkyNDMyREEzQUYyMzYxNzQxNDgyRUQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6ODA4MzIzNkZCQ0EyNEQyOEIzQzFCMDgxMEEzREYxRDk</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Covered Employees</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDhFQzU3RUQzQTNBNDI4ODhGNzdBOUVDMDY5RTlEMDU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NThBRTg0RUYwNTUyNEU3NzkxM0Q4ODcyNzFBMTE1Njk</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Definition of Employees</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QUIyNDcxQkExREQ4NDBEMkE1MkRERTE3QkI2RTkzNEY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6M0Y4OTVEMTE3QTc3NDI5QTkwMjMwMkRBNjRBMUM2NkM</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6N0FCMzAwOUNDQTE2NEJDMTlDNTE0M0JEQkVCOEZFNUU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NThBRTg0RUYwNTUyNEU3NzkxM0Q4ODcyNzFBMTE1Njk</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Serious Health Conditions</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDREMzk4RjVDQTU2NDE4ODhDM0NERDhCQ0Q5Njg4MTk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NThBRTg0RUYwNTUyNEU3NzkxM0Q4ODcyNzFBMTE1Njk</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Military &amp; Veterans Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NzM1OUEyRDNERTdENEU2MTk3RTlCNEJCRUY0NjRGRjQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Active Duty</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NkRFRTlCMkQxNzE4NDAzQThBRDMzNTJGOEVFRTVDRjI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RDE3QjNGOTc4Mzc2NDNDMjg0RDE5ODIzMkMwM0Y1Qzk</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Retirement</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OEM1RjAxMkU1OUE1NDI3MUI3RDAxQ0IwMzhGNTREMjU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RDE3QjNGOTc4Mzc2NDNDMjg0RDE5ODIzMkMwM0Y1Qzk</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification><classificationGroup classificationScheme="indexing-terms"><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem score="90"><className>Pensions &amp; Benefits</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QzNEOEE3NjhDNTJBNDhCOTgxRkQzNzc1Q0JCMkU4Q0I7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></classificationGroup></metadata></legislativeDoc>