<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#349#000045#     1#       161.64#">Va. Code Ann. § 45.1-161.64</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_45.1-161.64"/><heading><desig>§ 45.1-161.64.</desig><title>Maps of mines required to be made; contents; extension and preservation; use by Department; release; posting of map</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a"/><heading><desig>A.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Prior to commencing mining activity, the operator of a coal mine, or his agent, shall make, or cause to be made, unless already made and filed, an accurate map of such mine. Such map shall be submitted to the Chief prior to producing coal at the mine. All maps shall be presented on the Virginia Coordinate System of 1983, South Zone, unless otherwise approved by the Chief. At intervals not to exceed 12 months and when a coal mine is abandoned, the operator shall submit to the Chief copies of an up-to-date map of the entire mine in an electronic format approved by the Chief. The operator shall also submit to the Chief revisions that show directional changes whenever mine projections deviate more than 600 feet from the approved mine map. Only maps in an electronic format will be accepted unless otherwise approved by the Chief. If there are no changes in the information required to be submitted under this section at the time an updated map is due, the operator may submit a notice that there are no changes to the map in lieu of submitting an updated map to the Department.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b"/><heading><desig>B.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Underground coal mine maps shall show:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The active workings;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> All pillared, worked out, and abandoned areas, except as provided in this section;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Entries and aircourses with the quantity of airflow, direction of airflow indicated by arrows, and ventilation controls;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_4"/><heading><desig>4.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Contour lines of all elevations;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_5"/><heading><desig>5.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Dip of the coalbed;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_6"/><heading><desig>6.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Escapeways;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_7"/><heading><desig>7.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The locations that are known or should be known of (i) adjacent mine workings within 1,000 feet, (ii) mines above or below, and (iii) water pools above;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_8"/><heading><desig>8.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Either producing or abandoned oil and gas wells located within 500 feet of such mine and in any underground area of such mine; and</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_9"/><heading><desig>9.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Such other information as the Chief may require.</p><p><pre/>Such map shall identify those areas of the mine which have been pillared, worked out, or abandoned, which are inaccessible, or cannot be entered safely.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c"/><heading><desig>C.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Additional information required to be shown on underground coal mine maps shall include:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Mine name, company name, mine index number, and name of the person responsible for information on the map;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The scale and orientation of the map and symbols used on the map;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The property or boundary lines of the mine;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c_4"/><heading><desig>4.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> All known drill holes that penetrate the coalbed being mined;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c_5"/><heading><desig>5.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> All shaft, slope, drift, and tunnel openings and auger and strip mined areas of the coalbed being mined;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c_6"/><heading><desig>6.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The location of all surface mine ventilation fans; the location may be designated on the mine map by symbols;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c_7"/><heading><desig>7.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The location of railroad tracks and public highways leading to the mine, and mine buildings of a permanent nature with identifying names shown;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c_8"/><heading><desig>8.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The location and description of a least two permanent base line points coordinated with the underground and surface mine traverses, and the location and description of at least two permanent elevation bench marks used in connection with establishing or referencing mine elevation surveys;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c_9"/><heading><desig>9.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The location and elevation of any body of water dammed or held back in any portion of the mine; provided, however, such bodies of water may be shown on overlays or tracings attached to the mine maps used to show contour lines as provided under subdivision 12;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c_10"/><heading><desig>10.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The elevations of tops and bottoms of shafts and slopes, and the floor at the entrance to drift and tunnel openings;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c_11"/><heading><desig>11.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The elevation of the floor at intervals of not more than 200 feet in (i) at least one entry of each working section and main and cross entries; (ii) the last line of open crosscuts of each working section, and main and cross entries before such sections and main and cross entries that are abandoned; and (iii) rooms advancing toward or adjacent to property or boundary lines or adjacent mines; and</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c_12"/><heading><desig>12.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Contour lines passing through whole number elevations of the coalbed being mined. The spacing of such lines shall not exceed 10-foot elevation levels, except that a broader spacing of contour lines may be approved by the Chief for steeply-pitching coalbeds. Contour lines may be placed on overlays or tracings attached to mine maps.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d"/><heading><desig>D.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Underground coal mine maps submitted to the Chief shall be on a scale of not less than 100 or more than 500 feet to the inch. Mapping of the underground mine works shall be completed by a closed loop survey method of traversing or other equally accurate methods of traversing. All closed loop surveys shall meet a minimum accuracy standard of one part in 5,000. Elevations shall be tied to either the United States Geological Survey or the United States Coast and Geodetic Survey benchmark system. A registered engineer or licensed land surveyor shall certify that the map of the mine workings is accurate.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_e"/><heading><desig>E.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Underground coal mine maps shall be kept up-to-date by temporary notations and revised and supplemented at intervals not to exceed six months based on a survey made and certified by a registered engineer or licensed land surveyor who has exercised complete direction and control over the work to which it is affixed. Temporary notations shall include:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_e_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The location of each working face of each working place;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_e_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Pillars mined or other such second mining;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_e_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Permanent ventilation controls constructed or removed, such as seals, overcasts, undercasts, regulators, and permanent stoppings, and the direction of air currents indicated; and</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_e_4"/><heading><desig>4.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Escapeways designated by means of symbols.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_f"/><heading><desig>F.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> At underground coal mines, an accurate map of the mine showing clearly all avenues of ingress and egress in case of fire shall be posted in a place accessible to all miners.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_g"/><heading><desig>G.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Surface coal mine maps shall show:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_g_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Name and address of the mine;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_g_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The property or boundary lines of the active areas of the mine;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_g_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Contour lines passing through whole number elevations of the coalbed being mined. The spacing of such lines shall not exceed 25-foot elevation levels, except that a broader spacing of contour lines may be approved by the Chief for steeply pitching coalbeds. The Chief may approve alternate means of delineating seam elevations where multiple seams are being mined. Contour lines may be placed on overlays or tracings attached to mine maps;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_g_4"/><heading><desig>4.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The general elevation of the coalbed or coalbeds being mined, and the general elevation of the surface;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_g_5"/><heading><desig>5.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Either producing or abandoned oil and gas wells and gas transmission lines located on the mine property;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_g_6"/><heading><desig>6.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The location and elevation of any body of water dammed or held back in any portion of the mine: provided, however, such bodies of water may be shown on overlays or tracings attached to the mine maps;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_g_7"/><heading><desig>7.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> All prospect drill holes that penetrate the coalbed or coalbeds being mined on the mine property;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_g_8"/><heading><desig>8.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> All auger and surface mined areas of the coalbed or coalbeds being mined on the mine property together with the line of maximum depth of holes drilled during auger mining operations;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_g_9"/><heading><desig>9.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> All worked out and abandoned areas;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_g_10"/><heading><desig>10.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The location of railroad tracks and public highways leading to the mine, and mine buildings of a permanent nature with identifying names shown;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_g_11"/><heading><desig>11.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Underground mine workings underlying and within 1,000 feet of the active areas of the mine;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_g_12"/><heading><desig>12.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The location and description of at least two permanent baseline points, and the location and description of at least two permanent elevation bench marks used in connection with establishing or referencing mine elevation surveys;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_g_13"/><heading><desig>13.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The scale of the map; and</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_g_14"/><heading><desig>14.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Such other information required by the Chief.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_h"/><heading><desig>H.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Surface coal mine maps shall be kept up to date by temporary notations and revised and supplemented at intervals not to exceed six months based on a survey made and certified by a registered engineer or licensed land surveyor who has exercised complete direction and control over the work to which it is affixed. Temporary notations shall include:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_h_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The location of each working pit or pits;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_h_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Auger or highwall miner workings; and</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_h_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Other information that may affect the safety of miners including, but not limited to, updates of gas well or gas line locations.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_i"/><heading><desig>I.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Surface surveys shall originate from at least two permanent survey monuments on the mine property located with a minimum accuracy standard of one part in 10,000. The monuments shall be clearly referenced on the mine map. Elevations shall be tied to either the United States Geological Survey or the United States Coast and Geodetic benchmark system.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_j"/><heading><desig>J.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The original map, or a true copy thereof, shall be left by the operator at the active mine, open at all reasonable times for the examinations and use of the mine inspector.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_k"/><heading><desig>K.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Such maps may be used by the Department for the evaluation of the coal resources of the Commonwealth.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_l"/><heading><desig>L.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The map shall be filed and preserved among the records of the Department and copies of such maps shall be made available at a reasonable cost.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_m"/><heading><desig>M.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Any person who has conducted mining operations or prepared mine maps and who has a map or surveying data of any worked out or abandoned underground coal mine shall on request make such map or data available to the Department to copy or reproduce such material.</p></bodyText></level><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p>Code 1950, § 45-10; 1954, c. 191; 1966, c. 594, §§ 45.1-27, 45.1-91; 1978, c. 118; 1980, c. 5; 1984, c. 590; 1986, c. 222; <citation normalizedCite="1994 VA CH 28"><content><span normalizedCite="1994 Va. Ch. 28">1994, c. 28<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1994#000028#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1995 VA CH 265"><content><span normalizedCite="1995 Va. Ch. 265">1995, c. 265<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1995#000265#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1996 VA CH 774"><content><span normalizedCite="1996 Va. Ch. 774">1996, c. 774<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1996#000774#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1997 VA CH 390"><content><span normalizedCite="1997 Va. Ch. 390">1997, c. 390<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1997#000390#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1999 VA CH 256"><content><span normalizedCite="1999 Va. Ch. 256">1999, c. 256<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1999#000256#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2005 VA CH 3"><content><span normalizedCite="2005 Va. Ch. 3">2005, c. 3<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2005#000003#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2007 VA CH 894"><content><span normalizedCite="2007 Va. Ch. 894">2007, cc. 894<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2007#000894#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2007 VA CH 914"><content><span normalizedCite="2007 Va. Ch. 914">914<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2007#000914#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2011 VA CH 826"><content><span normalizedCite="2011 Va. Ch. 826">2011, cc. 826<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2011#000826#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2011 VA CH 862"><content><span normalizedCite="2011 Va. Ch. 862">862<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2011#000862#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2012 VA CH 109"><content><span normalizedCite="2012 Va. Ch. 109">2012, cc. 109<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2012#000109#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2012 VA CH 241"><content><span normalizedCite="2012 Va. Ch. 241">241<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2012#000241#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PT70-004G-K0VY-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 45.1.</desig><title>MINES AND MINING</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 14.2.</desig><title>COAL MINE SAFETY ACT</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="article"><heading><desig>ARTICLE 5.</desig><title>LICENSING OF MINES</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Abandonment of Lines</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RjQ4N0UxNjM1MkU4NEEyNzgyMjMzRjU1NTc3ODFGRTE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NjVENDlFMjM1NURFNEQwREI3MkRDMDE0RjQxMDUxMDQ</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Mining Regulations</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MEM1NjlGMUIyQzkwNDg0MUEwRjUyMUI1RDg3MzM2REU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QUUyRTcxRURBNEY2NEE2MDk3QzBCNzRDOEY0NTZDQzk</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Energy &amp; Utilities Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OUUzODAyRDk1QzVFNEZGMEJDM0RGMDYxOTlEMEEzRDA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QTU2OEY2MjlCMTQ4NEI1MTkwOEU5RUYyMTcxMDUzRUQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NkEyREE0NkU0MUQwNDhFQ0I0RTdBN0FCN0U2QzhDMTI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Real Property Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QUUyRTcxRURBNEY2NEE2MDk3QzBCNzRDOEY0NTZDQzk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NzA1QzAyRkNGMzA5NDQ2Q0JEQkUxNTc3REFDRDg2Njk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjlCOEFBQzRBMkRDNERFMkIyQ0YzQUQ0ODFGQjQ3QzI</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Location</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NjkwOEMzNEE0M0YzNEMxRDhBQTg1MkVFNzBBNUIzN0Q7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjlCOEFBQzRBMkRDNERFMkIyQ0YzQUQ0ODFGQjQ3QzI</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Mines &amp; Mining</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Q0UxNEY2N0JGRjY4NEUzQzg4QjE5NDEwOEE3NTJCQUI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6M0FCNDYzRTQzRTAyNDUzREIzNjBCNkRDMEVERUZCMzg</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Regulations</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MEM1NjlGMUIyQzkwNDg0MUEwRjUyMUI1RDg3MzM2REU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjlCOEFBQzRBMkRDNERFMkIyQ0YzQUQ0ODFGQjQ3QzI</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Surface Rights</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MTAzOUU2OENCRTk0NDQ3Mzk2NUMyNUQzN0U4QTNGOTU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjlCOEFBQzRBMkRDNERFMkIyQ0YzQUQ0ODFGQjQ3QzI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Transportation Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RTYzRTk5RDVBQkQ2NDcwQzk2NTU3ODQ5OEE3NDlBNzk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Abandonment of Lines</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RjQ4N0UxNjM1MkU4NEEyNzgyMjMzRjU1NTc3ODFGRTE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NjVENDlFMjM1NURFNEQwREI3MkRDMDE0RjQxMDUxMDQ</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Flight Crews</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MTUxODMzNDg0QkJCNDA5RTlDMzk0RjNDMTY4RTU0NjI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDc0QkUxRjIwOENFNDFFM0IyRjk2QzZCRjNCMjkwODU</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification><classificationGroup classificationScheme="indexing-terms"><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem score="90"><className>Energy &amp; Utilities</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OUUzODAyRDk1QzVFNEZGMEJDM0RGMDYxOTlEMEEzRDA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></classificationGroup></metadata></legislativeDoc>