<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#349#000002#     2#         5408#">Va. Code Ann. § 2.2-5408</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_2.2-5408"/><heading><desig>§ 2.2-5408.</desig><title>Administration of community action budget</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><bodyText><p>The designated agency shall adopt regulations detailing the formula for the distribution of community action program budget funds. The regulations shall take into consideration the distribution of low-income persons residing in the service areas of the community action agencies, the relative cost of living of the areas, as well as other factors considered appropriate.</p><p>Each community action agency and community action statewide organization annually shall develop and submit a program budget request for funds appropriated from the community action program budget. The designated agency shall publish annually guidelines detailing the nature and extent of information required in the program budget request for the succeeding fiscal year.</p><p>In order to carry out its overall responsibility for planning, coordinating, evaluating and administering a community action program, a community action agency may under its charter or applicable laws receive and administer funds pursuant to this chapter. The community action agency may receive and administer funds and contributions from private or public sources that may be used in support of a community action agency or program and funds under any federal or state assistance program pursuant to which a public or private nonprofit agency organized in accordance with this chapter could act as grantee, contractor or sponsor of projects appropriate for inclusion in a community action program. A community action agency or community action statewide organization may transfer funds so received between components and to delegate funds to other agencies subject to the powers of its governing board and its overall program responsibilities.</p><p>In accordance with the requirements of the federal Omnibus Budget Reconciliation Act of 1981 (Public Law 97-35), the designated agency in cooperation with community action agencies and community action statewide organizations, shall develop a state plan for submission annually by the Governor to the Secretary of Health and Human Services.</p><p>Community action agencies and community action statewide organizations shall provide the designated agency with quarterly financial and program reports.</p><p>Funds received in the Community Services Block Grant pursuant to the federal Omnibus Budget Reconciliation Act of 1981 (Public Law 97-35) shall be expended in support of the purposes of this chapter as follows:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Ninety percent of the funds received in the Community Services Block Grant shall be used for the development and implementation of programs and projects designed by community action agencies to serve poor or low-income areas of the Commonwealth in accordance with a formula approved by the Governor for the first year of the Community Services Block Grant and thereafter biennially by the General Assembly.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> No more than five percent of the funds received in the Community Services Block Grant shall be used for administration of the duties required by this chapter of the designated agency.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> At least five percent of the funds received in the Community Services Block Grant shall be used to support community action activities conducted by community action statewide organizations.</p></bodyText></level></level><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p>1982, c. 667, § 2.1-598; <citation normalizedCite="2001 VA CH 844"><content><span normalizedCite="2001 Va. Ch. 844">2001, c. 844<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2001#000844#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PV90-004G-K1VC-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 2.2.</desig><title>ADMINISTRATION OF GOVERNMENT</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="subtitle"><heading><desig>SUBTITLE II.</desig><title>ADMINISTRATION OF STATE GOVERNMENT</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="part"><heading><desig>PART B.</desig><title>TRANSACTION OF PUBLIC BUSINESS</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 54.</desig><title>COMMUNITY ACTION ACT</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Administrative Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NjMxMjc0MUIzQjkzNEM4MEI4NkZGQjVCREJCRDk4OUM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NEU2MUI0N0NCM0RDNDNDM0JBRDFFQzRDRDhGNkQwRjE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QkRFNDkwODkxNDVGNDI1NDg0RUU3RjREMTgwNEJEQzA</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Governments</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjdEQjE4OUJDMzQxNDNEMEI0RTI1QUFCMzJENjEwRTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Community Redevelopment</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NUMwM0U5RjhBRkQ1NEQ5Qzk0RDk2QUJDNEU2NTVCQjE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MEY3NUIxODI2RjU2NEY0NzgwMDQyNjFDMEQ1QUExRjM</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification><classificationGroup classificationScheme="indexing-terms"><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem score="90"><className>Governments</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjdEQjE4OUJDMzQxNDNEMEI0RTI1QUFCMzJENjEwRTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></classificationGroup></metadata></legislativeDoc>