<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#349#000046#     2#          694#">Va. Code Ann. § 46.2-694</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><note><bodyText><p>This section has more than one version with varying effective dates.  To view a complete list of the versions of this section see Table of Contents.</p></bodyText></note><anchor id="_46.2-694"/><heading><desig>§ 46.2-694.</desig><title>(Contingent expiration date) Fees for vehicles designed and used for transportation of passengers; weights used for computing fees; burden of proof</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a"/><heading><desig>A.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The annual registration fees for motor vehicles, trailers, and semitrailers designed and used for the transportation of passengers on the highways in the Commonwealth are:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Thirty-three dollars for each private passenger car or motor home if the passenger car or motor home weighs 4,000 pounds or less, provided that it is not used for the transportation of passengers for compensation and is not kept or used for rent or for hire, or is not operated under a lease without a chauffeur; however, the fee provided under this subdivision shall apply to a private passenger car or motor home that weighs 4,000 pounds or less and is used as a TNC partner vehicle as defined in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 46.2-2000"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 46.2-2000">§ 46.2-2000<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000046#     2#         2000#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Thirty-eight dollars for each private passenger car or motor home that weighs more than 4,000 pounds, provided that it is not used for the transportation of passengers for compensation and is not kept or used for rent or for hire, or is not operated under a lease without a chauffeur; however, the fee provided under this subdivision shall apply to a private passenger car or motor home that weighs more than 4,000 pounds and is used as a TNC partner vehicle as defined in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 46.2-2000"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 46.2-2000">§ 46.2-2000<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000046#     2#         2000#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Thirty cents per 100 pounds or major fraction thereof for a private motor vehicle other than a motorcycle with a normal seating capacity of more than 10 adults, including the driver, if the private motor vehicle is not used for the transportation of passengers for compensation and is not kept or used for rent or for hire or is not operated under a lease without a chauffeur. In no case shall the fee be less than $ 23 if the vehicle weighs 4,000 pounds or less or $ 28 if the vehicle weighs more than 4,000 pounds.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_4"/><heading><desig>4.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Thirty cents per 100 pounds or major fraction thereof for a school bus. In no case shall the fee be less than $ 23 if the vehicle weighs 4,000 pounds or less or $ 28 if the vehicle weighs more than 4,000 pounds.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_5"/><heading><desig>5.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Twenty-three dollars for each trailer or semitrailer designed for use as living quarters for human beings.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_6"/><heading><desig>6.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Thirteen dollars plus $ 0.30 per 100 pounds or major fraction thereof for each motor vehicle, trailer, or semitrailer used as a common carrier of passengers, operating either intrastate or interstate. Interstate common carriers of interstate passengers may elect to be licensed and pay the fees prescribed in subdivision 7 on submission to the Commissioner of a declaration of operations and equipment as he may prescribe. An additional $ 5 shall be charged if the motor vehicle weighs more than 4,000 pounds.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_7"/><heading><desig>7.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Thirteen dollars plus $ 0.70 per 100 pounds or major fraction thereof for each motor vehicle, trailer, or semitrailer used as a common carrier of interstate passengers if election is made to be licensed under this subsection. An additional $ 5 shall be charged if the motor vehicle weighs more than 4,000 pounds. In lieu of the foregoing fee of $ 0.70 per 100 pounds, a motor carrier of passengers, operating two or more vehicles both within and outside the Commonwealth and registered for insurance purposes with the Surface Transportation Board of the U.S. Department of Transportation, Federal Highway Administration, may apply to the Commissioner for prorated registration. Upon the filing of such application, in such form as the Commissioner may prescribe, the Commissioner shall apportion the registration fees provided in this subsection so that the total registration fees to be paid for such vehicles of such carrier shall be that proportion of the total fees, if there were no apportionment, that the total number of miles traveled by such vehicles of such carrier within the Commonwealth bears to the total number of miles traveled by such vehicles within and outside the Commonwealth. Such total mileage in each instance is the estimated total mileage to be traveled by such vehicles during the license year for which such fees are paid, subject to the adjustment in accordance with an audit to be made by representatives of the Commissioner at the end of such license year, the expense of such audit to be borne by the carrier being audited. Each vehicle passing into or through Virginia shall be registered and licensed in Virginia and the annual registration fee to be paid for each such vehicle shall not be less than $ 33. For the purpose of determining such apportioned registration fees, only those motor vehicles, trailers, or semitrailers operated both within and outside the Commonwealth shall be subject to inclusion in determining the apportionment provided for herein.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_8"/><heading><desig>8.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Thirteen dollars plus $ 0.80 per 100 pounds or major fraction thereof for each motor vehicle, trailer or semitrailer kept or used for rent or for hire or operated under a lease without a chauffeur for the transportation of passengers. An additional fee of $ 5 shall be charged if the vehicle weighs more than 4,000 pounds. This subdivision does not apply to vehicles used as common carriers or as TNC partner vehicles as defined in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 46.2-2000"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 46.2-2000">§ 46.2-2000<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000046#     2#         2000#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_9"/><heading><desig>9.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Twenty-three dollars for a taxicab or other vehicle which is kept for rent or hire operated with a chauffeur for the transportation of passengers, and which operates or should operate under permits issued by the Department as required by law. An additional fee of $ 5 shall be charged if the vehicle weighs more than 4,000 pounds. This subdivision does not apply to vehicles used as common carriers or as TNC partner vehicles as defined in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 46.2-2000"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 46.2-2000">§ 46.2-2000<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000046#     2#         2000#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_10"/><heading><desig>10.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Eighteen dollars for a motorcycle, with or without a sidecar. To this fee shall be added a surcharge of $ 3 which shall be distributed as provided in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 46.2-1191"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 46.2-1191">§ 46.2-1191<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000046#     2#         1191#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_10a"/><heading><desig>10a.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Fourteen dollars for a moped, to be paid into the state treasury and set aside as a special fund to be used to meet the expenses of the Department.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_10b"/><heading><desig>10b.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Eighteen dollars for an autocycle.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_11"/><heading><desig>11.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Twenty-three dollars for a bus used exclusively for transportation to and from church school, for the purpose of religious instruction, or church, for the purpose of divine worship. If the empty weight of the vehicle exceeds 4,000 pounds, the fee shall be $ 28.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_12"/><heading><desig>12.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Thirteen dollars plus $ 0.70 per 100 pounds or major fraction thereof for other passenger-carrying vehicles.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_13"/><heading><desig>13.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> An additional fee of $ 4.25 per year shall be charged and collected at the time of registration of each pickup or panel truck and each motor vehicle under subdivisions 1 through 12. All funds collected from $ 4 of the $ 4.25 fee shall be paid into the state treasury and shall be set aside as a special fund to be used only for emergency medical services purposes. The moneys in the special emergency medical services fund shall be distributed as follows:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_13_a"/><heading><desig>a.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Two percent shall be distributed to the State Department of Health to provide funding to the Virginia Association of Volunteer Rescue Squads to be used solely for the purpose of conducting volunteer recruitment, retention, and training activities;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_13_b"/><heading><desig>b.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Thirty percent shall be distributed to the State Department of Health to support (i) emergency medical services training programs (excluding advanced life support classes); (ii) advanced life support training; (iii) recruitment and retention programs (all funds for such support shall be used to recruit and retain volunteer emergency medical services personnel only, including public awareness campaigns, technical assistance programs, and similar activities); (iv) emergency medical services system development, initiatives, and priorities based on needs identified by the State Emergency Medical Services Advisory Board; (v) local, regional, and statewide performance contracts for emergency medical services to meet the objectives stipulated in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 32.1-111.3"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 32.1-111.3">§ 32.1-111.3<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000032#     1#        111.3#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; (vi) technology and radio communication enhancements; and (vii) improved emergency preparedness and response. Any funds set aside for distribution under this provision and remaining undistributed at the end of any fiscal year shall revert to the Rescue Squad Assistance Fund;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_13_c"/><heading><desig>c.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Thirty-two percent shall be distributed to the Rescue Squad Assistance Fund;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_13_d"/><heading><desig>d.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Ten percent shall be available to the State Department of Health's Office of Emergency Medical Services for use in emergency medical services; and</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_13_e"/><heading><desig>e.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Twenty-six percent shall be returned by the Comptroller to the locality wherein such vehicle is registered, to provide funding for training of volunteer or salaried emergency medical services personnel of nonprofit emergency medical services agencies that hold a valid license issued by the Commissioner of Health and for the purchase of necessary equipment and supplies for use in such locality for emergency medical services provided by nonprofit emergency medical services agencies that hold a valid license issued by the Commissioner of Health.</p><p><pre/>All revenues generated by the remaining $ 0.25 of the $ 4.25 fee approved by the 2008 Session of the General Assembly shall be deposited into the Rescue Squad Assistance Fund and used only to pay for the costs associated with the certification and recertification training of emergency medical services personnel.</p><p><pre/>The Comptroller shall clearly designate on the warrant, check, or other means of transmitting these funds that such moneys are only to be used for purposes set forth in this subdivision. Such funds shall be in addition to any local appropriations and local governing bodies shall not use these funds to supplant local funds. Each local governing body shall report annually to the Board of Health on the use of the funds returned to it pursuant to this section. In any case in which the local governing body grants the funds to a regional emergency medical services council to be distributed to the nonprofit emergency medical services agency that holds a valid license issued by the Commissioner of Health, the local governing body shall remain responsible for the proper use of the funds. If, at the end of any fiscal year, a report on the use of the funds returned to the locality pursuant to this section for that year has not been received from a local governing body, any funds due to that local governing body for the next fiscal year shall be retained until such time as the report has been submitted to the Board.</p></bodyText></level></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b"/><heading><desig>B.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> All motor vehicles, trailers, and semitrailers registered as provided in subsection B of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 46.2-646"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 46.2-646">§ 46.2-646<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000046#     2#          646#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> shall pay a registration fee equal to one-twelfth of all fees required by subsection A of this section or <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 46.2-697"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 46.2-697">§ 46.2-697<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000046#     2#          697#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> for such motor vehicle, trailer, or semitrailer, computed to the nearest cent, multiplied by the number of months in the registration period for such motor vehicles, trailers, and semitrailers.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c"/><heading><desig>C.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The manufacturer's shipping weight or scale weight shall be used for computing all fees required by this section to be based upon the weight of the vehicle.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d"/><heading><desig>D.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The applicant for registration bears the burden of proof that the vehicle for which registration is sought is entitled by weight, design, and use to be registered at the fee tendered by the applicant to the Commissioner or to his authorized agent.</p></bodyText></level><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p>Code 1950, §§ 46-154 through 46-156, 46-158.1, 46-159, 46-163.1, 46-166.1; 1950, p. 621; 1952, cc. 224, 418; 1956, cc. 132, 597, 705; 1958, c. 541, § 46.1-149; 1960, c. 243; 1964, c. 218; 1972, c. 609; 1974, c. 170; 1978, c. 708; 1980, c. 25; 1982, c. 671; 1983, c. 566; 1984, cc. 476, 545; 1985, c. 333; 1986, Sp. Sess., c. 11; 1988, cc. 701, 704; <citation normalizedCite="1989 VA CH 727"><content><span normalizedCite="1989 Va. Ch. 727">1989, c. 727<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1989#000727#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1990 VA CH 508"><content><span normalizedCite="1990 Va. Ch. 508">1990, c. 508<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1990#000508#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1991 VA CH 472"><content><span normalizedCite="1991 Va. Ch. 472">1991, c. 472<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1991#000472#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1994 VA CH 279"><content><span normalizedCite="1994 Va. Ch. 279">1994, c. 279<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1994#000279#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1997 VA CH 283"><content><span normalizedCite="1997 Va. Ch. 283">1997, c. 283<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1997#000283#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2002 VA CH 794"><content><span normalizedCite="2002 Va. Ch. 794">2002, c. 794<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2002#000794#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2004 VA CH 194"><content><span normalizedCite="2004 Va. Ch. 194">2004, c. 194<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2004#000194#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2005 VA CH 928"><content><span normalizedCite="2005 Va. Ch. 928">2005, c. 928<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2005#000928#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2007 VA CH 896"><content><span normalizedCite="2007 Va. Ch. 896">2007, c. 896<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2007#000896#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2008 VA CH 182"><content><span normalizedCite="2008 Va. Ch. 182">2008, c. 182<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2008#000182#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2013 VA CH 783"><content><span normalizedCite="2013 Va. Ch. 783">2013, c. 783<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2013#000783#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2014 VA CH 53"><content><span normalizedCite="2014 Va. Ch. 53">2014, cc. 53<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2014#000053#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2014 VA CH 256"><content><span normalizedCite="2014 Va. Ch. 256">256<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2014#000256#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2015 VA CH 2"><content><span normalizedCite="2015 Va. Ch. 2">2015, cc. 2<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2015#000002#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2015 VA CH 3"><content><span normalizedCite="2015 Va. Ch. 3">3<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2015#000003#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2015 VA CH 502"><content><span normalizedCite="2015 Va. Ch. 502">502<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2015#000502#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2015 VA CH 503"><content><span normalizedCite="2015 Va. Ch. 503">503<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2015#000503#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PTP0-004G-K27S-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 46.2.</desig><title>MOTOR VEHICLES</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="subtitle"><heading><desig>SUBTITLE II.</desig><title>TITLING, REGISTRATION AND LICENSURE</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 6.</desig><title>TITLING AND REGISTRATION OF MOTOR VEHICLES</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="article"><heading><desig>ARTICLE 7.</desig><title>FEES FOR REGISTRATION</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Licensing &amp; Registration</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NUYwQzU2QTY5NkVBNDBDQUEyOEZGNTA4MDlBNzhCQzU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OTU3NDRDNEM2QUYyNDdGQUE1NEU4NjRGMDRCMUEyNUU</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>US Surface Transportation Board</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QzVDQ0ExQjI1MTdCNDFCMEEyQzdCN0VCOERCRUY2RTk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MkIwQUVGRDJCQTgyNDIyOEE4ODYyMzkzRkEwNzE4MTk</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Contracts Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QzY0RTZFMzE0RjkwNDdFQUI5M0U5N0ZFMjYyREMyQzU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QTdGQUE3QkZDMDlBNDQ1MTkzRjEzMEQ1OEUwNzdDOTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NjZEOEU3MEJBRUQ2NDNFNzhFRjAxRTk1OEU1QjY2QTc</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Education Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDkzNUEzQzFBNEZBNEFBREIxNDM5MTc1MUU5QjI4MTY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NjVGNzlEQjlDOTVDNEExNjlCMUNERkQ5RDBBOEE5NzY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Qjg0MkJDQ0M1M0U4NDhFMDlGQUUxRjFCQzJFN0NGOUU</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Secular Programs</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NTU2NEJEOEVBNjc3NDVGRjg1NTg3NzE4OUNBQjgwOUU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Qjg0MkJDQ0M1M0U4NDhFMDlGQUUxRjFCQzJFN0NGOUU</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Governments</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjdEQjE4OUJDMzQxNDNEMEI0RTI1QUFCMzJENjEwRTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Finance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjMzOTBBRTg2MUVDNDdDNUE1M0QxNDk1RERCNjNCN0I7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Njg1MkM3RkYyNzIxNEVFRkJFMTI2NUM4NUU1ODdEM0Q</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Transportation Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RTYzRTk5RDVBQkQ2NDcwQzk2NTU3ODQ5OEE3NDlBNzk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Definitions</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDNBRUZENTcyQkM0NEZCQjgwNTg2MkUxNEEwQkRGRUM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Rjc3OTVCRDA5M0U3NEM5NTk1MjkxQzk3Qjg5Q0Y3RDk</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Expiration</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDYwRkEzMTcyN0I3NDZBRDk1MkI5NTQzNDE2RUI5MTk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NUE5RTcxOUU3RDczNDlDNjgzMkJCMTQwQTkxQzdFNUU</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Fees &amp; Taxes</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6N0UyRUYyQzg3RjZCNDA0RUEzQjVDNjNCMkFDM0U5NjA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NUE5RTcxOUU3RDczNDlDNjgzMkJCMTQwQTkxQzdFNUU</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjQwNzg3MTkwNEExNEY4MUE5NjVGMjM5NTFCRTk4OTg7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NUE5RTcxOUU3RDczNDlDNjgzMkJCMTQwQTkxQzdFNUU</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Licensing &amp; Registration</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NUYwQzU2QTY5NkVBNDBDQUEyOEZGNTA4MDlBNzhCQzU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OTU3NDRDNEM2QUYyNDdGQUE1NEU4NjRGMDRCMUEyNUU</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Sidecars</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjA2RDJERTU5MEUxNEM5NzlGRjBDNjU2QjMwMjNBMTg7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Rjc3OTVCRDA5M0U3NEM5NTk1MjkxQzk3Qjg5Q0Y3RDk</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>US Surface Transportation Board</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QzVDQ0ExQjI1MTdCNDFCMEEyQzdCN0VCOERCRUY2RTk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MkIwQUVGRDJCQTgyNDIyOEE4ODYyMzkzRkEwNzE4MTk</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification><classificationGroup classificationScheme="indexing-terms"><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem score="90"><className>Transportation</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RTYzRTk5RDVBQkQ2NDcwQzk2NTU3ODQ5OEE3NDlBNzk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></classificationGroup></metadata></legislativeDoc>