<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#123#000030#     19.03#">Va. Code Ann. § 30-19.03</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_30-19.03"/><heading><desig>§ 30-19.03.</desig><title>Estimates to be prepared for legislation affecting local government expenditures and revenues</title></heading><bodyText><p>Whenever any legislative bill requiring a net additional expenditure by any county, city, or town, or whenever any legislative bill requiring a net reduction of revenues by any county, city, or town, is filed during any session of the General Assembly, the Commission on Local Government shall investigate and prepare an estimate setting forth, to the extent practicable, the additional expenditures or reduction of revenues, if any, to be required of the affected localities in event of enactment of such legislation.</p><p>A bill shall be deemed to require an expenditure if it has the effect of requiring any county, city, or town to (i) perform or administer a new or expanded program or service, (ii) maintain an existing program or service at a specified level of spending or delivery, (iii) assume or incur administrative costs in support of a state or state-related program, or (iv) furnish capital facilities for state or state-related activities.</p><p>For purposes of this section, "net additional expenditure" means the cost anticipated to be incurred annually, less any revenues receivable on account of the program or service from fees charged recipients of the program or service, state or federal aid paid specifically and categorically in connection with the program or service, new or increased local sources of revenue authorized and designated specifically to offset the cost of the program or service, and any offsetting savings resulting from the reduction or elimination of any program or service directly attributable to the performance of the required program or service.</p><p>A bill shall be deemed to require a net reduction of revenues if it has the effect of requiring any county, city, or town to (i) relinquish an existing or potential source of local revenue by classification or exclusion or (ii) diminish an existing or potential source of revenue by classification or exclusion.</p><p>For the purposes of this section, "net reduction of revenues" means the reduction anticipated in local revenues, including, but not limited to, general levies, special levies, revenues received pursuant to <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 58.1-605"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 58.1-605">§§ 58.1-605<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000058#     1#          605#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> and <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 58.1-606"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 58.1-606">58.1-606<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000058#     1#          606#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> and administrative and user fees, to be incurred annually, less any new local revenues receivable and any offsetting savings resulting from the reduction of local revenues, caused by the classification or exclusion being proposed.</p><p>The provisions of this section shall not apply to a reduction in local revenues that is required or arises from a court order or judgment, nor to a revenue reduction that is adopted at the option of any county, city, or town under a law that is permissive rather than mandatory, nor to a revenue reduction that is the result of a measure providing tax relief on a statewide basis.</p><p>The Division of Legislative Services shall examine all bills and joint resolutions filed during any legislative session for the purpose of identifying and forwarding to the Commission on Local Government those bills requiring the preparation of fiscal estimates pursuant to this section and those joint resolutions calling for a study of local government revenues or expenditures.</p><p>The Department of Planning and Budget and the Department of Taxation are authorized to submit legislative bills to the Commission on Local Government to prepare local fiscal estimates.</p><p>As soon thereafter as may be practicable, the Commission on Local Government shall forward copies of such estimates to the Clerk of the House of Delegates for transmittal to each patron of the legislation and to the chairman of each committee of the General Assembly to consider the same.</p><p>All departments, agencies of government, the Division of Legislative Services, and all local governmental units of the Commonwealth are directed to make available such information and assistance as the Commission on Local Government may request in preparing the estimates required by this section.</p></bodyText><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p>1979, c. 257; 1980, cc. 747, 749; <citation normalizedCite="1995 VA CH 743"><content><span normalizedCite="1995 Va. Ch. 743">1995, c. 743<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1995#000743#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1999 VA CH 1016"><content><span normalizedCite="1999 Va. Ch. 1016">1999, c. 1016<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1999#001016#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2010 VA CH 410"><content><span normalizedCite="2010 Va. Ch. 410">2010, c. 410<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2010#000410#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2014 VA CH 807"><content><span normalizedCite="2014 Va. Ch. 807">2014, c. 807<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2014#000807#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PT20-004G-K34V-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 30.</desig><title>GENERAL ASSEMBLY</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 1.</desig><title>GENERAL ASSEMBLY AND OFFICERS THEREOF</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Governments</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjdEQjE4OUJDMzQxNDNEMEI0RTI1QUFCMzJENjEwRTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Duties &amp; Powers</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Njk1NTNGMzM0RTc3NDcyMUI4MENCQUQ1RDhEN0M1RUM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Njg1MkM3RkYyNzIxNEVFRkJFMTI2NUM4NUU1ODdEM0Q</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Finance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjMzOTBBRTg2MUVDNDdDNUE1M0QxNDk1RERCNjNCN0I7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Njg1MkM3RkYyNzIxNEVFRkJFMTI2NUM4NUU1ODdEM0Q</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification><classificationGroup classificationScheme="indexing-terms"><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem score="90"><className>Governments</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjdEQjE4OUJDMzQxNDNEMEI0RTI1QUFCMzJENjEwRTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></classificationGroup></metadata></legislativeDoc>