<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#349#000023#     1#         2912#">Va. Code Ann. § 23.1-2912</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_23.1-2912"/><heading><desig>§ 23.1-2912.</desig><title>(Effective October 1, 2016) Shipyard workers; applied sciences and apprenticeship programs; Virginia Vocational Incentive Scholarship Program for Shipyard Workers; Fund</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a"/><heading><desig>A.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> For purposes of this section:</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Applied sciences program"</emphasis> means a three-year program of educational instruction at the college that incorporates instruction in industrial applied sciences and leads to the conferral of an Associate in Applied Science degree on any person who successfully completes such program.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Apprenticeship program"</emphasis> means a three-year program at the college combining educational instruction and on-the-job training that is established for the purpose of enhancing the education and skills of shipyard workers.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"College"</emphasis> means Tidewater Community College.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Industrial applied sciences"</emphasis> may include applied sciences such as welding, burning, blasting, and other applied sciences.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Shipyard worker"</emphasis> means any employee employed full time on a salaried or wage basis, whose tenure is not restricted as to temporary or provisional appointment, at a ship manufacturing or ship repair company located in the Commonwealth.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b"/><heading><desig>B.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The Virginia Vocational Incentive Scholarship Program for Shipyard Workers is established.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c"/><heading><desig>C.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> From such funds as are appropriated for this purpose and from such gifts, donations, grants, bequests, and other funds as may be received on its behalf, there is created in the state treasury a special nonreverting fund to be known as the Virginia Vocational Incentive Scholarship Program for Shipyard Workers Fund, referred to in this section as "the Fund." The Fund shall be established on the books of the Comptroller. Interest earned on moneys in the Fund shall remain in the Fund and be credited to it. Any moneys remaining in the Fund, including interest thereon, at the end of each fiscal year shall not revert to the general fund but shall remain in the Fund. Moneys in the Fund shall be used solely for the purposes of (i) awarding scholarships to shipyard workers enrolled at the college in the applied sciences program or the apprenticeship program or (ii) the administration and implementation of the applied sciences program or the apprenticeship program or both. Expenditures and disbursements from the Fund shall be made by the State Treasurer on warrants issued by the Comptroller upon written request signed by the president of the college.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d"/><heading><desig>D.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Subject to the Council's authority to approve or disapprove all new academic programs as provided in subdivision 5 of § 23.1-203, the college may offer an applied sciences program and coordinate such program with an apprenticeship program offered to shipyard workers by their employers.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_e"/><heading><desig>E.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Beginning in the calendar year that the Council approves an applied sciences program and for calendar years thereafter, shipyard workers who are Virginia students enrolled full-time or part-time in the applied sciences program are eligible for scholarships for such program. Renewal of the scholarships of such shipyard workers is contingent upon maintaining (i) enrollment in the applied sciences program, (ii) a cumulative grade point average of at least 3.0 on a scale of 4.0 or its equivalent at the completion of each academic year, and (iii) full-time employment as a shipyard worker.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_f"/><heading><desig>F.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The college shall award scholarships to eligible students in the applied sciences program or the apprenticeship program for no more than three academic years. Scholarship amounts shall not exceed full tuition and required fees relating to such academic program or the apprenticeship program.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_g"/><heading><desig>G.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Before any scholarship is awarded in accordance with the provisions of this section, the scholarship recipient shall sign a promissory note under which he agrees (i) to continue full-time employment as a shipyard worker until his graduation and (ii) upon graduation, to work continuously as a shipyard worker for the same number of years that he was the beneficiary of the scholarship. The college shall recover the total amount of funds awarded as a scholarship, or the appropriate portion thereof, including any accrued interest, if the scholarship recipient fails to honor such requirements.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_h"/><heading><desig>H.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The Council shall adopt regulations for the implementation of the provisions of this section.</p></bodyText></level><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p><citation normalizedCite="2001 VA CH 656"><content><span normalizedCite="2001 Va. Ch. 656">2001, c. 656<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2001#000656#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 23-220.01"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 23 -220.01">§ 23-220.01<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#123#000023#    220.01#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2013 VA CH 566"><content><span normalizedCite="2013 Va. Ch. 566">2013, c. 566<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2013#000566#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 23-231.1:1"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 23 -231.1:1">§ 23-231.1:1<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#142#        23#     231.1#         1#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2014 VA CH 484"><content><span normalizedCite="2014 Va. Ch. 484">2014, c. 484<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2014#000484#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2016 VA CH 588"><content><span normalizedCite="2016 Va. Ch. 588">2016, c. 588<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2016#000588#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PWF0-004G-K42J-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 23.1.</desig><title>INSTITUTIONS OF HIGHER EDUCATION; OTHER EDUCATIONAL AND CULTURAL INSTITUTIONS</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="subtitle"><heading><desig>SUBTITLE IV.</desig><title>PUBLIC INSTITUTIONS OF HIGHER EDUCATION</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 29.</desig><title>STATE BOARD FOR COMMUNITY COLLEGES AND VIRGINIA COMMUNITY COLLEGE SYSTEM</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Education Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDkzNUEzQzFBNEZBNEFBREIxNDM5MTc1MUU5QjI4MTY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Institutional Assistance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OUM4Q0U0OUQyNUNFNDZBQUJGMUVEOEY3RDI2RUY1MjI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Njk4RUMyMDg4ODMwNDIwNUI1NEQwMDE0OUU3REYyOTM</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Payment</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6REJERDcyQ0M1RjkyNERFMjlCNUQ3NkJFMDVGNzA4RjY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RkQwQkFBMERCREE4NDQ4N0FCQzNGRDg3QjgwMEQ3RjY</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification><classificationGroup classificationScheme="indexing-terms"><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem score="90"><className>Education</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDkzNUEzQzFBNEZBNEFBREIxNDM5MTc1MUU5QjI4MTY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></classificationGroup></metadata></legislativeDoc>