<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#349#000010#     1#       1408.1#">Va. Code Ann. § 10.1-1408.1</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_10.1-1408.1"/><heading><desig>§ 10.1-1408.1.</desig><title>Permit required; open dumps prohibited</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a"/><heading><desig>A.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> No person shall operate any sanitary landfill or other facility for the disposal, treatment or storage of nonhazardous solid waste without a permit from the Director.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b"/><heading><desig>B.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> No application for (i) a new solid waste management facility permit or (ii) application for a permit amendment or variance allowing a category 2 landfill, as defined in this section, to expand or increase in capacity shall be complete unless it contains the following:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Certification from the governing body of the county, city or town in which the facility is to be located that the location and operation of the facility are consistent with all applicable ordinances. The governing body shall inform the applicant and the Department of the facility's compliance or noncompliance not more than 120 days from receipt of a request from the applicant. No such certification shall be required for the application for the renewal of a permit or transfer of a permit as authorized by regulations of the Board;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A disclosure statement, except that the Director, upon request and in his sole discretion, and when in his judgment other information is sufficient and available, may waive the requirement for a disclosure statement for a captive industrial landfill when such a statement would not serve the purposes of this chapter;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> If the applicant proposes to locate the facility on property not governed by any county, city or town zoning ordinance, certification from the governing body that it has held a public hearing, in accordance with the applicable provisions of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 15.2-2204"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 15.2-2204">§ 15.2-2204<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000015#     2#         2204#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, to receive public comment on the proposed facility. Such certification shall be provided to the applicant and the Department within 120 days from receipt of a request from the applicant;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_4"/><heading><desig>4.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> If the applicant proposes to operate a new sanitary landfill or transfer station, a statement, including a description of the steps taken by the applicant to seek the comments of the residents of the area where the sanitary landfill or transfer station is proposed to be located, regarding the siting and operation of the proposed sanitary landfill or transfer station. The public comment steps shall be taken prior to filing with the Department the notice of intent to apply for a permit for the sanitary landfill or transfer station as required by the Department's solid waste management regulations. The public comment steps shall include publication of a public notice once a week for two consecutive weeks in a newspaper of general circulation serving the locality where the sanitary landfill or transfer station is proposed to be located and holding at least one public meeting within the locality to identify issues of concern, to facilitate communication and to establish a dialogue between the applicant and persons who may be affected by the issuance of a permit for the sanitary landfill or transfer station. The public notice shall include a statement of the applicant's intent to apply for a permit to operate the proposed sanitary landfill or transfer station, the proposed sanitary landfill or transfer station site location, the date, time and location of the public meeting the applicant will hold and the name, address and telephone number of a person employed by the applicant, who can be contacted by interested persons to answer questions or receive comments on the siting and operation of the proposed sanitary landfill or transfer station. The first publication of the public notice shall be at least fourteen days prior to the public meeting date.</p><p><pre/>The provisions of this subdivision shall not apply to applicants for a permit to operate a new captive industrial landfill or a new construction-demolition-debris landfill;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_5"/><heading><desig>5.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> If the applicant is a local government or public authority that proposes to operate a new municipal sanitary landfill or transfer station, a statement, including a description of the steps taken by the applicant to seek the comments of the residents of the area where the sanitary landfill or transfer station is proposed to be located, regarding the siting and operation of the proposed sanitary landfill or transfer station. The public comment steps shall be taken prior to filing with the Department the notice of intent to apply for a permit for the sanitary landfill or transfer station as required by the Department's solid waste management regulations. The public comment steps shall include the formation of a citizens' advisory group to assist the locality or public authority with the selection of a proposed site for the sanitary landfill or transfer station, publication of a public notice once a week for two consecutive weeks in a newspaper of general circulation serving the locality where the sanitary landfill or transfer station is proposed to be located, and holding at least one public meeting within the locality to identify issues of concern, to facilitate communication and to establish a dialogue between the applicant and persons who may be affected by the issuance of a permit for the sanitary landfill or transfer station. The public notice shall include a statement of the applicant's intent to apply for a permit to operate the proposed sanitary landfill or transfer station, the proposed sanitary landfill or transfer station site location, the date, time and location of the public meeting the applicant will hold and the name, address and telephone number of a person employed by the applicant, who can be contacted by interested persons to answer questions or receive comments on the siting and operation of the proposed sanitary landfill or transfer station. The first publication of the public notice shall be at least fourteen days prior to the public meeting date. For local governments that have zoning ordinances, such public comment steps as required under <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 15.2-2204"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 15.2-2204">§§ 15.2-2204<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000015#     2#         2204#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> and <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 15.2-2285"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 15.2-2285">15.2-2285<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000015#     2#         2285#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> shall satisfy the public comment requirements for public hearings and public notice as required under this section. Any applicant which is a local government or public authority that proposes to operate a new transfer station on land where a municipal sanitary landfill is already located shall be exempt from the public comment requirements for public hearing and public notice otherwise required under this section;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_6"/><heading><desig>6.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> If the application is for a new municipal solid waste landfill or for an expansion of an existing municipal solid waste landfill, a statement, signed by the applicant, guaranteeing that sufficient disposal capacity will be available in the facility to enable localities within the Commonwealth to comply with solid waste management plans developed pursuant to <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 10.1-1411"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 10.1-1411">§ 10.1-1411<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000010#     1#         1411#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, and certifying that such localities will be allowed to contract for and to reserve disposal capacity in the facility. This provision shall not apply to permit applications from one or more political subdivisions for new landfills or expanded landfills that will only accept municipal solid waste generated within those political subdivisions' jurisdiction or municipal solid waste generated within other political subdivisions pursuant to an interjurisdictional agreement;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_7"/><heading><desig>7.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> If the application is for a new municipal solid waste landfill or for an expansion of an existing municipal solid waste landfill, certification from the governing body of the locality in which the facility would be located that a host agreement has been reached between the applicant and the governing body unless the governing body or a public service authority of which the governing body is a member would be the owner and operator of the landfill. The agreement shall, at a minimum, have provisions covering (i) the amount of financial compensation the applicant will provide the host locality, (ii) daily travel routes and traffic volumes, (iii) the daily disposal limit, and (iv) the anticipated service area of the facility. The host agreement shall contain a provision that the applicant will pay the full cost of at least one full-time employee of the locality whose responsibility it will be to monitor and inspect waste transportation and disposal practices in the locality. The host agreement shall also provide that the applicant shall, when requested by the host locality, split air and water samples so that the host locality may independently test the sample, with all associated costs paid for by the applicant. All such sampling results shall be provided to the Department. For purposes of this subdivision, "host agreement" means any lease, contract, agreement or land use permit entered into or issued by the locality in which the landfill is situated which includes terms or conditions governing the operation of the landfill;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_8"/><heading><desig>8.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> If the application is for a locality-owned and locality-operated new municipal solid waste landfill or for an expansion of an existing such municipal solid waste landfill, information on the anticipated (i) daily travel routes and traffic volumes, (ii) daily disposal limit, and (iii) service area of the facility; and</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_9"/><heading><desig>9.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> If the application is for a new solid waste management facility permit or for modification of a permit to allow an existing solid waste management facility to expand or increase its capacity, the application shall include certification from the governing body for the locality in which the facility is or will be located that: (i) the proposed new facility or the expansion or increase in capacity of the existing facility is consistent with the applicable local or regional solid waste management plan developed and approved pursuant to <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 10.1-1411"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 10.1-1411">§ 10.1-1411<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000010#     1#         1411#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; or (ii) the local government or solid waste management planning unit has initiated the process to revise the solid waste management plan to include the new or expanded facility. Inclusion of such certification shall be sufficient to allow processing of the permit application, up to but not including publication of the draft permit or permit amendment for public comment, but shall not bind the Director in making the determination required by subdivision D 1.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c"/><heading><desig>C.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Notwithstanding any other provision of law:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Every holder of a permit issued under this article who has not earlier filed a disclosure statement shall, prior to July 1, 1991, file a disclosure statement with the Director.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Every applicant for a permit under this article shall file a disclosure statement with the Director, together with the permit application or prior to September 1, 1990, whichever comes later. No permit application shall be deemed incomplete for lack of a disclosure statement prior to September 1, 1990.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Every applicant shall update its disclosure statement quarterly to indicate any change of condition that renders any portion of the disclosure statement materially incomplete or inaccurate.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c_4"/><heading><desig>4.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The Director, upon request and in his sole discretion, and when in his judgment other information is sufficient and available, may waive the requirements of this subsection for a captive industrial waste landfill when such requirements would not serve the purposes of this chapter.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d"/><heading><desig>D.</desig></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Except as provided in subdivision D 2, no permit for a new solid waste management facility nor any amendment to a permit allowing facility expansion or an increase in capacity shall be issued until the Director has determined, after an investigation and analysis of the potential human health, environmental, transportation infrastructure, and transportation safety impacts and needs and an evaluation of comments by the host local government, other local governments and interested persons, that (i) the proposed facility, expansion, or increase protects present and future human health and safety and the environment; (ii) there is a need for the additional capacity; (iii) sufficient infrastructure will exist to safely handle the waste flow; (iv) the increase is consistent with locality-imposed or state-imposed daily disposal limits; (v) the public interest will be served by the proposed facility's operation or the expansion or increase in capacity of a facility; and (vi) the proposed solid waste management facility, facility expansion, or additional capacity is consistent with regional and local solid waste management plans developed pursuant to <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 10.1-1411"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 10.1-1411">§ 10.1-1411<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000010#     1#         1411#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>. The Department shall hold a public hearing within the said county, city or town prior to the issuance of any such permit for the management of nonhazardous solid waste. Subdivision D 2, in lieu of this subdivision, shall apply to nonhazardous industrial solid waste management facilities owned or operated by the generator of the waste managed at the facility, and that accept only waste generated by the facility owner or operator. The Board shall have the authority to promulgate regulations to implement this subdivision.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> No new permit for a nonhazardous industrial solid waste management facility that is owned or operated by the generator of the waste managed at the facility, and that accepts only waste generated by the facility owner or operator, shall be issued until the Director has determined, after investigation and evaluation of comments by the local government, that the proposed facility poses no substantial present or potential danger to human health or the environment. The Department shall hold a public hearing within the county, city or town where the facility is to be located prior to the issuance of any such permit for the management of nonhazardous industrial solid waste.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_e"/><heading><desig>E.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The permit shall contain such conditions or requirements as are necessary to comply with the requirements of this Code and the regulations of the Board and to protect present and future human health and the environment. To the extent allowed by federal law, any person holding a permit that is intending to upgrade the permitted solid waste management facility by installing technology, control equipment, or other apparatus that the permittee demonstrates to the satisfaction of the Director will result in improved energy efficiency, protect waters of the state, including both surface and ground water, and protect air quality shall not be required to obtain a modified or amended permit.</p><p>The Director may include in any permit such recordkeeping, testing and reporting requirements as are necessary to ensure that the local governing body of the county, city or town where the waste management facility is located is kept timely informed regarding the general nature and quantity of waste being disposed of at the facility. Such recordkeeping, testing and reporting requirements shall require disclosure of proprietary information only as is necessary to carry out the purposes of this chapter. At least once every ten years, the Director shall review and issue written findings on the environmental compliance history of each permittee, material changes, if any, in key personnel, and technical limitations, standards, or regulations on which the original permit was based. The time period for review of each category of permits shall be established by Board regulation. If, upon such review, the Director finds that repeated material or substantial violations of the permittee or material changes in the permittee's key personnel would make continued operation of the facility not in the best interests of human health or the environment, the Director shall amend or revoke the permit, in accordance herewith. Whenever such review is undertaken, the Director may amend the permit to include additional limitations, standards, or conditions when the technical limitations, standards, or regulations on which the original permit was based have been changed by statute or amended by regulation or when any of the conditions in subsection B of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 10.1-1409"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 10.1-1409">§ 10.1-1409<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000010#     1#         1409#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> exist. The Director may deny, revoke, or suspend any permit for any of the grounds listed under subsection A of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 10.1-1409"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 10.1-1409">§ 10.1-1409<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000010#     1#         1409#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_f"/><heading><desig>F.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> There shall exist no right to operate a landfill or other facility for the disposal, treatment or storage of nonhazardous solid waste or hazardous waste within the Commonwealth. Permits for solid waste management facilities shall not be transferable except as authorized in regulations promulgated by the Board. The issuance of a permit shall not convey or establish any property rights or any exclusive privilege, nor shall it authorize any injury to private property or any invasion of personal rights or any infringement of federal, state, or local law or regulation.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_g"/><heading><desig>G.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> No person shall dispose of solid waste in open dumps.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_h"/><heading><desig>H.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> No person shall own, operate or allow to be operated on his property an open dump.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_i"/><heading><desig>I.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> No person shall allow waste to be disposed of on his property without a permit. Any person who removes trees, brush, or other vegetation from land used for agricultural or forestal purposes shall not be required to obtain a permit if such material is deposited or placed on the same or other property of the same landowner from which such materials were cleared. The Board shall by regulation provide for other reasonable exemptions from permitting requirements for the disposal of trees, brush and other vegetation when such materials are removed for agricultural or forestal purposes.</p><p>When promulgating any regulation pursuant to this section, the Board shall consider the character of the land affected, the density of population, and the volume of waste to be disposed, as well as other relevant factors.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_j"/><heading><desig>J.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> No permit shall be required pursuant to this section for recycling or for temporary storage incidental to recycling. As used in this subsection, "recycling" means any process whereby material which would otherwise be solid waste is used or reused, or prepared for use or reuse, as an ingredient in an industrial process to make a product, or as an effective substitute for a commercial product.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_k"/><heading><desig>K.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The Board shall provide for reasonable exemptions from the permitting requirements, both procedural and substantive, in order to encourage the development of yard waste composting facilities. To accomplish this, the Board is authorized to exempt such facilities from regulations governing the treatment of waste and to establish an expedited approval process. Agricultural operations receiving only yard waste for composting shall be exempt from permitting requirements provided that (i) the composting area is located not less than 300 feet from a property boundary, is located not less than 1,000 feet from an occupied dwelling not located on the same property as the composting area, and is not located within an area designated as a flood plain as defined in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 10.1-600"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 10.1-600">§ 10.1-600<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000010#     1#          600#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; (ii) the agricultural operation has at least one acre of ground suitable to receive yard waste for each 150 cubic yards of finished compost generated; (iii) the total time for the composting process and storage of material that is being composted or has been composted shall not exceed eighteen months prior to its field application or sale as a horticultural or agricultural product; and (iv) the owner or operator of the agricultural operation notifies the Director in writing of his intent to operate a yard waste composting facility and the amount of land available for the receipt of yard waste. In addition to the requirements set forth in clauses (i) through (iv) of the preceding sentence, the owner and operator of any agricultural operation that receives more than 6,000 cubic yards of yard waste generated from property not within the control of the owner or the operator in any twelve-month period shall be exempt from permitting requirements provided (i) the owner and operator submit to the Director an annual report describing the volume and types of yard waste received by such operation for composting and (ii) the operator shall certify that the yard waste composting facility complies with local ordinances. The Director shall establish a procedure for the filing of the notices, annual reports and certificates required by this subsection and shall prescribe the forms for the annual reports and certificates. Nothing contained in this article shall prohibit the sale of composted yard waste for horticultural or agricultural use, provided that any composted yard waste sold as a commercial fertilizer with claims of specific nutrient values, promoting plant growth, or of conditioning soil shall be sold in accordance with Chapter 36 (<citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 3.2-3600"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 3.2-3600">§ 3.2-3600<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000003#     2#         3600#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> et seq.) of Title 3.2. As used in this subsection, "agricultural operation" shall have the same meaning ascribed to it in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 3.2-300"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 3.2-300">§ 3.2-300<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000003#     2#          300#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><bodyText><p>The operation of a composting facility as provided in this subsection shall not relieve the owner or operator of such a facility from liability for any violation of this chapter.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_l"/><heading><desig>L.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The Board shall provide for reasonable exemptions from the permitting requirements, both procedural and substantive, in order to encourage the development of facilities for the decomposition of vegetative waste. To accomplish this, the Board shall approve an expedited approval process. As used in this subsection, the decomposition of vegetative waste means a natural aerobic or anaerobic process, active or passive, which results in the decay and chemical breakdown of the vegetative waste. Nothing in this subsection shall be construed to prohibit a city or county from exercising its existing authority to regulate such facilities by requiring, among other things, permits and proof of financial security.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_m"/><heading><desig>M.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> In receiving and processing applications for permits required by this section, the Director shall assign top priority to applications which (i) agree to accept nonhazardous recycling residues and (ii) pledge to charge tipping fees for disposal of nonhazardous recycling residues which do not exceed those charged for nonhazardous municipal solid waste. Applications meeting these requirements shall be acted upon no later than six months after they are deemed complete.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_n"/><heading><desig>N.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Every solid waste management facility shall be operated in compliance with the regulations promulgated by the Board pursuant to this chapter. To the extent consistent with federal law, those facilities which were permitted prior to March 15, 1993, and upon which solid waste has been disposed of prior to October 9, 1993, may continue to receive solid waste until they have reached their vertical design capacity, provided that the facility is in compliance with the requirements for liners and leachate control in effect at the time of permit issuance, and further provided that on or before October 9, 1993, the owner or operator of the solid waste management facility submits to the Director:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_n_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> An acknowledgement that the owner or operator is familiar with state and federal law and regulations pertaining to solid waste management facilities operating after October 9, 1993, including postclosure care, corrective action and financial responsibility requirements;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_n_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A statement signed by a registered professional engineer that he has reviewed the regulations established by the Department for solid waste management facilities, including the open dump criteria contained therein; that he has inspected the facility and examined the monitoring data compiled for the facility in accordance with applicable regulations; and that, on the basis of his inspection and review, he has concluded that: (i) the facility is not an open dump, (ii) the facility does not pose a substantial present or potential hazard to human health and the environment, and (iii) the leachate or residues from the facility do not pose a threat of contamination or pollution of the air, surface water or ground water in a manner constituting an open dump or resulting in a substantial present or potential hazard to human health or the environment; and</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_n_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A statement signed by the owner or operator (i) that the facility complies with applicable financial assurance regulations and (ii) estimating when the facility will reach its vertical design capacity.</p><p><pre/>The facility may not be enlarged prematurely to avoid compliance with state or federal regulations when such enlargement is not consistent with past operating practices, the permit or modified operating practices to ensure good management.</p><p><pre/>Facilities which are authorized by this subsection to accept waste for disposal beyond the waste boundaries existing on October 9, 1993, shall be as follows:</p><p><pre/>Category 1: Nonhazardous industrial waste facilities that are located on property owned or controlled by the generator of the waste disposed of in the facility;</p><p><pre/>Category 2: Nonhazardous industrial waste facilities other than those that are located on property owned or controlled by the generator of the waste disposed of in the facility, provided that the facility accepts only industrial waste streams which the facility has lawfully accepted prior to July 1, 1995, or other nonhazardous industrial waste as approved by the Department on a case-by-case basis; and</p><p><pre/>Category 3: Facilities that accept only construction-demolition-debris waste as defined in the Board's regulations.</p><p><pre/>The Director may prohibit or restrict the disposal of waste in facilities described in this subsection which contains hazardous constituents as defined in applicable regulations which, in the opinion of the Director, would pose a substantial risk to health or the environment. Facilities described in category 3 may expand laterally beyond the waste disposal boundaries existing on October 9, 1993, provided that there is first installed, in such expanded areas, liners and leachate control systems meeting the applicable performance requirements of the Board's regulations, or a demonstration is made to the satisfaction of the Director that such facilities satisfy the applicable variance criteria in the Board's regulations.</p><p><pre/>Owners or operators of facilities which are authorized under this subsection to accept waste for disposal beyond the waste boundaries existing on October 9, 1993, shall ensure that such expanded disposal areas maintain setback distances applicable to such facilities under the Board's current regulations and local ordinances. Prior to the expansion of any facility described in category 2 or 3, the owner or operator shall provide the Director with written notice of the proposed expansion at least sixty days prior to commencement of construction. The notice shall include recent groundwater monitoring data sufficient to determine that the facility does not pose a threat of contamination of groundwater in a manner constituting an open dump or creating a substantial present or potential hazard to human health or the environment. The Director shall evaluate the data included with the notification and may advise the owner or operator of any additional requirements that may be necessary to ensure compliance with applicable laws and prevent a substantial present or potential hazard to health or the environment.</p><p><pre/>Facilities, or portions thereof, which have reached their vertical design capacity shall be closed in compliance with regulations promulgated by the Board.</p><p><pre/>Nothing in this subsection shall alter any requirement for groundwater monitoring, financial responsibility, operator certification, closure, postclosure care, operation, maintenance or corrective action imposed under state or federal law or regulation, or impair the powers of the Director pursuant to § 10.1-1409.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_o"/><heading><desig>O.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Portions of a permitted solid waste management facility used solely for the storage of household hazardous waste may store household hazardous waste for a period not to exceed one year, provided that such wastes are properly contained and are segregated to prevent mixing of incompatible wastes.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_p"/><heading><desig>P.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Any permit for a new municipal solid waste landfill, and any permit amendment authorizing expansion of an existing municipal solid waste landfill, shall incorporate conditions to require that capacity in the landfill will be available to localities within the Commonwealth that choose to contract for and reserve such capacity for disposal of such localities' solid waste in accordance with solid waste management plans developed by such localities pursuant to <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 10.1-1411"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 10.1-1411">§ 10.1-1411<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000010#     1#         1411#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>. This provision shall not apply to permit applications from one or more political subdivisions for new landfills or expanded landfills that will only accept municipal solid waste generated within the political subdivision or subdivisions' jurisdiction or municipal solid waste generated within other political subdivisions pursuant to an interjurisdictional agreement.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_q"/><heading><desig>Q.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> No application for coverage under a permit-by-rule or for modification of coverage under a permit-by-rule shall be complete unless it contains certification from the governing body of the locality in which the facility is to be located that the facility is consistent with the solid waste management plan developed and approved in accordance with <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 10.1-1411"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 10.1-1411">§ 10.1-1411<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000010#     1#         1411#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></level><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p>1988, cc. 696, 891; <citation normalizedCite="1989 VA CH 623"><content><span normalizedCite="1989 Va. Ch. 623">1989, c. 623<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1989#000623#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1990 VA CH 360"><content><span normalizedCite="1990 Va. Ch. 360">1990, cc. 360<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1990#000360#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1990 VA CH 781"><content><span normalizedCite="1990 Va. Ch. 781">781<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1990#000781#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1990 VA CH 919"><content><span normalizedCite="1990 Va. Ch. 919">919<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1990#000919#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1992 VA CH 286"><content><span normalizedCite="1992 Va. Ch. 286">1992, c. 286<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1992#000286#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1993 VA CH 214"><content><span normalizedCite="1993 Va. Ch. 214">1993, cc. 214<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1993#000214#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1993 VA CH 469"><content><span normalizedCite="1993 Va. Ch. 469">469<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1993#000469#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1993 VA CH 476"><content><span normalizedCite="1993 Va. Ch. 476">476<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1993#000476#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1993 VA CH 496"><content><span normalizedCite="1993 Va. Ch. 496">496<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1993#000496#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1994 VA CH 614"><content><span normalizedCite="1994 Va. Ch. 614">1994, c. 614<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1994#000614#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1995 VA CH 442"><content><span normalizedCite="1995 Va. Ch. 442">1995, c. 442<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1995#000442#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1996 VA CH 236"><content><span normalizedCite="1996 Va. Ch. 236">1996, c. 236<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1996#000236#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1997 VA CH 875"><content><span normalizedCite="1997 Va. Ch. 875">1997, c. 875<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1997#000875#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1999 VA CH 580"><content><span normalizedCite="1999 Va. Ch. 580">1999, cc. 580<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1999#000580#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1999 VA CH 584"><content><span normalizedCite="1999 Va. Ch. 584">584<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1999#000584#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1999 VA CH 611"><content><span normalizedCite="1999 Va. Ch. 611">611<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1999#000611#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1999 VA CH 613"><content><span normalizedCite="1999 Va. Ch. 613">613<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1999#000613#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1999 VA CH 947"><content><span normalizedCite="1999 Va. Ch. 947">947<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1999#000947#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2000 VA CH 420"><content><span normalizedCite="2000 Va. Ch. 420">2000, cc. 420<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2000#000420#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2000 VA CH 422"><content><span normalizedCite="2000 Va. Ch. 422">422<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2000#000422#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2006 VA CH 62"><content><span normalizedCite="2006 Va. Ch. 62">2006, c. 62<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2006#000062#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2007 VA CH 23"><content><span normalizedCite="2007 Va. Ch. 23">2007, c. 23<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2007#000023#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2012 VA CH 581"><content><span normalizedCite="2012 Va. Ch. 581">2012, c. 581<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2012#000581#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PSJ0-004G-K1VR-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 10.1.</desig><title>CONSERVATION</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="subtitle"><heading><desig>SUBTITLE II.</desig><title>ACTIVITIES ADMINISTERED BY OTHER ENTITIES</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 14.</desig><title>VIRGINIA WASTE MANAGEMENT ACT</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="article"><heading><desig>ARTICLE 2.</desig><title>SOLID WASTE MANAGEMENT</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Distribution, Processing &amp; Storage of Food &amp; Agricultural Products</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NENGNzZCMDU5RjcyNEM0NEFFOUU4ODFCQkZCOThBRkI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NkVDMzM4QkJENTg3NDQ0RDg3NTA5OEM3RkMyQTlENDI</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Hazardous Materials</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QzM5RkFCRDVCNzgyNERFQkEyNjFGODU0NjYxN0U2NTc7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QzczQ0MwNDEzMjhGNDIxQ0FEM0ExM0EwQjk0QjI0RTk</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Resource Recovery &amp; Recycling</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RTk4QTlBODAyQTJDNEM3NUJDNTMxOENDQUVDMDZEN0M7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OTVBMjY4ODg4OEM2NEIyMDg1MDBFQTVDQTgwNTczRTc</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Energy &amp; Utilities Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OUUzODAyRDk1QzVFNEZGMEJDM0RGMDYxOTlEMEEzRDA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6ODcxOEQ3MjY5MjY4NDIwQUFFODlGNTYxQTcxQzkyOUY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NTAwOTgyMTVBNkJFNENFMzgyODE3NEYxNzdBQTU4RkM</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Environmental Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NzFDRDYyNkI2QjhBNDg3NTkyRjRDRkZEQjlCRkRBQzM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Disposal</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjhBMzQwMTIzMUJFNDFCMUIxRTk1RDYxQTQyOThDNEQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NzY4MTI1MkI1NTcyNEM1NEI5MEQyNjc1QTQzOEI4QzY</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Disposal Planning</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDk1OTcxRTZCMEZCNDRBNkI2NEJFM0YyMDc2QzQzQjA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OTVBMjY4ODg4OEM2NEIyMDg1MDBFQTVDQTgwNTczRTc</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Disposal Standards</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MEZBQUU3OTJGRDU4NDE1Nzg0Q0I1QTBBM0M2QzMyMEI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OTVBMjY4ODg4OEM2NEIyMDg1MDBFQTVDQTgwNTczRTc</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Flow Control</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6ODMxMzUzNTRGQzgyNDU4RkE1OEI3Mzc2N0YxOEEyQTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OTVBMjY4ODg4OEM2NEIyMDg1MDBFQTVDQTgwNTczRTc</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MThEMDg1N0VCNkI1NEQ4ODkwQjUwMzMxMzNGQTFBRTc7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NzY4MTI1MkI1NTcyNEM1NEI5MEQyNjc1QTQzOEI4QzY</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Operating Permits</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MzI5MUM5MTI2RkUyNDM4QjlCQURBQkU0QzEzRkE5MEE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NUVDODc1M0EwM0ZFNEJGMzk0MDM1NzMxNjQ4NjMyODc</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Resource Recovery &amp; Recycling</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RTk4QTlBODAyQTJDNEM3NUJDNTMxOENDQUVDMDZEN0M7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OTVBMjY4ODg4OEM2NEIyMDg1MDBFQTVDQTgwNTczRTc</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Transportation</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RjNEOUYyRTIzRUQwNERDRUI0QkZEMTBENjBCRjVGRDg7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NzY4MTI1MkI1NTcyNEM1NEI5MEQyNjc1QTQzOEI4QzY</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Governments</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjdEQjE4OUJDMzQxNDNEMEI0RTI1QUFCMzJENjEwRTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Administrative Boards</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QTYwRUFCMDc5MzQ5NDEyREFEQkU2NkE2MjRGQTlCNzY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Njg1MkM3RkYyNzIxNEVFRkJFMTI2NUM4NUU1ODdEM0Q</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Distribution, Processing &amp; Storage</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NENGNzZCMDU5RjcyNEM0NEFFOUU4ODFCQkZCOThBRkI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NkVDMzM4QkJENTg3NDQ0RDg3NTA5OEM3RkMyQTlENDI</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Enactment</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NjQ3NDdBNUU0RDM2NDJENTgzOTZFRjM0QzIzMjg1MjA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Q0M3QUYzNjlBN0UzNEVBMDk4OEIyMzdBMDlGQzA2RjI</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Ordinances &amp; Regulations</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NjQ1MzRDRUY1OTZBNDRDNTlDODQzRDRCMUFCNDc2RTU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Njg1MkM3RkYyNzIxNEVFRkJFMTI2NUM4NUU1ODdEM0Q</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Real Property Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QUUyRTcxRURBNEY2NEE2MDk3QzBCNzRDOEY0NTZDQzk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Public Entities</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RjYyQkY4N0Y5QjJDNDkxQkFGNkIwMTEyQ0Y2MzY4MTQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RURDNjE0NDUzN0QxNDE4OTg0OERFMzU4MzFCNUU1NUI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Transportation Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RTYzRTk5RDVBQkQ2NDcwQzk2NTU3ODQ5OEE3NDlBNzk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Hazardous Materials</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QzM5RkFCRDVCNzgyNERFQkEyNjFGODU0NjYxN0U2NTc7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QzczQ0MwNDEzMjhGNDIxQ0FEM0ExM0EwQjk0QjI0RTk</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification><classificationGroup classificationScheme="indexing-terms"><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem score="90"><className>Environmental &amp; Natural Resources</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NzFDRDYyNkI2QjhBNDg3NTkyRjRDRkZEQjlCRkRBQzM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></classificationGroup></metadata></legislativeDoc>