<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#349#000024#     2#          659#">Va. Code Ann. § 24.2-659</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><note><bodyText><p>This section has more than one version with varying effective dates.  To view a complete list of the versions of this section see Table of Contents.</p></bodyText></note><anchor id="_24.2-659"/><heading><desig>§ 24.2-659.</desig><title>(Effective until July 1, 2020) Locking voting and counting machines after election and delivering keys to clerk; printed returns as evidence</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a"/><heading><desig>A.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> If the voting or counting machine is secured by the use of equipment keys, after the officers of election lock and seal each machine, the equipment keys shall be enclosed in an envelope that shall be sealed and have endorsed thereon a certificate of an officer of election stating the election precinct, the number of each machine, the number on the seal, and the number of the protective counter, if one, on the machine. The sealed envelope shall be delivered by one of the officers of the election to the clerk of the circuit court where the election was held. The custodians of the voting equipment shall enclose and seal in an envelope, properly endorsed, all other keys to all voting equipment in their jurisdictions and deliver the envelope to the clerk of the circuit court by noon on the day following the election.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b"/><heading><desig>B.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> If the voting or counting machines are secured by the use of equipment keys or electronic activation devices that are not specific to a particular machine, after the officers of election lock and seal each machine, the equipment keys and electronic activation devices shall be enclosed in an envelope that shall be sealed and have endorsed thereon a certificate of an officer of election stating the election precinct. The sealed envelope shall be delivered by one of the officers of election to the clerk of the circuit court where the election was held.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c"/><heading><desig>C.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> If the voting or counting machine is secured by removal of the data storage device used in that election, the officers shall remove the data storage device and proceed to lock and seal each machine. The data storage device shall be enclosed in an envelope that shall be sealed and have endorsed thereon a certificate of an officer of election stating the election precinct, the number of each machine, the number on the seal, and the number of the protective counter, if one, on the machine. The sealed envelope shall be delivered by one of the officers of election to the clerk of the circuit court where the election was held. The equipment keys used at the polls shall be sealed in a different envelope and delivered to the clerk who shall release them to the general registrar upon request or at the expiration of the time specified by subsection F.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d"/><heading><desig>D.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> If the voting or counting machine provides for the creation of a separate master electronic back-up on a data storage device that combines the data for all of the voting or counting machines in a given precinct, that data storage device shall be enclosed in an envelope that shall be sealed and have endorsed thereon a certificate of an officer of election stating the name of the precinct. The sealed envelope shall be delivered by one of the officers of election to the clerk of the circuit court where the election was held. The data storage device for the individual machines may remain sealed in its individual machine until the expiration of the time specified by subsection F. The equipment keys and the electronic activation devices used at the polls shall be sealed together in a separate envelope and delivered to the clerk who shall release them to the general registrar upon request or at the expiration of the time specified by subsection F.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_e"/><heading><desig>E.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> If the voting or counting machine is secured by removal of the data storage device used in that election, and the only record of votes cast for any office or on any question is saved on that data storage device and not on the machine itself, the officers shall remove the data storage device and proceed to lock and seal each machine. Each such machine shall remain locked and sealed until it is returned to the site at which voting and counting machines are stored in the locality. The data storage device shall be enclosed in an envelope that shall be sealed and have endorsed thereon a certificate of an officer of election stating the election precinct, the number of each machine, the number on the seal, and the number of the protective counter, if one, on the machine. The sealed envelope shall be delivered by one of the officers of election to the clerk of the circuit court where the election was held. The equipment keys used at the polls shall be sealed in a different envelope and delivered to the electoral board no later than noon on the day after the election.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_f"/><heading><desig>F.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The voting and counting machines described in subsections A, B, C, and D shall remain locked and sealed until the deadline to request a recount under Chapter 8 (<citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 24.2-800"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 24.2-800">§ 24.2-800<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000024#     2#          800#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> et seq.) has passed and, if any contest or recount is pending thereafter, until it has been concluded. Such machines and any envelope containing data storage devices shall be opened and all data examined only (i) on the order of a court of competent jurisdiction or (ii) on the request of an authorized representative of the State Board, or the electoral board or general registrar at the direction of the State Board, in order to ensure the accuracy of the returns. In the event that machines and data storage devices are examined under clause (ii), each political party and each independent candidate on the ballot, or each primary candidate, shall be entitled to have a representative present during such examination. The representatives and observers lawfully present shall be prohibited from interfering with the officers of election in any way. The State Board, local electoral board, or general registrar shall provide such parties and candidates reasonable advance notice of the examination.</p><p>When recounts occur in precincts using direct recording electronic machines with printed return sheets, the printed return sheets delivered to the clerk may be used as the official evidence of the results.</p><p>When the required time has expired, the clerk of the circuit court shall return all voting equipment keys and data storage devices to the general registrar.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_g"/><heading><desig>G.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The local electoral board or general registrar may direct the officers of election and custodians that any sealed equipment keys or data storage devices that are otherwise required by the provisions of this section to be delivered to the clerk of the circuit court shall instead be delivered to the principal office of the general registrar no later than noon on the day following the election. The general registrar shall secure and retain the sealed equipment keys and any other electronic locking or activation devices in his office and shall convey them to the clerk of the court by noon on the day following the ascertainment of the results of the election by the electoral board.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_h"/><heading><desig>H.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The provisions of this section requiring the locking and sealing of voting and counting machines shall not apply to any ballot marking device and its data storage device provided pursuant to <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 24.2-626.1"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 24.2-626.1">§ 24.2-626.1<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000024#     2#        626.1#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, where the number of persons voting in the election or the number of votes cast for any office or on any question are not recorded by the ballot marking device.</p></bodyText></level><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p>Code 1950, § 24-314; 1962, c. 230; 1966, c. 453; 1970, c. 462, § 24.1-224; 1974, c. 428; 1978, c. 778; 1985, c. 458; <citation normalizedCite="1993 VA CH 641"><content><span normalizedCite="1993 Va. Ch. 641">1993, c. 641<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1993#000641#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1995 VA CH 197"><content><span normalizedCite="1995 Va. Ch. 197">1995, c. 197<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1995#000197#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2003 VA CH 1015"><content><span normalizedCite="2003 Va. Ch. 1015">2003, c. 1015<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2003#001015#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2004 VA CH 835"><content><span normalizedCite="2004 Va. Ch. 835">2004, cc. 835<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2004#000835#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2004 VA CH 993"><content><span normalizedCite="2004 Va. Ch. 993">993<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2004#000993#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2004 VA CH 1010"><content><span normalizedCite="2004 Va. Ch. 1010">1010<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2004#001010#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2006 VA CH 689"><content><span normalizedCite="2006 Va. Ch. 689">2006, c. 689<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2006#000689#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2008 VA CH 107"><content><span normalizedCite="2008 Va. Ch. 107">2008, cc. 107<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2008#000107#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2008 VA CH 385"><content><span normalizedCite="2008 Va. Ch. 385">385<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2008#000385#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2014 VA CH 540"><content><span normalizedCite="2014 Va. Ch. 540">2014, cc. 540<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2014#000540#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2014 VA CH 576"><content><span normalizedCite="2014 Va. Ch. 576">576<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2014#000576#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2016 VA CH 18"><content><span normalizedCite="2016 Va. Ch. 18">2016, cc. 18<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2016#000018#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2016 VA CH 218"><content><span normalizedCite="2016 Va. Ch. 218">218<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2016#000218#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2016 VA CH 489"><content><span normalizedCite="2016 Va. Ch. 489">489<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2016#000489#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2016 VA CH 492"><content><span normalizedCite="2016 Va. Ch. 492">492<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2016#000492#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PT10-004G-K2H4-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 24.2.</desig><title>ELECTIONS</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 6.</desig><title>THE ELECTION</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="article"><heading><desig>ARTICLE 4.</desig><title>CONDUCT OF ELECTION; ELECTION RESULTS</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Criminal Law &amp; Procedure</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NEU0RkE1OUQwNUQwNDgxODhEODZCMjkzOTg3NThBNzk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6ODkxNzIxNjIyNzI3NEEzQUJBQkMwRTNEMzEzNzE4OUM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OUZFNjdFRTc4Q0UzNDc5NkI2MjVFQTBFRDBGRTM4MjA</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Governments</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjdEQjE4OUJDMzQxNDNEMEI0RTI1QUFCMzJENjEwRTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Administrative Boards</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QTYwRUFCMDc5MzQ5NDEyREFEQkU2NkE2MjRGQTlCNzY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Njg1MkM3RkYyNzIxNEVFRkJFMTI2NUM4NUU1ODdEM0Q</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Clerks of Court</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6REVFMjkzRDI1MkU2NERDNjk3OEUxODY0REYwMUI1NjE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NURENzJGNTEyQzM0NEREQUI2RkVCRTM4RTc1RTZBREU</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></metadata></legislativeDoc>