<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#349#000010#     1#         1603#">Va. Code Ann. § 10.1-1603</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_10.1-1603"/><heading><desig>§ 10.1-1603.</desig><title>Powers of Authority</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><bodyText><p>The Authority is granted all powers necessary or convenient for carrying out its statutory purposes, including the following rights and powers:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> To acquire by gift, devise, purchase, or otherwise, absolutely or in trust, and to hold, use, lease as lessee and unless otherwise restricted by the terms of the gift or devise, to lease as lessor, convey, sell or otherwise dispose of any property, real or personal, or any estate or interest therein including water rights.  However, the Authority shall have no power to encumber its real property or create any estate or interest therein other than encumbrances on structures not extending to the real property upon which such structures are constructed.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> To make and enter into any contracts and agreements with any appropriate person or federal agency. Such contracts include but are not limited to (i) agreements with the Commonwealth, or any agency thereof, to lease property owned or controlled by the Commonwealth, for the purpose of construction, improvement, maintenance, or operation of any project or activity that will further the purposes described in this chapter; and (ii) agreements with any person to sublease property owned or controlled by the Commonwealth or to issue licenses for the purpose of construction, improvement, maintenance, or operation of any project or activity that will further the purposes described in this chapter.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> To plan, develop, carry out, construct, improve, rehabilitate, repair, furnish, maintain, and operate projects.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_4"/><heading><desig>4.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> To promulgate regulations concerning the use of properties under its control to protect such property and the public thereon.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_5"/><heading><desig>5.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> To fix, alter, charge, and collect rates, rentals, and other charges for the use of projects of, or for the sale of products of or for the services rendered by the Authority. Such charges shall be used to pay the expenses of the Authority, the planning, development, construction, improvement, rehabilitation, repair, furnishing, maintenance, and operation of its projects and properties, the costs of accomplishing its purposes set forth in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 10.1-1601"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 10.1-1601">§ 10.1-1601<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000010#     1#         1601#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, and the principal of and interest on its obligations, and to fulfill the terms and provisions of any agreements made with the purchasers or holders of any such obligations. Such fees, rents and charges shall not be subject to supervision or regulation by any commission, board, or agency of the Commonwealth or any political subdivision thereof.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_6"/><heading><desig>6.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> To borrow money, make and issue bonds including bonds that the Authority may determine to issue for the purposes set forth in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 10.1-1601"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 10.1-1601">§ 10.1-1601<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000010#     1#         1601#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> or of refunding bonds previously issued by the Authority. The Authority shall have the right to secure the payment of all bonds, or any part thereof, by pledge or deed of trust of all or any of its revenues, rentals, and receipts or of any project or property, tangible or intangible, or any interest therein. However, the Authority shall have no power to encumber its real property or create any estate or interest therein other than encumbrances on structures not extending to the real property upon which such structures are located.  The bonds may be secured by a pledge of any grant or contribution from a person or federal agency. The Authority shall have the power to make agreements with the purchasers or holders of the bonds or with others in connection with the bonds, whether issued or to be issued, as it deems advisable, and in general to provide for the security for the bonds and the rights of the bond holders.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_7"/><heading><desig>7.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> To employ consultants, attorneys, architects, engineers, accountants, financial experts, investment bankers, superintendents, managers and such other employees and agents as may be necessary, and to fix their compensation to be payable from funds made available to the Authority.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_8"/><heading><desig>8.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> To receive and accept from any federal agency, foundation, or person, grants, loans, gifts or contributions of money, property, or other things of value, to be held, used and applied only for the purposes for which the grant or contribution is made or to be expended in accomplishing the objectives of the Authority.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_9"/><heading><desig>9.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> To develop, undertake and provide programs, alone or in conjunction with any person or federal agency, for scientific research, continuing education, and in-service training, provided that credit towards a degree, certificate or diploma shall be granted only if the education is provided in conjunction with an institution of higher education authorized to operate in the Commonwealth; and to foster the utilization of scientific research information, discoveries and data.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_10"/><heading><desig>10.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> To pledge or otherwise encumber all or any of the revenues or receipts of the Authority as security for all or any of the obligations of the Authority.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_11"/><heading><desig>11.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> To do all acts and things necessary or convenient to carry out the powers granted by this chapter or any other acts.</p></bodyText></level></level><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p>1986, c. 360, § 10-158.5; 1988, c. 891; <citation normalizedCite="1991 VA CH 706"><content><span normalizedCite="1991 Va. Ch. 706">1991, c. 706<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1991#000706#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PSJ0-004G-K1XN-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 10.1.</desig><title>CONSERVATION</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="subtitle"><heading><desig>SUBTITLE II.</desig><title>ACTIVITIES ADMINISTERED BY OTHER ENTITIES</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 16.</desig><title>VIRGINIA RECREATIONAL FACILITIES AUTHORITY ACT</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Contracts Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QzY0RTZFMzE0RjkwNDdFQUI5M0U5N0ZFMjYyREMyQzU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QTdGQUE3QkZDMDlBNDQ1MTkzRjEzMEQ1OEUwNzdDOTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NjZEOEU3MEJBRUQ2NDNFNzhFRjAxRTk1OEU1QjY2QTc</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Estate, Gift &amp; Trust Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OENGNTY0MEQ2RTU2NDA2NTk4QjcyNzI2NTBERUU3NUI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NTM0MTFFRkQ3M0E2NEQwREFFMzc3QjBDQjhEQjZEOTM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RkJCNEFGNEQyOEM1NEZBQ0ExREJFNUQyMDM5N0U2Rjg</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Public Contracts Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDA5QTlFMDVCQUY0NEY0NUE1QzMyQzA1QkQyQzJGRUY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Construction Contracts</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OTNGMDU1RUVEN0YxNDZCNzgyODUzMzIyNUE1RTdCQ0E7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MEUwMDBBNjZENjYzNEIzQzg5N0NFMUNDNkZDRjU0QzU</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Real Property Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QUUyRTcxRURBNEY2NEE2MDk3QzBCNzRDOEY0NTZDQzk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Subleases</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NUFENzY1MzRBQUFBNDgwNzk1MTY3RTFBMDJDOUZBMDg7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDU3NDIyNUI2MzczNEUwMzk0M0Y4MkZDQjk2OUUyRTQ</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification><classificationGroup classificationScheme="indexing-terms"><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem score="90"><className>Environmental &amp; Natural Resources</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NzFDRDYyNkI2QjhBNDg3NTkyRjRDRkZEQjlCRkRBQzM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></classificationGroup></metadata></legislativeDoc>