<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#349#000059#     1#        280.1#">Va. Code Ann. § 59.1-280.1</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_59.1-280.1"/><heading><desig>§ 59.1-280.1.</desig><title>Enterprise zone real property investment tax credit</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a"/><heading><desig>A.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> As used in this section:</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Large qualified zone resident"</emphasis> means a qualified zone resident making qualified zone investments in excess of $ 100 million when such qualified zone investments result in the creation of at least 200 permanent full-time positions.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Permanent full-time position"</emphasis> means a job of an indefinite duration at a business firm located within an enterprise zone requiring the employee to report for work within the enterprise zone, and requiring either (i) a minimum of 35 hours of an employee's time a week for the entire normal year of the business firm's operations, which "normal year" must consist of at least 48 weeks, (ii) a minimum of 35 hours of an employee's time a week for the portion of the taxable year in which the employee was initially hired for, or transferred to, the business firm, or (iii) a minimum of 1,680 hours per year if the standard fringe benefits are paid by the business firm for the employee. Seasonal or temporary positions, or a position created when a job function is shifted from an existing location in the Commonwealth to a business firm located within an enterprise zone shall not qualify as permanent full-time positions.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Qualified zone improvements"</emphasis> means the amount properly chargeable to a capital account for improvements to rehabilitate or expand depreciable real property placed in service during the taxable year within an enterprise zone, provided that the total amount of such improvements equals or exceeds (i) $ 50,000 and (ii) the assessed value of the original facility immediately prior to the rehabilitation or expansion. Qualified zone improvements include expenditures associated with any exterior, structural, mechanical, or electrical improvements necessary to expand or rehabilitate a building for commercial or industrial use and excavations, grading, paving, driveways, roads, sidewalks, landscaping, or other land improvements. Qualified zone improvements shall include, but not be limited to, costs associated with demolition, carpentry, sheetrock, plaster, painting, ceilings, fixtures, doors, windows, fire suppression systems, roofing and flashing, exterior repair, cleaning, and cleanup.</p><p>Qualified zone improvements shall not include:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The cost of acquiring any real property or building; however, the cost of any newly constructed depreciable nonresidential real property (excluding land, land improvements, paving, grading, driveways, and interest) shall be considered to be a qualified zone improvement eligible for the credit if the total amount of such expenditure is at least $ 250,000 with respect to a single facility.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> (i) The cost of furnishings; (ii) any expenditure associated with appraisal, architectural, engineering and interior design fees; (iii) loan fees, points, or capitalized interest; (iv) legal, accounting, realtor, sales and marketing, or other professional fees; (v) closing costs, permits, user fees, zoning fees, impact fees, and inspection fees; (vi) bids, insurance, signage, utilities, bonding, copying, rent loss, or temporary facilities incurred during construction; (vii) utility hook-up or access fees; (viii) outbuildings; or (ix) the cost of any well or septic or sewer system.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The basis of any property: (i) for which a credit under this section was previously granted; (ii) which was previously placed in service in Virginia by the taxpayer, a related party as defined by <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="26 USC 267"><content><span normalizedCite="26 U.S.C. 267">Internal Revenue Code § 267 (b)<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#29854#1127#00000000267#1#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, or a trade or business under common control as defined by <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="26 USC 52"><content><span normalizedCite="26 U.S.C. 52">Internal Revenue Code § 52 (b)<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#29854#1127#00000000052#1#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; or (iii) which was previously in service in Virginia and has a basis in the hands of the person acquiring it, determined in whole or in part by reference to the basis of such property in the hands of the person from whom acquired or <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="26 USC 1014"><content><span normalizedCite="26 U.S.C. 1014">Internal Revenue Code § 1014 (a)<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#29854#1127#00000001014#1#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p><p><pre/><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Qualified zone investments"</emphasis> means the sum of qualified zone improvements and the cost of machinery, tools and equipment used in manufacturing tangible personal property within an enterprise zone. For purposes of this section, machinery, tools and equipment shall only be deemed to include the cost of such property which is placed in service in the enterprise zone on or after July 1, 1995. Machinery, tools and equipment shall not include the basis of any property: (i) for which a credit under this section was previously granted; (ii) which was previously placed in service in Virginia by the taxpayer, a related party as defined by <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="26 USC 267"><content><span normalizedCite="26 U.S.C. 267">Internal Revenue Code § 267 (b)<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#29854#1127#00000000267#1#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, or a trade or business under common control as defined by <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="26 USC 52"><content><span normalizedCite="26 U.S.C. 52">Internal Revenue Code § 52 (b)<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#29854#1127#00000000052#1#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; or (iii) which was previously in service in Virginia and has a basis in the hands of the person acquiring it, determined in whole or part by reference to the basis of such property in the hands of the person from whom acquired, or <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="26 USC 1014"><content><span normalizedCite="26 U.S.C. 1014">Internal Revenue Code § 1014 (a)<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#29854#1127#00000001014#1#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p><p><pre/><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Qualified zone resident"</emphasis> means an owner or tenant of real property located in an enterprise zone who expands or rehabilitates such real property to facilitate the conduct of a trade or business within the enterprise zone.</p><p><pre/><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Real property investment tax credit"</emphasis> means a credit against the taxes imposed by Articles 2 (<citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 58.1-320"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 58.1-320">§ 58.1-320<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000058#     1#          320#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> et seq.) and 10 (<citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 58.1-400"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 58.1-400">§ 58.1-400<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000058#     1#          400#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> et seq.) of Chapter 3, Chapter 12 (<citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 58.1-1200"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 58.1-1200">§ 58.1-1200<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000058#     1#         1200#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> et seq.), Article 1 (<citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 58.1-2500"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 58.1-2500">§ 58.1-2500<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000058#     1#         2500#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> et seq.) of Chapter 25, or Article 2 (<citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 58.1-2620"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 58.1-2620">§ 58.1-2620<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000058#     1#         2620#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> et seq.) of Chapter 26 of Title 58.1.</p><p><pre/><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Small qualified zone resident"</emphasis> means any qualified zone resident other than a large qualified zone resident.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b"/><heading><desig>B.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> For all taxable years beginning on and after July 1, 1995, but before July 1, 2005, a qualified zone resident shall be allowed a real property investment tax credit as set forth in this section.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c"/><heading><desig>C.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> For any small qualified zone resident, a real property investment tax credit shall be allowed in an amount equaling 30 percent of the qualified zone improvements. Any tax credit granted pursuant to this subsection is refundable; however, in no event shall the cumulative credit allowed to a small qualified zone resident pursuant to this subsection exceed $ 125,000 in any five-year period.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d"/><heading><desig>D.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> For any large qualified zone resident, a real property investment tax credit shall be allowed in an amount of up to five percent of such qualified zone investments. The percentage amount of the real property investment tax credit granted to a large qualified zone resident shall be determined by agreement between the Department and the large qualified zone resident, provided such percentage amount shall not exceed five percent. The real property investment tax credit provided by this subsection shall not exceed the tax imposed for such taxable year, but any credit not usable for the taxable year generated may be carried over until the full amount of such credit has been utilized.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_e"/><heading><desig>E.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The Department shall certify the nature and amount of qualified zone improvements and qualified zone investments eligible for a real property investment tax credit in any taxable year. Only qualified zone improvements and qualified zone investments that have been properly certified shall be eligible for the credit. Any form filed with the Department of Taxation or State Corporation Commission for the purpose of claiming the credit shall be accompanied by a copy of the certification furnished to the taxpayer by the Department. Any certification by the Department pursuant to this section shall not impair the authority of the Department of Taxation or State Corporation Commission to deny in whole or in part any claimed tax credit if the Department of Taxation or State Corporation Commission determines that the taxpayer is not entitled to such tax credit. The Department of Taxation or State Corporation Commission shall notify the Department in writing upon determining that a taxpayer is ineligible for such tax credit.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_f"/><heading><desig>F.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> In the case of a partnership, limited liability company or S corporation, the term "qualified zone resident" as used in this section means the partnership, limited liability company or S corporation. Credits granted to a partnership, limited liability company or S corporation shall be passed through to the partners, members or shareholders, respectively.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_g"/><heading><desig>G.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The Tax Commissioner shall have the authority to issue regulations relating to the computation and carryover of the credit provided under this section.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_h"/><heading><desig>H.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> In the first taxable year only, the credit provided in this section shall be prorated equally against the taxpayer's estimated payments made in the third and fourth quarters and the final payment, if such taxpayer is required to make quarterly payments.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_i"/><heading><desig>I.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Tax credits awarded under this section and under <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 59.1-280"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 59.1-280">§ 59.1-280<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000059#     1#          280#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> shall not exceed $ 7.5 million annually until the end of fiscal year 2019.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_j"/><heading><desig>J.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The provisions of this section shall apply only as follows:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_j_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> To those large qualified zone residents that have initiated use of enterprise zone tax credits pursuant to this section on or before July 1, 2005;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_j_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> To those large qualified zone residents that have signed agreements with the Commonwealth regarding the use of enterprise zone tax credits in accordance with this section on or before July 1, 2005.</p></bodyText></level></level><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p><citation normalizedCite="1995 VA CH 792"><content><span normalizedCite="1995 Va. Ch. 792">1995, c. 792<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1995#000792#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1997 VA CH 517"><content><span normalizedCite="1997 Va. Ch. 517">1997, cc. 517<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1997#000517#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1997 VA CH 634"><content><span normalizedCite="1997 Va. Ch. 634">634<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1997#000634#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1997 VA CH 669"><content><span normalizedCite="1997 Va. Ch. 669">669<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1997#000669#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1998 VA CH 759"><content><span normalizedCite="1998 Va. Ch. 759">1998, c. 759<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1998#000759#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2005 VA CH 863"><content><span normalizedCite="2005 Va. Ch. 863">2005, cc. 863<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2005#000863#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2005 VA CH 884"><content><span normalizedCite="2005 Va. Ch. 884">884<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2005#000884#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PV10-004G-K173-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 59.1.</desig><title>TRADE AND COMMERCE</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 22.</desig><title>ENTERPRISE ZONE ACT</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjA4OEVGODBENzY4NDcxM0IyQzA1OTEwQzVDODRBOUE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MzZCNTdCQ0Q2OTRDNDYxOTg2MTY2NTREQUVGNjBBQzE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RTYwRjBDQTc2RUU5NDVGQkEwNjMwMTExRkI4QjQwNEQ</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RkE2ODg4Mjk1MTE2NDgzOTk1NTVERDRBRUJFRUUxMjk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NjMzQjkyNzZDOUQ4NEQ2NEIyOEYxNkJCNzBGNTk1OEY</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NUUwRjE5Nzk1QUU0NEZGQTgxNjExMzg4QjMxQTYwMzI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NUFDMUUyMjFERDQ1NDg3NTg1NzVCNzQyMTU5QzlBODI</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Member Duties &amp; Liabilities</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDM4QzlDMjYxODY0NDYwNjg2OUFBMjVGNzYyQjFGMzQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NUFDMUUyMjFERDQ1NDg3NTg1NzVCNzQyMTU5QzlBODI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Governments</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjdEQjE4OUJDMzQxNDNEMEI0RTI1QUFCMzJENjEwRTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Financing</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Q0QyN0IxRDI1MTE0NDQ3NkEzMzZCMTBCMkE2QkM3RTM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MEY3NUIxODI2RjU2NEY0NzgwMDQyNjFDMEQ1QUExRjM</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Real Property Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QUUyRTcxRURBNEY2NEE2MDk3QzBCNzRDOEY0NTZDQzk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Impact Fees</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6M0RCOTBBQjUwOTg4NEE0OThDODM4MTU3OUUyNDFEREM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NjcyQTdEMEUxODYyNDY0OThFQTg1NUNGMjFBMTkxQ0M</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Tax Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OTNEM0E2OEE0RkQyNEY1MDhBQzdGMkQ4ODI4QTJDODE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QkFDMkYzNjc0NDQ4NDVGNkE4OTRBODgzOUM3RDdFREY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RDMzMjY1RUM1NjRGNEUxRUIxMUMyRDk4NjBFQUEyRjk</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NTg0MzYyNTU4M0VGNDIyMzgxMzUzQUZEMzIxRkNCMEE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Mzc5NjFFQjM2M0U3NEQ2NUI5RjMyNzFDRjU5NEY4NjI</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OUVBNjZBRDAyNkJFNDIxRDlCMDM2QzZFREJENTE1NDQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QTQ0Nzk5NDQyRkY4NEY5NUI3OTI1QzNDNUNERUY4MkQ</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MTdCMzZBOUNFNjAwNEZFM0E0NEU3ODJFM0EyRDMyNEI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RUYwREVBQ0NGQ0UxNDY2REE0MzMzMDE5RDRGNTEyNjg</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6ODIyOTM3NTQwMkM3NDkxNjk3NUVDRjhENjQ1QTQwMTQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MzRCRkI3RTBDNEE3NEQxQkE5Q0RGRTMxQTQyMkU4RDg</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUQwQzk1N0I3QUUyNDc5RkI0NDg1NjQ4MTY3RUIyQTY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6ODE3RjE0NUIxQzc1NEUyN0I0QkIxNTU1NUE1QTEwMjc</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Imposition of Tax</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QTA2MjBCODUyNEEzNDMxMjk4Qzc0RjEzM0ExMzQ3MTg7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MzRCRkI3RTBDNEE3NEQxQkE5Q0RGRTMxQTQyMkU4RDg</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Income &amp; Loss Computations</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NEJEQ0NBREE0RDY3NEM2MUIzNTQyQUFENzE5NEMyN0U7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Mzc5NjFFQjM2M0U3NEQ2NUI5RjMyNzFDRjU5NEY4NjI</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Investment Tax Credit</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6REI2QjZBMDVBRjMyNDRGMTg3MUQ5MTI4RkQ4Q0UyMjM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RUQ5RjkwMkMyQUQ3NEU1QThGQzYwNzU0RkIxQzQ2NEU</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Partnerships</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Q0Y5NzhEMkE3RTUzNEY3NThCMjU3NUY2NjYyMjk4NEM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NTJBRkNFNjAxRTE2NEM1NDgyNjBCMkQ1MTgyQkMxQ0Q</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Tax Liability Determination</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MzQyMUI1NjlFNzA4NDRBNUEwNkQ4QUZBNzFFNEExMzA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QTQ0Nzk5NDQyRkY4NEY5NUI3OTI1QzNDNUNERUY4MkQ</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification><classificationGroup classificationScheme="indexing-terms"><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem score="90"><className>Antitrust</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6REEyRTNDM0JGQzYyNEMyOEFGNTAwNUJEOUU1MDg4NjU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></classificationGroup></metadata></legislativeDoc>