<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#123#000036#        19#">Va. Code Ann. § 36-19</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_36-19"/><heading><desig>§ 36-19.</desig><title>Enumeration of powers</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><bodyText><p>An authority shall constitute a political subdivision of the Commonwealth with public and corporate powers, and having all the powers necessary or convenient to carry out and effectuate the purposes and provisions of this chapter, including the following powers in addition to others herein granted:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> To sue and to be sued; to have a seal and to alter the same at pleasure; to have perpetual succession; to make and execute contracts and other instruments necessary or convenient to the exercise of the powers of the authority; and to make, amend and repeal bylaws, rules and regulations, not inconsistent with law, to carry into effect the powers and purposes of the authority.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Within its area of operation, to prepare, carry out, acquire, lease and operate housing projects and residential buildings, and to provide for the construction, reconstruction, improvement, alteration or repair of any housing project, residential building, or any part thereof, and to construct, remodel or renovate any public building or other facility used for public purposes provided the authority is requested to do so by the governing body of the political subdivision wherein the public building or facility is located.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> To arrange or contract for the furnishing by any person or agency, public or private, of services, privileges, works, or facilities for, or in connection with, a housing project or the occupants thereof; and (notwithstanding anything to the contrary contained in this chapter or in any other provision of law) to include in any contract let in connection with a project, any provisions required to comply with any conditions which the federal government may have attached to its financial aid of the project.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_4"/><heading><desig>4.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> In connection with any housing project: to lease or rent any dwelling, houses, accommodations, lands, buildings, structures or facilities embraced in any housing project and (subject to the limitations contained in this chapter) to establish and revise the rents or charges therefor; to own, hold, and improve real or personal property; to purchase, lease, obtain options upon, acquire by gift, grant, bequest, devise, or otherwise any real or personal property or any interest therein; to acquire by the exercise of the power of eminent domain any real property; to sell, lease, exchange, transfer, assign, pledge or dispose of any real or personal property or any interest therein; to insure or provide for the insurance of any real or personal property or operations of the authority against any risks or hazards, to procure or agree to the procurement of insurance or guarantees from the federal government of the payment of any bonds or parts thereof issued by an authority, including the power to pay premiums on any such insurance.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_5"/><heading><desig>5.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> To invest any funds held in reserves or sinking funds, or any funds not required for immediate disbursement, in property or security in which savings banks may legally invest funds subject to their control; to purchase its bonds at a price not more than the principal amount thereof and accrued interest, all bonds so purchased to be cancelled.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_6"/><heading><desig>6.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Within its area of operation, to investigate into living, dwelling and housing conditions and into the means and methods of improving such conditions; to determine where blighted or slum areas exist or where there is a shortage of decent, safe and sanitary dwelling accommodations for persons of low income; to make studies and recommendations relating to the problem of clearing, replanning and reconstructing of blighted or slum areas, and the problem of providing dwelling accommodations for persons of low income, and to cooperate with the locality, the Commonwealth or any other political subdivision thereof in action taken in connection with such problems; and to engage in research, studies and experimentation on the subject of housing.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_7"/><heading><desig>7.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> To make loans or grants for the prevention and elimination of blighted or slum areas and for assistance in housing construction or rehabilitation by private sponsors of any and all funds received through federal programs and any and all funds received from other sources, public or private including but not limited to, rehabilitation loans received pursuant to the provisions of § 312 of the Federal Housing Act of 1964, as amended and the Housing and Community Development Act of 1974.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_8"/><heading><desig>8.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Within its area of operation, to act as agent for a political subdivision or agency of the Commonwealth or for a federal agency in making construction or rehabilitation loans to persons of low or moderate income in accordance with the rules and regulations of the political subdivision or agency.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_9"/><heading><desig>9.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Within its area of operation to make grants, loans or refinance loans made by others for assistance in planning, development, acquisition, construction, repair, rehabilitation, equipping or maintenance of commercial, residential or other buildings; provided that prior approval of any such loan by the local governing body shall be required if the building is not located within a housing, redevelopment or conservation area, or rehabilitation area and provided further that any rehabilitation funded by any such grant or loan is in compliance with property maintenance standards contained in duly adopted redevelopment or conservation plans in effect in such area of operation.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_10"/><heading><desig>10.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> To borrow money and issue evidence of indebtedness in the name of and for the use of the authority, to issue bonds and other obligations, and give security therefor, subject to such limitations as may be imposed by law.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_11"/><heading><desig>11.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> To conduct examinations and investigations, and to make available to appropriate agencies (including those charged with the duty of abating or requiring the correction of nuisances or like conditions, or of demolishing unsafe or unsanitary structures within its area of operation) its findings and recommendations with regard to any building or property where conditions exist which are dangerous to the public health, morals, safety or welfare.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_12"/><heading><desig>12.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> With the approval of the local governing body or its designee, to form corporations, partnerships, joint ventures, trusts, or any other legal entity or combination thereof, on its own behalf or with any person or public or private entity.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_13"/><heading><desig>13.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> To exercise all or any part or combination of powers herein granted.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><bodyText><p><pre/>No provisions of law with respect to the acquisition, operation or disposition of property by other political subdivisions or public bodies shall be applicable to an authority unless the legislature shall specifically state.</p></bodyText></level><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p>1938, p. 450; Michie Code 1942, § 3145(8); 1971, Ex. Sess., c. 153; 1976, c. 510; 1977, c. 136; 1978, c. 679; 1982, c. 596; 1983, c. 27; 1984, cc. 350, 450; 1988, cc. 217, 416; <citation normalizedCite="1995 VA CH 193"><content><span normalizedCite="1995 Va. Ch. 193">1995, c. 193<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1995#000193#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2002 VA CH 548"><content><span normalizedCite="2002 Va. Ch. 548">2002, c. 548<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2002#000548#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2006 VA CH 784"><content><span normalizedCite="2006 Va. Ch. 784">2006, c. 784<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2006#000784#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PT30-004G-K3S5-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 36.</desig><title>HOUSING</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 1.</desig><title>HOUSING AUTHORITIES LAW</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="article"><heading><desig>ARTICLE 3.</desig><title>GENERAL POWERS OF AUTHORITY</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Accessibility, Construction &amp; Design</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OTExOTRCMkE4Mjg3NEVDOEJDRkZBQzNFNUU4Nzc1OTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Q0IyOTcxREY5OTBCNEI3N0I4NDBDOEJCQTJDMjc5NUM</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjA4OEVGODBENzY4NDcxM0IyQzA1OTEwQzVDODRBOUE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Property</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RjlENTVCNDU3NTMwNDA4MThDQTlDNjdBNjhFNjNCNzI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RUZBNTgwODk0QkRCNDUwQkExNzBFRkU0NkI4MkE5OTU</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Civil Procedure</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MzUxNjJDMEQ5N0YwNDMzM0JDMjEzM0UzOTYzMzI3OTU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDQ1MzNGQjY0MDg4NEFGNUI1M0MwNTNFRDREQjAwN0U7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RUQyRTFGQTg5NEU1NDQzODlBNUNCNUEzNTU5MjkzRTc</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Contracts Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QzY0RTZFMzE0RjkwNDdFQUI5M0U5N0ZFMjYyREMyQzU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QTdGQUE3QkZDMDlBNDQ1MTkzRjEzMEQ1OEUwNzdDOTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NjZEOEU3MEJBRUQ2NDNFNzhFRjAxRTk1OEU1QjY2QTc</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Governments</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjdEQjE4OUJDMzQxNDNEMEI0RTI1QUFCMzJENjEwRTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Community Redevelopment</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NUMwM0U5RjhBRkQ1NEQ5Qzk0RDk2QUJDNEU2NTVCQjE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MEY3NUIxODI2RjU2NEY0NzgwMDQyNjFDMEQ1QUExRjM</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Finance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjMzOTBBRTg2MUVDNDdDNUE1M0QxNDk1RERCNjNCN0I7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Njg1MkM3RkYyNzIxNEVFRkJFMTI2NUM4NUU1ODdEM0Q</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Insurance Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDM4MzQ2QUYzMTY0NDQzQTkxRDQwRUUzRUM5RDg0OEM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MTFDNEI4Q0Y0MTk0NDgyRTkzOEY5NDY2ODM1MkJFRUY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QzZFRUM3RDQ3M0Y1NDc1RUE2N0E4M0ZGQjY0MDk1MTY</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Public Contracts Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDA5QTlFMDVCQUY0NEY0NUE1QzMyQzA1QkQyQzJGRUY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Assignment &amp; Novation</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NTBDOUE5ODY2RkU2NDFGOUI5QjMzNDZGRkMxRUJCNkY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RDEzOEIxRUU2RDc4NDAxM0E2QzUwRkRGMUZCN0JDMkQ</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Public Health &amp; Welfare Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDYwRTY1MDg3MTk5NDUyNkFFRDI1RjJBRERGQ0UxNzI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Accessibility, Construction &amp; Design</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OTExOTRCMkE4Mjg3NEVDOEJDRkZBQzNFNUU4Nzc1OTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Q0IyOTcxREY5OTBCNEI3N0I4NDBDOEJCQTJDMjc5NUM</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Community &amp; Economic Development</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MEUxOUMwOTFCRDdFNEVFOUJFMjE2RDE0NERDOTM0QjY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDZDNTZENUNCRjVBNEY4OEIyQzVBNjRDRTcyOEQ4NDQ</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Real Property Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QUUyRTcxRURBNEY2NEE2MDk3QzBCNzRDOEY0NTZDQzk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Assignments</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6ODVCN0FCRTQ3MEE4NEJCRkE3OTRGOUQzODE4RDZENjc7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDU3NDIyNUI2MzczNEUwMzk0M0Y4MkZDQjk2OUUyRTQ</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Construction Loans</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RDNGMDlENjQ4NUYyNEM0MEIxRTAwMjAyRTdFRUNBRkY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MTY1MzRERDhBMDZCNDFBMDk0QUEwRjcyN0ZFNEY3REM</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QzNGRTg3NUQyRkMyNEZENEE5M0VDQ0RGMEFEQjc4MTQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MTY1MzRERDhBMDZCNDFBMDk0QUEwRjcyN0ZFNEY3REM</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Residential Leases</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NEIyMzc4RDNCMzc2NDA1NzhCOEY3MDhGMTMwQUM1RTc7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDU3NDIyNUI2MzczNEUwMzk0M0Y4MkZDQjk2OUUyRTQ</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></metadata></legislativeDoc>