<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#349#000016#     1#          252#">Va. Code Ann. § 16.1-252</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_16.1-252"/><heading><desig>§ 16.1-252.</desig><title>Preliminary removal order; hearing</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a"/><heading><desig>A.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A preliminary removal order in cases in which a child is alleged to have been abused or neglected may be issued by the court after a hearing wherein the court finds that reasonable efforts have been made to prevent removal of the child from his home. The hearing shall be in the nature of a preliminary hearing rather than a final determination of custody.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b"/><heading><desig>B.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Prior to the removal hearing, notice of the hearing shall be given at least 24 hours in advance of the hearing to the guardian ad litem for the child, to the parents, guardian, legal custodian or other person standing in loco parentis of the child and to the child if he or she is 12 years of age or older. If notice to the parents, guardian, legal custodian or other person standing in loco parentis cannot be given despite diligent efforts to do so, the hearing shall be held nonetheless, and the parents, guardian, legal custodian or other person standing in loco parentis shall be afforded a later hearing on their motion regarding a continuation of the summary removal order. The notice provided herein shall include (i) the time, date and place for the hearing; (ii) a specific statement of the factual circumstances which allegedly necessitate removal of the child; and (iii) notice that child support will be considered if a determination is made that the child must be removed from the home.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c"/><heading><desig>C.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> All parties to the hearing shall be informed of their right to counsel pursuant to <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 16.1-266"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 16.1-266">§ 16.1-266<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000016#     1#          266#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d"/><heading><desig>D.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> At the removal hearing the child and his parent, guardian, legal custodian or other person standing in loco parentis shall have the right to confront and cross-examine all adverse witnesses and evidence and to present evidence on their own behalf. If the child was 14 years of age or under on the date of the alleged offense and is 16 or under at the time of the hearing, the child's attorney or guardian ad litem, or if the child has been committed to the custody of the Department of Social Services, the local department of social services, may apply for an order from the court that the child's testimony be taken in a room outside the courtroom and be televised by two-way closed-circuit television. The provisions of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 63.2-1521"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 63.2-1521">§ 63.2-1521<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000063#     2#         1521#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> shall apply, mutatis mutandis, to the use of two-way closed-circuit television except that the person seeking the order shall apply for the order at least 48 hours before the hearing, unless the court for good cause shown allows the application to be made at a later time.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_e"/><heading><desig>E.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> In order for a preliminary order to issue or for an existing order to be continued, the petitioning party or agency must prove:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_e_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The child would be subjected to an imminent threat to life or health to the extent that severe or irremediable injury would be likely to result if the child were returned to or left in the custody of his parents, guardian, legal custodian or other person standing in loco parentis pending a final hearing on the petition; and</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_e_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Reasonable efforts have been made to prevent removal of the child from his home and there are no alternatives less drastic than removal of the child from his home which could reasonably and adequately protect the child's life or health pending a final hearing on the petition. The alternatives less drastic than removal may include but not be limited to the provision of medical, educational, psychiatric, psychological, homemaking or other similar services to the child or family or the issuance of a preliminary protective order pursuant to <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 16.1-253"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 16.1-253">§ 16.1-253<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000016#     1#          253#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p><p>When a child is removed from his home and there is no reasonable opportunity to provide preventive services, reasonable efforts to prevent removal shall be deemed to have been made.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_f"/><heading><desig>F.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> If the court determines that pursuant to subsection E hereof the removal of the child is proper, the court shall:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_f_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Order that the child be placed in the temporary care and custody of a suitable person, subject to the provisions of subsection F1 of this section and under the supervision of the local department of social services, with consideration being given to placement in the temporary care and custody of a relative or other interested individual, including grandparents, until such time as the court enters an order of disposition pursuant to <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 16.1-278.2"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 16.1-278.2">§ 16.1-278.2<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000016#     1#        278.2#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, or, if such placement is not available, in the care and custody of a suitable agency;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_f_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Order that reasonable visitation be allowed between the child and his parents, guardian, legal custodian or other person standing in loco parentis, and between the child and his siblings, if such visitation would not endanger the child's life or health; and</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_f_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Order that the parent or other legally obligated person pay child support pursuant to <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 16.1-290"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 16.1-290">§ 16.1-290<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000016#     1#          290#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p><p>In addition, the court may enter a preliminary protective order pursuant to <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 16.1-253"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 16.1-253">§ 16.1-253<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000016#     1#          253#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> imposing requirements and conditions as specified in that section which the court deems appropriate for protection of the welfare of the child.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_f1"/><heading><desig>F1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Prior to the entry of an order pursuant to subsection F of this section transferring temporary custody of the child to a relative or other interested individual, including grandparents, the court shall consider whether the relative or other interested individual is one who (i) is willing and qualified to receive and care for the child; (ii) is willing to have a positive, continuous relationship with the child; and (iii) is willing and has the ability to protect the child from abuse and neglect. The court's order transferring temporary custody to a relative or other interested individual should provide for compliance with any preliminary protective order entered on behalf of the child in accordance with the provisions of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 16.1-253"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 16.1-253">§ 16.1-253<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000016#     1#          253#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; initiation and completion of the investigation as directed by the court and court review of the child's placement required in accordance with the provisions of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 16.1-278.2"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 16.1-278.2">§ 16.1-278.2<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000016#     1#        278.2#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; and, as appropriate, ongoing provision of social services to the child and the temporary custodian.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_g"/><heading><desig>G.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> At the conclusion of the preliminary removal order hearing, the court shall determine whether the allegations of abuse or neglect have been proven by a preponderance of the evidence. Any finding of abuse or neglect shall be stated in the court order. However, if, before such a finding is made, a person responsible for the care and custody of the child, the child's guardian ad litem or the local department of social services objects to a finding being made at the hearing, the court shall schedule an adjudicatory hearing to be held within 30 days of the date of the initial preliminary removal hearing. The adjudicatory hearing shall be held to determine whether the allegations of abuse and neglect have been proven by a preponderance of the evidence. Parties who are present at the preliminary removal order hearing shall be given notice of the date set for the adjudicatory hearing and parties who are not present shall be summoned as provided in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 16.1-263"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 16.1-263">§ 16.1-263<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000016#     1#          263#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>. The hearing shall be held and an order may be entered, although a party to the preliminary removal order hearing fails to appear and is not represented by counsel, provided personal or substituted service was made on the person, or the court determines that such person cannot be found, after reasonable effort, or in the case of a person who is without the Commonwealth, the person cannot be found or his post office address cannot be ascertained after reasonable effort.</p><p>The preliminary removal order and any preliminary protective order issued shall remain in full force and effect pending the adjudicatory hearing.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_h"/><heading><desig>H.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> If the preliminary removal order includes a finding of abuse or neglect and the child is removed from his home or a preliminary protective order is issued, a dispositional hearing shall be held pursuant to <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 16.1-278.2"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 16.1-278.2">§ 16.1-278.2.<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000016#     1#        278.2#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> The dispositional hearing shall be scheduled at the time of the preliminary removal order hearing and shall be held within 60 days of the preliminary removal order hearing. If an adjudicatory hearing is requested pursuant to subsection G, the dispositional hearing shall nonetheless be scheduled at the initial preliminary removal order hearing. All parties present at the preliminary removal order hearing shall be given notice of the date scheduled for the dispositional hearing; parties who are not present shall be summoned to appear as provided in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 16.1-263"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 16.1-263">§ 16.1-263<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000016#     1#          263#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_i"/><heading><desig>I.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The local department of social services having "legal custody" of a child as defined in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 16.1-228"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 16.1-228">§ 16.1-228 (i)<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000016#     1#          228#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> shall not be required to comply with the requirements of this section in order to redetermine where and with whom the child shall live, notwithstanding that the child had been placed with a natural parent.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_j"/><heading><desig>J.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Violation of any order issued pursuant to this section shall constitute contempt of court.</p></bodyText></level><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p>1977, c. 559; 1984, c. 499; 1985, c. 584; 1986, c. 308; <citation normalizedCite="1990 VA CH 769"><content><span normalizedCite="1990 Va. Ch. 769">1990, c. 769<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1990#000769#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1994 VA CH 42"><content><span normalizedCite="1994 Va. Ch. 42">1994, c. 42<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1994#000042#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1995 VA CH 817"><content><span normalizedCite="1995 Va. Ch. 817">1995, c. 817<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1995#000817#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1997 VA CH 790"><content><span normalizedCite="1997 Va. Ch. 790">1997, c. 790<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1997#000790#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1999 VA CH 668"><content><span normalizedCite="1999 Va. Ch. 668">1999, c. 668<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1999#000668#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2000 VA CH 385"><content><span normalizedCite="2000 Va. Ch. 385">2000, c. 385<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2000#000385#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2008 VA CH 397"><content><span normalizedCite="2008 Va. Ch. 397">2008, c. 397<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2008#000397#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2013 VA CH 130"><content><span normalizedCite="2013 Va. Ch. 130">2013, c. 130<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2013#000130#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PW70-004G-K18B-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 16.1.</desig><title>COURTS NOT OF RECORD</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 11.</desig><title>JUVENILE AND DOMESTIC RELATIONS DISTRICT COURTS</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="article"><heading><desig>ARTICLE 4.</desig><title>IMMEDIATE CUSTODY, ARREST, DETENTION AND SHELTER CARE</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Civil Procedure</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MzUxNjJDMEQ5N0YwNDMzM0JDMjEzM0UzOTYzMzI3OTU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDFDNTVFNUY0MDdENDU1MDg3OTNEOTM5NEE5MzYzNDU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RTg2NzQwMzNGN0M4NEM3RUFGNUU5QzJGMTcxMTNFRUY</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Criminal Law &amp; Procedure</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NEU0RkE1OUQwNUQwNDgxODhEODZCMjkzOTg3NThBNzk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Child Witnesses</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDI4QTVFOTA3MzU3NEY0NzkxRURFNTE2MkYwMzMzMTk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OUI4QUY1MEJGQjk4NEFCMDlFMzMyOEQ1N0VFNUU0NEI</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NUIxQTE2NTMyRENCNDdFOUFBRTAyMEJGODFCQzA5RDA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6REVEMDZCMjVGNTNGNDlDN0E1QjBCRDJCMjNBQzdGNDg</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDIwRjc0N0I2NkE2NDI3QjkyMzI4NjFGNTc5MzQ1NEE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NEU4N0IwOEEwRjdCNEM5MzhCQzE0Njc3NTNFMDVGMTA</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Procedural Matters</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MURFRUY1Q0NBM0VGNDlGNzlGMzhCQjIxNDMyQTNCRDE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Rjc1RkU3OTY2QUYyNEM5N0JDRjc4OEZEQ0JFQTQ5OTY</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Right to Counsel During Questioning</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RkI4NzkxODEzOEJENDc5OUI0QzBGQzI3ODc5M0Q0REM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MEZDNDMxRkU5MTE2NDJFMTk4QjlENjk4RjE0NkM4Njg</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Time Limitations</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QzcwNkI2OTY4MDExNDU5MkE3RDUxRDdCNzczOTNBMEY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Rjc1RkU3OTY2QUYyNEM5N0JDRjc4OEZEQ0JFQTQ5OTY</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Family Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NEI4M0U5Qzg3RTk0NDdBRUJGNDRGNkZEQkU3RDdFNDU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Q0RCREM3QzU5OEVDNDlEM0FGRDgxQkQwRTFBOEREQzU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6N0UzRjg5QjhFNTdFNDQ3N0FEMUY0NTVEQkEzQ0M2RTA</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6REI1MDI3OTE1NDZENDYzRjlCNDgyNzFEMDc3MDNFQUE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RkE2MkE5MTUwMzk5NEJFN0E5RUFCRUIyNDg3RkU4Rjc</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NjA1MUYxNEQzQUZGNERBOUE5QUJFRDk0RDIwMEJBNzY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDkyNkUxNzIzNzZFNDI3OUI1MTI2NTBEOUMyNERGNTE</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Guardians Ad Litem</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NzRDMUI5QzVFNzc0NDk3ODhBQzg2RjQ1QTlFRUNGMTc7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OUJEMEI4NEQyMzdBNDczREJFOEYzQkZBOUMzMzc0MzM</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Public Health &amp; Welfare Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDYwRTY1MDg3MTk5NDUyNkFFRDI1RjJBRERGQ0UxNzI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NEQ3OEVEMjEwMEI4NEY1OTgyODZBMURDRkREMEM5RTg7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDZDNTZENUNCRjVBNEY4OEIyQzVBNjRDRTcyOEQ4NDQ</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification><classificationGroup classificationScheme="indexing-terms"><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem score="90"><className>Governments</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjdEQjE4OUJDMzQxNDNEMEI0RTI1QUFCMzJENjEwRTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></classificationGroup></metadata></legislativeDoc>