<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#123#000036#     55.26#">Va. Code Ann. § 36-55.26</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_36-55.26"/><heading><desig>§ 36-55.26.</desig><title>Definitions</title></heading><bodyText><p>As used in this chapter the following words and terms have the following meanings, unless a different meaning clearly appears from the context:</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Bonds," "notes," "bond anticipation notes,"</emphasis> and <emphasis typeStyle="it">"other obligations"</emphasis> mean any bonds, notes, debentures, interim certificates or other evidences of financial indebtedness issued by HDA pursuant to this chapter.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"City"</emphasis> means any city or town in the Commonwealth.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"County"</emphasis> means any county in the Commonwealth.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Earned surplus"</emphasis> shall have the same meaning as in generally accepted accounting standards.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Economically mixed project"</emphasis> means residential housing or housing development, which may consist of one or more buildings located on contiguous or noncontiguous parcels that the HDA determines to finance as a single economically mixed project, to be occupied by persons and families of low and moderate income and by other persons and families as the HDA shall determine.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Federal government"</emphasis> means the United States of America or any agency or instrumentality, corporate or otherwise, of the United States of America.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Federal mortgage"</emphasis> means a mortgage loan for land development for residential housing or residential housing made by the United States or an instrumentality thereof or for which there is a commitment by the United States of America or an instrumentality thereof to make such a mortgage loan.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Federally insured mortgage"</emphasis> means a mortgage loan for land development for residential housing or residential housing insured or guaranteed by the United States or an instrumentality thereof, or a commitment by the United States or an instrumentality thereof to insure such a mortgage.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"HDA"</emphasis> means the Virginia Housing Development Authority created and established pursuant to <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 36-55.27"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 36 -55.27">§ 36-55.27<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#123#000036#     55.27#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> of this chapter.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Housing development costs"</emphasis> means the sum total of all costs incurred in the development of a housing development, which are approved by the HDA as reasonable and necessary, which costs shall include, but are not necessarily limited to: fair value of land owned by the sponsor, or cost of land acquisition and any buildings thereon, including payments for options, deposits, or contracts to purchase properties on the proposed housing site or payments for the purchase of such properties; cost of site preparation, demolition and development; architecture, engineering, legal, accounting, HDA, and other fees paid or payable in connection with the planning, execution and financing of the housing development; cost of necessary studies, surveys, plans and permits; insurance, interest; financing, tax and assessment costs and other operating and carrying costs during construction; cost of construction, rehabilitation, reconstruction, fixtures, furnishings, equipment, machinery and apparatus related to the real property; cost of land improvements, including without limitation, landscaping and off-site improvements, whether or not such costs have been paid in cash or in a form other than cash; necessary expenses in connection with initial occupancy of the housing development; a reasonable profit and risk fee in addition to job overhead to the general contractor and, if applicable, a limited profit housing sponsor; an allowance established by HDA for working capital and contingency reserves, and reserves for any anticipated operating deficits during the first two years of occupancy; in the case of an economically mixed project within a revitalization area designated in or pursuant to <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 36-55.30:2"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 36 -55.30:2">§ 36-55.30:2<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#142#        36#     55.30#         2#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, the costs of any nonhousing buildings that are financed in conjunction with such project and that are incidental to such project or are determined by such governing body to be necessary or appropriate for the revitalization of such area or for the industrial, commercial or other economic development of such area; the cost of such other items, including tenant relocation, if such tenant relocation costs are not otherwise being provided for, as HDA shall determine to be reasonable and necessary for the development of the housing development, less any and all net rents and other net revenues received from the operation of the real and personal property on the development site during construction.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Housing development"</emphasis> or <emphasis typeStyle="it">"housing project"</emphasis> means any work or undertaking, whether new construction or rehabilitation, which is designed and financed pursuant to the provisions of this chapter for the primary purpose of providing sanitary, decent, and safe dwelling accommodations for persons and families of low or moderate income in need of housing and, in the case of an economically mixed project, other persons and families; such undertaking may include any buildings, land, equipment, facilities, or other real or personal properties which are necessary, convenient, or desirable appurtenances, such as but not limited to streets, sewers, utilities, parks, site preparation, landscaping, and such offices, and other nonhousing facilities incidental or related to such development or project such as administrative, community, health, nursing care, medical, educational and recreational facilities as HDA determines to be necessary, convenient, or desirable. For the purposes of this chapter, medical and related facilities for the residence and care of the aged shall be deemed to be dwelling accommodations.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Housing lender"</emphasis> means any bank or trust company, mortgage banker approved by the Federal National Mortgage Association, savings bank, national banking association, savings and loan association or building and loan association, mortgage broker, mortgage company, mortgage lender, life insurance company, credit union, agency or authority of the Commonwealth or any other state, or locality authorized to finance housing loans on properties located in or outside of the Commonwealth to persons and families of any income.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Housing sponsor"</emphasis> means individuals, joint ventures, partnerships, limited partnerships, public bodies, trusts, firms, associations, or other legal entities or any combination thereof, corporations, cooperatives and condominiums, approved by HDA as qualified either to own, construct, acquire, rehabilitate, operate, manage or maintain a housing development whether nonprofit or organized for limited profit subject to the regulatory powers of HDA and other terms and conditions set forth in this chapter.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Land development"</emphasis> means the process of acquiring land for residential housing construction, and of making, installing, or constructing nonresidential housing improvements, including, without limitation, waterlines and water supply installations, sewer lines and sewage disposal and treatment installations, steam, gas and electric lines and installations, roads, streets, curbs, gutters, sidewalks, storm drainage facilities, other related pollution control facilities, and other installations or works, whether on or off the site, which HDA deems necessary or desirable to prepare such land primarily for residential housing construction within the Commonwealth.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Loan servicer"</emphasis> means any person who, on behalf of a housing lender, collects or receives payments, including payments of principal, interest, escrow amounts, and other amounts due, on obligations due and owing to the housing lender pursuant to a residential mortgage loan or who, when the borrower is in default or in foreseeable likelihood of default, works on behalf of the housing lender with the borrower to modify or refinance, either temporarily or permanently, the obligations in order to avoid foreclosure or otherwise to finalize collection through the foreclosure process.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Mortgage"</emphasis> means a mortgage deed, deed of trust, or other security instrument which shall constitute a lien in the Commonwealth on improvements and real property in fee simple, on a leasehold under a lease having a remaining term, which at the time such mortgage is acquired does not expire for at least that number of years beyond the maturity date of the interest-bearing obligation secured by such mortgage as is equal to the number of years remaining until the maturity date of such obligation or on personal property, contract rights or other assets.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Mortgage lender"</emphasis> means any bank or trust company, mortgage banker approved by the Federal National Mortgage Association, savings bank, national banking association, savings and loan association, or building and loan association, life insurance company, the federal government or other financial institutions or government agencies which are authorized to and customarily provide service or otherwise aid in the financing of mortgages on residential housing located in the Commonwealth for persons and families of low or moderate income.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Mortgage loan"</emphasis> means an interest-bearing obligation secured by a mortgage.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Multifamily residential housing"</emphasis> means residential housing other than single-family residential housing, as hereinafter defined.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Municipality"</emphasis> means any city, town, county or other political subdivision of the Commonwealth.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Nonhousing building"</emphasis> means a building or portion thereof and any related improvements and facilities used or to be used for manufacturing, industrial, commercial, governmental, educational, entertainment, community development, healthcare or nonprofit enterprises or undertakings other than residential housing.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Persons and families of low and moderate income"</emphasis> means persons and families, irrespective of race, creed, national origin or sex, determined by the HDA to require such assistance as is made available by this chapter on account of insufficient personal or family income taking into consideration, without limitation, such factors as follows: (i) the amount of the total income of such persons and families available for housing needs, (ii) the size of the family, (iii) the cost and condition of housing facilities available, (iv) the ability of such persons and families to compete successfully in the normal private housing market and to pay the amounts at which private enterprise is providing sanitary, decent and safe housing, and (v) if appropriate, standards established for various federal programs determining eligibility based on income of such persons and families.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Real property"</emphasis> means all lands, including improvements and fixtures thereon, and property of any nature appurtenant thereto, or used in connection therewith, and every estate, interest and right, legal or equitable, therein, including terms for years and liens by way of judgment, mortgage or otherwise and the indebtedness secured by such liens.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Residential housing"</emphasis> means a specific work or improvement within the Commonwealth, whether multifamily residential housing or single-family residential housing undertaken primarily to provide dwelling accommodations, including the acquisition, construction, rehabilitation, preservation or improvement of land, buildings and improvements thereto, for residential housing, and such other nonhousing facilities as may be incidental, related, or appurtenant thereto. For the purposes of this chapter, medical and related facilities for the residence and care of the aged shall be deemed to be dwelling accommodations.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Single-family residential housing"</emphasis> means residential housing consisting of four or fewer dwelling units, the person or family owning or intending to acquire such dwelling units, upon completion of the construction, rehabilitation or improvement thereof, also occupying or intending to occupy one of such dwelling units.</p></bodyText><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p>1972, c. 830; 1975, c. 536; 1987, c. 363; 1988, c. 218; <citation normalizedCite="1996 VA CH 498"><content><span normalizedCite="1996 Va. Ch. 498">1996, c. 498<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1996#000498#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2004 VA CH 187"><content><span normalizedCite="2004 Va. Ch. 187">2004, c. 187<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2004#000187#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2011 VA CH 690"><content><span normalizedCite="2011 Va. Ch. 690">2011, c. 690<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2011#000690#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PT30-004G-K3V7-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 36.</desig><title>HOUSING</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 1.2.</desig><title>VIRGINIA HOUSING DEVELOPMENT AUTHORITY ACT</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Banking Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjQyMUFCOUJBNURBNEFDREE3MTNCNDk5QkQ4NUM3RjI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Federal Savings Associations</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Q0MyMUVFMUM2ODMyNDYyODlCRkMxODg1N0E3MjQwRTk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RTc3MUQ5Rjg4MjYzNENDQzk2QjQ0NzA5RjFDNzY0RDk</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Credit Unions</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Qjk2QUZBNDI1QUQxNEE1OTg1MUE4QUUxMEYwQ0M2REI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OUE0QUQ4OUIxOURCNDA3RUEyQkY0NzhBREMxNzk1RTM</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Local &amp; State Regulation</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6REJGMERERjc4MkRBNDc2OTgzNjk2RDgzNzFBNUM2QzY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDRBQjAyQkEzOTZFNEJCOEFEQjg3MjVEODM2QTM1REU</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjA4OEVGODBENzY4NDcxM0IyQzA1OTEwQzVDODRBOUE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RDVCRkUzRjg3NUFFNDMwNjhGMDc3MkNENDMxNzhFOEM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDFEQjUyNDAyMzQ0NDQyNUE5RjNGOEZEMzNBRDA1RUY</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Energy &amp; Utilities Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OUUzODAyRDk1QzVFNEZGMEJDM0RGMDYxOTlEMEEzRDA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Local &amp; State Regulation</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6REJGMERERjc4MkRBNDc2OTgzNjk2RDgzNzFBNUM2QzY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDRBQjAyQkEzOTZFNEJCOEFEQjg3MjVEODM2QTM1REU</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Siting of Facilities</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MzQyMTQxMDkzRjgzNDUxQ0JBMzIxNkM4QzVBMEE2OTE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MzMyRjFDNjRCQUVENEJBMkEzMjZEMUVBQzA2MUIwQ0I</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Estate, Gift &amp; Trust Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OENGNTY0MEQ2RTU2NDA2NTk4QjcyNzI2NTBERUU3NUI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Estates in Fee Simple</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Q0E3NUI1NDVCNTQ5NDMxNThFRjc2N0VGRjkyNEYzMEQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6ODk2NEYwQzY4MjVCNDE2RjlFOTNFQUJBODY5MUEwNzI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Insurance Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDM4MzQ2QUYzMTY0NDQzQTkxRDQwRUUzRUM5RDg0OEM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Credit Life Insurance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MTFFRTIyRUQwMkQ2NDM4M0JGM0FEQjQ0RDcyMUNEQUI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MzFEOTQ4RjM2RDk4NDJDNEJERDY1NjREOEVGMTRCOTA</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Credit Unions</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Qjk2QUZBNDI1QUQxNEE1OTg1MUE4QUUxMEYwQ0M2REI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OUE0QUQ4OUIxOURCNDA3RUEyQkY0NzhBREMxNzk1RTM</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Real Property Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QUUyRTcxRURBNEY2NEE2MDk3QzBCNzRDOEY0NTZDQzk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Construction Loans</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RDNGMDlENjQ4NUYyNEM0MEIxRTAwMjAyRTdFRUNBRkY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MTY1MzRERDhBMDZCNDFBMDk0QUEwRjcyN0ZFNEY3REM</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Federal National Mortgage Association</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjI2QzQwRTFCRTdCNDI0Njg4QzFERTI3MTY5MjY5NTE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6ODdGMkREOEEwRERENDA4RkJGRDVDMzBCNEVCNzg3QzQ</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QzNGRTg3NUQyRkMyNEZENEE5M0VDQ0RGMEFEQjc4MTQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MTY1MzRERDhBMDZCNDFBMDk0QUEwRjcyN0ZFNEY3REM</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUQ4QUQ1MjRFNkZENDJGNDgxN0JEQzcxNDc1Q0EyMjc7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDhDNTc4RkY3N0RDNDhDRkI1ODk3RjI2RkEyRTMwNEI</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NEUwMDJBRDEzMDgxNEREMzhCMDEyMERCQTk0OTczNzA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjE3QzYyNDEwRkVCNEFGQkIwNDU0RDUxQjU5RUU3OTg</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjEzOUJBMkVFMTkzNDlCQTkwQTM2Q0QwRkIyQUUwMTc7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6ODdGMkREOEEwRERENDA4RkJGRDVDMzBCNEVCNzg3QzQ</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Mortgagee's Interests</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MzQwOUI5Qjk2Qzg5NEJDNUFBODI4M0NFNjE0MzYwNzI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDhDNTc4RkY3N0RDNDhDRkI1ODk3RjI2RkEyRTMwNEI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></metadata></legislativeDoc>