<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#349#000004#     1#          206#">Va. Code Ann. § 4.1-206</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_4.1-206"/><heading><desig>§ 4.1-206.</desig><title>Alcoholic beverage licenses</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a"/><heading><desig>A.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The Board may grant the following licenses relating to alcoholic beverages generally:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Distillers' licenses, which shall authorize the licensee to manufacture alcoholic beverages other than wine and beer, and to sell and deliver or ship the same, in accordance with Board regulations, in closed containers, to the Board and to persons outside the Commonwealth for resale outside the Commonwealth. When the Board has established a government store on the distiller's licensed premises pursuant to subsection D of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 4.1-119"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 4.1-119">§ 4.1-119<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000004#     1#          119#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, such license shall also authorize the licensee to make a charge to consumers to participate in an organized tasting event conducted in accordance with subsection G of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 4.1-119"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 4.1-119">§ 4.1-119<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000004#     1#          119#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> and Board regulations.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Limited distiller's licenses, to distilleries that manufacture not more than 36,000 gallons of alcoholic beverages other than wine or beer per calendar year, provided (i) the distillery is located on a farm in the Commonwealth on land zoned agricultural and owned or leased by such distillery or its owner and (ii) agricultural products used by such distillery in the manufacture of its alcoholic beverages are grown on the farm. Limited distiller's licensees shall be treated as distillers for all purposes of this title except as otherwise provided in this subdivision. For purposes of this subdivision, "land zoned agricultural" means (a) land zoned as an agricultural district or classification or (b) land otherwise permitted by a locality for limited distillery use. For purposes of this subdivision, "land zoned agricultural" does not include land zoned "residential conservation." Except for the limitation on land zoned "residential conservation," nothing in this definition shall otherwise limit or affect local zoning authority.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Fruit distillers' licenses, which shall authorize the licensee to manufacture any alcoholic beverages made from fruit or fruit juices, and to sell and deliver or ship the same, in accordance with Board regulations, in closed containers, to the Board and to persons outside the Commonwealth for resale outside the Commonwealth.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_4"/><heading><desig>4.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Banquet facility licenses to volunteer fire departments and volunteer emergency medical services agencies, which shall authorize the licensee to permit the consumption of lawfully acquired alcoholic beverages on the premises of the licensee by any person, and bona fide members and guests thereof, otherwise eligible for a banquet license. However, lawfully acquired alcoholic beverages shall not be purchased or sold by the licensee or sold or charged for in any way by the person permitted to use the premises. Such premises shall be a volunteer fire or volunteer emergency medical services agency station or both, regularly occupied as such and recognized by the governing body of the county, city, or town in which it is located. Under conditions as specified by Board regulation, such premises may be other than a volunteer fire or volunteer emergency medical services agency station, provided such other premises are occupied and under the control of the volunteer fire department or volunteer emergency medical services agency while the privileges of its license are being exercised.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_5"/><heading><desig>5.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Bed and breakfast licenses, which shall authorize the licensee to (i) serve alcoholic beverages in dining areas, private guest rooms and other designated areas to persons to whom overnight lodging is being provided, with or without meals, for on-premises consumption only in such rooms and areas, and without regard to the amount of gross receipts from the sale of food prepared and consumed on the premises and (ii) permit the consumption of lawfully acquired alcoholic beverages by persons to whom overnight lodging is being provided in (a) bedrooms or private guest rooms or (b) other designated areas of the bed and breakfast establishment. For purposes of this subdivision, "other designated areas" includes outdoor dining areas, whether or not contiguous to the licensed premises, which may have more than one means of ingress and egress to an adjacent public thoroughfare, provided that such outdoor dining areas are under the control of the licensee and approved by the Board. Such noncontiguous designated areas shall not be approved for any retail license issued pursuant to subdivision A 5 of § 4.1-201.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_6"/><heading><desig>6.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Tasting licenses, which shall authorize the licensee to sell or give samples of alcoholic beverages of the type specified in the license in designated areas at events held by the licensee. A tasting license shall be issued for the purpose of featuring and educating the consuming public about the alcoholic beverages being tasted. A separate license shall be required for each day of each tasting event. No tasting license shall be required for conduct authorized by <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 4.1-201.1"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 4.1-201.1">§ 4.1-201.1.<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000004#     1#        201.1#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation></p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_7"/><heading><desig>7.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Museum licenses, which may be issued to nonprofit museums exempt from taxation under <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="26 USC 501"><content><span normalizedCite="26 U.S.C. 501">§ 501(c)(3) of the Internal Revenue Code<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#29854#1127#00000000501#1#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, which shall authorize the licensee to (i) permit the consumption of lawfully acquired alcoholic beverages on the premises of the licensee by any bona fide member and guests thereof and (ii) serve alcoholic beverages on the premises of the licensee to any bona fide member and guests thereof. However, alcoholic beverages shall not be sold or charged for in any way by the licensee. The privileges of this license shall be limited to the premises of the museum, regularly occupied and utilized as such.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_8"/><heading><desig>8.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Equine sporting event licenses, which may be issued to organizations holding equestrian, hunt and steeplechase events, which shall authorize the licensee to permit the consumption of lawfully acquired alcoholic beverages on the premises of the licensee by patrons thereof during such event. However, alcoholic beverages shall not be sold or charged for in any way by the licensee. The privileges of this license shall be (i) limited to the premises of the licensee, regularly occupied and utilized for equestrian, hunt and steeplechase events and (ii) exercised on no more than four calendar days per year.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_9"/><heading><desig>9.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Day spa licenses, which shall authorize the licensee to (i) permit the consumption of lawfully acquired wine or beer on the premises of the licensee by any bona fide customer of the day spa and (ii) serve wine or beer on the premises of the licensee to any such bona fide customer; however, the licensee shall not give more than two five-ounce glasses of wine or one 12-ounce glass of beer to any such customer, nor shall it sell or otherwise charge a fee to such customer for the wine or beer served or consumed. The privileges of this license shall be limited to the premises of the day spa regularly occupied and utilized as such.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_10"/><heading><desig>10.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Motor car sporting event facility licenses, which shall authorize the licensee to permit the consumption of lawfully acquired alcoholic beverages on the premises of the licensee by patrons thereof during such events. However, alcoholic beverages shall not be sold or charged for in any way, directly or indirectly, by the licensee. The privileges of this license shall be limited to those areas of the licensee's premises designated by the Board that are regularly occupied and utilized for motor car sporting events.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_11"/><heading><desig>11.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Meal-assembly kitchen license, which shall authorize the licensee to serve wine or beer on the premises of the licensee to any such bona fide customer attending either a private gathering or a special event; however, the licensee shall not give more than two five-ounce glasses of wine or two 12-ounce glasses of beer to any such customer, nor shall it sell or otherwise charge a fee to such customer for the wine or beer served or consumed. The privileges of this license shall be limited to the premises of the meal-assembly kitchen regularly occupied and utilized as such.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_12"/><heading><desig>12.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Canal boat operator license, which shall authorize the licensee to permit the consumption of lawfully acquired alcoholic beverages on the premises of the licensee by any bona fide customer attending either a private gathering or a special event; however, the licensee shall not sell or otherwise charge a fee to such customer for the alcoholic beverages so consumed. The privileges of this license shall be limited to the premises of the licensee, including the canal, the canal boats while in operation, and any pathways adjacent thereto. Upon authorization of the licensee, any person may keep and consume his own lawfully acquired alcoholic beverages on the premises in all areas and locations covered by the license.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_13"/><heading><desig>13.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Annual arts venue event licenses, to persons operating an arts venue, which shall authorize the licensee participating in a community art walk that is open to the public to serve lawfully acquired wine or beer on the premises of the licensee to adult patrons thereof during such events. However, alcoholic beverages shall not be sold or charged for in any way, directly or indirectly, by the licensee, and the licensee shall not give more than two five-ounce glasses of wine or one 12-ounce glass of beer to any one adult patron. The privileges of this license shall be (i) limited to the premises of the arts venue regularly occupied and used as such and (ii) exercised on no more than 12 calendar days per year.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_14"/><heading><desig>14.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Art instruction studio licenses, which shall authorize the licensee to serve wine or beer on the premises of the licensee to any such bona fide customer; however, the licensee shall not give more than two five-ounce glasses of wine or one 12-ounce glass of beer to any such customer, nor shall it sell or otherwise charge a fee to such customer for the wine or beer served or consumed. The privileges of this license shall be limited to the premises of the art instruction studio regularly occupied and utilized as such.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b"/><heading><desig>B.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Any limited distillery that, prior to July 1, 2016, (i) holds a valid license granted by the Alcoholic Beverage Control Board (the Board) in accordance with this title and (ii) is in compliance with the local zoning ordinance as an agricultural district or classification or as otherwise permitted by a locality for limited distillery use shall be allowed to continue such use as provided in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 15.2-2307"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 15.2-2307">§ 15.2-2307<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000015#     2#         2307#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, notwithstanding (a) the provisions of this section or (b) a subsequent change in ownership of the limited distillery on or after July 1, 2016, whether by transfer, acquisition, inheritance, or other means. Any such limited distillery located on land zoned residential conservation prior to July 1, 2016, may expand any existing building or structure and the uses thereof so long as specifically approved by the locality by special exception. Any such limited distillery located on land zoned residential conservation prior to July 1, 2016, may construct a new building or structure so long as specifically approved by the locality by special exception. All such licensees shall comply with the requirements of this title and Board regulations for renewal of such license or the issuance of a new license in the event of a change in ownership of the limited distillery on or after July 1, 2016.</p></bodyText></level><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p>Code 1950, § 4-25; 1952, c. 535; 1956, c. 520; 1962, c. 532; 1964, c. 210; 1970, cc. 627, 723; 1972, c. 679; 1973, c. 343; 1974, c. 267; 1975, c. 408; 1976, cc. 134, 447, 496, 703; 1977, c. 439; 1978, c. 190; 1979, c. 258; 1980, cc. 526, 528; 1981, cc. 410, 412; 1982, c. 66; 1984, c. 200; 1987, c. 365; 1988, c. 893; <citation normalizedCite="1989 VA CH 42"><content><span normalizedCite="1989 Va. Ch. 42">1989, c. 42<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1989#000042#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1990 VA CH 707"><content><span normalizedCite="1990 Va. Ch. 707">1990, c. 707<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1990#000707#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1991 VA CH 628"><content><span normalizedCite="1991 Va. Ch. 628">1991, c. 628<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1991#000628#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1992 VA CH 215"><content><span normalizedCite="1992 Va. Ch. 215">1992, cc. 215<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1992#000215#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1992 VA CH 350"><content><span normalizedCite="1992 Va. Ch. 350">350<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1992#000350#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1993 VA CH 866"><content><span normalizedCite="1993 Va. Ch. 866">1993, c. 866<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1993#000866#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1996 VA CH 584"><content><span normalizedCite="1996 Va. Ch. 584">1996, cc. 584<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1996#000584#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1996 VA CH 596"><content><span normalizedCite="1996 Va. Ch. 596">596<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1996#000596#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1998 VA CH 489"><content><span normalizedCite="1998 Va. Ch. 489">1998, c. 489<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1998#000489#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1999 VA CH 325"><content><span normalizedCite="1999 Va. Ch. 325">1999, c. 325<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1999#000325#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2005 VA CH 911"><content><span normalizedCite="2005 Va. Ch. 911">2005, c. 911<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2005#000911#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2006 VA CH 737"><content><span normalizedCite="2006 Va. Ch. 737">2006, cc. 737<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2006#000737#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2006 VA CH 826"><content><span normalizedCite="2006 Va. Ch. 826">826<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2006#000826#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2007 VA CH 101"><content><span normalizedCite="2007 Va. Ch. 101">2007, c. 101<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2007#000101#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2008 VA CH 198"><content><span normalizedCite="2008 Va. Ch. 198">2008, c. 198<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2008#000198#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2013 VA CH 476"><content><span normalizedCite="2013 Va. Ch. 476">2013, c. 476<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2013#000476#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2014 VA CH 510"><content><span normalizedCite="2014 Va. Ch. 510">2014, c. 510<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2014#000510#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2015 VA CH 348"><content><span normalizedCite="2015 Va. Ch. 348">2015, cc. 348<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2015#000348#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2015 VA CH 393"><content><span normalizedCite="2015 Va. Ch. 393">393<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2015#000393#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2015 VA CH 412"><content><span normalizedCite="2015 Va. Ch. 412">412<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2015#000412#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2015 VA CH 502"><content><span normalizedCite="2015 Va. Ch. 502">502<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2015#000502#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2015 VA CH 503"><content><span normalizedCite="2015 Va. Ch. 503">503<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2015#000503#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2015 VA CH 695"><content><span normalizedCite="2015 Va. Ch. 695">695<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2015#000695#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2016 VA CH 644"><content><span normalizedCite="2016 Va. Ch. 644">2016, c. 644<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2016#000644#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PTX0-004G-K01J-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 4.1.</desig><title>ALCOHOLIC BEVERAGE CONTROL ACT</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 2.</desig><title>ADMINISTRATION OF LICENSES</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="article"><heading><desig>ARTICLE 2.</desig><title>LICENSES GRANTED BY BOARD; LIMITATIONS; REVOCATION AND SUSPENSION</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Admiralty &amp; Maritime Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QzRDNDVDOTdGRUQ1NDE1M0I1RjRBRDFBRTI3ODFGMDk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Licensing &amp; Registration</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QkQ2NzAwOTIzNjIwNDJCQTkyRTYwQzM3RkY2NUJFNDk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NUNBQjc0Q0M5OTI5NEU1RUFCODY4OTgyODhCNkM0OTg</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Distribution, Processing &amp; Storage of Food &amp; Agricultural Products</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NENGNzZCMDU5RjcyNEM0NEFFOUU4ODFCQkZCOThBRkI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NkVDMzM4QkJENTg3NDQ0RDg3NTA5OEM3RkMyQTlENDI</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Licensing &amp; Registration</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6ODIzRDQwRTNBQUZBNDI2MTlFRjcxQTkyNEQzNzUyNzA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUJGMzIwOUU1NUY0NDU3MzhFRjhFRkMxQzgxOEI3MEY</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Vessel Licensing &amp; Registration</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QkQ2NzAwOTIzNjIwNDJCQTkyRTYwQzM3RkY2NUJFNDk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QzRDNDVDOTdGRUQ1NDE1M0I1RjRBRDFBRTI3ODFGMDk</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Civil Procedure</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MzUxNjJDMEQ5N0YwNDMzM0JDMjEzM0UzOTYzMzI3OTU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NUNCNTk2MkFDQTFGNDE5REJGNTBCRTk5MEFGMDZDNDE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Mjk4NzRCMDI4Q0IyNDc4MEE5ODA0RDc1MDU4RkQ2RjI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Criminal Law &amp; Procedure</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NEU0RkE1OUQwNUQwNDgxODhEODZCMjkzOTg3NThBNzk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Elements</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NTE4RkFBM0ExMzNENEU0MTlDN0RCMDE2OTZDRTdEN0Q7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MENDNzlDNTAzNUE1NEExQkIyOTZFMzYzNzZCMDlFMTI</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MzdBNTI0Mjg4MDNDNDEwN0FCNTE2RkY4RTRFMTI0NTY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QTFFQTQ3NTQ1M0IzNEUwQkE5QkFDNkM1RDNDMUJDMkU</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjM5NzFCMDVCOEQ4NEUwNTk4NDZGQTM0NzM1NkRDN0M7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MENDNzlDNTAzNUE1NEExQkIyOTZFMzYzNzZCMDlFMTI</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NjQ3MTc3MEZFODg3NDMyMDg0NjNBNDdFRjJDMkRGMDU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RkJBQkZFMjg4NzBGNDI3NUI4N0FENzBDMTdCNkYyREE</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Governments</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjdEQjE4OUJDMzQxNDNEMEI0RTI1QUFCMzJENjEwRTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Administrative Boards</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QTYwRUFCMDc5MzQ5NDEyREFEQkU2NkE2MjRGQTlCNzY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Njg1MkM3RkYyNzIxNEVFRkJFMTI2NUM4NUU1ODdEM0Q</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Distribution, Processing &amp; Storage</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NENGNzZCMDU5RjcyNEM0NEFFOUU4ODFCQkZCOThBRkI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NkVDMzM4QkJENTg3NDQ0RDg3NTA5OEM3RkMyQTlENDI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Healthcare Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NkUxMkVDQjJDOEY5NDVDQ0E5NTFEMTlDMjIwNzVERjc7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NTVDMzIyNkJCMTRBNDI0NUJBOTlBOTYyMjQ0MDkyODU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QTJGRDdFQzgwODczNDI0NDgwMzEyM0JBOEQ2MUVDNjg</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Real Property Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QUUyRTcxRURBNEY2NEE2MDk3QzBCNzRDOEY0NTZDQzk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Variances</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RkIxOThDMjUxN0JFNEEwNkI3MDNEMTA2NzdBMzU5REI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NjcyQTdEMEUxODYyNDY0OThFQTg1NUNGMjFBMTkxQ0M</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Tax Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OTNEM0E2OEE0RkQyNEY1MDhBQzdGMkQ4ODI4QTJDODE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6M0I0RjYxOUVCQ0NENDE3NjkyQ0E0REVDNDQzMUEwRDA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MTZFRjlERTdEMjk0NEMwNUEzNzVBQUU4OEI4NjdFN0M</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RDlBNDNBN0ZFMUYyNEI0MjlBQjE0QjUyRDkzREE3N0I7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MEM1NzJCQkEzQTc0NDNFRjk3MDk3NjkyNUFCN0VCNTA</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Transportation Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RTYzRTk5RDVBQkQ2NDcwQzk2NTU3ODQ5OEE3NDlBNzk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Canal Boats</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MzVBN0JCOTRDQzgzNDA5RDlFMzQzQ0Y3QzI2RDRCRTU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OTRBRTk5NEIyQzA2NEI4MTk0NDI2RTFEMjdCMTg0RTg</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Infirmities</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RUIxQkM5QzAwM0M5NDUxMkI3NTVBNzc0MzNENUEwOTg7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6ODY1RjFBNDEzNUFBNEYzMjhCMjhDRkU1NDlCQ0U3RkU</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Licensing &amp; Registration</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6ODIzRDQwRTNBQUZBNDI2MTlFRjcxQTkyNEQzNzUyNzA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUJGMzIwOUU1NUY0NDU3MzhFRjhFRkMxQzgxOEI3MEY</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></metadata></legislativeDoc>