<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#349#000064#     2#         1307#">Va. Code Ann. § 64.2-1307</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_64.2-1307"/><heading><desig>§ 64.2-1307.</desig><title>Testamentary trustees under a will waiving accounts; waiver where beneficiary also trustee</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a"/><heading><desig>A.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> For purposes of this section, the term "sole beneficiary" means a person who is (i) the only income beneficiary who is entitled to the principal, or the remaining principal goes to the trustee's estate or (ii) the only income beneficiary and has either a general power of appointment over the principal or has a special power of appointment that is not limited to a particular class of persons.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b"/><heading><desig>B.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> If (i) the will of a decedent probated on or after July 1, 1993, contains a waiver of the obligations of the testamentary trustee nominated therein to account or (ii) the sole beneficiary of the trust also is a trustee, the trustee will not be required to file accounts with the commissioner of accounts.</p><p>Where the waiver is contained in the decedent's will, the trustee shall within 90 days after qualification notify in writing all beneficiaries of the trust, other than the trustee, who are adults, whose addresses are known to the trustee, and to whom income or principal of the trust could be currently distributed; provide each such beneficiary with a copy of the applicable provisions of the will; advise each such beneficiary of his right to require an annual accounting; and provide each such beneficiary with a copy of this section and annually thereafter provide each such beneficiary an accounting upon request. The trustee shall send to the commissioner of accounts a copy of the notice given to each beneficiary or, in the alternative, file a writing with the commissioner of accounts stating that the requirements of this section have been met. For receiving and filing such notice or writing, the commissioner of accounts shall be allowed a fee not to exceed $ 25.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c"/><heading><desig>C.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Language substantially in form and effect as follows shall be sufficient to constitute a waiver in the will of the decedent of the trustee's obligation to account: "I hereby direct that my trustee(s) shall not be required to file annual accounts with a court as otherwise required by Virginia law."</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d"/><heading><desig>D.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Notwithstanding a waiver in the will of the decedent or any prior consent of a beneficiary, any such adult beneficiary may, at any time during the administration of the trust, demand in a writing delivered to the trustee and to the commissioner of accounts that the trustee settle annually with the commissioner of accounts. Upon notice of such demand to the trustee and the commissioner of accounts, such trustee shall file an account with the commissioner of accounts for a period acceptable to the commissioner of accounts as though there were no waiver by the testator. The beneficiary making such demand may later revoke his demand by a writing delivered to the trustee and the commissioner of accounts. The demand for settlement of the trustee's account before the commissioner of accounts may also be made by the personal representative of a deceased beneficiary whose estate is a beneficiary, an attorney-in-fact for a beneficiary, a guardian of an incapacitated beneficiary, a committee of a convict or insane beneficiary, the duly qualified guardian of a minor, or if none exists, a custodial parent of a minor or by any minor who has attained 14 years of age.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_e"/><heading><desig>E.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Notwithstanding the provisions of this section, any trustee under a will of a decedent containing the requisite waiver, whenever probated, shall be relieved of the duty to file an inventory or annual accounts with the commissioner of accounts if the trustee (i) obtains the written consent of all adult beneficiaries, other than the trustee, to whom income or principal of the trust could be currently distributed, after providing those beneficiaries with the documents and information specified in subsection B, and (ii) files those consents with the commissioner of accounts on or before the date on which the inventory or next required accounting would otherwise be due. For receiving and filing such written consent, the commissioner of accounts shall be allowed a fee not to exceed $ 25.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_f"/><heading><desig>F.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Notwithstanding the provisions of this section, any trustee under a will of a decedent probated on or after July 1, 2010, shall be relieved of the duty to file an inventory or annual accounts with the commissioner of accounts if the will of the decedent does not direct the filing of such inventory or accounts and the trustee (i) obtains the written consent of all adult beneficiaries, other than the trustee, to whom income or principal of the trust could be currently distributed, after providing those beneficiaries with the documents and information specified in subsection B; (ii) obtains the written consent of the representatives of all incapacitated beneficiaries, other than the trustee, to whom income or principal of the trust could be currently distributed, after providing those representatives with the documents and information specified in subsection B; and (iii) files those consents with the commissioner of accounts on or before the date on which the inventory or next required accounting would otherwise be due. For receiving and filing such written consent, the commissioner of accounts shall be allowed a fee not to exceed $ 25. The consent of an incapacitated beneficiary may be made by the personal representative of a deceased beneficiary whose estate is a beneficiary, an attorney-in-fact for a beneficiary, a guardian of an incapacitated beneficiary, a committee of a convict or insane beneficiary, the duly qualified guardian of a minor, or if none exists, a custodial parent of a minor who is not also the trustee. Language substantially in form and effect as follows shall be sufficient to constitute a direction in the will of the decedent of the trustee's obligation to account: "I hereby direct that my trustee(s) shall be required to file annual accounts with a court as otherwise required by Virginia law."</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_g"/><heading><desig>G.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A circuit court having jurisdiction may order the filing of annual accounts if it deems such filings to be in the best interests of one or more beneficiaries of the trust.</p></bodyText></level><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p><citation normalizedCite="1993 VA CH 689"><content><span normalizedCite="1993 Va. Ch. 689">1993, c. 689<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1993#000689#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, § 26-17.7; <citation normalizedCite="2001 VA CH 73"><content><span normalizedCite="2001 Va. Ch. 73">2001, c. 73<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2001#000073#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2005 VA CH 821"><content><span normalizedCite="2005 Va. Ch. 821">2005, c. 821<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2005#000821#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2010 VA CH 197"><content><span normalizedCite="2010 Va. Ch. 197">2010, cc. 197<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2010#000197#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2010 VA CH 651"><content><span normalizedCite="2010 Va. Ch. 651">651<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2010#000651#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2012 VA CH 614"><content><span normalizedCite="2012 Va. Ch. 614">2012, c. 614<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2012#000614#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PW10-004G-K0RY-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 64.2.</desig><title>WILLS, TRUSTS, AND FIDUCIARIES</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="subtitle"><heading><desig>SUBTITLE IV.</desig><title>FIDUCIARIES AND GUARDIANS</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="part"><heading><desig>PART A.</desig><title>FIDUCIARIES</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 13.</desig><title>INVENTORIES AND ACCOUNTS</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Estate, Gift &amp; Trust Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OENGNTY0MEQ2RTU2NDA2NTk4QjcyNzI2NTBERUU3NUI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Accounting</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OTA4Qjc0MENGRkZCNEU5QkFEMTRCMEMwMzE1Njg0QjY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RDUzQjA0REZDODBDNDA4RDlGQ0JEMzcxQjU1RTkxNEQ</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RDFGMkQ1Q0UyNDdDNDAzOTg0RkUzMTM3MkJCRTc2OUE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NURBQTAzNDNEOTI1NEE0REFBQkZERkIyQjdFRkJBRkI</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Q0VEQ0U4QTFCMzc1NDkyQjgzMjNBQUJFREFDOEJCOTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NUQ4NThEMTk0MTQ4NDM3N0FGOEM5RkU2QUQ4RjA1MkQ</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QUYyRTI1QTg1RDVENEM1RUExOTczNDU0MkEzRDhFOTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NzgwQzFGOTA0NDM5NDVGMEE5NkRCNjQ1NEM2NkZEN0Y</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RkM5NEM1RTczNTEzNDMwREIzODZFNkU3MDk1RTcxMjI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RUEwMTQ5RDk2OTM4NEIyNDgwNTY2RTNBOUYyOTk1REQ</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDVBOTM4QkNERjQ3NDgzQUI5OEVFRDIzMDI4MkUzRjU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6REY3NUVGNDYyREFENDIzRTkxMUM3MTc1MTJCMjU2Q0Y</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Subsequent Written Instruments</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjcwRThFOUVDMDBCNEQ3M0FBNDhFOTlBMzZEQTEyRkY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QTg2MDkxMzJGMkIyNDE4REFGN0I0OEQ3MEU1QjAxNTY</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Trust Administration</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDVDOTFGMDRBNkUyNEUyQzlDODU3N0E5ODVGNEQ5NzE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NUQ4NThEMTk0MTQ4NDM3N0FGOEM5RkU2QUQ4RjA1MkQ</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Governments</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjdEQjE4OUJDMzQxNDNEMEI0RTI1QUFCMzJENjEwRTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Fiduciaries</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RDRDQjYwNDkxREQ4NDE4Nzk4QzY0QTIyMzYzOTM0REQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjdEQjE4OUJDMzQxNDNEMEI0RTI1QUFCMzJENjEwRTA</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Patent Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QkQzRkZBQjVFNkJCNDdGOEE3MjZGQUY1NkVCRUQ1QjU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RDhGMzM2Q0U3MzUxNDlEMTkwQTg1RUFGQzNGODI3Qjk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QUQyNTEyODBDQUYxNDlDODg3MUUwMTMzNEY1MTI2OEQ</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Tax Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OTNEM0E2OEE0RkQyNEY1MDhBQzdGMkQ4ODI4QTJDODE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Powers</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NUE4NTU1RTdDRTE0NEVDQjkyREEwOERCRjE5QkVFNjc7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Rjc4MjVCMzFFQUZBNEE4RDg0MEEwMDVCMzI2MTZCRDM</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification><classificationGroup classificationScheme="indexing-terms"><classification classificationScheme="legal"/></classificationGroup></metadata></legislativeDoc>