<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#349#000032#     1#          371#">Va. Code Ann. ยง 32.1-371</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="hierarchy-note"><heading><title>ยง 32.1-371. (Contingent expiration date -- see note) Recognition of Emergency Medical Services Personnel Licensure Interstate Compact</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><bodyText><p>The Recognition of Emergency Medical Services Personnel Licensure Interstate Compact is hereby enacted into law and entered into with all jurisdictions legally joining therein in the form substantially as follows:</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_1"/><heading><desig>SECTION 1.</desig><title> PURPOSE</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><bodyText><p>In order to protect the public through verification of competency and ensure accountability for patient-care-related activities, all states license emergency medical services (EMS) personnel, such as emergency medical technicians (EMTs), advanced EMTs, and paramedics. This compact is intended to facilitate the day-to-day movement of EMS personnel across state boundaries in the performance of their EMS duties as assigned by an appropriate authority and authorize state EMS offices to afford immediate legal recognition to EMS personnel licensed in a member state. This compact recognizes that states have a vested interest in protecting the public's health and safety through their licensing and regulation of EMS personnel and that such state regulation shared among the member states will best protect public health and safety. This compact is designed to achieve the following purposes and objectives:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_1_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Increase public access to EMS personnel;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_1_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Enhance the states' ability to protect the public's health and safety, especially patient safety;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_1_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Encourage the cooperation of member states in the areas of EMS licensure and regulation;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_1_4"/><heading><desig>4.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Support licensing of military members who are separating from an active duty tour and licensing of their spouses;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_1_5"/><heading><desig>5.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Facilitate the exchange of information between member states regarding EMS personnel licensure, adverse action, and significant investigatory information;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_1_6"/><heading><desig>6.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Promote compliance with the laws governing EMS personnel practice in each member state; and</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_1_7"/><heading><desig>7.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Invest all member states with the authority to hold EMS personnel accountable through the mutual recognition of member state licenses.</p></bodyText></level></level></level><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_2"/><heading><desig>SECTION 2.</desig><title> DEFINITIONS</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><bodyText><p>In this compact:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_2_a"/><heading><desig>A.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> "Advanced Emergency Medical Technician (AEMT)" means an individual licensed with cognitive knowledge and a scope of practice that corresponds to that level in the National EMS Education Standards and National EMS Scope of Practice Model.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_2_b"/><heading><desig>B.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> "Adverse action" means any administrative, civil, equitable, or criminal action permitted by a state's laws which may be imposed against licensed EMS personnel by a state EMS authority or state court, including, but not limited to, actions against an individual's license such as revocation, suspension, probation, consent agreement, monitoring or other limitation or encumbrance on the individual's practice, letters of reprimand or admonition, fines, criminal convictions, and state court judgments enforcing adverse actions by the state EMS authority.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_2_c"/><heading><desig>C.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> "Alternative program" means a voluntary, non-disciplinary substance abuse recovery program approved by a state EMS authority.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_2_d"/><heading><desig>D.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> "Certification" means the successful verification of entry-level cognitive and psychomotor competency using a reliable, validated, and legally defensible examination.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_2_e"/><heading><desig>E.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> "Commission" means the national administrative body of which all states that have enacted the compact are members.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_2_f"/><heading><desig>F.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> "Emergency medical technician (EMT)" means an individual licensed with cognitive knowledge and a scope of practice that corresponds to that level in the National EMS Education Standards and National EMS Scope of Practice Model.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_2_g"/><heading><desig>G.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> "Home state" means a member state where an individual is licensed to practice emergency medical services.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_2_h"/><heading><desig>H.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> "License" means the authorization by a state for an individual to practice as an EMT, AEMT, or paramedic or at a level in between EMT and paramedic.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_2_i"/><heading><desig>I.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> "Medical director" means a physician licensed in a member state who is accountable for the care delivered by EMS personnel.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_2_j"/><heading><desig>J.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> "Member state" means a state that has enacted this compact.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_2_k"/><heading><desig>K.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> "Privilege to practice" means an individual's authority to deliver emergency medical services in remote states as authorized under this compact.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_2_l"/><heading><desig>L.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> "Paramedic" means an individual licensed with cognitive knowledge and a scope of practice that corresponds to that level in the National EMS Education Standards and National EMS Scope of Practice Model.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_2_m"/><heading><desig>M.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> "Remote state" means a member state in which an individual is not licensed.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_2_n"/><heading><desig>N.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> "Restricted" means the outcome of an adverse action that limits a license or the privilege to practice.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_2_o"/><heading><desig>O.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> "Rule" means a written statement by the interstate Commission promulgated pursuant to Section 12 of this compact that is of general applicability; implements, interprets, or prescribes a policy or provision of the compact; or is an organizational, procedural, or practice requirement of the Commission and has the force and effect of statutory law in a member state and includes the amendment, repeal, or suspension of an existing rule.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_2_p"/><heading><desig>P.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> "Scope of practice" means defined parameters of various duties or services that may be provided by an individual with specific credentials. Whether regulated by rule, statute, or court decision, it tends to represent the limits of services an individual may perform.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_2_q"/><heading><desig>Q.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> "Significant investigatory information" means:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_2_q_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Investigative information that a state EMS authority, after a preliminary inquiry that includes notification and an opportunity to respond if required by state law, has reason to believe, if proved true, would result in the imposition of an adverse action on a license or privilege to practice; or</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_2_q_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Investigative information that indicates that the individual represents an immediate threat to public health and safety regardless of whether the individual has been notified and had an opportunity to respond.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_2_r"/><heading><desig>R.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> "State" means any state, commonwealth, district, or territory of the United States.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_2_s"/><heading><desig>S.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> "State EMS authority" means the board, office, or other agency with the legislative mandate to license EMS personnel.</p></bodyText></level></level></level><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_3"/><heading><desig>SECTION 3.</desig><title> HOME STATE LICENSURE</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_3_a"/><heading><desig>A.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Any member state in which an individual holds a current license shall be deemed a home state for purposes of this compact.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_3_b"/><heading><desig>B.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Any member state may require an individual to obtain and retain a license to be authorized to practice in the member state under circumstances not authorized by the privilege to practice under the terms of this compact.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_3_c"/><heading><desig>C.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A home state's license authorizes an individual to practice in a remote state under the privilege to practice only if the home state:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_3_c_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Currently requires the use of the National Registry of Emergency Medical Technicians (NREMT) examination as a condition of issuing initial licenses at the EMT and paramedic levels;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_3_c_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Has a mechanism in place for receiving and investigating complaints about individuals;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_3_c_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Notifies the Commission, in compliance with the terms herein, of any adverse action or significant investigatory information regarding an individual;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_3_c_4"/><heading><desig>4.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> No later than five years after activation of the compact, requires a criminal background check of all applicants for initial licensure, including the use of the results of fingerprint or other biometric data checks compliant with the requirements of the Federal Bureau of Investigation with the exception of federal employees who have suitability determination in accordance with <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="5 CFR 731.202"><content><span normalizedCite="5 C.F.R. 731.202">5 C.F.R. ยง 731.202<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#14829#571#000005#000000731 #                          202 #"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> and submit documentation of such as promulgated in the rules of the Commission; and</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_3_c_5"/><heading><desig>5.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Complies with the rules of the Commission.</p></bodyText></level></level></level><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_4"/><heading><desig>SECTION 4.</desig><title> COMPACT PRIVILEGE TO PRACTICE</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_4_a"/><heading><desig>A.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Member states shall recognize the privilege to practice of an individual licensed in another member state that is in conformance with Section 3.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_4_b"/><heading><desig>B.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> To exercise the privilege to practice under the terms and provisions of this compact, an individual must:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_4_b_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Be at least 18 years of age;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_4_b_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Possess a current unrestricted license in a member state as an EMT, AEMT, paramedic, or state recognized and licensed level with a scope of practice and authority between EMT and paramedic; and</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_4_b_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Practice under the supervision of a medical director.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_4_c"/><heading><desig>C.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> An individual providing patient care in a remote state under the privilege to practice shall function within the scope of practice authorized by the home state unless and until modified by an appropriate authority in the remote state as may be defined in the rules of the Commission.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_4_d"/><heading><desig>D.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Except as provided in Section 4 subsection C, an individual practicing in a remote state will be subject to the remote state's authority and laws. A remote state may, in accordance with due process and that state's laws, restrict, suspend, or revoke an individual's privilege to practice in the remote state and may take any other necessary actions to protect the health and safety of its citizens. If a remote state takes action, it shall promptly notify the home state and the Commission.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_4_e"/><heading><desig>E.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> If an individual's license in any home state is restricted or suspended, the individual shall not be eligible to practice in a remote state under the privilege to practice until the individual's home state license is restored.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_4_f"/><heading><desig>F.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> If an individual's privilege to practice in any remote state is restricted, suspended, or revoked, the individual shall not be eligible to practice in any remote state until the individual's privilege to practice is restored.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_5"/><heading><desig>SECTION 5.</desig><title> CONDITIONS OF PRACTICE IN A REMOTE STATE</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><bodyText><p>An individual may practice in a remote state under a privilege to practice only in the performance of the individual's EMS duties as assigned by an appropriate authority, as defined in the rules of the Commission, and under the following circumstances:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_5_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The individual originates a patient transport in a home state and transports the patient to a remote state;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_5_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The individual originates in the home state and enters a remote state to pick up a patient and provide care and transport of the patient to the home state;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_5_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The individual enters a remote state to provide patient care and/or transport within that remote state;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_5_4"/><heading><desig>4.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The individual enters a remote state to pick up a patient and provide care and transport to a third member state;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_5_5"/><heading><desig>5.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Other conditions as determined by rules promulgated by the Commission.</p></bodyText></level></level></level><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_6"/><heading><desig>SECTION 6.</desig><title> RELATIONSHIP TO EMERGENCY MANAGEMENT ASSISTANCE COMPACT</title></heading><bodyText><p>Upon a member state's governor's declaration of a state of emergency or disaster that activates the Emergency Management Assistance Compact (EMAC), all relevant terms and provisions of EMAC shall apply and to the extent any terms or provisions of this compact conflict with EMAC, the terms of EMAC shall prevail with respect to any individual practicing in the remote state in response to such declaration.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_7"/><heading><desig>SECTION 7.</desig><title> VETERANS, SERVICE MEMBERS SEPARATING FROM ACTIVE DUTY MILITARY, AND THEIR SPOUSES</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_7_a"/><heading><desig>A.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Member states shall consider a veteran, active military service member, and member of the National Guard and Reserves separating from an active duty tour, and a spouse thereof, who holds a current valid and unrestricted NREMT certification at or above the level of the state license being sought as satisfying the minimum training and examination requirements for such licensure.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_7_b"/><heading><desig>B.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Member states shall expedite the processing of licensure applications submitted by veterans, active military service members, and members of the National Guard and Reserves separating from an active duty tour, and their spouses.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_7_c"/><heading><desig>C.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> All individuals functioning with a privilege to practice under this Section remain subject to the adverse actions provisions of Section 8.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_8"/><heading><desig>SECTION 8.</desig><title> ADVERSE ACTIONS</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_8_a"/><heading><desig>A.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A home state shall have exclusive power to impose adverse action against an individual's license issued by the home state.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_8_b"/><heading><desig>B.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> If an individual's license in any home state is restricted or suspended, the individual shall not be eligible to practice in a remote state under the privilege to practice until the individual's home state license is restored.</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_8_b_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> All home state adverse action orders shall include a statement that the individual's compact privileges are inactive. The order may allow the individual to practice in remote states with prior written authorization from both the home state and remote state's EMS authority.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_8_b_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> An individual currently subject to adverse action in the home state shall not practice in any remote state without prior written authorization from both the home state and remote state's EMS authority.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_8_c"/><heading><desig>C.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A member state shall report adverse actions and any occurrences that the individual's compact privileges are restricted, suspended, or revoked to the Commission in accordance with the rules of the Commission.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_8_d"/><heading><desig>D.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A remote state may take adverse action on an individual's privilege to practice within that state.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_8_e"/><heading><desig>E.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Any member state may take adverse action against an individual's privilege to practice in that state based on the factual findings of another member state, so long as each state follows its own procedures for imposing such adverse action.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_8_f"/><heading><desig>F.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A home state's EMS authority shall investigate and take appropriate action with respect to reported conduct in a remote state as it would if such conduct had occurred within the home state. In such cases, the home state's law shall control in determining the appropriate adverse action.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_8_g"/><heading><desig>G.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Nothing in this compact shall override a member state's decision that participation in an alternative program may be used in lieu of adverse action and that such participation shall remain nonpublic if required by the member state's laws. Member states must require individuals who enter any alternative programs to agree not to practice in any other member state during the term of the alternative program without prior authorization from such other member state.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_9"/><heading><desig>SECTION 9.</desig><title> ADDITIONAL POWERS INVESTED IN A MEMBER STATE'S EMS AUTHORITY</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><bodyText><p>A member state's EMS authority, in addition to any other powers granted under state law, is authorized under this compact to:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_9_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Issue subpoenas for both hearings and investigations that require the attendance and testimony of witnesses and the production of evidence. Subpoenas issued by a member state's EMS authority for the attendance and testimony of witnesses, and/or the production of evidence from another member state, shall be enforced in the remote state by any court of competent jurisdiction, according to that court's practice and procedure in considering subpoenas issued in its own proceedings. The issuing state's EMS authority shall pay any witness fees, travel expenses, mileage, and other fees required by the service statutes of the state where the witnesses and/or evidence are located; and</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_9_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Issue cease and desist orders to restrict, suspend, or revoke an individual's privilege to practice in the state.</p></bodyText></level></level></level><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_10"/><heading><desig>SECTION 10.</desig><title> ESTABLISHMENT OF THE INTERSTATE COMMISSION FOR EMS PERSONNEL PRACTICE</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_10_a"/><heading><desig>A.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The compact states hereby create and establish a joint public agency known as the Interstate Commission for EMS Personnel Practice.</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_10_a_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The Commission is a body politic and an instrumentality of the compact states.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_10_a_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Venue is proper and judicial proceedings by or against the Commission shall be brought solely and exclusively in a court of competent jurisdiction where the principal office of the Commission is located. The Commission may waive venue and jurisdictional defenses to the extent it adopts or consents to participate in alternative dispute resolution proceedings.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_10_a_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Nothing in this compact shall be construed to be a waiver of sovereign immunity.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_10_b"/><heading><desig>B.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Membership, Voting, and Meetings.</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_10_b_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Each member state shall have and be limited to one (1) delegate. The responsible official of the state EMS authority or his designee shall be the delegate to this compact for each member state. Any delegate may be removed or suspended from office as provided by the law of the state from which the delegate is appointed. Any vacancy occurring in the Commission shall be filled in accordance with the laws of the member state in which the vacancy exists. In the event that more than one board, office, or other agency with the legislative mandate to license EMS personnel at and above the level of EMT exists, the governor of the state will determine which entity will be responsible for assigning the delegate.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_10_b_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Each delegate shall be entitled to one (1) vote with regard to the promulgation of rules and creation of bylaws and shall otherwise have an opportunity to participate in the business and affairs of the Commission. A delegate shall vote in person or by such other means as provided in the bylaws. The bylaws may provide for delegates' participation in meetings by telephone or other means of communication.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_10_b_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The Commission shall meet at least once during each calendar year. Additional meetings shall be held as set forth in the bylaws.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_10_b_4"/><heading><desig>4.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> All meetings shall be open to the public, and public notice of meetings shall be given in the same manner as required under the rulemaking provisions in Section 12.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_10_b_5"/><heading><desig>5.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The Commission may convene in a closed, nonpublic meeting if the Commission must discuss:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_10_b_5_a"/><heading><desig>a.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Noncompliance of a member state with its obligations under the compact;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_10_b_5_b"/><heading><desig>b.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The employment, compensation, discipline or other personnel matters, practices or procedures related to specific employees or other matters related to the Commission's internal personnel practices and procedures;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_10_b_5_c"/><heading><desig>c.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Current, threatened, or reasonably anticipated litigation;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_10_b_5_d"/><heading><desig>d.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Negotiation of contracts for the purchase or sale of goods, services, or real estate;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_10_b_5_e"/><heading><desig>e.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Accusing any person of a crime or formally censuring any person;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_10_b_5_f"/><heading><desig>f.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Disclosure of trade secrets or commercial or financial information that is privileged or confidential;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_10_b_5_g"/><heading><desig>g.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Disclosure of information of a personal nature where disclosure would constitute a clearly unwarranted invasion of personal privacy;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_10_b_5_h"/><heading><desig>h.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Disclosure of investigatory records compiled for law-enforcement purposes;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_10_b_5_i"/><heading><desig>i.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Disclosure of information related to any investigatory reports prepared by or on behalf of or for use of the Commission or other committee charged with responsibility of investigation or determination of compliance issues pursuant to the compact; or</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_10_b_5_j"/><heading><desig>j.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Matters specifically exempted from disclosure by federal or member state statute.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_10_b_6"/><heading><desig>6.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> If a meeting, or portion of a meeting, is closed pursuant to this provision, the Commission's legal counsel or designee shall certify that the meeting may be closed and shall reference each relevant exempting provision. The Commission shall keep minutes that fully and clearly describe all matters discussed in a meeting and shall provide a full and accurate summary of actions taken, and the reasons therefor, including a description of the views expressed. All documents considered in connection with an action shall be identified in such minutes. All minutes and documents of a closed meeting shall remain under seal, subject to release by a majority vote of the Commission or order of a court of competent jurisdiction.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_10_c"/><heading><desig>C.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The Commission shall, by a majority vote of the delegates, prescribe bylaws and/or rules to govern its conduct as may be necessary or appropriate to carry out the purposes and exercise the powers of the compact, including but not limited to:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_10_c_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Establishing the fiscal year of the Commission;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_10_c_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Providing reasonable standards and procedures:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_10_c_2_a"/><heading><desig>a.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> For the establishment and meetings of other committees; and</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_10_c_2_b"/><heading><desig>b.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Governing any general or specific delegation of any authority or function of the Commission;</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_10_c_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Providing reasonable procedures for calling and conducting meetings of the Commission, ensuring reasonable advance notice of all meetings, and providing an opportunity for attendance of such meetings by interested parties, with enumerated exceptions designed to protect the public's interest, the privacy of individuals, and proprietary information, including trade secrets. The Commission may meet in closed session only after a majority of the membership votes to close a meeting in whole or in part. As soon as practicable, the Commission must make public a copy of the vote to close the meeting revealing the vote of each member with no proxy votes allowed;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_10_c_4"/><heading><desig>4.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Establishing the titles, duties and authority, and reasonable procedures for the election of the officers of the Commission;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_10_c_5"/><heading><desig>5.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Providing reasonable standards and procedures for the establishment of the personnel policies and programs of the Commission. Notwithstanding any civil service or other similar laws of any member state, the bylaws shall exclusively govern the personnel policies and programs of the Commission;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_10_c_6"/><heading><desig>6.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Promulgating a code of ethics to address permissible and prohibited activities of Commission members and employees;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_10_c_7"/><heading><desig>7.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Providing a mechanism for winding up the operations of the Commission and the equitable disposition of any surplus funds that may exist after the termination of the compact after the payment and/or reserving of all of its debts and obligations;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_10_c_8"/><heading><desig>8.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Publishing its bylaws and filing a copy thereof, and a copy of any amendment thereto, with the appropriate agency or officer in each of the member states, if any;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_10_c_9"/><heading><desig>9.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Maintaining its financial records in accordance with the bylaws; and</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_10_c_10"/><heading><desig>10.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Meeting and taking such actions as are consistent with the provisions of this compact and the bylaws.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_10_d"/><heading><desig>D.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The Commission shall have the following powers:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_10_d_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> To promulgate uniform rules to facilitate and coordinate implementation and administration of this compact. The rules shall have the force and effect of law and shall be binding in all member states;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_10_d_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> To bring and prosecute legal proceedings or actions in the name of the Commission, provided that the standing of any state EMS authority or other regulatory body responsible for EMS personnel licensure to sue or be sued under applicable law shall not be affected;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_10_d_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> To purchase and maintain insurance and bonds;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_10_d_4"/><heading><desig>4.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> To borrow, accept, or contract for services of personnel, including, but not limited to, employees of a member state;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_10_d_5"/><heading><desig>5.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> To hire employees, elect or appoint officers, fix compensation, define duties, grant such individuals appropriate authority to carry out the purposes of the compact, and to establish the Commission's personnel policies and programs relating to conflicts of interest, qualifications of personnel, and other related personnel matters;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_10_d_6"/><heading><desig>6.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> To accept any and all appropriate donations and grants of money, equipment, supplies, materials, and services and to receive, utilize, and dispose of the same, provided that at all times the Commission shall strive to avoid any appearance of impropriety and/or conflict of interest;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_10_d_7"/><heading><desig>7.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> To lease, purchase, accept appropriate gifts or donations of, or otherwise own, hold, improve, or use any property, real, personal, or mixed, provided that at all times the Commission shall strive to avoid any appearance of impropriety;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_10_d_8"/><heading><desig>8.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> To sell convey, mortgage, pledge, lease, exchange, abandon, or otherwise dispose of any property, real, personal, or mixed;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_10_d_9"/><heading><desig>9.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> To establish a budget and make expenditures;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_10_d_10"/><heading><desig>10.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> To borrow money;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_10_d_11"/><heading><desig>11.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> To appoint committees, including advisory committees composed of members, state regulators, state legislators or their representatives, and consumer representatives and such other interested persons as may be designated in this compact and the bylaws;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_10_d_12"/><heading><desig>12.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> To provide and receive information from, and cooperate with, law-enforcement agencies;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_10_d_13"/><heading><desig>13.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> To adopt and use an official seal; and</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_10_d_14"/><heading><desig>14.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> To perform such other functions as may be necessary or appropriate to achieve the purposes of this compact consistent with the state regulation of EMS personnel licensure and practice.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_10_e"/><heading><desig>E.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Financing of the Commission.</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_10_e_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The Commission shall pay, or provide for the payment of, the reasonable expenses of its establishment, organization, and ongoing activities.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_10_e_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The Commission may accept any and all appropriate revenue sources, donations, and grants of money, equipment, supplies, materials, and services.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_10_e_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The Commission may levy on and collect an annual assessment from each member state or impose fees on other parties to cover the cost of the operations and activities of the Commission and its staff, which must be in a total amount sufficient to cover its annual budget as approved each year for which revenue is not provided by other sources. The aggregate annual assessment amount shall be allocated based upon a formula to be determined by the Commission, which shall promulgate a rule binding upon all member states.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_10_e_4"/><heading><desig>4.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The Commission shall not incur obligations of any kind prior to securing the funds adequate to meet the same; nor shall the Commission pledge the credit of any of the member states, except by and with the authority of the member state.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_10_e_5"/><heading><desig>5.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The Commission shall keep accurate accounts of all receipts and disbursements. The receipts and disbursements of the Commission shall be subject to the audit and accounting procedures established under its bylaws. However, all receipts and disbursements of funds handled by the Commission shall be audited yearly by a certified or licensed public accountant, and the report of the audit shall be included in and become part of the annual report of the Commission.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_10_f"/><heading><desig>F.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Qualified Immunity, Defense, and Indemnification.</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_10_f_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The members, officers, executive director, employees, and representatives of the Commission shall be immune from suit and liability, either personally or in their official capacity, for any claim for damage to or loss of property or personal injury or other civil liability caused by or arising out of any actual or alleged act, error, or omission that occurred, or that the person against whom the claim is made had a reasonable basis for believing occurred, within the scope of Commission employment, duties, or responsibilities, provided that nothing in this paragraph shall be construed to protect any such person from suit and/or liability for any damage, loss, injury, or liability caused by the intentional or willful or wanton misconduct of that person.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_10_f_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The Commission shall defend any member, officer, executive director, employee, or representative of the Commission in any civil action seeking to impose liability arising out of any actual or alleged act, error, or omission that occurred within the scope of Commission employment, duties, or responsibilities or that the person against whom the claim is made had a reasonable basis for believing occurred within the scope of Commission employment, duties, or responsibilities, provided that nothing herein shall be construed to prohibit that person from retaining his or her own counsel, and provided further that the actual or alleged act, error, or omission did not result from that person's intentional or willful or wanton misconduct.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_10_f_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The Commission shall indemnify and hold harmless any member, officer, executive director, employee, or representative of the Commission for the amount of any settlement or judgment obtained against that person arising out of any actual or alleged act, error, or omission that occurred within the scope of Commission employment, duties, or responsibilities or that such person had a reasonable basis for believing occurred within the scope of Commission employment, duties, or responsibilities, provided that the actual or alleged act, error, or omission did not result from the intentional or willful or wanton misconduct of that person.</p></bodyText></level></level></level><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_11"/><heading><desig>SECTION 11.</desig><title> COORDINATED DATABASE</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_11_a"/><heading><desig>A.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The Commission shall provide for the development and maintenance of a coordinated database and reporting system containing licensure, adverse action, and significant investigatory information on all licensed individuals in member states.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_11_b"/><heading><desig>B.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Notwithstanding any other provision of state law to the contrary, a member state shall submit a uniform data set to the coordinated database on all individuals to whom this compact is applicable as required by the rules of the Commission, including:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_11_b_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Identifying information;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_11_b_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Licensure data;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_11_b_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Significant investigatory information;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_11_b_4"/><heading><desig>4.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Adverse actions against an individual's license;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_11_b_5"/><heading><desig>5.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> An indicator that an individual's privilege to practice is restricted, suspended, or revoked;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_11_b_6"/><heading><desig>6.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Nonconfidential information related to alternative program participation;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_11_b_7"/><heading><desig>7.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Any denial of application for licensure and the reason(s) for such denial; and</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_11_b_8"/><heading><desig>8.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Other information that may facilitate the administration of this compact, as determined by the rules of the Commission.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_11_c"/><heading><desig>C.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The coordinated database administrator shall promptly notify all member states of any adverse action taken against, or significant investigative information on, any individual in a member state.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_11_d"/><heading><desig>D.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Member states contributing information to the coordinated database may designate information that may not be shared with the public without the express permission of the contributing state.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_11_e"/><heading><desig>E.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Any information submitted to the coordinated database that is subsequently required to be expunged by the laws of the member state contributing the information shall be removed from the coordinated database.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_12"/><heading><desig>SECTION 12.</desig><title> RULEMAKING</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_12_a"/><heading><desig>A.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The Commission shall exercise its rulemaking powers pursuant to the criteria set forth in this Section and the rules adopted thereunder. Rules and amendments shall become binding as of the date specified in each rule or amendment.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_12_b"/><heading><desig>B.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> If a majority of the legislatures of the member states rejects a rule, by enactment of a statute or resolution in the same manner used to adopt the compact, then such rule shall have no further force and effect in any member state.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_12_c"/><heading><desig>C.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Rules or amendments to the rules shall be adopted at a regular or special meeting of the Commission.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_12_d"/><heading><desig>D.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Prior to promulgation and adoption of a final rule or rules by the Commission, and at least sixty (60) days in advance of the meeting at which the rule will be considered and voted upon, the Commission shall file a Notice of Proposed Rulemaking:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_12_d_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> On the website of the Commission; and</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_12_d_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> On the website of each member state EMS authority or the publication in which each state would otherwise publish proposed rules.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_12_e"/><heading><desig>E.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The Notice of Proposed Rulemaking shall include:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_12_e_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The proposed time, date, and location of the meeting in which the rule will be considered and voted upon;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_12_e_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The text of the proposed rule or amendment and the reason for the proposed rule;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_12_e_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A request for comments on the proposed rule from any interested person; and</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_12_e_4"/><heading><desig>4.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The manner in which interested persons may submit notice to the Commission of their intention to attend the public hearing and any written comments.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_12_f"/><heading><desig>F.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Prior to adoption of a proposed rule, the Commission shall allow persons to submit written data, facts, opinions, and arguments, which shall be made available to the public.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_12_g"/><heading><desig>G.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The Commission shall grant an opportunity for a public hearing before it adopts a rule or amendment if a hearing is requested by:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_12_g_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> At least twenty-five (25) persons;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_12_g_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A governmental subdivision or agency; or</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_12_g_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> An association having at least twenty-five (25) members.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_12_h"/><heading><desig>H.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> If a hearing is held on the proposed rule or amendment, the Commission shall publish the place, time, and date of the scheduled public hearing.</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_12_h_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> All persons wishing to be heard at the hearing shall notify the executive director of the Commission or other designated member in writing of their desire to appear and testify at the hearing not less than five (5) business days before the scheduled date of the hearing.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_12_h_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Hearings shall be conducted in a manner providing each person who wishes to comment a fair and reasonable opportunity to comment orally or in writing.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_12_h_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> No transcript of the hearing is required, unless a written request for a transcript is made, in which case the person requesting the transcript shall bear the cost of producing the transcript. A recording may be made in lieu of a transcript under the same terms and conditions as a transcript. This subsection shall not preclude the Commission from making a transcript or recording of the hearing if it so chooses.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_12_h_4"/><heading><desig>4.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Nothing in this section shall be construed as requiring a separate hearing on each rule. Rules may be grouped for the convenience of the Commission at hearings required by this section.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_12_i"/><heading><desig>I.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Following the scheduled hearing date, or by the close of business on the scheduled hearing date if the hearing was not held, the Commission shall consider all written and oral comments received.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_12_j"/><heading><desig>J.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The Commission shall, by majority vote of all members, take final action on the proposed rule and shall determine the effective date of the rule, if any, based on the rulemaking record and the full text of the rule.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_12_k"/><heading><desig>K.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> If no written notice of intent to attend the public hearing by interested parties is received, the Commission may proceed with promulgation of the proposed rule without a public hearing.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_12_l"/><heading><desig>L.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Upon determination that an emergency exists, the Commission may consider and adopt an emergency rule without prior notice, opportunity for comment, or hearing, provided that the usual rulemaking procedures provided in the compact and in this section shall be retroactively applied to the rule as soon as reasonably possible, in no event later than ninety (90) days after the effective date of the rule. For the purposes of this provision, an emergency rule is one that must be adopted immediately in order to:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_12_l_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Meet an imminent threat to public health, safety, or welfare;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_12_l_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Prevent a loss of Commission or member state funds;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_12_l_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Meet a deadline for the promulgation of an administrative rule that is established by federal law or rule; or</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_12_l_4"/><heading><desig>4.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Protect public health and safety.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_12_m"/><heading><desig>M.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The Commission or an authorized committee of the Commission may direct revisions to a previously adopted rule or amendment for purposes of correcting typographical errors, errors in format, errors in consistency, or grammatical errors. Public notice of any revisions shall be posted on the website of the Commission. The revision shall be subject to challenge by any person for a period of thirty (30) days after posting. The revision may be challenged only on grounds that the revision results in a material change to a rule. A challenge shall be made in writing and delivered to the chair of the Commission prior to the end of the notice period. If no challenge is made, the revision will take effect without further action. If the revision is challenged, the revision may not take effect without the approval of the Commission.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_13"/><heading><desig>SECTION 13.</desig><title> OVERSIGHT, DISPUTE RESOLUTION, AND ENFORCEMENT</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_13_a"/><heading><desig>A.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Oversight.</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_13_a_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The executive, legislative, and judicial branches of state government in each member state shall enforce this compact and take all actions necessary and appropriate to effectuate the compact's purposes and intent. The provisions of this compact and the rules promulgated hereunder shall have standing as statutory law.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_13_a_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> All courts shall take judicial notice of the compact and the rules in any judicial or administrative proceeding in a member state pertaining to the subject matter of this compact which may affect the powers, responsibilities, or actions of the Commission.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_13_a_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The Commission shall be entitled to receive service of process in any such proceeding and shall have standing to intervene in such a proceeding for all purposes. Failure to provide service of process to the Commission shall render a judgment or order void as to the Commission, this compact, or promulgated rules.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_13_b"/><heading><desig>B.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Default, Technical Assistance, and Termination.</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_13_b_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> If the Commission determines that a member state has defaulted in the performance of its obligations or responsibilities under this compact or the promulgated rules, the Commission shall:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_13_b_1_a"/><heading><desig>a.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Provide written notice to the defaulting state and other member states of the nature of the default, the proposed means of curing the default, and/or any other action to be taken by the Commission; and</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_13_b_1_b"/><heading><desig>b.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Provide remedial training and specific technical assistance regarding the default.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_13_b_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> If a state in default fails to cure the default, the defaulting state may be terminated from the compact upon an affirmative vote of a majority of the member states, and all rights, privileges, and benefits conferred by this compact may be terminated on the effective date of termination. A cure of the default does not relieve the offending state of obligations or liabilities incurred during the period of default.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_13_b_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Termination of membership in the compact shall be imposed only after all other means of securing compliance have been exhausted. Notice of intent to suspend or terminate shall be given by the Commission to the governor, the majority and minority leaders of the defaulting state's legislature, and each of the member states.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_13_b_4"/><heading><desig>4.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A state that has been terminated from the compact is responsible for all assessments, obligations, and liabilities incurred through the effective date of termination, including obligations that extend beyond the effective date of termination.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_13_b_5"/><heading><desig>5.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The Commission shall not bear any costs related to a state that is found to be in default or that has been terminated from the compact, unless agreed upon in writing between the Commission and the defaulting state.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_13_b_6"/><heading><desig>6.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The defaulting state may appeal the action of the Commission by petitioning the U.S. District Court for the District of Columbia or the federal district where the Commission has its principal offices. The prevailing member shall be awarded all costs of such litigation, including reasonable attorney fees.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_13_c"/><heading><desig>C.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Dispute Resolution.</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_13_c_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Upon request by a member state, the Commission shall attempt to resolve disputes related to the compact that arise among member states and between member and nonmember states.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_13_c_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The Commission shall promulgate a rule providing for both mediation and binding dispute resolution for disputes as appropriate.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_13_d"/><heading><desig>D.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Enforcement.</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_13_d_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The Commission, in the reasonable exercise of its discretion, shall enforce the provisions and rules of this compact.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_13_d_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> By majority vote, the Commission may initiate legal action in the United States District Court for the District of Columbia or the federal district where the Commission has its principal offices against a member state in default to enforce compliance with the provisions of the compact and its promulgated rules and bylaws. The relief sought may include both injunctive relief and damages. In the event judicial enforcement is necessary, the prevailing member shall be awarded all costs of such litigation, including reasonable attorney fees.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_13_d_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The remedies herein shall not be the exclusive remedies of the Commission. The Commission may pursue any other remedies available under federal or state law.</p></bodyText></level></level></level><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_14"/><heading><desig>SECTION 14.</desig><title> DATE OF IMPLEMENTATION OF THE INTERSTATE COMMISSION FOR EMS PERSONNEL PRACTICE AND ASSOCIATED RULES, WITHDRAWAL, AND AMENDMENT</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_14_a"/><heading><desig>A.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The compact shall come into effect on the date on which the compact statute is enacted into law in the tenth member state. The provisions, which become effective at that time, shall be limited to the powers granted to the Commission relating to assembly and the promulgation of rules. Thereafter, the Commission shall meet and exercise rulemaking powers necessary to the implementation and administration of the compact.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_14_b"/><heading><desig>B.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Any state that joins the compact subsequent to the Commission's initial adoption of the rules shall be subject to the rules as they exist on the date on which the compact becomes law in that state. Any rule that has been previously adopted by the Commission shall have the full force and effect of law on the day the compact becomes law in that state.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_14_c"/><heading><desig>C.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Any member state may withdraw from this compact by enacting a statute repealing the same.</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_14_c_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A member state's withdrawal shall not take effect until six (6) months after enactment of the repealing statute.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_14_c_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Withdrawal shall not affect the continuing requirement of the withdrawing state's EMS authority to comply with the investigative and adverse action reporting requirements of this act prior to the effective date of withdrawal.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_14_d"/><heading><desig>D.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Nothing contained in this compact shall be construed to invalidate or prevent any EMS personnel licensure agreement or other cooperative arrangement between a member state and a nonmember state that does not conflict with the provisions of this compact.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_14_e"/><heading><desig>E.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> This compact may be amended by the member states. No amendment to this compact shall become effective and binding upon any member state until it is enacted into the laws of all member states.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_15"/><heading><desig>SECTION 15.</desig><title> CONSTRUCTION AND SEVERABILITY</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><bodyText><p>This compact shall be liberally construed so as to effectuate the purposes thereof. If this compact shall be held contrary to the constitution of any member state thereto, the compact shall remain in full force and effect as to the remaining member states. Nothing in this compact supersedes state law or rules related to licensure of EMS agencies.</p></bodyText></level></level><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p><citation normalizedCite="2016 VA CH 75"><content><span normalizedCite="2016 Va. Ch. 75">2016, cc. 75<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2016#000075#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2016 VA CH 107"><content><span normalizedCite="2016 Va. Ch. 107">107<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2016#000107#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PWF0-004G-K4FW-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright ยฉ 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 32.1.</desig><title>HEALTH</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 18.</desig><title>RECOGNITION OF EMS PERSONNEL LICENSURE INTERSTATE COMPACT</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Administrative Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NjMxMjc0MUIzQjkzNEM4MEI4NkZGQjVCREJCRDk4OUM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NUMwRjNCRUQ4NUI2NEIwMkI1RTcyRUEzRDgxMEZCMDQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6REJGNjMzRTJDMDRGNDM0Mjg3QjAxNTE2MDU2RjlDMDY</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Sovereign Immunity</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MkU3M0VEOTNCOUZGNDg0Q0IzRjA5OThBQTVCRTM1ODM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NjMxMjc0MUIzQjkzNEM4MEI4NkZGQjVCREJCRDk4OUM</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Civil Procedure</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MzUxNjJDMEQ5N0YwNDMzM0JDMjEzM0UzOTYzMzI3OTU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NUNCNTk2MkFDQTFGNDE5REJGNTBCRTk5MEFGMDZDNDE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Mjk4NzRCMDI4Q0IyNDc4MEE5ODA0RDc1MDU4RkQ2RjI</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Public Officials</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RUI1MUZDRUZDQkM2NDBBMDk2QTczNzdERjE0OUE5REE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Mjk4NzRCMDI4Q0IyNDc4MEE5ODA0RDc1MDU4RkQ2RjI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Contracts Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QzY0RTZFMzE0RjkwNDdFQUI5M0U5N0ZFMjYyREMyQzU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QTdGQUE3QkZDMDlBNDQ1MTkzRjEzMEQ1OEUwNzdDOTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NjZEOEU3MEJBRUQ2NDNFNzhFRjAxRTk1OEU1QjY2QTc</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Criminal Law &amp; Procedure</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NEU0RkE1OUQwNUQwNDgxODhEODZCMjkzOTg3NThBNzk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Fines</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NUY4M0RBNUNERDlGNEI1QUJFMDc4QzU5OTU4RjNDRTY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUIzQ0NGRDZERUU3NERCODg2MEZFMDI2RTI0RTA3RTc</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QkI1Q0REQzk1NzRENDZFRDlEQjc4NzM2MDQ2QkVCREM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RjY3NzQ2MTUzQUVENDQ0REFBN0Q5M0JFRjk1NDBGMDk</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Presentation</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RUIyMTA4Qjk2MERCNDFDMTg3ODZBQjdDNjBDMzRENUQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Q0I5OTMyMkI1NDE3NDUyMDhDM0NFRjU2OUQ2Q0YzQkU</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Substance Abuse Programs</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RTVFMjYwRkVBNUYwNDI4MUE2NEY3RUZBMkZDQUYwNjU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QUM4NjRENzc2NUY4NEQwMUEyQTdBNkM4MDhEQURCQjU</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Estate, Gift &amp; Trust Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OENGNTY0MEQ2RTU2NDA2NTk4QjcyNzI2NTBERUU3NUI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NTM0MTFFRkQ3M0E2NEQwREFFMzc3QjBDQjhEQjZEOTM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RkJCNEFGNEQyOEM1NEZBQ0ExREJFNUQyMDM5N0U2Rjg</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Evidence</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUVGQkU0QjJFMTIzNDNBM0FCNTVEQjAxQTM3RDcwOTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RDEyMzQyREQxODk1NDFCMEEzQTY5MEEwOTgwMTNFRjU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NjE0NTg5RTY2RjY1NDA4NTgzOEU0MkJDN0UzNDc5ODk</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDM3Nzk3MEFCRUNBNDFBOTk0NDJGNzAxOEQ0MEM3MUQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MTFEQjJDMUFBNzcwNDdBNUI3QjkxOTc1MjYzNDRFNDU</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6M0MzNjE5MkM3MjczNEM2RDlCMURBNTZGMENCQjMzNkY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QUFBMEM5OUVCQTVENDYxRTk4RTFFQTcxMzBGOTlBQTQ</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Governments</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjdEQjE4OUJDMzQxNDNEMEI0RTI1QUFCMzJENjEwRTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Claims By &amp; Against</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QzMzOUFCQTMxMDM3NDREMkJBMUFCNzlBQjY4Mjk2M0E7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MkM1MTYwRDE0NkJBNEVFMEIxQjM3RUE2NDRFQUFEODY</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Employees &amp; Officials</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NzhCNTkxRUNENDI5NDQxMDk3NkNGOTI5REE1RjI0QjM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MkM1MTYwRDE0NkJBNEVFMEIxQjM3RUE2NDRFQUFEODY</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Healthcare Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NkUxMkVDQjJDOEY5NDVDQ0E5NTFEMTlDMjIwNzVERjc7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6N0U1NEQ5NkFBQjhENEUyMjhDMjM2MjRFQkVBOTFDODI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MkIwM0E1RTM4NkY5NEU4QjhBM0RCNzc5QjE4RkIzOEI</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NTVDMzIyNkJCMTRBNDI0NUJBOTlBOTYyMjQ0MDkyODU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QTJGRDdFQzgwODczNDI0NDgwMzEyM0JBOEQ2MUVDNjg</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Labor &amp; Employment Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MTE3QUQwOTA0MUYzNDlCMEFFMjUwRUNDM0RDRkM5QzM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Employer Handbooks</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6N0UwMTQwQzQzMDhDNEIxOEFDMTI5RkVBRERFRjdEQTc7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MTVFNUFFREQyQzIwNEIwQThCMDMzQzEwNTBEN0U1QUU</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Employment Contract Formation</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RkQzQUVENUE2OTM5NDFBRjg4OUY0QzIxNDBERThFNUI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MTVFNUFFREQyQzIwNEIwQThCMDMzQzEwNTBEN0U1QUU</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Military &amp; Veterans Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NzM1OUEyRDNERTdENEU2MTk3RTlCNEJCRUY0NjRGRjQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Deliberations &amp; Voting</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RjU4NUFGMDZGNUU1NDJCQkFBOUQyMTFGMzM1RjBCMkQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6N0E1RThDM0QxMkM1NEI1RkIzODY1MUI2ODlCODg3RkI</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Investigations</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OEQwNTY3NDUxMUNFNDE1M0JBMTc1NjI0NzM3QjY0MTc7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6N0I2ODhGMjFEQTU4NDIzMjhEMzBDQzExMDg4MjAxQjY</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Marital Privileges</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6N0VBQkU4NTNCQzQ1NERBRDk4MzkxNzVFNDA5MkU1Mzk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NzFDNDZBQTcxNENCNDRFMzkxQ0M2NzgxMTY3ODIyQTY</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>US National Guard</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NTkwM0VGNDEwNEJENEExOEJGMzY1NUQxM0MwNzVGQjQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MEZGOTk3QzJDQUY1NDk5MDlDOTI5MDI4NDYxRDU5NjE</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Real Property Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QUUyRTcxRURBNEY2NEE2MDk3QzBCNzRDOEY0NTZDQzk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Compensatory Damages</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OTQwOTkxNzFDNzk0NDczRjg0MTIxNjYwRTVBNDIwNkQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MTcxREUxQjQ0NTE3NEE3MjlGQkQxQzFBQjAxQTZDNTE</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification><classificationGroup classificationScheme="indexing-terms"><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem score="90"><className>Healthcare</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NkUxMkVDQjJDOEY5NDVDQ0E5NTFEMTlDMjIwNzVERjc7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></classificationGroup></metadata></legislativeDoc>