<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#349#000053#     1#           10#">Va. Code Ann. § 53.1-10</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_53.1-10"/><heading><desig>§ 53.1-10.</desig><title>Powers and duties of Director</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><bodyText><p>The Director shall be the chief executive officer of the Department and shall have the following duties and powers:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> To supervise and manage the Department and its system of state correctional facilities;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> To implement the standards and goals of the Board as formulated for local and community correctional programs and facilities and lock-ups;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> To employ such personnel and develop and implement such programs as may be necessary to carry out the provisions of this title, subject to Chapter 29 (<citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 2.2-2900"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 2.2-2900">§ 2.2-2900<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000002#     2#         2900#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> et seq.) of Title 2.2, and within the limits of appropriations made therefor by the General Assembly;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_4"/><heading><desig>4.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> To establish and maintain a general system of schools for persons committed to the institutions and community-based programs for adults as set forth in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 53.1-67.7"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 53.1-67.7">§§ 53.1-67.7<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000053#     1#         67.7#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> and <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 53.1-67.8"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 53.1-67.8">53.1-67.8.<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000053#     1#         67.8#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> Such system shall include, as applicable, elementary, secondary, post-secondary, career and technical education, adult, and special education schools.</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_4_a"/><heading><desig>a.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The Director shall employ a Superintendent who will oversee the operation of educational and vocational programs in all institutions and community-based programs for adults as set forth in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 53.1-67.7"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 53.1-67.7">§§ 53.1-67.7<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000053#     1#         67.7#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> and <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 53.1-67.8"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 53.1-67.8">53.1-67.8<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000053#     1#         67.8#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> operated by the Department. The Department shall be designated as a local education agency (LEA) but shall not be eligible to receive state funds appropriated for direct aid to public education.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_4_b"/><heading><desig>b.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> When the Department employs a teacher licensed by the Board of Education to provide instruction in the schools of the correctional centers, the Department of Human Resource Management shall establish salary schedules for the teachers which endeavor to be competitive with those in effect for the school division in which the correctional center is located.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_4_c"/><heading><desig>c.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The Superintendent shall develop a functional literacy program for inmates testing below a selected grade level, which shall be at least at the twelfth grade level. The program shall include guidelines for implementation and test administration, participation requirements, criteria for satisfactory completion, and a strategic plan for encouraging enrollment in college or an accredited vocational training program or other accredited continuing education program.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_4_d"/><heading><desig>d.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> For the purposes of this section, the term "functional literacy" shall mean those educational skills necessary to function independently in society, including, but not limited to, reading, writing, comprehension, and arithmetic computation.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_4_e"/><heading><desig>e.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> In evaluating a prisoner's educational needs and abilities pursuant to <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 53.1-32.1"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 53.1-32.1">§ 53.1-32.1<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000053#     1#         32.1#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, the Superintendent shall create a system for identifying prisoners with learning disabilities.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_5"/><heading><desig>5.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> a. To make and enter into all contracts and agreements necessary or incidental to the performance of the Department's duties and the execution of its powers under this title, including, but not limited to, contracts with the United States, other states, and agencies and governmental subdivisions of this Commonwealth, and contracts with corporations, partnerships, or individuals which include, but are not limited to, the purchase of water or wastewater treatment services or both as necessary for the expansion or construction of correctional facilities, consistent with applicable standards and goals of the Board;</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_5_b"/><heading><desig>b.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Notwithstanding the Director's discretion to make and enter into all contracts and agreements necessary or incidental to the performance of the Department's duties and the execution of its powers under this title, upon determining that it shall be desirable to contract with a public or private entity for the provision of community-based residential services pursuant to Chapter 5 (<citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 53.1-177"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 53.1-177">§ 53.1-177<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000053#     1#          177#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> et seq.), the Director shall notify the local governing body of the jurisdiction in which the facility is to be located of the proposal and of the facility's proposed location and provide notice, where requested, to the chief law-enforcement officer for such locality when an offender is placed in the facility at issue;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_5_c"/><heading><desig>c.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Notwithstanding the Director's discretion to make and enter into all contracts and agreements necessary or incidental to the performance of the Department's duties and the execution of its powers under this title, upon determining that it is necessary to transport Virginia prisoners through or to another state and for other states to transport their prisoners within the Commonwealth, the Director may execute reciprocal agreements with other states' corrections agencies governing such transports that shall include provisions allowing each state to retain authority over its prisoners while in the other state.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_6"/><heading><desig>6.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> To accept, hold and enjoy gifts, donations and bequests on behalf of the Department from the United States government and agencies and instrumentalities thereof, and any other source, subject to the approval of the Governor. To these ends, the Director shall have the power to comply with such conditions and execute such agreements as may be necessary, convenient or desirable, consistent with applicable standards and goals of the Board;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_7"/><heading><desig>7.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> To collect data pertaining to the demographic characteristics of adults, and juveniles who are adjudicated as adults, incarcerated in state correctional institutions, including, but not limited to, the race or ethnicity, age, and gender of such persons, whether they are a member of a criminal gang, and the types of and extent to which health-related problems are prevalent among such persons. Beginning July 1, 1997, such data shall be collected, tabulated quarterly, and reported by the Director to the Governor and the General Assembly at each regular session of the General Assembly thereafter. The report shall be submitted as provided in the procedures of the Division of Legislative Automated Systems for the processing of legislative documents and reports;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_8"/><heading><desig>8.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> To make application to the appropriate state and federal entities so as to provide any prisoner who is committed to the custody of the state a Department of Motor Vehicles approved identification card that would expire 90 days from issuance, a copy of his birth certificate if such person was born in the Commonwealth, and a social security card from the Social Security Administration;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_9"/><heading><desig>9.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> To forward to the Commonwealth's Attorneys' Services Council, updated on a monthly basis, a list of all identified criminal gang members incarcerated in state correctional institutions. The list shall contain identifying information for each criminal gang member, as well as his criminal record;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_10"/><heading><desig>10.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> To give notice, to the attorney for the Commonwealth prosecuting a defendant for an offense that occurred in a state correctional facility, of that defendant's known gang membership. The notice shall contain identifying information for each criminal gang member as well as his criminal record;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_11"/><heading><desig>11.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> To designate employees of the Department with internal investigations authority to have the same power as a sheriff or a law-enforcement officer in the investigation of allegations of criminal behavior affecting the operations of the Department. Such employees shall be subject to any minimum training standards established by the Department of Criminal Justice Services under § 9.1-102 for law-enforcement officers prior to exercising any law-enforcement power granted under this subdivision. Nothing in this section shall be construed to grant the Department any authority over the operation and security of local jails not specified in any other provision of law. The Department shall investigate allegations of criminal behavior in accordance with a written agreement entered into with the Department of State Police. The Department shall not investigate any action falling within the authority vested in the Office of the State Inspector General pursuant to Chapter 3.2 (§ 2.2-307 et seq.) of Title 2.2 unless specifically authorized by the Office of the State Inspector General;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_12"/><heading><desig>12.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> To enforce and direct the Department to enforce regulatory policies promulgated by the Board prohibiting the possession of obscene materials, as defined in Article 5 (<citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 18.2-372"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 18.2-372">§ 18.2-372<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000018#     2#          372#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> et seq.) of Chapter 8 of Title 18.2, by prisoners incarcerated in state correctional facilities; and</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_13"/><heading><desig>13.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> To develop and administer a survey of each correctional officer, as defined in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 53.1-1"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 53.1-1">§ 53.1-1<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000053#     1#            1#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, who resigns, is terminated, or is transitioned to a position other than correctional officer for the purpose of evaluating employment conditions and factors that contribute to or impede the retention of correctional officers.</p></bodyText></level></level><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p>Code 1950, §§ 53-19.8, 53-19.14; 1974, cc. 44, 45; 1982, c. 636; 1994, 2nd Sp. Sess., c. 7; <citation normalizedCite="1995 VA CH 725"><content><span normalizedCite="1995 Va. Ch. 725">1995, c. 725<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1995#000725#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1997 VA CH 894"><content><span normalizedCite="1997 Va. Ch. 894">1997, c. 894<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1997#000894#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2003 VA CH 94"><content><span normalizedCite="2003 Va. Ch. 94">2003, cc. 94<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2003#000094#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2003 VA CH 516"><content><span normalizedCite="2003 Va. Ch. 516">516<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2003#000516#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2003 VA CH 854"><content><span normalizedCite="2003 Va. Ch. 854">854<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2003#000854#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2006 VA CH 431"><content><span normalizedCite="2006 Va. Ch. 431">2006, cc. 431<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2006#000431#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2006 VA CH 500"><content><span normalizedCite="2006 Va. Ch. 500">500<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2006#000500#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2007 VA CH 392"><content><span normalizedCite="2007 Va. Ch. 392">2007, c. 392<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2007#000392#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2009 VA CH 39"><content><span normalizedCite="2009 Va. Ch. 39">2009, cc. 39<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2009#000039#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2009 VA CH 621"><content><span normalizedCite="2009 Va. Ch. 621">621<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2009#000621#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2012 VA CH 803"><content><span normalizedCite="2012 Va. Ch. 803">2012, cc. 803<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2012#000803#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2012 VA CH 835"><content><span normalizedCite="2012 Va. Ch. 835">835<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2012#000835#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2013 VA CH 143"><content><span normalizedCite="2013 Va. Ch. 143">2013, cc. 143<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2013#000143#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2013 VA CH 214"><content><span normalizedCite="2013 Va. Ch. 214">214<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2013#000214#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2014 VA CH 84"><content><span normalizedCite="2014 Va. Ch. 84">2014, c. 84<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2014#000084#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2015 VA CH 99"><content><span normalizedCite="2015 Va. Ch. 99">2015, cc. 99<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2015#000099#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2015 VA CH 293"><content><span normalizedCite="2015 Va. Ch. 293">293<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2015#000293#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2016 VA CH 205"><content><span normalizedCite="2016 Va. Ch. 205">2016, c. 205<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2016#000205#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PT80-004G-K1KK-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 53.1.</desig><title>PRISONS AND OTHER METHODS OF CORRECTION</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 1.</desig><title>ADMINISTRATION GENERALLY</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="article"><heading><desig>ARTICLE 3.</desig><title>DEPARTMENT OF CORRECTIONS AND DIRECTOR OF CORRECTIONS</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Contracts Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QzY0RTZFMzE0RjkwNDdFQUI5M0U5N0ZFMjYyREMyQzU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Reciprocal Contracts</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RjA0N0U4RjM3Nzc1NDUzOThFOUU0MENGOUY1M0EwQzU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Qjg1NzgyRDNGQzg1NEM5Nzg3RjA3MEUwRTA1QUI0NkU</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Criminal Law &amp; Procedure</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NEU0RkE1OUQwNUQwNDgxODhEODZCMjkzOTg3NThBNzk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Imprisonment</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NURCMTExOEEzNDJBNDk4RjhFQTQ0NzEwMzc0OTg3RTE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QTFGRjg4NjA3RTg1NDA2RkIzMDk4QzdGREIyQzVGMDk</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Education Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDkzNUEzQzFBNEZBNEFBREIxNDM5MTc1MUU5QjI4MTY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Allocation of Funds</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RTk0MTc3MzdGQkU0NDI1OEFGOTA3NTkyRTJFM0VCQTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjZBQUM2RjM4QkI4NDlFMkFCNTBDMzJGNDg0MTgxOUU</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Salary Schedules</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RDJCREJFNkI0RjQ1NERCQjk3QkU1MDAxRTA5Q0U3NDc7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RkQwQkFBMERCREE4NDQ4N0FCQzNGRDg3QjgwMEQ3RjY</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Estate, Gift &amp; Trust Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OENGNTY0MEQ2RTU2NDA2NTk4QjcyNzI2NTBERUU3NUI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NTM0MTFFRkQ3M0E2NEQwREFFMzc3QjBDQjhEQjZEOTM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RkJCNEFGNEQyOEM1NEZBQ0ExREJFNUQyMDM5N0U2Rjg</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></metadata></legislativeDoc>