<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#349#000037#     2#        817.2#">Va. Code Ann. § 37.2-817.2</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_37.2-817.2"/><heading><desig>§ 37.2-817.2.</desig><title>Court review of mandatory outpatient treatment plan or discharge plan</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a"/><heading><desig>A.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The district court judge or special justice shall hold a hearing within five days after receiving the petition for review of the mandatory outpatient treatment plan or discharge plan; however, if the fifth day is a Saturday, Sunday, legal holiday, or day on which the court is lawfully closed, the hearing shall be held by the close of business on the next day that is not a Saturday, Sunday, legal holiday, or day on which the court is lawfully closed. If the person is being detained under a temporary detention order, the hearing shall be scheduled within the same time frame provided for a commitment hearing under § 37.2-814. The clerk shall provide notice of the hearing to the person, the community services board, all treatment providers listed in the comprehensive mandatory outpatient treatment order or discharge plan, and the original petitioner for the person's involuntary treatment. If the person is not represented by counsel, the court shall appoint an attorney to represent the person in this hearing and any subsequent hearings under <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 37.2-817.3"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 37.2-817.3">§§ 37.2-817.3<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000037#     2#        817.3#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> and <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 37.2-817.4"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 37.2-817.4">37.2-817.4<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000037#     2#        817.4#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, giving consideration to appointing the attorney who represented the person at the proceeding that resulted in the issuance of the mandatory outpatient treatment order or order authorizing discharge to mandatory outpatient treatment following inpatient treatment. The same judge or special justice that presided over the hearing resulting in the mandatory outpatient treatment order or order authorizing discharge to mandatory outpatient treatment following inpatient treatment need not preside at the noncompliance hearing or any subsequent hearings. The community services board shall offer to arrange the person's transportation to the hearing if the person is not detained and has no other source of transportation.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b"/><heading><desig>B.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> If requested by the person, the community services board, a treatment provider listed in the comprehensive mandatory outpatient treatment plan or discharge plan, or the original petitioner for the person's involuntary treatment, the court shall appoint an examiner in accordance with <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 37.2-815"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 37.2-815">§ 37.2-815<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000037#     2#          815#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> who shall personally examine the person and certify to the court whether or not he has probable cause to believe that the person meets the criteria for involuntary inpatient admission or mandatory outpatient treatment as specified in subsections C, C1, C2, and D of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 37.2-817"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 37.2-817">§ 37.2-817<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000037#     2#          817#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>. The examination shall include all applicable requirements of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 37.2-815"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 37.2-815">§ 37.2-815<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000037#     2#          815#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>. The certification of the examiner may be admitted into evidence without the appearance of the examiner at the hearing if not objected to by the person or his attorney. If the person is not detained in an inpatient facility, the community services board shall arrange for the person to be examined at a convenient location and time. The community services board shall offer to arrange for the person's transportation to the examination, if the person has no other source of transportation and resides within the service area or an adjacent service area of the community services board. If the person refuses or fails to appear, the community services board shall notify the court, or a magistrate if the court is not available, and the court or magistrate shall issue a mandatory examination order and capias directing the primary law-enforcement agency in the jurisdiction where the person resides to transport the person to the examination. The person shall remain in custody until a temporary detention order is issued or until the person is released, but in no event shall the period exceed eight hours.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c"/><heading><desig>C.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> If the person fails to appear for the hearing, the court shall, after consideration of any evidence from the person, from the community services board, or from any treatment provider identified in the mandatory outpatient treatment plan or discharge plan regarding why the person failed to appear at the hearing, either (i) reschedule the hearing pursuant to subsection A, (ii) issue an emergency custody order pursuant to <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 37.2-808"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 37.2-808">§ 37.2-808<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000037#     2#          808#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, or (iii) issue a temporary detention order pursuant to <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 37.2-809"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 37.2-809">§ 37.2-809<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000037#     2#          809#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d"/><heading><desig>D.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> After hearing the evidence regarding the person's material noncompliance with the mandatory outpatient treatment order or order authorizing discharge to mandatory outpatient treatment following inpatient treatment and the person's current condition, and any other relevant information referenced in subsection C of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 37.2-817"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 37.2-817">§ 37.2-817<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000037#     2#          817#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, the judge or special justice shall make one of the following dispositions:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Upon finding by clear and convincing evidence that the person meets the criteria for involuntary admission and treatment specified in subsection C of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 37.2-817"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 37.2-817">§ 37.2-817<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000037#     2#          817#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, the judge or special justice shall order the person's involuntary admission to a facility designated by the community services board for a period of treatment not to exceed 30 days;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Upon finding that the person continues to meet the criteria for mandatory outpatient treatment specified in subsection C1, C2, or D of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 37.2-817"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 37.2-817">§ 37.2-817<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000037#     2#          817#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, and that a continued period of mandatory outpatient treatment appears warranted, the judge or special justice shall renew the order for mandatory outpatient treatment, making any necessary modifications that are acceptable to the community services board or treatment provider responsible for the person's treatment. In determining the appropriateness of outpatient treatment, the court may consider the person's material noncompliance with the previous mandatory treatment order; or</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Upon finding that neither of the above dispositions is appropriate, the judge or special justice shall rescind the order for mandatory outpatient treatment or order authorizing discharge to mandatory outpatient treatment following inpatient treatment.</p><p><pre/>Upon entry of an order for involuntary inpatient admission, transportation shall be provided in accordance with <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 37.2-829"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 37.2-829">§ 37.2-829<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000037#     2#          829#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></level></level><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p><citation normalizedCite="2008 VA CH 850"><content><span normalizedCite="2008 Va. Ch. 850">2008, cc. 850<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2008#000850#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2008 VA CH 870"><content><span normalizedCite="2008 Va. Ch. 870">870<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2008#000870#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2009 VA CH 112"><content><span normalizedCite="2009 Va. Ch. 112">2009, cc. 112<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2009#000112#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2009 VA CH 697"><content><span normalizedCite="2009 Va. Ch. 697">697<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2009#000697#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2010 VA CH 330"><content><span normalizedCite="2010 Va. Ch. 330">2010, cc. 330<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2010#000330#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2010 VA CH 461"><content><span normalizedCite="2010 Va. Ch. 461">461<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2010#000461#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2014 VA CH 691"><content><span normalizedCite="2014 Va. Ch. 691">2014, cc. 691<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2014#000691#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2014 VA CH 761"><content><span normalizedCite="2014 Va. Ch. 761">761<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2014#000761#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PVJ0-004G-K17M-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 37.2.</desig><title>BEHAVIORAL HEALTH AND DEVELOPMENTAL SERVICES</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="subtitle"><heading><desig>SUBTITLE 3.</desig><title>ADMISSIONS AND DISPOSITIONS</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 8.</desig><title>EMERGENCY CUSTODY AND VOLUNTARY AND INVOLUNTARY CIVIL ADMISSIONS</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="article"><heading><desig>ARTICLE 5.</desig><title>INVOLUNTARY ADMISSIONS</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Criminal Law &amp; Procedure</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NEU0RkE1OUQwNUQwNDgxODhEODZCMjkzOTg3NThBNzk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Detention</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NjhEMjRDMkUwQTJDNDNEQTk1MTZGOTQ1NDRGN0FGNUM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QTc2N0NFQzYyRUE3NDZBMTk3REExRTgyMUQ4OEY4MjU</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Governments</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjdEQjE4OUJDMzQxNDNEMEI0RTI1QUFCMzJENjEwRTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Sunday Closing Laws</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NjE1QTMyMzg5RjAyNDA1QUE4RkFFREQ1MjgzRUFGMzM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6ODM0MTQxODNGMEIyNDI0QkE5NTYzMEJBM0E4NTJBM0U</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></metadata></legislativeDoc>