<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#349#000015#     2#         5301#">Va. Code Ann. § 15.2-5301</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_15.2-5301"/><heading><desig>§ 15.2-5301.</desig><title>Definitions</title></heading><bodyText><p>As used or referred to in this chapter unless a different meaning clearly appears from the context:</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Authority"</emphasis> or <emphasis typeStyle="it">"hospital authority"</emphasis> means a body corporate organized in accordance with the provisions of this chapter for the purposes, with the powers and subject to the restrictions hereinafter set forth.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Bonds"</emphasis> means any bonds, interim certificates, notes, debentures, or other obligations of the authority issued pursuant to this chapter.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"City,"</emphasis> means both cities and counties, and city-specific terms such as "mayor" shall be deemed to also include the equivalent county term.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Commissioner"</emphasis> means one of the members of an authority appointed in accordance with the provisions of this chapter.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Contract"</emphasis> means any agreement of an authority with or for the benefit of an obligee whether contained in a resolution, trust indenture, mortgage, lease, bond or other instrument.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Cost,"</emphasis> as applied to a hospital project, means all or any part of the cost of acquisition, construction, alteration, enlargement, reconstruction and remodeling of a hospital project, including all lands, structures, real or personal property, interest in land and air rights, the cost of demolishing or removing any buildings or structures on land so acquired, including the cost of acquiring any lands to which such buildings or structures may be moved, the cost of all labor, materials, machinery and equipment, financing charges, interest on all bonds prior to, during and for a period of time not to exceed two years after completion, provisions for working capital, the cost of architectural engineering, financial and legal services, plans, specifications, studies, surveys, estimates of cost and revenues, administrative expenses, expenses necessary or incident to determining the feasibility or practicability of acquiring or constructing the hospital project and such other expenses as may be necessary or incidental to the acquisition and construction of such project, the financing of such acquisition and construction and the placing of the project in operation.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Federal government"</emphasis> means the United States of America or any agency or instrumentality, corporate or otherwise, of the United States of America.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Government"</emphasis> means the Commonwealth and the federal government and any subdivision, agency or instrumentality, corporate or otherwise, of either of them.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Hospital project"</emphasis> or <emphasis typeStyle="it">"project"</emphasis> means any and all medical facilities and approaches thereto and appurtenances thereof. Medical facilities shall include any and all facilities suitable for providing adequate hospital facilities and medical care for concentrated centers of population, and also includes any and all structures, buildings, improvements, additions, extensions, replacements, appurtenances, lands, rights in land, franchises, machinery, equipment, furnishings, landscaping, approaches, roadways and other facilities necessary or desirable in connection therewith or incidental thereto, including, without limitation, hospitals, nursing homes, assisted living facilities, continuing care facilities, self-care facilities, medical office facilities, clinics, out-patient surgical centers, alcohol, substance abuse and drug treatment centers, laboratories, research facilities, sanitariums, hospices, facilities for the residence or care of the elderly, the handicapped or the chronically ill, residential facilities for nurses, interns, and physicians and any other kind of facility for the diagnosis, treatment, rehabilitation, prevention or palliation of any human illness, injury, disorder, or disability; together with all related and supporting facilities and equipment necessary and desirable in connection therewith or incidental thereto; or equipment alone, including, without limitation, parking facilities, kitchen, laundry, laboratory, pharmaceutical, administrative, communications, computer and recreational facilities and equipment, storage space, mobile medical facilities, vehicles, and other equipment necessary or desirable for the transportation of medical equipment or the transportation of patients.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Obligee of the authority"</emphasis> or <emphasis typeStyle="it">"obligee"</emphasis> includes any bondholder, trustee or trustees for any bondholders, any lessor demising property to the authority used in connection with a hospital project or any assignee or assignees of such lessor's interest or any part thereof, and the United States of America when it is a party to any contract with the authority.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Real property"</emphasis> includes lands under water, structures, and any and all easements, franchises and incorporeal hereditaments and every estate and right therein, legal and equitable, including terms for years and liens by way of judgments, mortgage or otherwise.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Trust indenture"</emphasis> includes instruments pledging the revenues of real or personal properties but not conveying such properties or conferring a right to foreclose and cause a sale thereof.</p></bodyText><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p>Code 1950, § 32-214; 1973, c. 462, § 15.1-1534; 1979, c. 719; <citation normalizedCite="1997 VA CH 587"><content><span normalizedCite="1997 Va. Ch. 587">1997, c. 587<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1997#000587#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2006 VA CH 658"><content><span normalizedCite="2006 Va. Ch. 658">2006, c. 658<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2006#000658#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2014 VA CH 502"><content><span normalizedCite="2014 Va. Ch. 502">2014, c. 502<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2014#000502#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PSM0-004G-K418-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 15.2.</desig><title>COUNTIES, CITIES AND TOWNS</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="subtitle"><heading><desig>SUBTITLE IV.</desig><title>OTHER GOVERNMENTAL ENTITIES</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 53.</desig><title>HOSPITAL AUTHORITIES</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="article"><heading><desig>ARTICLE 1.</desig><title>IN GENERAL</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjA4OEVGODBENzY4NDcxM0IyQzA1OTEwQzVDODRBOUE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Assignments &amp; Transfers</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OUUzQ0IwQzJGMzA1NEJERDhGMkRCQjRGQjBEQTAwNEQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NTRDNjY1QjAxNkE5NDlERThCNjhFRTg4RjdCMTkzRTk</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Contracts Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QzY0RTZFMzE0RjkwNDdFQUI5M0U5N0ZFMjYyREMyQzU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Assignees &amp; Assignors</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NzU4Qjc1Nzk4NDIxNDU1RDk3RDFBNjlCMjBCNEJCREQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RkQyOUVFMzQ2Q0IwNDY1OEJFMjJCQjI0MjM3NkYzOTk</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Governments</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjdEQjE4OUJDMzQxNDNEMEI0RTI1QUFCMzJENjEwRTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Duties &amp; Powers</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Njk1NTNGMzM0RTc3NDcyMUI4MENCQUQ1RDhEN0M1RUM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Njg1MkM3RkYyNzIxNEVFRkJFMTI2NUM4NUU1ODdEM0Q</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Finance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjMzOTBBRTg2MUVDNDdDNUE1M0QxNDk1RERCNjNCN0I7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Njg1MkM3RkYyNzIxNEVFRkJFMTI2NUM4NUU1ODdEM0Q</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Public Health &amp; Welfare Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDYwRTY1MDg3MTk5NDUyNkFFRDI1RjJBRERGQ0UxNzI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Community Residence</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NkE0NDMxRUNDMTRDNDM3Qzk0NEE3MTMxNjI2Mjc3Rjc7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NjVGRUIzQkI1QTg1NDUxNkJFM0UwN0IxRTVENDlBNTM</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NUVCNTZERDE5OTI4NDJDRUEzMDVFNjQ3NkEyMjI5QUI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MTlCM0Q3MTlFNUQ0NDA5OTgwQTEwQjE1M0ZGMTlFQjc</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Real Property Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QUUyRTcxRURBNEY2NEE2MDk3QzBCNzRDOEY0NTZDQzk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Construction Loans</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RDNGMDlENjQ4NUYyNEM0MEIxRTAwMjAyRTdFRUNBRkY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MTY1MzRERDhBMDZCNDFBMDk0QUEwRjcyN0ZFNEY3REM</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification><classificationGroup classificationScheme="indexing-terms"><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem score="90"><className>Governments</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjdEQjE4OUJDMzQxNDNEMEI0RTI1QUFCMzJENjEwRTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></classificationGroup></metadata></legislativeDoc>