<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#349#000022#     1#        305.2#">Va. Code Ann. § 22.1-305.2</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_22.1-305.2"/><heading><desig>§ 22.1-305.2.</desig><title>Advisory Board on Teacher Education and Licensure</title></heading><bodyText><p>There is hereby established the Advisory Board on Teacher Education and Licensure which shall consist of 21 members to be appointed by the Board of Education. Ten members of the Advisory Board shall be classroom teachers, with at least the following representation: three elementary school teachers, three middle school teachers, and three high school teachers. Three members of the Advisory Board shall be school administrators, one of whom shall be a school principal, one of whom shall be a division superintendent, and one of whom shall be a school personnel administrator. Four members of the Advisory Board shall be faculty members in teacher preparation programs in public or private institutions of higher education, who may represent the arts and sciences. One member of the Advisory Board shall be a member of a school board. One member of the Advisory Board shall be a member of a parent-teacher association. One member of the Advisory Board shall be a representative of the business community and one member shall be a citizen at large. The Superintendent of Public Instruction or his designee and the Director of the State Council of Higher Education or his designee and the Chancellor of the Virginia Community College System or his designee shall serve as nonvoting ex officio members of the Advisory Board.</p><p>The Superintendent of Public Instruction shall designate a staff liaison to coordinate the activities of the Advisory Board. The Advisory Board shall meet five times per year or upon the request of its chairman or the Board of Education. The Advisory Board shall annually elect a chairman from its membership. The members of the Advisory Board shall serve without compensation; however, the necessary expenses incurred in the performance of their duties as members of the Advisory Board shall be reimbursed by the Department of Education.</p><p>The members of the Advisory Board shall be appointed for three-year terms. However, the incumbent members of the Teacher Education Advisory Board serving on July 1, 1990, shall be appointed to serve as initial members of the Advisory Board on Teacher Education and Licensure for the duration of the terms for which they were originally appointed. Upon the expiration of the terms of these incumbent members, the members appointed to replace them shall serve for three-year terms. No person may be appointed to serve for more than two consecutive terms. Those serving as incumbent members on July 1, 1990, shall be eligible to be reappointed to serve for one additional term. Members shall hold office after expiration of their terms until their successors are duly appointed.</p><p>The Advisory Board on Teacher Education and Licensure shall advise the Board of Education and submit recommendations on policies applicable to the qualifications, examination, licensure, and regulation of school personnel including revocation, suspension, denial, cancellation, reinstatement, and renewals of licensure, fees for processing applications, standards for the approval of preparation programs, reciprocal approval of preparation programs, and other related matters as the Board of Education may request or the Advisory Board may deem necessary. The final authority for licensure of school personnel shall remain with the Board of Education.</p></bodyText><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p><citation normalizedCite="1990 VA CH 970"><content><span normalizedCite="1990 Va. Ch. 970">1990, c. 970<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1990#000970#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1992 VA CH 132"><content><span normalizedCite="1992 Va. Ch. 132">1992, c. 132<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1992#000132#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2014 VA CH 334"><content><span normalizedCite="2014 Va. Ch. 334">2014, c. 334<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2014#000334#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PTS0-004G-K30X-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 22.1.</desig><title>EDUCATION</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 15.</desig><title>TEACHERS, OFFICERS AND EMPLOYEES</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="article"><heading><desig>ARTICLE 2.1.</desig><title>THE ADVISORY BOARD ON TEACHER EDUCATION AND LICENSURE</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Criminal Law &amp; Procedure</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NEU0RkE1OUQwNUQwNDgxODhEODZCMjkzOTg3NThBNzk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Consecutive Sentences</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Mjk5MTI5MTkzMTk3NDczQkE2QTJGOTgzN0E4NDdFMDE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUIzQ0NGRDZERUU3NERCODg2MEZFMDI2RTI0RTA3RTc</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Education Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDkzNUEzQzFBNEZBNEFBREIxNDM5MTc1MUU5QjI4MTY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Decisions &amp; Findings</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NzY0RkNEMkU4RUM4NEMzNkFGOTIwQzA3MjRDMDlFRjk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NjI3RDJERjQ4Rjc5NDM5NjlBMDNEN0ZBMUU4QUZCRUQ</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDI3MzE4RDhBODY5NDM3NjgyNTIzNUYwQzI5QjVDRjk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QzIyNDE4RDQ5NkNGNDBDREFBNzc3QkJBRjdERDlCQ0Y</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Lack of Certification</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RjI5MUYxMDdCRkNENDk5OTkyNTg1RTg1NjRERjUyM0Q7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDk4Mzg2MUI0QzJCNDc2RjkwMDM5QUMzQUY2NEI5Mzk</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification><classificationGroup classificationScheme="indexing-terms"><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem score="90"><className>Education</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDkzNUEzQzFBNEZBNEFBREIxNDM5MTc1MUU5QjI4MTY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></classificationGroup></metadata></legislativeDoc>