<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#349#000016#     1#        278.8#">Va. Code Ann. § 16.1-278.8</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_16.1-278.8"/><heading><desig>§ 16.1-278.8.</desig><title>Delinquent juveniles</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a"/><heading><desig>A.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> If a juvenile is found to be delinquent, except where such finding involves a refusal to take a blood or breath test in violation of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 18.2-268.2"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 18.2-268.2">§ 18.2-268.2<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000018#     2#        268.2#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> or a similar ordinance, the juvenile court or the circuit court may make any of the following orders of disposition for his supervision, care and rehabilitation:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Enter an order pursuant to the provisions of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 16.1-278"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 16.1-278">§ 16.1-278<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000016#     1#          278#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Permit the juvenile to remain with his parent, subject to such conditions and limitations as the court may order with respect to the juvenile and his parent;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Order the parent of a juvenile living with him to participate in such programs, cooperate in such treatment or be subject to such conditions and limitations as the court may order and as are designed for the rehabilitation of the juvenile and his parent;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_4"/><heading><desig>4.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Defer disposition for a specific period of time established by the court with due regard for the gravity of the offense and the juvenile's history, after which time the charge may be dismissed by the judge if the juvenile exhibits good behavior during the period for which disposition is deferred;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_4a"/><heading><desig>4a.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Defer disposition and place the juvenile in the temporary custody of the Department to attend a boot camp established pursuant to <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 66-13"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 66 -13">§ 66-13<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#123#000066#        13#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> provided bed space is available for confinement and the juvenile (i) has been found delinquent for an offense that would be a Class 1 misdemeanor or felony if committed by an adult, (ii) has not previously been and is not currently being adjudicated delinquent or found guilty of a violent juvenile felony, (iii) has not previously attended a boot camp, (iv) has not previously been committed to and received by the Department, and (v) has had an assessment completed by the Department or its contractor concerning the appropriateness of the candidate for a boot camp. Upon the juvenile's withdrawal, removal or refusal to comply with the terms and conditions of participation in the program, he shall be brought before the court for a hearing at which the court may impose any other disposition as authorized by this section which could have been imposed at the time the juvenile was placed in the custody of the Department;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_5"/><heading><desig>5.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Without entering a judgment of guilty and with the consent of the juvenile and his attorney, defer disposition of the delinquency charge for a specific period of time established by the court with due regard for the gravity of the offense and the juvenile's history, and place the juvenile on probation under such conditions and limitations as the court may prescribe. Upon fulfillment of the terms and conditions, the court shall discharge the juvenile and dismiss the proceedings against him. Discharge and dismissal under these provisions shall be without adjudication of guilt;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_6"/><heading><desig>6.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Order the parent of a juvenile with whom the juvenile does not reside to participate in such programs, cooperate in such treatment or be subject to such conditions and limitations as the court may order and as are designed for the rehabilitation of the juvenile where the court determines this participation to be in the best interest of the juvenile and other parties concerned and where the court determines it reasonable to expect the parent to be able to comply with such order;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_7"/><heading><desig>7.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Place the juvenile on probation under such conditions and limitations as the court may prescribe;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_7a"/><heading><desig>7a.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Place the juvenile on probation and order treatment for the abuse or dependence on alcohol or drugs in a program licensed by the Department of Behavioral Health and Developmental Services for the treatment of juveniles for substance abuse provided that (i) the juvenile has received a substance abuse screening and assessment pursuant to <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 16.1-273"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 16.1-273">§ 16.1-273<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000016#     1#          273#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> and that such assessment reasonably indicates that the commission of the offense was motivated by, or closely related to, the habitual use of alcohol or drugs and indicates that the juvenile is in need of treatment for this condition; (ii) the juvenile has not previously been and is not currently being adjudicated for a violent juvenile felony; and (iii) such facility is available. Upon the juvenile's withdrawal, removal, or refusal to comply with the conditions of participation in the program, he shall be brought before the court for a hearing at which the court may impose any other disposition authorized by this section. The court shall review such placements at 30-day intervals;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_8"/><heading><desig>8.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Impose a fine not to exceed $ 500 upon such juvenile;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_9"/><heading><desig>9.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Suspend the motor vehicle and driver's license of such juvenile or impose a curfew on the juvenile as to the hours during which he may operate a motor vehicle. Any juvenile whose driver's license is suspended may be referred for an assessment and subsequent referral to appropriate services, upon such terms and conditions as the court may order. The court, in its discretion and upon a demonstration of hardship, may authorize the use of a restricted permit to operate a motor vehicle by any juvenile who enters such program for any of the purposes set forth in subsection E of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 18.2-271.1"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 18.2-271.1">§ 18.2-271.1<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000018#     2#        271.1#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> or for travel to and from school. The restricted permit shall be issued in accordance with the provisions of such subsection. However, only an abstract of the court order that identifies the juvenile and the conditions under which the restricted license is to be issued shall be sent to the Department of Motor Vehicles.</p><p><pre/>If a curfew is imposed, the juvenile shall surrender his driver's license, which shall be held in the physical custody of the court during any period of curfew restriction. The court shall send an abstract of any order issued under the provisions of this section to the Department of Motor Vehicles, which shall preserve a record thereof. Notwithstanding the provisions of Article 12 (<citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 16.1-299"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 16.1-299">§ 16.1-299<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000016#     1#          299#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> et seq.) of this chapter or the provisions of Title 46.2, this record shall be available only to all law-enforcement officers, attorneys for the Commonwealth and courts. A copy of the court order, upon which shall be noted all curfew restrictions, shall be provided to the juvenile and shall contain such information regarding the juvenile as is reasonably necessary to identify him. The juvenile may operate a motor vehicle under the court order in accordance with its terms.</p><p><pre/>Any juvenile who operates a motor vehicle in violation of any restrictions imposed pursuant to this section shall be guilty of a violation of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 46.2-301"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 46.2-301">§ 46.2-301<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000046#     2#          301#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p><p><pre/>The Department of Motor Vehicles shall refuse to issue a driver's license to any juvenile denied a driver's license until such time as is stipulated in the court order or until notification by the court of withdrawal of the order imposing the curfew;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_10"/><heading><desig>10.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Require the juvenile to make restitution or reparation to the aggrieved party or parties for actual damages or loss caused by the offense for which the juvenile was found to be delinquent;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_11"/><heading><desig>11.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Require the juvenile to participate in a public service project under such conditions as the court prescribes;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_12"/><heading><desig>12.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> In case of traffic violations, impose only those penalties that are authorized to be imposed on adults for such violations. However, for those violations punishable by confinement if committed by an adult, confinement shall be imposed only as authorized by this title;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_13"/><heading><desig>13.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Transfer legal custody to any of the following:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_13_a"/><heading><desig>a.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A relative or other individual who, after study, is found by the court to be qualified to receive and care for the juvenile;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_13_b"/><heading><desig>b.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A child welfare agency, private organization or facility that is licensed or otherwise authorized by law to receive and provide care for such juvenile. The court shall not transfer legal custody of a delinquent juvenile to an agency, organization or facility outside of the Commonwealth without the approval of the Director; or</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_13_c"/><heading><desig>c.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The local board of social services of the county or city in which the court has jurisdiction or, at the discretion of the court, to the local board of the county or city in which the juvenile has residence if other than the county or city in which the court has jurisdiction. The board shall accept the juvenile for care and custody, provided that it has been given reasonable notice of the pendency of the case and an opportunity to be heard. However, in an emergency in the county or city in which the court has jurisdiction, such local board may be required to temporarily accept a juvenile for a period not to exceed 14 days without prior notice or an opportunity to be heard if the judge entering the placement order describes the emergency and the need for such temporary placement in the order. Nothing in this subdivision shall prohibit the commitment of a juvenile to any local board of social services in the Commonwealth when such local board consents to the commitment. The board to which the juvenile is committed shall have the final authority to determine the appropriate placement for the juvenile. Any order authorizing removal from the home and transferring legal custody of a juvenile to a local board of social services as provided in this subdivision shall be entered only upon a finding by the court that reasonable efforts have been made to prevent removal and that continued placement in the home would be contrary to the welfare of the juvenile, and the order shall so state;</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_14"/><heading><desig>14.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Unless waived by an agreement between the attorney for the Commonwealth and the juvenile and his attorney or other legal representative, upon consideration of the results of an investigation completed pursuant to <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 16.1-273"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 16.1-273">§ 16.1-273<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000016#     1#          273#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, commit the juvenile to the Department of Juvenile Justice, but only if he is 11 years of age or older and the current offense is (i) an offense that would be a felony if committed by an adult, (ii) an offense that would be a Class 1 misdemeanor if committed by an adult and the juvenile has previously been found to be delinquent based on an offense that would be a felony if committed by an adult, or (iii) an offense that would be a Class 1 misdemeanor if committed by an adult and the juvenile has previously been adjudicated delinquent of three or more offenses that would be a Class 1 misdemeanor if committed by an adult, and each such offense was not a part of a common act, transaction or scheme;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_15"/><heading><desig>15.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Impose the penalty authorized by <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 16.1-284"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 16.1-284">§ 16.1-284<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000016#     1#          284#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_16"/><heading><desig>16.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Impose the penalty authorized by <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 16.1-284.1"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 16.1-284.1">§ 16.1-284.1<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000016#     1#        284.1#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_17"/><heading><desig>17.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Unless waived by an agreement between the attorney for the Commonwealth and the juvenile and his attorney or other legal representative, upon consideration of the results of an investigation completed pursuant to <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 16.1-273"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 16.1-273">§ 16.1-273<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000016#     1#          273#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, impose the penalty authorized by <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 16.1-285.1"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 16.1-285.1">§ 16.1-285.1<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000016#     1#        285.1#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_18"/><heading><desig>18.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Impose the penalty authorized by <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 16.1-278.9"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 16.1-278.9">§ 16.1-278.9<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000016#     1#        278.9#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; or</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_19"/><heading><desig>19.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Require the juvenile to participate in a gang-activity prevention program including, but not limited to, programs funded under the Virginia Juvenile Community Crime Control Act pursuant to <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 16.1-309.7"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 16.1-309.7">§ 16.1-309.7<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000016#     1#        309.7#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, if available, when a juvenile has been found delinquent of any of the following violations: <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 18.2-51"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 18.2-51">§ 18.2-51<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000018#     2#           51#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 18.2-51.1"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 18.2-51.1">18.2-51.1<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000018#     2#         51.1#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 18.2-52"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 18.2-52">18.2-52<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000018#     2#           52#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 18.2-53"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 18.2-53">18.2-53<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000018#     2#           53#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 18.2-55"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 18.2-55">18.2-55<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000018#     2#           55#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 18.2-56"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 18.2-56">18.2-56<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000018#     2#           56#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 18.2-57"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 18.2-57">18.2-57<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000018#     2#           57#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 18.2-57.2"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 18.2-57.2">18.2-57.2<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000018#     2#         57.2#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 18.2-121"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 18.2-121">18.2-121<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000018#     2#          121#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 18.2-127"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 18.2-127">18.2-127<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000018#     2#          127#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 18.2-128"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 18.2-128">18.2-128<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000018#     2#          128#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 18.2-137"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 18.2-137">18.2-137<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000018#     2#          137#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 18.2-138"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 18.2-138">18.2-138<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000018#     2#          138#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 18.2-146"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 18.2-146">18.2-146<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000018#     2#          146#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, or <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 18.2-147"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 18.2-147">18.2-147<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000018#     2#          147#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, or any violation of a local ordinance adopted pursuant to <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 15.2-1812.2"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 15.2-1812.2">§ 15.2-1812.2.<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000015#     2#       1812.2#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation></p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b"/><heading><desig>B.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> If the court finds a juvenile delinquent of any of the following offenses, the court shall require the juvenile to make at least partial restitution or reparation for any property damage, for loss caused by the offense, or for actual medical expenses incurred by the victim as a result of the offense: <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 18.2-51"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 18.2-51">§ 18.2-51<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000018#     2#           51#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 18.2-51.1"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 18.2-51.1">18.2-51.1<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000018#     2#         51.1#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 18.2-52"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 18.2-52">18.2-52<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000018#     2#           52#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 18.2-53"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 18.2-53">18.2-53<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000018#     2#           53#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 18.2-55"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 18.2-55">18.2-55<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000018#     2#           55#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 18.2-56"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 18.2-56">18.2-56<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000018#     2#           56#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 18.2-57"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 18.2-57">18.2-57<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000018#     2#           57#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 18.2-57.2"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 18.2-57.2">18.2-57.2<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000018#     2#         57.2#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 18.2-121"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 18.2-121">18.2-121<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000018#     2#          121#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 18.2-127"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 18.2-127">18.2-127<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000018#     2#          127#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 18.2-128"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 18.2-128">18.2-128<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000018#     2#          128#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 18.2-137"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 18.2-137">18.2-137<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000018#     2#          137#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 18.2-138"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 18.2-138">18.2-138<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000018#     2#          138#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 18.2-146"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 18.2-146">18.2-146<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000018#     2#          146#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, or <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 18.2-147"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 18.2-147">18.2-147<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000018#     2#          147#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; or for any violation of a local ordinance adopted pursuant to <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 15.2-1812.2"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 15.2-1812.2">§ 15.2-1812.2.<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000015#     2#       1812.2#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> The court shall further require the juvenile to participate in a community service project under such conditions as the court prescribes.</p></bodyText></level><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p><citation normalizedCite="1991 VA CH 534"><content><span normalizedCite="1991 Va. Ch. 534">1991, c. 534<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1991#000534#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1992 VA CH 830"><content><span normalizedCite="1992 Va. Ch. 830">1992, c. 830<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1992#000830#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1994 VA CH 859"><content><span normalizedCite="1994 Va. Ch. 859">1994, cc. 859<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1994#000859#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1994 VA CH 949"><content><span normalizedCite="1994 Va. Ch. 949">949<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1994#000949#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1996 VA CH 755"><content><span normalizedCite="1996 Va. Ch. 755">1996, cc. 755<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1996#000755#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1996 VA CH 914"><content><span normalizedCite="1996 Va. Ch. 914">914<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1996#000914#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1997 VA CH 318"><content><span normalizedCite="1997 Va. Ch. 318">1997, c. 318<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1997#000318#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1999 VA CH 350"><content><span normalizedCite="1999 Va. Ch. 350">1999, cc. 350<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1999#000350#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1999 VA CH 622"><content><span normalizedCite="1999 Va. Ch. 622">622<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1999#000622#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2000 VA CH 954"><content><span normalizedCite="2000 Va. Ch. 954">2000, cc. 954<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2000#000954#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2000 VA CH 978"><content><span normalizedCite="2000 Va. Ch. 978">978<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2000#000978#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2000 VA CH 981"><content><span normalizedCite="2000 Va. Ch. 981">981<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2000#000981#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2000 VA CH 988"><content><span normalizedCite="2000 Va. Ch. 988">988<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2000#000988#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2000 VA CH 1020"><content><span normalizedCite="2000 Va. Ch. 1020">1020<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2000#001020#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2000 VA CH 1041"><content><span normalizedCite="2000 Va. Ch. 1041">1041<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2000#001041#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2004 VA CH 325"><content><span normalizedCite="2004 Va. Ch. 325">2004, cc. 325<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2004#000325#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2004 VA CH 462"><content><span normalizedCite="2004 Va. Ch. 462">462<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2004#000462#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2005 VA CH 810"><content><span normalizedCite="2005 Va. Ch. 810">2005, c. 810<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2005#000810#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2009 VA CH 813"><content><span normalizedCite="2009 Va. Ch. 813">2009, cc. 813<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2009#000813#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2009 VA CH 840"><content><span normalizedCite="2009 Va. Ch. 840">840<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2009#000840#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2014 VA CH 20"><content><span normalizedCite="2014 Va. Ch. 20">2014, cc. 20<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2014#000020#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2014 VA CH 249"><content><span normalizedCite="2014 Va. Ch. 249">249<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2014#000249#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PTT0-004G-K3RT-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 16.1.</desig><title>COURTS NOT OF RECORD</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 11.</desig><title>JUVENILE AND DOMESTIC RELATIONS DISTRICT COURTS</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="article"><heading><desig>ARTICLE 9.</desig><title>DISPOSITION</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Criminal Law &amp; Procedure</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NEU0RkE1OUQwNUQwNDgxODhEODZCMjkzOTg3NThBNzk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Community Service</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MzQ1NENDRjI2N0VCNDBDQjlFREUzMEM2QjVBRDgyRTM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QUM4NjRENzc2NUY4NEQwMUEyQTdBNkM4MDhEQURCQjU</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Conditions</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NzY3NkM1QTQ5NTlGNDFGMjlCQzdBNjBBMjQ2NjUyNDI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OUM3MzRDMkUwM0Y3NENCNDk1OEM1OEM2NTE2NjQxODY</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Entry of Judgments</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUYzRjVDOUVEOTY2NDg5MzgwQkQxQjVFQzNGRDM5NTM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MEUzMkE2MTZCMThENDAwNDhCM0I4RDA2OURFRDAwNDI</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Mjk5MEU5MDg5QjBFNEFBMjg2QkE5RjMyMERFQzVDNkE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RkQ2MkRCMUMxMjAzNEMxMUI2MDE3RTQ4NzY2QUFCQjU</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NEFGMjMyRTAxQTFDNDIzNThGNzE3ODhEM0FGOEY4M0M7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OTFERjY2NkMxNTAwNDQyODk2QzgzQkJCMkZDQ0I1OTY</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDU5QUFFRDk4N0QxNDEzRkE4RDhBNEZGMzRCMTFBN0Y7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OUM3MzRDMkUwM0Y3NENCNDk1OEM1OEM2NTE2NjQxODY</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Judicial Discretion</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RjZFQkExMjgxODRCNDZCNDhDOTkwNzY2NUVCNjg3NDA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MEUzMkE2MTZCMThENDAwNDhCM0I4RDA2OURFRDAwNDI</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Refusals to Submit</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MzdFQkI4QzEzMjE1NDQxQkFDMkE2QjBDODcxRTA5QUI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RThDODAwRTE1OUI3NEE0M0FCNTMwNjM5MzNFRERCMjI</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Shock Incarceration</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6ODg2ODRGRjNDN0JENDQ5RDgyQTQ5QzQ2NkU2NUJDODM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QUM4NjRENzc2NUY4NEQwMUEyQTdBNkM4MDhEQURCQjU</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Family Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NEI4M0U5Qzg3RTk0NDdBRUJGNDRGNkZEQkU3RDdFNDU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Delinquency Proceedings</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RTE4NjRFQzE4QTRGNEQzQzk1MTE0MTY4NzU5N0Q5RDM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QUJCOTZBNkIyQjFFNDI2MDlGN0I2M0I4ODA5NzE5OTk</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NkQzNDVBNDkwRkM2NDY2RkFEOUI2MzZENjREMkRCODg7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QUJCOTZBNkIyQjFFNDI2MDlGN0I2M0I4ODA5NzE5OTk</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Governments</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjdEQjE4OUJDMzQxNDNEMEI0RTI1QUFCMzJENjEwRTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Administrative Boards</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QTYwRUFCMDc5MzQ5NDEyREFEQkU2NkE2MjRGQTlCNzY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Njg1MkM3RkYyNzIxNEVFRkJFMTI2NUM4NUU1ODdEM0Q</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Public Health &amp; Welfare Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDYwRTY1MDg3MTk5NDUyNkFFRDI1RjJBRERGQ0UxNzI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NEQ3OEVEMjEwMEI4NEY1OTgyODZBMURDRkREMEM5RTg7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDZDNTZENUNCRjVBNEY4OEIyQzVBNjRDRTcyOEQ4NDQ</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Transportation Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RTYzRTk5RDVBQkQ2NDcwQzk2NTU3ODQ5OEE3NDlBNzk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Revocation &amp; Suspension</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QUNDMUM0MDYwNEE1NDZGQkIyNzQyNzQ0RTIzNkFBMzk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6ODY1RjFBNDEzNUFBNEYzMjhCMjhDRkU1NDlCQ0U3RkU</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification><classificationGroup classificationScheme="indexing-terms"><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem score="90"><className>Governments</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjdEQjE4OUJDMzQxNDNEMEI0RTI1QUFCMzJENjEwRTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></classificationGroup></metadata></legislativeDoc>