<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#349#000022#     1#        298.1#">Va. Code Ann. § 22.1-298.1</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_22.1-298.1"/><heading><desig>§ 22.1-298.1.</desig><title>Regulations governing licensure</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a"/><heading><desig>A.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> As used in this section:</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Alternate route to licensure"</emphasis> means a nontraditional route to teacher licensure available to individuals who meet the criteria specified in the regulations issued by the Board of Education.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Industry certification credential"</emphasis> means an active career and technical education credential that is earned by successfully completing a Board of Education-approved industry certification examination, being issued a professional license in the Commonwealth, or successfully completing an occupational competency examination.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Licensure by reciprocity"</emphasis> means a process used to issue a license to an individual coming into the Commonwealth from another state when that individual meets certain conditions specified in the Board of Education's regulations.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Professional teacher's assessment"</emphasis> means those tests mandated for licensure as prescribed by the Board of Education.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Provisional license"</emphasis> means a nonrenewable license issued by the Board of Education for a specified period of time, not to exceed three years, to an individual who may be employed by a school division in the Commonwealth and who generally meets the requirements specified in the Board of Education's regulations for licensure, but who may need to take additional coursework or pass additional assessments to be fully licensed with a renewable license.</p><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Renewable license"</emphasis> means a license issued by the Board of Education for five years to an individual who meets the requirements specified in the Board of Education's regulations.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b"/><heading><desig>B.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The Board of Education shall prescribe, by regulation, the requirements for the licensure of teachers and other school personnel required to hold a license. Such regulations shall include requirements for the denial, suspension, cancellation, revocation, and reinstatement of licensure. The Board of Education shall revoke the license of any person for whom it has received a notice of dismissal or resignation pursuant to subsection F of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 22.1-313"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 22.1-313">§ 22.1-313<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000022#     1#          313#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> and, in the case of a person who is the subject of a founded complaint of child abuse or neglect, after all rights to any appeal provided by <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 63.2-1526"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 63.2-1526">§ 63.2-1526<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000063#     2#         1526#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> have been exhausted. Regardless of the authority of any other agency of the Commonwealth to approve educational programs, only the Board of Education shall have the authority to license teachers to be regularly employed by school boards, including those teachers employed to provide nursing education.</p><p>The Board of Education shall prescribe by regulation the licensure requirements for teachers who teach only online courses, as defined in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 22.1-212.23"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 22.1-212.23">§ 22.1-212.23.<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000022#     1#       212.23#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> Such license shall be valid only for teaching online courses. Teachers who hold a five-year renewable license issued by the Board of Education may teach online courses for which they are properly endorsed.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c"/><heading><desig>C.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The Board of Education's regulations shall include requirements that a person seeking initial licensure:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Complete professional assessments as prescribed by the Board of Education;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Complete study in attention deficit disorder;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Complete study in gifted education, including the use of multiple criteria to identify gifted students; and</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c_4"/><heading><desig>4.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Complete study in methods of improving communication between schools and families and ways of increasing family involvement in student learning at home and at school.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d"/><heading><desig>D.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> In addition, such regulations shall include requirements that:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Every person seeking initial licensure or renewal of a license demonstrate proficiency in the use of educational technology for instruction;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Every person seeking initial licensure and persons seeking licensure renewal as teachers who have not completed such study shall complete study in child abuse recognition and intervention in accordance with curriculum guidelines developed by the Board of Education in consultation with the Department of Social Services that are relevant to the specific teacher licensure routes;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Every person seeking initial licensure or renewal of a license shall receive professional development in instructional methods tailored to promote student academic progress and effective preparation for the Standards of Learning end-of-course and end-of-grade assessments;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d_4"/><heading><desig>4.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Every person seeking renewal of a license shall complete all renewal requirements, including professional development in a manner prescribed by the Board, except that no person seeking renewal of a license shall be required to satisfy any such requirement by completing coursework and earning credit at an institution of higher education;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d_5"/><heading><desig>5.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Every person seeking initial licensure or renewal of a license shall provide evidence of completion of certification or training in emergency first aid, cardiopulmonary resuscitation, and the use of automated external defibrillators. The certification or training program shall be based on the current national evidence-based emergency cardiovascular care guidelines for cardiopulmonary resuscitation and the use of an automated external defibrillator, such as a program developed by the American Heart Association or the American Red Cross. The Board shall provide a waiver for this requirement for any person with a disability whose disability prohibits such person from completing the certification or training;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d_6"/><heading><desig>6.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Every person seeking licensure with an endorsement as a teacher of the blind and visually impaired shall demonstrate proficiency in reading and writing Braille;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d_7"/><heading><desig>7.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Every teacher seeking an initial license in the Commonwealth with an endorsement in the area of career and technical education shall have an industry certification credential in the area in which the teacher seeks endorsement. If a teacher seeking an initial license in the Commonwealth has not attained an industry certification credential in the area in which the teacher seeks endorsement, the Board may, upon request of the employing school division or educational agency, issue the teacher a provisional license to allow time for the teacher to attain such credential; and</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d_8"/><heading><desig>8.</desig><title><emphasis typeStyle="it"> (Effective July 1, 2017)</emphasis></title></heading><bodyText><p> Every person seeking initial licensure or renewal of a license shall complete awareness training, provided by the Department of Education, on the indicators of dyslexia, as that term is defined by the Board pursuant to regulations, and the evidence-based interventions and accommodations for dyslexia.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_e"/><heading><desig>E.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The Board's regulations shall require that initial licensure for principals and assistant principals be contingent upon passage of an assessment as prescribed by the Board.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_f"/><heading><desig>F.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The Board shall establish criteria in its regulations to effectuate the substitution of experiential learning for coursework for those persons seeking initial licensure through an alternate route as defined in Board regulations.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_g"/><heading><desig>G.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Notwithstanding any provision of law to the contrary, the Board (i) may provide for the issuance of a provisional license, valid for a period not to exceed three years, pursuant to subdivision D 7 or to any person who does not meet the requirements of this section or any other requirement for licensure imposed by law and (ii) shall provide for the issuance of a provisional license, valid for a period not to exceed three years, to any former member of the Armed Forces of the United States or the Virginia National Guard who has received an honorable discharge and has the appropriate level of experience or training but does not meet the requirements for a renewable license.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_h"/><heading><desig>H.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The Board's licensure regulations shall also provide for licensure by reciprocity:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_h_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> With comparable endorsement areas for those individuals holding a valid out-of-state teaching license and national certification from the National Board for Professional Teaching Standards or a nationally recognized certification program approved by the Board of Education. The application for such individuals shall require evidence of such valid licensure and national certification and shall not require official student transcripts;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_h_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> For individuals who have obtained a valid out-of-state license, with full credentials and without deficiencies, that is in force at the time the application for a Virginia license is received by the Department of Education. The individual must establish a file in the Department of Education by submitting a complete application packet, which shall include official student transcripts. An assessment of basic skills as provided in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 22.1-298.2"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 22.1-298.2">§ 22.1-298.2<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000022#     1#        298.2#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> and service requirements shall not be imposed for these licensed individuals; however, other licensing assessments, as prescribed by the Board of Education, shall be required; and</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_h_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The Board may include other provisions for reciprocity in its regulations.</p></bodyText></level></level><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p><citation normalizedCite="2006 VA CH 27"><content><span normalizedCite="2006 Va. Ch. 27">2006, cc. 27<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2006#000027#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2006 VA CH 349"><content><span normalizedCite="2006 Va. Ch. 349">349<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2006#000349#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2008 VA CH 474"><content><span normalizedCite="2008 Va. Ch. 474">2008, cc. 474<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2008#000474#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2008 VA CH 827"><content><span normalizedCite="2008 Va. Ch. 827">827<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2008#000827#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2012 VA CH 365"><content><span normalizedCite="2012 Va. Ch. 365">2012, c. 365<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2012#000365#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2013 VA CH 498"><content><span normalizedCite="2013 Va. Ch. 498">2013, cc. 498<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2013#000498#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2013 VA CH 530"><content><span normalizedCite="2013 Va. Ch. 530">530<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2013#000530#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2013 VA CH 588"><content><span normalizedCite="2013 Va. Ch. 588">588<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2013#000588#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2013 VA CH 650"><content><span normalizedCite="2013 Va. Ch. 650">650<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2013#000650#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2014 VA CH 79"><content><span normalizedCite="2014 Va. Ch. 79">2014, c. 79<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2014#000079#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2015 VA CH 385"><content><span normalizedCite="2015 Va. Ch. 385">2015, cc. 385<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2015#000385#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2015 VA CH 562"><content><span normalizedCite="2015 Va. Ch. 562">562<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2015#000562#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2016 VA CH 389"><content><span normalizedCite="2016 Va. Ch. 389">2016, cc. 389<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2016#000389#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2016 VA CH 649"><content><span normalizedCite="2016 Va. Ch. 649">649<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2016#000649#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PVH0-004G-K0FT-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 22.1.</desig><title>EDUCATION</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 15.</desig><title>TEACHERS, OFFICERS AND EMPLOYEES</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="article"><heading><desig>ARTICLE 2.</desig><title>TERMS OF EMPLOYMENT GENERALLY</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Employment Regulations &amp; Rules</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjNGM0U1N0E4RDhBNEU4RUI5NDQwRjE2RUQxM0E5Q0U7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDkzNUEzQzFBNEZBNEFBREIxNDM5MTc1MUU5QjI4MTY</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Requirements for Certification &amp; Licensure</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6ODdGQUMyN0E0NTVBNDM3NThEMTg2Mzc2RDg5NUU3NUY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDkzNUEzQzFBNEZBNEFBREIxNDM5MTc1MUU5QjI4MTY</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Education Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDkzNUEzQzFBNEZBNEFBREIxNDM5MTc1MUU5QjI4MTY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Appeals &amp; Reviews</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NzVGMkU3RkJBNkQ3NDI2OUFENjBCNDg4QTQxQjdEMTM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NjI3RDJERjQ4Rjc5NDM5NjlBMDNEN0ZBMUU4QUZCRUQ</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Certification &amp; Licensure Renewal</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QkMwREJFMDg4NUVFNDFERUJEMzhBNjZDNkI0QTc2RDI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDk4Mzg2MUI0QzJCNDc2RjkwMDM5QUMzQUY2NEI5Mzk</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Curriculum Challenges</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QTc2QUEyQkIzOEJFNDEwRTk3RDY2QzI5NjBDQzY3MzI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QUZCQjQ2OEI4MzZFNDE5NUE4MTczNEQwRjEwQzE3NEY</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Employment Regulations &amp; Rules</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjNGM0U1N0E4RDhBNEU4RUI5NDQwRjE2RUQxM0E5Q0U7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6ODhDOTBDNkNGQUQwNDUxRTk0M0ZDQ0RBRUNFNjM3ODg</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDI3MzE4RDhBODY5NDM3NjgyNTIzNUYwQzI5QjVDRjk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QzIyNDE4RDQ5NkNGNDBDREFBNzc3QkJBRjdERDlCQ0Y</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6M0VBQjFCRDVGMEY5NDhFNEIzQTQwQ0QwOEJBRTdERTE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDk4Mzg2MUI0QzJCNDc2RjkwMDM5QUMzQUY2NEI5Mzk</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Gifted Students</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6M0M1QTgwRjdDRDBCNEVBM0E3NTdCRDI1MkZEODE2Nzk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QzMyRkUwN0EzNzQ2NENEMUJEMDY4MEYxRjJCNzUxODE</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Notice</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDY3RTlDN0M0RjhCNEI2Rjg2OURERUQ2QkUwNThCOUM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6REM1MkZFRUQwMzBBNDk5QjgwQkI0RDBDQzc2MTI0ODc</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Professional Growth</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6ODRGOTcwNjNDQUE5NDFFMkFDQkQ1Mjc3MDVBNTY0QjY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QzIyNDE4RDQ5NkNGNDBDREFBNzc3QkJBRjdERDlCQ0Y</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Promotions</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjM2M0Q5N0YwOTUzNEZGQzkwNURFODBCMzYwNzExMjI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjY3RDZFQTA3NjQ3NEFCRUJENjY1RUJFRTg5NDIyRTc</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Requirements for Certification &amp; Licensure</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6ODdGQUMyN0E0NTVBNDM3NThEMTg2Mzc2RDg5NUU3NUY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDk4Mzg2MUI0QzJCNDc2RjkwMDM5QUMzQUY2NEI5Mzk</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Revocation &amp; Suspension</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RDJDOUFBNDI0NjRCNDI1Mjk5RkJEM0E1ODFEMDBFQjk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDk4Mzg2MUI0QzJCNDc2RjkwMDM5QUMzQUY2NEI5Mzk</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Governments</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjdEQjE4OUJDMzQxNDNEMEI0RTI1QUFCMzJENjEwRTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Licenses</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6N0IyQjkyQkVENEM2NDczNzg5MDUwQ0U5RDMzRjlDNUM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QURCRDNBRjBGRTE0NEFBRUEzNUU1MzFGQjg3MTM4MDI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Healthcare Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NkUxMkVDQjJDOEY5NDVDQ0E5NTFEMTlDMjIwNzVERjc7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Personnel Licensing</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6M0VCMTAwM0MwNDA1NEI4OThDNUVEMEIwRTJDQjU2QTM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QTJGRDdFQzgwODczNDI0NDgwMzEyM0JBOEQ2MUVDNjg</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Military &amp; Veterans Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NzM1OUEyRDNERTdENEU2MTk3RTlCNEJCRUY0NjRGRjQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RTkwRDAwRDBEM0NCNDQ2Qzk3QkQzM0VFOTRDQkJGRUU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RDE3QjNGOTc4Mzc2NDNDMjg0RDE5ODIzMkMwM0Y1Qzk</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification><classificationGroup classificationScheme="indexing-terms"><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem score="90"><className>Education</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDkzNUEzQzFBNEZBNEFBREIxNDM5MTc1MUU5QjI4MTY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></classificationGroup></metadata></legislativeDoc>