<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#349#000002#     2#          419#">Va. Code Ann. § 2.2-419</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_2.2-419"/><heading><desig>§ 2.2-419.</desig><title>Definitions</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><bodyText><p>As used in this article, unless the context requires a different meaning:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><bodyText><p><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Anything of value"</emphasis> means:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A pecuniary item, including money, or a bank bill or note;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A promissory note, bill of exchange, order, draft, warrant, check, or bond given for the payment of money;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A contract, agreement, promise, or other obligation for an advance, conveyance, forgiveness of indebtedness, deposit, distribution, loan, payment, gift, pledge, or transfer of money;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_4"/><heading><desig>4.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A stock, bond, note, or other investment interest in an entity;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_5"/><heading><desig>5.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A receipt given for the payment of money or other property;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_6"/><heading><desig>6.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A right in action;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_7"/><heading><desig>7.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A gift, tangible good, chattel, or an interest in a gift, tangible good, or chattel;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_8"/><heading><desig>8.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A loan or forgiveness of indebtedness;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_9"/><heading><desig>9.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A work of art, antique, or collectible;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_10"/><heading><desig>10.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> An automobile or other means of personal transportation;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_11"/><heading><desig>11.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Real property or an interest in real property, including title to realty, a fee simple or partial interest, present or future, contingent or vested within realty, a leasehold interest, or other beneficial interest in realty;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_12"/><heading><desig>12.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> An honorarium or compensation for services;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_13"/><heading><desig>13.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A rebate or discount in the price of anything of value unless the rebate or discount is made in the ordinary course of business to a member of the public without regard to that person's status as an executive or legislative official, or the sale or trade of something for reasonable compensation that would ordinarily not be available to a member of the public;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_14"/><heading><desig>14.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A promise or offer of employment; or</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_15"/><heading><desig>15.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Any other thing of value that is pecuniary or compensatory in value to a person.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><bodyText><p><pre/>"Anything of value" does not mean a campaign contribution properly received and reported pursuant to Chapter 9.3 (<citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 24.2-945"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 24.2-945">§ 24.2-945<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000024#     2#          945#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> et seq.) of Title 24.2.</p><p><pre/><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Compensation"</emphasis> means:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_1_seq_2"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> An advance, conveyance, forgiveness of indebtedness, deposit, distribution, loan, payment, gift, pledge, or transfer of money or anything of value; or</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_2_seq_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A contract, agreement, promise or other obligation for an advance, conveyance, forgiveness of indebtedness, deposit, distribution, loan, payment, gift, pledge, or transfer of money or anything of value, for services rendered or to be rendered.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><bodyText><p><pre/>"Compensation" does not mean reimbursement of expenses if the reimbursement does not exceed the amount actually expended for the expenses and it is substantiated by an itemization of expenses.</p><p><pre/><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Council"</emphasis> means the Virginia Conflict of Interest and Ethics Advisory Council established in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 30-355"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 30 -355">§ 30-355<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#123#000030#       355#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p><p><pre/><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Executive action"</emphasis> means the proposal, drafting, development, consideration, amendment, adoption, approval, promulgation, issuance, modification, rejection, or postponement by an executive agency or official of legislation or executive orders issued by the Governor. "Executive action" includes procurement transactions.</p><p><pre/><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Executive agency"</emphasis> means an agency, board, commission, or other body in the executive branch of state government. "Executive agency" includes the State Corporation Commission, the Virginia Workers' Compensation Commission, and the Virginia Lottery.</p><p><pre/><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Executive official"</emphasis> means:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_1_seq_3"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The Governor;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_2_seq_3"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The Lieutenant Governor;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_3_seq_2"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The Attorney General;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_4_seq_2"/><heading><desig>4.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Any officer or employee of the office of the Governor, Lieutenant Governor, or Attorney General other than a clerical or secretarial employee;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_5_seq_2"/><heading><desig>5.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The Governor's Secretaries, the Deputy Secretaries, and the chief executive officer of each executive agency; or</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_6_seq_2"/><heading><desig>6.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Members of supervisory and policy boards, commissions and councils, as defined in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 2.2-2100"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 2.2-2100">§ 2.2-2100<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000002#     2#         2100#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, however selected.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><bodyText><p><pre/><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Expenditure"</emphasis> means:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_1_seq_4"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A purchase, payment, distribution, loan, forgiveness of a loan or payment of a loan by a third party, advance, deposit, transfer of funds, a promise to make a payment, or a gift of money or anything of value for any purpose;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_2_seq_4"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A payment to a lobbyist for salary, fee, reimbursement for expenses, or other purpose by a person employing, retaining, or contracting for the services of the lobbyist separately or jointly with other persons;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_3_seq_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A payment in support of or assistance to a lobbyist or the lobbyist's activities, including the direct payment of expenses incurred at the request or suggestion of the lobbyist;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_4_seq_3"/><heading><desig>4.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A payment that directly benefits an executive or legislative official or a member of the official's immediate family;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_5_seq_3"/><heading><desig>5.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A payment, including compensation, payment, or reimbursement for the services, time, or expenses of an employee for or in connection with direct communication with an executive or legislative official;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_6_seq_3"/><heading><desig>6.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A payment for or in connection with soliciting or urging other persons to enter into direct communication with an executive or legislative official; or</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_7_seq_2"/><heading><desig>7.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A payment or reimbursement for categories of expenditures required to be reported pursuant to this chapter.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><bodyText><p><pre/>"Expenditure" does not mean a campaign contribution properly received and reported pursuant to Chapter 9.3 (<citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 24.2-945"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 24.2-945">§ 24.2-945<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000024#     2#          945#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> et seq.) of Title 24.2.</p><p><pre/><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Fair market value"</emphasis> means the price that a good or service would bring between a willing seller and a willing buyer in the open market after negotiations. If the fair market value cannot be determined, the actual price paid for the good or service shall be given consideration.</p><p><pre/><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Gift"</emphasis> means anything of value, including any gratuity, favor, discount, entertainment, hospitality, loan, forbearance, or other item having monetary value, and includes services as well as gifts of transportation, local travel, lodgings, and meals, whether provided in-kind or by purchase of a ticket, payment in advance, or reimbursement after the expense has been incurred.</p><p><pre/>"Gift" does not mean:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_1_seq_5"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Printed informational or promotional material;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_2_seq_5"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A gift that is not used and, no later than 60 days after receipt, is returned to the donor or delivered to a charitable organization and is not claimed as a charitable contribution for federal income tax purposes;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_3_seq_4"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A devise or inheritance;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_4_seq_4"/><heading><desig>4.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A gift of a value of less than $ 20;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_5_seq_4"/><heading><desig>5.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Any offer of a ticket, coupon, or other admission or pass unless the ticket, coupon, admission, or pass is used;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_6_seq_4"/><heading><desig>6.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Any food or beverages provided to an individual at an event at which the individual is performing official duties related to his public service;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_7_seq_3"/><heading><desig>7.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Any food and beverages received at or registration or attendance fees waived for any event at which the individual is a featured speaker, presenter, or lecturer;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_8_seq_2"/><heading><desig>8.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> An unsolicited award of appreciation or recognition in the form of a plaque, trophy, wall memento, or similar item that is given in recognition of public, civic, charitable, or professional service;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_9_seq_2"/><heading><desig>9.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Any gift to an individual's spouse, child, uncle, aunt, niece, nephew, or first cousin; a person to whom the donee is engaged to be married; the donee's or his spouse's parent, grandparent, grandchild, brother, sister, step-parent, step-grandparent, step-grandchild, step-brother, or step-sister; or the donee's brother's or sister's spouse;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_10_seq_2"/><heading><desig>10.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Travel provided to facilitate attendance by a legislator at a regular or special session of the General Assembly, a meeting of a legislative committee or commission, or a national conference where attendance is approved by the House Committee on Rules or its Chairman or the Senate Committee on Rules or its Chairman; or</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_11_seq_2"/><heading><desig>11.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Travel related to an official meeting of the Commonwealth, its political subdivisions, or any board, commission, authority, or other entity, or any charitable organization established pursuant to <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="26 USC 501"><content><span normalizedCite="26 U.S.C. 501">§ 501(c)(3) of the Internal Revenue Code<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#29854#1127#00000000501#1#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> affiliated with such entity, to which such person has been appointed or elected or is a member by virtue of his office or employment.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><bodyText><p><pre/><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Immediate family"</emphasis> means (i) the spouse and (ii) any other person who resides in the same household as the executive or legislative official and who is a dependent of the official.</p><p><pre/><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Legislative action"</emphasis> means:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_1_seq_6"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Preparation, research, drafting, introduction, consideration, modification, amendment, approval, passage, enactment, tabling, postponement, defeat, or rejection of a bill, resolution, amendment, motion, report, nomination, appointment, or other matter by the General Assembly or a legislative official;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_2_seq_6"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Action by the Governor in approving, vetoing, or recommending amendments for a bill passed by the General Assembly; or</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_3_seq_5"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Action by the General Assembly in overriding or sustaining a veto by the Governor, considering amendments recommended by the Governor, or considering, confirming, or rejecting an appointment of the Governor.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><bodyText><p><pre/><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Legislative official"</emphasis> means:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_1_seq_7"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A member or member-elect of the General Assembly;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_2_seq_7"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A member of a committee, subcommittee, commission, or other entity established by and responsible to the General Assembly or either house of the General Assembly; or</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_3_seq_6"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Persons employed by the General Assembly or an entity established by and responsible to the General Assembly.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><bodyText><p><pre/><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Lobbying"</emphasis> means:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_1_seq_8"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Influencing or attempting to influence executive or legislative action through oral or written communication with an executive or legislative official; or</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_2_seq_8"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Solicitation of others to influence an executive or legislative official.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><bodyText><p><pre/>"Lobbying" does not mean:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_1_seq_9"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Requests for appointments, information on the status of pending executive and legislative actions, or other ministerial contacts if there is no attempt to influence executive or legislative actions;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_2_seq_9"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Responses to published notices soliciting public comment submitted to the public official designated in the notice to receive the responses;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_3_seq_7"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The solicitation of an association by its members to influence legislative or executive action; or</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_4_seq_5"/><heading><desig>4.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Communications between an association and its members and communications between a principal and its lobbyists.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><bodyText><p><pre/><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Lobbyist"</emphasis> means:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_1_seq_10"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> An individual who is employed and receives payments, or who contracts for economic consideration, including reimbursement for reasonable travel and living expenses, for the purpose of lobbying;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_2_seq_10"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> An individual who represents an organization, association, or other group for the purpose of lobbying; or</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_3_seq_8"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A local government employee who lobbies.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><bodyText><p><pre/><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Lobbyist's principal"</emphasis> or <emphasis typeStyle="it">"principal"</emphasis> means the entity on whose behalf the lobbyist influences or attempts to influence executive or legislative action. An organization whose employees conduct lobbying activities on its behalf is both a principal and an employer of the lobbyists. In the case of a coalition or association that employs or retains others to conduct lobbying activities on behalf of its membership, the principal is the coalition or association and not its individual members.</p><p><pre/><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Local government"</emphasis> means:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_1_seq_11"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Any county, city, town, or other local or regional political subdivision;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_2_seq_11"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Any school division;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_3_seq_9"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Any organization or entity that exercises governmental powers that is established pursuant to an interstate compact; or</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_4_seq_6"/><heading><desig>4.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Any organization composed of members representing entities listed in subdivisions 1, 2, or 3 of this definition.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><bodyText><p><pre/><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Local government employee"</emphasis> means a public employee of a local government.</p><p><pre/><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Person"</emphasis> means an individual, proprietorship, firm, partnership, joint venture, joint stock company, syndicate, business trust, estate, company, corporation, association, club, committee, organization, or group of persons acting in concert.</p><p><pre/><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Procurement transaction"</emphasis> means all functions that pertain to obtaining all goods, services, or construction on behalf of an executive agency, including description of requirements, selection and solicitation of sources, preparation and award of contract, and all phases of contract administration where the stated or expected value of the contract is $ 5 million or more.</p><p><pre/><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Secretary"</emphasis> means the Secretary of the Commonwealth.</p><p><pre/><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Value"</emphasis> means the actual cost or fair market value of an item or items, whichever is greater. If the fair market value cannot be determined, the actual amount paid for the item or items shall be given consideration.</p><p><pre/><emphasis typeStyle="it">"Widely attended event"</emphasis> means an event at which at least 25 persons have been invited to attend or there is a reasonable expectation that at least 25 persons will attend the event and the event is open to individuals (i) who share a common interest, (ii) who are members of a public, civic, charitable, or professional organization, (iii) who are from a particular industry or profession, or (iv) who represent persons interested in a particular issue.</p></bodyText></level></level><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p><citation normalizedCite="1994 VA CH 857"><content><span normalizedCite="1994 Va. Ch. 857">1994, cc. 857<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1994#000857#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1994 VA CH 937"><content><span normalizedCite="1994 Va. Ch. 937">937<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1994#000937#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, § 2.1-780; <citation normalizedCite="2001 VA CH 844"><content><span normalizedCite="2001 Va. Ch. 844">2001, c. 844<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2001#000844#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2006 VA CH 787"><content><span normalizedCite="2006 Va. Ch. 787">2006, cc. 787<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2006#000787#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2006 VA CH 843"><content><span normalizedCite="2006 Va. Ch. 843">843<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2006#000843#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2006 VA CH 892"><content><span normalizedCite="2006 Va. Ch. 892">892<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2006#000892#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2014 VA CH 225"><content><span normalizedCite="2014 Va. Ch. 225">2014, cc. 225<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2014#000225#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2014 VA CH 792"><content><span normalizedCite="2014 Va. Ch. 792">792<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2014#000792#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2014 VA CH 804"><content><span normalizedCite="2014 Va. Ch. 804">804<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2014#000804#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2015 VA CH 763"><content><span normalizedCite="2015 Va. Ch. 763">2015, cc. 763<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2015#000763#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2015 VA CH 777"><content><span normalizedCite="2015 Va. Ch. 777">777<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2015#000777#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2016 VA CH 773"><content><span normalizedCite="2016 Va. Ch. 773">2016, cc. 773<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2016#000773#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2016 VA CH 774"><content><span normalizedCite="2016 Va. Ch. 774">774<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2016#000774#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PWC0-004G-K349-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 2.2.</desig><title>ADMINISTRATION OF GOVERNMENT</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="subtitle"><heading><desig>SUBTITLE I.</desig><title>ORGANIZATION OF STATE GOVERNMENT</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="part"><heading><desig>PART A.</desig><title>OFFICE OF THE GOVERNOR</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 4.</desig><title>SECRETARY OF THE COMMONWEALTH</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="article"><heading><desig>ARTICLE 3.</desig><title>REGISTRATION OF LOBBYISTS</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Banking Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjQyMUFCOUJBNURBNEFDREE3MTNCNDk5QkQ4NUM3RjI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6ODU3OEVBMUY0ODg3NDY5ODgxQjY1QkI1M0QzQjUxQjc7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MkQ2RDkwNzExNkE4NDgwOUI3MDEyMDU4RDY4MEI0QkQ</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Distribution, Processing &amp; Storage of Food &amp; Agricultural Products</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NENGNzZCMDU5RjcyNEM0NEFFOUU4ODFCQkZCOThBRkI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NkVDMzM4QkJENTg3NDQ0RDg3NTA5OEM3RkMyQTlENDI</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Food Product Promotions</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OUM5MDE2NEFCMjRFNDk2NUJERUQ0QzYyNEQzNDk3NEQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NkVDMzM4QkJENTg3NDQ0RDg3NTA5OEM3RkMyQTlENDI</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Formation</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDJENDRCOUZDMTg5NEU1N0JGNjFCNjFFMTNDOTEzRDQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Njg2NjY4ODFGMkM4NDBERjg2ODkwNEMyNTM4QTgyQjk</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjA4OEVGODBENzY4NDcxM0IyQzA1OTEwQzVDODRBOUE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Formation</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDJENDRCOUZDMTg5NEU1N0JGNjFCNjFFMTNDOTEzRDQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Njg2NjY4ODFGMkM4NDBERjg2ODkwNEMyNTM4QTgyQjk</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RjI3QTdDNjdBOUE1NDg2MTk5Q0ZGNEQ1MDUyRjBFN0Q7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Njg2NjY4ODFGMkM4NDBERjg2ODkwNEMyNTM4QTgyQjk</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Management Duties &amp; Liabilities</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDcyMUU5QzVDQTE1NDFGNUFCODdDREU3NDYxRDlCMkY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Njg2NjY4ODFGMkM4NDBERjg2ODkwNEMyNTM4QTgyQjk</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Contracts Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QzY0RTZFMzE0RjkwNDdFQUI5M0U5N0ZFMjYyREMyQzU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Forgery, Fraud &amp; Mistake</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RTI5RjAxRDlDNzRGNEFBMkE4NTI1RjIzNDc3ODBCMDE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MTg5OTE0NDQzNTJCNERDRkI3NDZEMzdBMjREMERGRDM</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Interest</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NzNFN0EyRkNCRTJENDJFRkFFNDM0ODBFMUM4QzkyRDk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MkUyQjY4NDMwRDBFNDVEQ0E4N0Y3M0Y0QkU2MzI3Rjc</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Transfer of Negotiable Instruments</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6REM4MDY0REIxODc4NEI5NjlGRTVGQzA2NjA5QjhCNTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDMzOTAwOUFFMTFCNEE3Njg4QUEzQTJFOUE1NzE5MkM</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Estate, Gift &amp; Trust Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OENGNTY0MEQ2RTU2NDA2NTk4QjcyNzI2NTBERUU3NUI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NTM0MTFFRkQ3M0E2NEQwREFFMzc3QjBDQjhEQjZEOTM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RkJCNEFGNEQyOEM1NEZBQ0ExREJFNUQyMDM5N0U2Rjg</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OEU4RkRBQUE3RDcxNDI5MEJGNzBGOURERkU1MzdBNDU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MERDQUM4QkY4OERBNDU2RjlCM0FBOUE1NTBGN0ZEODc</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Governments</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjdEQjE4OUJDMzQxNDNEMEI0RTI1QUFCMzJENjEwRTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Distribution, Processing &amp; Storage</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NENGNzZCMDU5RjcyNEM0NEFFOUU4ODFCQkZCOThBRkI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NkVDMzM4QkJENTg3NDQ0RDg3NTA5OEM3RkMyQTlENDI</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Employees &amp; Officials</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDNCMDQzRTY3RDY3NDNEOEE4RDg2OUFEOTRBNDREQzg7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Njg1MkM3RkYyNzIxNEVFRkJFMTI2NUM4NUU1ODdEM0Q</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Finance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjMzOTBBRTg2MUVDNDdDNUE1M0QxNDk1RERCNjNCN0I7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Njg1MkM3RkYyNzIxNEVFRkJFMTI2NUM4NUU1ODdEM0Q</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OTI0MkYyMDU1OEFCNDczQTgxNTc1NTczREYzMUQ3MzI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QURCRDNBRjBGRTE0NEFBRUEzNUU1MzFGQjg3MTM4MDI</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Product Promotions</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OUM5MDE2NEFCMjRFNDk2NUJERUQ0QzYyNEQzNDk3NEQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NkVDMzM4QkJENTg3NDQ0RDg3NTA5OEM3RkMyQTlENDI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Labor &amp; Employment Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MTE3QUQwOTA0MUYzNDlCMEFFMjUwRUNDM0RDRkM5QzM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Definition of Employees</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QUIyNDcxQkExREQ4NDBEMkE1MkRERTE3QkI2RTkzNEY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6M0Y4OTVEMTE3QTc3NDI5QTkwMjMwMkRBNjRBMUM2NkM</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Real Property Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QUUyRTcxRURBNEY2NEE2MDk3QzBCNzRDOEY0NTZDQzk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OUMxMzhDNkRFNkYxNEVCQzkxMzEzQTgyRjA3QzBEODA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6N0ZFMkU1NEFCMjY5NDY0MjhBNTE5Njk1QjZCNTkzMzI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification><classificationGroup classificationScheme="indexing-terms"><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem score="90"><className>Governments</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjdEQjE4OUJDMzQxNDNEMEI0RTI1QUFCMzJENjEwRTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></classificationGroup></metadata></legislativeDoc>