<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#349#000016#     1#          253#">Va. Code Ann. § 16.1-253</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_16.1-253"/><heading><desig>§ 16.1-253.</desig><title>Preliminary protective order</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a"/><heading><desig>A.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Upon the motion of any person or upon the court's own motion, the court may issue a preliminary protective order, after a hearing, if necessary to protect a child's life, health, safety or normal development pending the final determination of any matter before the court. The order may require a child's parents, guardian, legal custodian, other person standing in loco parentis or other family or household member of the child to observe reasonable conditions of behavior for a specified length of time. These conditions shall include any one or more of the following:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> To abstain from offensive conduct against the child, a family or household member of the child or any person to whom custody of the child is awarded;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> To cooperate in the provision of reasonable services or programs designed to protect the child's life, health or normal development;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> To allow persons named by the court to come into the child's home at reasonable times designated by the court to visit the child or inspect the fitness of the home and to determine the physical or emotional health of the child;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_4"/><heading><desig>4.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> To allow visitation with the child by persons entitled thereto, as determined by the court;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_5"/><heading><desig>5.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> To refrain from acts of commission or omission which tend to endanger the child's life, health or normal development;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_6"/><heading><desig>6.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> To refrain from such contact with the child or family or household members of the child, as the court may deem appropriate, including removal of such person from the residence of the child. However, prior to the issuance by the court of an order removing such person from the residence of the child, the petitioner must prove by a preponderance of the evidence that such person's probable future conduct would constitute a danger to the life or health of such child, and that there are no less drastic alternatives which could reasonably and adequately protect the child's life or health pending a final determination on the petition; or</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_7"/><heading><desig>7.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> To grant the person on whose behalf the order is issued the possession of any companion animal as defined in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 3.2-6500"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 3.2-6500">§ 3.2-6500<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000003#     2#         6500#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> if such person meets the definition of owner in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 3.2-6500"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 3.2-6500">§ 3.2-6500<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000003#     2#         6500#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b"/><heading><desig>B.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> A preliminary protective order may be issued ex parte upon motion of any person or the court's own motion in any matter before the court, or upon petition. The motion or petition shall be supported by an affidavit or by sworn testimony in person before the judge or intake officer which establishes that the child would be subjected to an imminent threat to life or health to the extent that delay for the provision of an adversary hearing would be likely to result in serious or irremediable injury to the child's life or health. If an ex parte order is issued without an affidavit being presented, the court, in its order, shall state the basis upon which the order was entered, including a summary of the allegations made and the court's findings. Following the issuance of an ex parte order the court shall provide an adversary hearing to the affected parties within the shortest practicable time not to exceed five business days after the issuance of the order.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c"/><heading><desig>C.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Prior to the hearing required by this section, notice of the hearing shall be given at least 24 hours in advance of the hearing to the guardian ad litem for the child, to the parents, guardian, legal custodian, or other person standing in loco parentis of the child, to any other family or household member of the child to whom the protective order may be directed and to the child if he or she is 12 years of age or older. The notice provided herein shall include (i) the time, date and place for the hearing and (ii) a specific statement of the factual circumstances which allegedly necessitate the issuance of a preliminary protective order.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d"/><heading><desig>D.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> All parties to the hearing shall be informed of their right to counsel pursuant to <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 16.1-266"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 16.1-266">§ 16.1-266<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000016#     1#          266#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_e"/><heading><desig>E.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> At the hearing the child, his or her parents, guardian, legal custodian or other person standing in loco parentis and any other family or household member of the child to whom notice was given shall have the right to confront and cross-examine all adverse witnesses and evidence and to present evidence on their own behalf.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_f"/><heading><desig>F.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> If a petition alleging abuse or neglect of a child has been filed, at the hearing pursuant to this section the court shall determine whether the allegations of abuse or neglect have been proven by a preponderance of the evidence. Any finding of abuse or neglect shall be stated in the court order. However, if, before such a finding is made, a person responsible for the care and custody of the child, the child's guardian ad litem or the local department of social services objects to a finding being made at the hearing, the court shall schedule an adjudicatory hearing to be held within 30 days of the date of the initial preliminary protective order hearing. The adjudicatory hearing shall be held to determine whether the allegations of abuse and neglect have been proven by a preponderance of the evidence. Parties who are present at the hearing shall be given notice of the date set for the adjudicatory hearing and parties who are not present shall be summoned as provided in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 16.1-263"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 16.1-263">§ 16.1-263<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000016#     1#          263#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>. The adjudicatory hearing shall be held and an order may be entered, although a party to the hearing fails to appear and is not represented by counsel, provided personal or substituted service was made on the person, or the court determines that such person cannot be found, after reasonable effort, or in the case of a person who is without the Commonwealth, the person cannot be found or his post office address cannot be ascertained after reasonable effort.</p><p>Any preliminary protective order issued shall remain in full force and effect pending the adjudicatory hearing.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_g"/><heading><desig>G.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> If at the preliminary protective order hearing held pursuant to this section the court makes a finding of abuse or neglect and a preliminary protective order is issued, a dispositional hearing shall be held pursuant to <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 16.1-278.2"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 16.1-278.2">§ 16.1-278.2.<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000016#     1#        278.2#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> The court shall forthwith, but in all cases no later than the end of the business day on which the order was issued, enter and transfer electronically to the Virginia Criminal Information Network the respondent's identifying information and the name, date of birth, sex, and race of each protected person provided to the court. A copy of the preliminary protective order containing any such identifying information shall be forwarded forthwith to the primary law-enforcement agency responsible for service and entry of protective orders. Upon receipt of the order by the primary law-enforcement agency, the agency shall forthwith verify and enter any modification as necessary to the identifying information and other appropriate information required by the Department of State Police into the Virginia Criminal Information Network established and maintained by the Department of State Police pursuant to Chapter 2 (§ 52-12 et seq.) of Title 52 and the order shall be served forthwith on the allegedly abusing person in person as provided in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 16.1-264"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 16.1-264">§ 16.1-264<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000016#     1#          264#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> and due return made to the court. However, if the order is issued by the circuit court, the clerk of the circuit court shall forthwith forward an attested copy of the order containing the respondent's identifying information and the name, date of birth, sex, and race of each protected person provided to the court to the primary law-enforcement agency providing service and entry of protective orders and upon receipt of the order, the primary law-enforcement agency shall enter the name of the person subject to the order and other appropriate information required by the Department of State Police into the Virginia Criminal Information Network established and maintained by the Department pursuant to Chapter 2 (§ 52-12 et seq.) of Title 52 and the order shall be served forthwith upon the allegedly abusing person in person as provided in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 16.1-264"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 16.1-264">§ 16.1-264<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000016#     1#          264#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>. Upon service, the agency making service shall enter the date and time of service and other appropriate information required by the Department of State Police into the Virginia Criminal Information Network and make due return to the court. The preliminary order shall specify a date for the dispositional hearing. The dispositional hearing shall be scheduled at the time of the hearing pursuant to this section, and shall be held within 60 days of this hearing. If an adjudicatory hearing is requested pursuant to subsection F, the dispositional hearing shall nonetheless be scheduled at the hearing pursuant to this section. All parties present at the hearing shall be given notice of the date and time scheduled for the dispositional hearing; parties who are not present shall be summoned to appear as provided in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 16.1-263"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 16.1-263">§ 16.1-263<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000016#     1#          263#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_h"/><heading><desig>H.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Nothing in this section enables the court to remove a child from the custody of his or her parents, guardian, legal custodian or other person standing in loco parentis, except as provided in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 16.1-278.2"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 16.1-278.2">§ 16.1-278.2<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000016#     1#        278.2#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, and no order hereunder shall be entered against a person over whom the court does not have jurisdiction.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_i"/><heading><desig>I.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Neither a law-enforcement agency, the attorney for the Commonwealth, a court nor the clerk's office, nor any employee of them, may disclose, except among themselves, the residential address, telephone number, or place of employment of the person protected by the order or that of the family of such person, except to the extent that disclosure is (i) required by law or the Rules of the Supreme Court, (ii) necessary for law-enforcement purposes, or (iii) permitted by the court for good cause.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_j"/><heading><desig>J.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Violation of any order issued pursuant to this section shall constitute contempt of court.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_k"/><heading><desig>K.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The court shall forthwith, but in all cases no later than the end of the business day on which the order was issued, enter and transfer electronically to the Virginia Criminal Information Network the respondent's identifying information and the name, date of birth, sex, and race of each protected person provided to the court. A copy of the preliminary protective order containing any such identifying information shall be forwarded forthwith to the primary law-enforcement agency responsible for service and entry of protective orders. Upon receipt of the order by the primary law-enforcement agency, the agency shall forthwith verify and enter any modification as necessary to the identifying information and other appropriate information required by the Department of State Police into the Virginia Criminal Information Network established and maintained by the Department pursuant to Chapter 2 (§ 52-12 et seq.) of Title 52 and the order shall be served forthwith on the allegedly abusing person in person as provided in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 16.1-264"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 16.1-264">§ 16.1-264<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000016#     1#          264#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> and due return made to the court. However, if the order is issued by the circuit court, the clerk of the circuit court shall forthwith forward an attested copy of the order containing the respondent's identifying information and the name, date of birth, sex, and race of each protected person provided to the court to the primary law-enforcement agency providing service and entry of protective orders and upon receipt of the order, the primary law-enforcement agency shall enter the name of the person subject to the order and other appropriate information required by the Department of State Police into the Virginia Criminal Information Network established and maintained by the Department pursuant to Chapter 2 (§ 52-12 et seq.) of Title 52 and the order shall be served forthwith on the allegedly abusing person in person as provided in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 16.1-264"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 16.1-264">§ 16.1-264<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000016#     1#          264#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>. Upon service, the agency making service shall enter the date and time of service and other appropriate information required by the Department of State Police into the Virginia Criminal Information Network and make due return to the court. The preliminary order shall specify a date for the full hearing.</p><p>Upon receipt of the return of service or other proof of service pursuant to subsection C of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 16.1-264"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 16.1-264">§ 16.1-264<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000016#     1#          264#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, the clerk shall forthwith forward an attested copy of the preliminary protective order to the primary law-enforcement agency and the agency shall forthwith verify and enter any modification as necessary into the Virginia Criminal Information Network as described above. If the order is later dissolved or modified, a copy of the dissolution or modification order shall also be attested, forwarded forthwith to the primary law-enforcement agency responsible for service and entry of protective orders, and upon receipt of the order by the primary law-enforcement agency, the agency shall forthwith verify and enter any modification as necessary to the identifying information and other appropriate information required by the Department of State Police into the Virginia Criminal Information Network as described above and the order shall be served forthwith and due return made to the court.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_l"/><heading><desig>L.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> No fee shall be charged for filing or serving any petition or order pursuant to this section.</p></bodyText></level><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p>1977, c. 559; 1985, c. 595; 1986, c. 308; 1987, c. 497; <citation normalizedCite="1996 VA CH 866"><content><span normalizedCite="1996 Va. Ch. 866">1996, c. 866<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1996#000866#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1997 VA CH 790"><content><span normalizedCite="1997 Va. Ch. 790">1997, c. 790<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1997#000790#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1998 VA CH 550"><content><span normalizedCite="1998 Va. Ch. 550">1998, c. 550<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1998#000550#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2002 VA CH 508"><content><span normalizedCite="2002 Va. Ch. 508">2002, cc. 508<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2002#000508#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2002 VA CH 810"><content><span normalizedCite="2002 Va. Ch. 810">810<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2002#000810#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2002 VA CH 818"><content><span normalizedCite="2002 Va. Ch. 818">818<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2002#000818#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2008 VA CH 73"><content><span normalizedCite="2008 Va. Ch. 73">2008, cc. 73<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2008#000073#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="2008 VA CH 246"><content><span normalizedCite="2008 Va. Ch. 246">246<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2008#000246#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2009 VA CH 732"><content><span normalizedCite="2009 Va. Ch. 732">2009, c. 732<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2009#000732#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2013 VA CH 130"><content><span normalizedCite="2013 Va. Ch. 130">2013, c. 130<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2013#000130#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2014 VA CH 346"><content><span normalizedCite="2014 Va. Ch. 346">2014, c. 346<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2014#000346#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PV10-004G-K1PW-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 16.1.</desig><title>COURTS NOT OF RECORD</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 11.</desig><title>JUVENILE AND DOMESTIC RELATIONS DISTRICT COURTS</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="article"><heading><desig>ARTICLE 4.</desig><title>IMMEDIATE CUSTODY, ARREST, DETENTION AND SHELTER CARE</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjA4OEVGODBENzY4NDcxM0IyQzA1OTEwQzVDODRBOUE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Notice Requirements</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MTI1NzY0MjlDODEwNDE1QTkxMzMxNjM3RDM4MDc5MTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NjcxMDAyODc5OTA1NDBEMjhFMEVEQUM2NzI1NkM2NTA</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Criminal Law &amp; Procedure</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NEU0RkE1OUQwNUQwNDgxODhEODZCMjkzOTg3NThBNzk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NUIxQTE2NTMyRENCNDdFOUFBRTAyMEJGODFCQzA5RDA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6REVEMDZCMjVGNTNGNDlDN0E1QjBCRDJCMjNBQzdGNDg</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RTIzNjhCQkNFREVGNERFMjkxM0I3RkM1RDZFNTAyQzA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6ODU5RDY4RjZDQzhENDg1REJEQ0Q5MkI5REU5MTY5RDI</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDIwRjc0N0I2NkE2NDI3QjkyMzI4NjFGNTc5MzQ1NEE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NEU4N0IwOEEwRjdCNEM5MzhCQzE0Njc3NTNFMDVGMTA</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Right to Counsel During Questioning</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RkI4NzkxODEzOEJENDc5OUI0QzBGQzI3ODc5M0Q0REM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MEZDNDMxRkU5MTE2NDJFMTk4QjlENjk4RjE0NkM4Njg</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Family Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NEI4M0U5Qzg3RTk0NDdBRUJGNDRGNkZEQkU3RDdFNDU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Abuse, Endangerment &amp; Neglect</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OEI5RTc4NDg3RDY5NDM4Qzg2RkZFRDk0QTI2REFGNUI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RkE2MkE5MTUwMzk5NEJFN0E5RUFCRUIyNDg3RkU4Rjc</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjVCREI2RjlFM0VBNDQxQThCM0ExREREQTYxRDdGNkY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RjU5MjVFRkRBNUE2NDEwOTk4NUIyRkQ1NkYxNjU0MDY</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Q0RCREM3QzU5OEVDNDlEM0FGRDgxQkQwRTFBOEREQzU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6N0UzRjg5QjhFNTdFNDQ3N0FEMUY0NTVEQkEzQ0M2RTA</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6REI1MDI3OTE1NDZENDYzRjlCNDgyNzFEMDc3MDNFQUE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RkE2MkE5MTUwMzk5NEJFN0E5RUFCRUIyNDg3RkU4Rjc</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NjA1MUYxNEQzQUZGNERBOUE5QUJFRDk0RDIwMEJBNzY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDkyNkUxNzIzNzZFNDI3OUI1MTI2NTBEOUMyNERGNTE</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Guardians Ad Litem</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NzRDMUI5QzVFNzc0NDk3ODhBQzg2RjQ1QTlFRUNGMTc7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OUJEMEI4NEQyMzdBNDczREJFOEYzQkZBOUMzMzc0MzM</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Governments</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjdEQjE4OUJDMzQxNDNEMEI0RTI1QUFCMzJENjEwRTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Clerks of Court</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6REVFMjkzRDI1MkU2NERDNjk3OEUxODY0REYwMUI1NjE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NURENzJGNTEyQzM0NEREQUI2RkVCRTM4RTc1RTZBREU</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Torts</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDAwOEM2NTEzQkVDNEI4NzlGMEZERUEyRjQwODM4Njg7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MkQwMTc0MUU5MzkxNEMwQzhEQkU0QjA2REQzQzNGMTc7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RjMzQjNFQ0U1MDdFNEQzMjg0MTA0MTY4MUZCQTZBM0U</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification><classificationGroup classificationScheme="indexing-terms"><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem score="90"><className>Governments</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjdEQjE4OUJDMzQxNDNEMEI0RTI1QUFCMzJENjEwRTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></classificationGroup></metadata></legislativeDoc>