<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#349#000038#     2#          613#">Va. Code Ann. § 38.2-613</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_38.2-613"/><heading><desig>§ 38.2-613.</desig><title>Disclosure limitations and conditions</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a"/><heading><desig>A.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> An insurance institution, agent, or insurance-support organization shall not disclose any medical-record information or privileged information about an individual collected or received in connection with an insurance transaction unless the disclosure is with the written authorization of the individual, provided:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> If the authorization is submitted by another insurance institution, agent, or insurance-support organization, the authorization meets the requirements of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 38.2-606"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 38.2-606">§ 38.2-606<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000038#     2#          606#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; or</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> If the authorization is submitted by a person other than an insurance institution, agent, or insurance-support organization, the authorization is:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_2_a"/><heading><desig>a.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Dated,</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_2_b"/><heading><desig>b.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Signed by the individual, and</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_2_c"/><heading><desig>c.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Obtained two years or less prior to the date a disclosure is sought pursuant to this subdivision.</p></bodyText></level></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b"/><heading><desig>B.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Notwithstanding the provisions of subsection A of this section, an insurance institution, agent, or insurance-support organization may disclose personal or privileged information about an individual collected or received in connection with an insurance transaction, without written authorization, if the disclosure is:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> To a person other than an insurance institution, agent, or insurance-support organization, provided the disclosure is reasonably necessary:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_1_a"/><heading><desig>a.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> To enable that person to perform a business, professional or insurance function for the disclosing insurance institution, agent, or insurance-support organization and that person agrees not to disclose the information further without the individual's written authorization unless the further disclosure:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_1_a_1"/><heading><desig>(1)</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Would otherwise be permitted by this section if made by an insurance institution, agent, or insurance-support organization; or</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_1_a_2"/><heading><desig>(2)</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Is reasonably necessary for that person to perform its function for the disclosing insurance institution, agent, or insurance-support organization; or</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_1_b"/><heading><desig>b.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> To enable that person to provide information to the disclosing insurance institution, agent, or insurance-support organization for the purpose of:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_1_b_1"/><heading><desig>(1)</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Determining an individual's eligibility for an insurance benefit or payment; or</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_1_b_2"/><heading><desig>(2)</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Detecting or preventing criminal activity, fraud, material misrepresentation, or material nondisclosure in connection with an insurance transaction; or</p></bodyText></level></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> To an insurance institution, agent, or insurance-support organization, or self-insurer, provided the information disclosed is limited to that which is reasonably necessary:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_2_a"/><heading><desig>a.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> To detect or prevent criminal activity, fraud, material misrepresentation, or material nondisclosure in connection with insurance transactions; or</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_2_b"/><heading><desig>b.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> For either the disclosing or receiving insurance institution, agent or insurance-support organization to perform its function in connection with an insurance transaction involving the individual; or</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> To a medical-care institution or medical professional for the purpose of (i) verifying insurance coverage or benefits, (ii) informing an individual of a medical problem of which the individual may not be aware or (iii) conducting an operations or services audit, provided only that information is disclosed as is reasonably necessary to accomplish the foregoing purposes; or</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_4"/><heading><desig>4.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> To an insurance regulatory authority; or</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_5"/><heading><desig>5.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> To a law-enforcement or other government authority:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_5_a"/><heading><desig>a.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> To protect the interests of the insurance institution, agent or insurance-support organization in preventing or prosecuting the perpetration of fraud upon it; or</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_5_b"/><heading><desig>b.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> If the insurance institution, agent, or insurance-support organization reasonably believes that illegal activities have been conducted by the individual; or</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_5_c"/><heading><desig>c.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Upon written request of any law-enforcement agency, for all insured or claimant information in the possession of an insurance institution, agent, or insurance-support organization which relates an ongoing criminal investigation. Such insurance institution, agent, or insurance-support organization shall release such information, including, but not limited to, policy information, premium payment records, record of prior claims by the insured or by another claimant, and information collected in connection with an insurance company's investigation of an application or claim. Any information released to a law-enforcement agency pursuant to such request shall be treated as confidential criminal investigation information and not be disclosed further except as provided by law. Notwithstanding any provision in this chapter, no insurance institution, agent, or insurance-support organization shall notify any insured or claimant that information has been requested or supplied pursuant to this section prior to notification from the requesting law-enforcement agency that its criminal investigation is completed. Within ninety days following the completion of any such criminal investigation, the law-enforcement agency making such a request for information shall notify any insurance institution, agent, or insurance-support organization from whom information was requested that the criminal investigation has been completed; or</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_6"/><heading><desig>6.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Otherwise permitted or required by law; or</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_7"/><heading><desig>7.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> In response to a facially valid administrative or judicial order, including a search warrant or subpoena; or</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_8"/><heading><desig>8.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Made for the purpose of conducting actuarial or research studies, provided:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_8_a"/><heading><desig>a.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> No individual may be identified in any actuarial or research report, and</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_8_b"/><heading><desig>b.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Materials allowing the individual to be identified are returned or destroyed as soon as they are no longer needed, and</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_8_c"/><heading><desig>c.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The actuarial or research organization agrees not to disclose the information unless the disclosure would otherwise be permitted by this section if made by an insurance institution, agent, or insurance-support organization; or</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_9"/><heading><desig>9.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> To a party or a representative of a party to a proposed or consummated sale, transfer, merger, or consolidation of all or part of the business of the insurance institution, agent, or insurance-support organization, provided:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_9_a"/><heading><desig>a.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Prior to the consummation of the sale, transfer, merger, or consolidation only such information is disclosed as is reasonably necessary to enable the recipient to make business decisions about the purchase, transfer, merger, or consolidation, and</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_9_b"/><heading><desig>b.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The recipient agrees not to disclose the information unless the disclosure would otherwise be permitted by this section if made by an insurance institution, agent, or insurance-support organization; or</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_10"/><heading><desig>10.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> To a nonaffiliated third party whose only use of such information will be in connection with the marketing of a nonfinancial product or service, provided:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_10_a"/><heading><desig>a.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> No medical-record information, privileged information, or personal information relating to an individual's character, personal habits, mode of living, or general reputation is disclosed, and no classification derived from the information is disclosed,</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_10_b"/><heading><desig>b.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The individual has been given an opportunity, in accordance with the provisions of subsection A of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 38.2-612.1"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 38.2-612.1">§ 38.2-612.1<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000038#     2#        612.1#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, to indicate that he does not want financial information disclosed for marketing purposes and has given no indication that he does not want the information disclosed, and</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_10_c"/><heading><desig>c.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The nonaffiliated third party receiving such information agrees not to use it except in connection with the marketing of the product or service; or</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_11"/><heading><desig>11.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> (i) To a consumer reporting agency in accordance with the Fair Credit Reporting Act <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="15 USC 1681"><content><span normalizedCite="15 U.S.C. 1681">(15 U.S.C. § 1681<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1828#123#000015#       1681#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> et seq.) or (ii) from a consumer report reported by a consumer reporting agency; or</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_12"/><heading><desig>12.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> To a group policyholder for the purpose of reporting claims experience or conducting an audit of the insurance institution's or agent's operations or services, provided the information disclosed is reasonably necessary for the group policyholder to conduct the review or audit; or</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_13"/><heading><desig>13.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> To a professional peer review organization for the purpose of reviewing the service or conduct of a medical-care institution or medical professional; or</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_14"/><heading><desig>14.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> To a governmental authority for the purpose of determining the individual's eligibility for health benefits for which the governmental authority may be liable; or</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_15"/><heading><desig>15.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> To a certificate holder or policyholder for the purpose of providing information regarding the status of an insurance transaction; or</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_16"/><heading><desig>16.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> To a lienholder, mortgagee, assignee, lessor or other person shown on the records of an insurance institution or agent as having a legal or beneficial interest in a policy of insurance, or to persons acting in a fiduciary or representative capacity on behalf of the individual, provided that:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_16_a"/><heading><desig>a.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> No medical record information is disclosed unless the disclosure would be permitted by this section; and</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_16_b"/><heading><desig>b.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The information disclosed is limited to that which is reasonably necessary to permit such person to protect his interest in the policy; or</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_17"/><heading><desig>17.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Necessary to effect, administer, or enforce a transaction requested or authorized by the individual, or in connection with servicing or processing an insurance product or service requested or authorized by the individual, or necessary for reinsurance purposes, or for stop loss or excess loss agreements provided for in subsection B of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 38.2-109"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 38.2-109">§ 38.2-109<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000038#     2#          109#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; or</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b_18"/><heading><desig>18.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Pursuant to any federal Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act privacy rules promulgated by the United States Department of Health and Human Services.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c"/><heading><desig>C.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> An insurance institution, agent, or insurance-support organization may disclose information about an individual collected or received in connection with an insurance transaction, without written authorization, if the disclosure is:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> To a nonaffiliated third party whose only use of such information will be to perform services for or functions on behalf of the insurance institution in connection with the marketing of the insurance institution's product or service or the marketing of products or services offered pursuant to a joint marketing agreement, provided:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c_1_a"/><heading><desig>a.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> No medical-record information or privileged information is disclosed without the individual's written authorization unless such disclosure is otherwise permitted by subsection B of this section,</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c_1_b"/><heading><desig>b.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> With respect to financial information, the individual has been given the notice required by subsection B of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 38.2-604.1"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 38.2-604.1">§ 38.2-604.1<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000038#     2#        604.1#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, and</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c_1_c"/><heading><desig>c.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The person receiving such financial information agrees, by contract, (i) not to use it except to perform services for or functions on behalf of the insurance institution in connection with the marketing of the insurance institution's product or service or the marketing of products or services offered pursuant to a joint marketing agreement, or as permitted under subsection B of this section and (ii) to maintain the confidentiality of such information and not disclose it to any other nonaffiliated third party unless such disclosure would otherwise be permitted by this section if made by the insurance institution, agent, or insurance-support organization;</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> To an affiliate, provided:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c_2_a"/><heading><desig>a.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> No medical-record information or privileged information is disclosed without the individual's written authorization unless such disclosure is otherwise permitted by subsection B of this section, and</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c_2_b"/><heading><desig>b.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The affiliate receiving the information does not disclose the information except as would otherwise be permitted by this section if such disclosure were made by the insurance institution, agent, or insurance-support organization.</p></bodyText></level></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d"/><heading><desig>D.</desig></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> No person proposing to issue, re-issue, or renew any policy, contract, or plan of accident and sickness insurance defined in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 38.2-109"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 38.2-109">§ 38.2-109<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000038#     2#          109#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, but excluding disability income insurance, issued by any (i) insurer providing hospital, medical and surgical or major medical coverage on an expense incurred basis, (ii) corporation providing a health services plan, or (iii) health maintenance organization providing a health care plan for health care services shall disclose any genetic information about an individual or a member of such individual's family collected or received in connection with any insurance transaction unless the disclosure is made with the written authorization of the individual.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> For the purpose of this subsection, "genetic information" means information about genes, gene products, or inherited characteristics that may derive from an individual or a family member.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_d_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Agents and insurance support organizations shall be subject to the provisions of this subsection to the extent of their participation in the issue, re-issue, or renewal of any policy, contract, or plan of accident and sickness insurance defined in <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 38.2-109"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 38.2-109">§ 38.2-109<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000038#     2#          109#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, but excluding disability income insurance.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_e"/><heading><desig>E.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Any notices, disclosures, or authorizations required by this section may be provided electronically if the individual agrees.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_f"/><heading><desig>F.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Any privileged information about an individual that is disclosed in violation of this section shall be available to that individual in accordance with the provisions of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 38.2-608"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 38.2-608">§§ 38.2-608<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000038#     2#          608#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> and <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 38.2-609"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 38.2-609">38.2-609<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000038#     2#          609#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_g"/><heading><desig>G.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Except in the case of disclosures made pursuant to subdivision B 10 of this section, the requirements of subsection A of <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 38.2-612.1"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 38.2-612.1">§ 38.2-612.1<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000038#     2#        612.1#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> shall not apply when information is disclosed pursuant to this section.</p></bodyText></level><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p>1981, c. 389, § 38.1-57.16; 1986, c. 562; 1987, c. 325; <citation normalizedCite="1996 VA CH 704"><content><span normalizedCite="1996 Va. Ch. 704">1996, c. 704<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1996#000704#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="2001 VA CH 371"><content><span normalizedCite="2001 Va. Ch. 371">2001, c. 371<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#2001#000371#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PT40-004G-K45P-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 38.2.</desig><title>INSURANCE</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 6.</desig><title>INSURANCE INFORMATION AND PRIVACY PROTECTION</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Banking Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjQyMUFCOUJBNURBNEFDREE3MTNCNDk5QkQ4NUM3RjI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Consumer Reports</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NkZDNDZGMzE5Mjk2NDE0RkIyQjI1NTFDMkQzRTE0QzE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NTBENkY4NTNENTk0NEE0RUJBMDVBMTYyNjJBNjU2Njc</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NzIwNzNERjZDMUNCNEY5Mzk0OUY2NjdFM0E3N0ZBQTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NTBENkY4NTNENTk0NEE0RUJBMDVBMTYyNjJBNjU2Njc</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Fair Credit Reporting Act</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDVCNDg1QjUyNEJENDdCRUFCNUQ2NUYxOTI2NzhBRTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDZBQjAwRjNDNUNDNEJGQkE1QjQ1NjJDRTMxNkQyRTA</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Health Insurance Portability &amp; Accountability Act</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NjVFNjYwOEVBNEUyNEMwQjk3NzlCRjI5NzBDNDlBOTM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QzNEOEE3NjhDNTJBNDhCOTgxRkQzNzc1Q0JCMkU4Q0I</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Health Maintenance Organizations</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MzNDMEYyOTY3NjdBNEE4MDlCQTlDMUQxRDMyMUZCNDM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NkUxMkVDQjJDOEY5NDVDQ0E5NTFEMTlDMjIwNzVERjc</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Supporting Documentation Requirement</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6REFDNjY1QTg3RDUwNDRFRDgwNkU2M0YxRjA2NUY3MkU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NjFGQ0Q3QUZFNUFENEFBMjhGNkE1MUREQzZERUY5RkI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjA4OEVGODBENzY4NDcxM0IyQzA1OTEwQzVDODRBOUE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Application of Agency Law Principles</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6M0M2N0FDQzc3MDM0NEQ5Q0ExNTk0QjE4QUM1QTUxNjA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NUM4MDgzNEIzQ0VDNEJCODk5MzE1ODk2MUZFREU5NkI</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjQ1NzI5NzRGQUEwNDg1RThBNDE0NTE2MkYzODc3NUQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RUZBNTgwODk0QkRCNDUwQkExNzBFRkU0NkI4MkE5OTU</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Criminal Law &amp; Procedure</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NEU0RkE1OUQwNUQwNDgxODhEODZCMjkzOTg3NThBNzk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NEY5NTAzODM4MjUzNDNCMzg1QjI0NTdFNkVCMEU1Mjg7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QTYxNERFOEFFQUJFNEJENzk2RUVGOUQ0NkY3MTczNEQ</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Evidence</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUVGQkU0QjJFMTIzNDNBM0FCNTVEQjAxQTM3RDcwOTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Elements</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUMxQTkwQTcxRjRDNEVBRTk4RERCMThEQjE2NkI1RDg7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QzBDMEM3QTE3RUU3NENGQzhEOTBCMEJENkI3QkNDNzI</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Exceptions</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NEJFMzlFNTc2NUI5NDJFOTgyODdEMUZBN0Q2MzYyRTk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QzBDMEM3QTE3RUU3NENGQzhEOTBCMEJENkI3QkNDNzI</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NzA2QzU2MkFCMzMzNDgwNkEzMDIzRDE2ODgxRjUzMkY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QzBDMEM3QTE3RUU3NENGQzhEOTBCMEJENkI3QkNDNzI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Healthcare Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NkUxMkVDQjJDOEY5NDVDQ0E5NTFEMTlDMjIwNzVERjc7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MkM0RjM1NjlERDhBNDk2Q0I2RTZCOEIxM0Y0MjI0RDE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NTg4RTkyNjk5MUY0NEU4Q0FBMDg2MzI1ODBCRUQ3OEY</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6ODZDMjQzOUU2MTM4NEJENzgxQTNDRjkzNkExRDcxNEU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUVGMzQ2NUZDREVCNEEwQkI0N0I4NjQ2RDVBQTFEQzI</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Health Maintenance Organizations</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MzNDMEYyOTY3NjdBNEE4MDlCQTlDMUQxRDMyMUZCNDM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUVGMzQ2NUZDREVCNEEwQkI0N0I4NjQ2RDVBQTFEQzI</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Organizations</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QzYyMzU0NUI2MTg4NDU5NEFFRkI3ODQxRUM2QTY2ODQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6M0JBQTc2MDg4OUY4NDRDQzk5QkQ0OTVFMUVCQzY4NkY</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Insurance Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDM4MzQ2QUYzMTY0NDQzQTkxRDQwRUUzRUM5RDg0OEM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Agent &amp; Broker Premiums</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NzEzMDRGOUJDNzVDNDg5REJDRjJCODlGMUMyQjE4Q0Q7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QkE5N0U0RkQwM0VENDRCRjkzN0M3RjA1Qjg4OEJERDA</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Disclosure Obligations</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjAwNTBBNUY4RkY3NEM1M0FEQkFDN0Y1QTY4Q0I5N0E7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NTM4NzQwMkQwQkUyNEVDRTg0QjUxNDQ2NTkwRDVGRjE</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Fair Credit Reporting Act</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDVCNDg1QjUyNEJENDdCRUFCNUQ2NUYxOTI2NzhBRTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDZBQjAwRjNDNUNDNEJGQkE1QjQ1NjJDRTMxNkQyRTA</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6ODk1Qzg5MzA4MEQ2NDM4QUJGOTZBNkJDOEQ1MTUwNUQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RkE3MEM1QjNFMTFFNEY2MThGNDIwMzQzMzI4RTc4M0M</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RTFEMDYzQTAxQTZDNEYzQzkzODFBM0RBODNGNERDRDQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NzVCREFBMEI5RUMxNEVGNzhCNjRCRTNGODY5RTVBMTE</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MzlEMURCMkFEQTNDNDcxQUFGQjFCMzY4OEE1QjIwQkM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OUM1QjU1RTk4NjlCNEIwN0IwRjVBQjNFRjgzMTA4Rjc</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Health Conditions</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OTcwMUM3OEY0QzMyNDRDOThDNUU1NzE4RUE1MkRFMTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MEVBQUY4MEE4MTAxNEFDREJBRDYzMjdDOTZDMjM4NTI</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Materiality</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RjI5OTc3NEI1M0IzNDQzRjlFNTk0QTc2MkZEQUVCMDg7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MEVBQUY4MEE4MTAxNEFDREJBRDYzMjdDOTZDMjM4NTI</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Notice Requirements</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OTYxMDAzQTRFREI2NDgxRUE3NzU0NTQzMEZBNjNBNjM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDE2MEM1NDREREFDNDgwNEE4RDgxRjUxN0Y0QzEzRjI</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Supporting Documentation Requirement</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6REFDNjY1QTg3RDUwNDRFRDgwNkU2M0YxRjA2NUY3MkU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NjFGQ0Q3QUZFNUFENEFBMjhGNkE1MUREQzZERUY5RkI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Labor &amp; Employment Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MTE3QUQwOTA0MUYzNDlCMEFFMjUwRUNDM0RDRkM5QzM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Disability Evidence</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OTZCNjgzQkU0ODM0NDdFMEFDRURDQTg0ODAwMDU1QzM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MzBEMkJFMTg2NTJDNEVGRjlGREQ2Nzg2ODkzMzkwQTQ</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MEU3M0E2RTJENUY0NDBBNzkyRTEyRTEyRTVEMkRGQkY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NTQ5RjUxOTZCOTk0NDRDNjg2NzJCMURBODk2NzZFOUY</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Types of Disabilities</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MzE5QkExM0Y1OEI2NEIyQjgyNDM3OTAzOTg0NDlEMkQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NTQ5RjUxOTZCOTk0NDRDNjg2NzJCMURBODk2NzZFOUY</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Mergers &amp; Acquisitions Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjRDRTUzQzBCMEIyNDU5QkE4QjFDMEE2Qjg2MUZDOTk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RTIwNkVGOTZGODdBNDg0MEFDRTdDM0FDNTM5MEU3MDU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MkZCODBEQTBEMjdDNDA1Njk5NDIxQjQ3MThGQ0MyMUM</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Pensions &amp; Benefits Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QzNEOEE3NjhDNTJBNDhCOTgxRkQzNzc1Q0JCMkU4Q0I7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Health Insurance Portability &amp; Accountability Act</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NjVFNjYwOEVBNEUyNEMwQjk3NzlCRjI5NzBDNDlBOTM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QzNEOEE3NjhDNTJBNDhCOTgxRkQzNzc1Q0JCMkU4Q0I</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification><classificationGroup classificationScheme="indexing-terms"><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem score="90"><className>Insurance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDM4MzQ2QUYzMTY0NDQzQTkxRDQwRUUzRUM5RDg0OEM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></classificationGroup></metadata></legislativeDoc>