<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#142#        23#     50.16#        25#">Va. Code Ann. § 23-50.16:25</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_23-50.16_25"/><heading><desig>§ 23-50.16:25.</desig><title>(Repealed effective October 1, 2016) Power to issue bonds</title></heading><bodyText><p>The Authority may issue bonds from time to time for any of its purposes, including financing or refinancing all or any part of its programs or general operations, costs of any project, including the hospital facilities, whether or not owned by the Authority, or to refund bonds or other obligations issued therefor by or on behalf of the Authority, the University or otherwise, including bonds or obligations not then subject to redemption, and may guarantee, assume or otherwise agree to pay, in whole or in part, indebtedness issued by the University or any other party resulting in the acquisition or construction of facilities for the benefit of the Authority or the refinancing thereof. Notwithstanding Article 1 (<citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 2.2-1800"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 2.2-1800">§ 2.2-1800<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000002#     2#         1800#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation> et seq.) of Chapter 18 of Title 2.2, bonds may be issued under the provisions of this chapter without obtaining the consent of any commission, board, bureau or agency of the Commonwealth or of any political subdivision, and without any proceedings or the happening of conditions or things other than those proceedings, conditions or things that are specifically required by this chapter; however, each debt offering shall be submitted to the State Treasurer sufficiently prior to the sale of such offering to allow the State Treasurer to undertake a review for the sole purposes of determining (i) whether the offering may constitute tax-supported debt of the Commonwealth and (ii) the potential impact of the offering on the debt capacity of the Commonwealth. After such review, the State Treasurer shall determine if the offering constitutes tax-supported debt of the Commonwealth and the potential impact of the offering on the debt capacity of the Commonwealth. If the State Treasurer determines that the debt offering may constitute tax-supported debt of the Commonwealth, or may have an adverse impact on the debt capacity of the Commonwealth, then the debt offering shall be submitted to the Treasury Board for review and approval of the terms and structure of the offering in a manner consistent with <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 2.2-2416"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 2.2-2416">§ 2.2-2416<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#349#000002#     2#         2416#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>. The Authority may issue such types of bonds as it may determine, including, without limitation, bonds payable as to principal and interest from any one or more of the following sources: (i) its revenues generally; (ii) income and revenues derived from the operation, sale or lease of a particular project or projects, whether or not they are financed or refinanced from the proceeds of such bonds; (iii) funds realized from the enforcement of security interests or other liens or obligations securing such bonds; (iv) proceeds from the sale of bonds; (v) payments under letters of credit, policies of municipal bond insurance, guarantees or other credit enhancements; (vi) any reserve or sinking funds created to secure such payment; (vii) accounts receivable of the Authority; or (viii) other available funds of the Authority.</p><p>Any bonds may be additionally guaranteed by, or secured by a pledge of, any grant, contribution or appropriation from a participating political subdivision, the University, the Commonwealth or any political subdivision, agency or instrumentality thereof, any federal agency or any unit, private corporation, partnership, association or individual.</p></bodyText><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p><citation normalizedCite="1996 VA CH 905"><content><span normalizedCite="1996 Va. Ch. 905">1996, cc. 905<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1996#000905#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>, <citation normalizedCite="1996 VA CH 1046"><content><span normalizedCite="1996 Va. Ch. 1046">1046<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1996#001046#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PV20-004G-K1SG-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 23.</desig><title>EDUCATIONAL INSTITUTIONS</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 6.2.</desig><title>VIRGINIA COMMONWEALTH UNIVERSITY HEALTH SYSTEM AUTHORITY</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Education Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDkzNUEzQzFBNEZBNEFBREIxNDM5MTc1MUU5QjI4MTY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Bonds &amp; Other Indebtedness</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RUNENDg1ODI1NTc1NEREMUI4REY3QjA1RDRDQzExRDE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjZBQUM2RjM4QkI4NDlFMkFCNTBDMzJGNDg0MTgxOUU</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NUJBMkUxQjc0M0QyNEJFQkEwQjQ4MDMzMEUxNTBGQTE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MjZBQUM2RjM4QkI4NDlFMkFCNTBDMzJGNDg0MTgxOUU</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification><classificationGroup classificationScheme="indexing-terms"><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem score="90"><className>Education</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NDkzNUEzQzFBNEZBNEFBREIxNDM5MTc1MUU5QjI4MTY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></classificationGroup></metadata></legislativeDoc>