<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!--Transformation version 1.3--><legislativeDoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.lexisnexis.com/xmlschemas/content/public/legislativedoc/1/" schemaVersion="1.0"><legislativeDocHead><citations><citeForThisResource citeDefinition="#7159#958#0000000045#0000000001#   161.292#0000000032#">Va. Code Ann. § 45.1-161.292:32</citeForThisResource></citations><legislativeBodyInfo><jurisdiction><jurisSystem normalizedLongName="Virginia" normalizedShortName="VA"/></jurisdiction></legislativeBodyInfo></legislativeDocHead><legislativeDocBody><statute><level levelType="section"><anchor id="_45.1-161.292_32"/><heading><desig>§ 45.1-161.292:32.</desig><title>Application for license</title></heading><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a"/><heading><desig>A.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> An application for a license shall be submitted by the person who will be the licensed operator of the mine. No application for a license or a renewal thereof shall be complete unless it contains the following:</p></bodyText><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_1"/><heading><desig>1.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Identity regarding the applicant. If the applicant is a sole proprietorship, the applicant shall state: (i) his full name and address; (ii) the name and address of the mine and its federal mine identification number; (iii) the name and address of the person with overall responsibility for operating decisions at the mine; (iv) the name and address of the person with overall responsibility for health and safety at the mine; (v) the federal mine identification numbers of all other mines in which the sole proprietor has a twenty percent or greater ownership interest; and (vi) the trade name, if any, and the full name, address of record and telephone number of the proprietorship. If the applicant is a partnership, the applicant shall state: (i) the name and address of the mine and its federal mine identification number; (ii) the name and address of the person with overall responsibility for operating decisions at the mine; (iii) the name and address of the person with overall responsibility for health and safety at the mine; (iv) the federal mine identification numbers of all other mines in which the partnership has a twenty percent or greater ownership interest; (v) the full name and address of all partners; (vi) the trade name, if any, and the full name and address of record and telephone number of the partnership; and (vii) the federal mine identification numbers of all other mines in which any partner has a twenty percent or greater ownership interest. If the applicant is a corporation, the applicant shall state: (i) the name and address of the mine and its federal mine identification number; (ii) the name and address of the person with overall responsibility for operating decisions at the mine; (iii) the name and address of the person with overall responsibility for health and safety at the mine; (iv) the federal mine identification numbers of all other mines in which the corporation has a twenty percent or greater ownership interest; (v) the full name, address of record and telephone number of the corporation and the state of incorporation; (vi) the full name and address of each officer and director of the corporation; (vii) if the corporation is a subsidiary corporation, the applicant shall state the full name, address, and state of incorporation of the parent corporation; and (viii) the federal mine identification numbers of all other mines in which any corporate officer has a twenty percent or greater ownership interest. If the applicant is any organization other than a sole proprietorship, partnership, or corporation, the applicant shall state: (i) the nature and type, or legal identity of the organization; (ii) the name and address of the mine and its federal mine identification number; (iii) the name and address of the person with overall responsibility for operating decisions at the mine; (iv) the name and address of the person with overall responsibility for health and safety at the mine; (v) the federal mine identification numbers of all other mines in which the organization has a twenty percent or greater ownership interest; (vi) the full name, address of record and telephone number of the organization; (vii) the name and address of each individual who has an ownership interest in the organization; (viii) the name and address of the principal organization officials or members; and (ix) the federal mine identification numbers of all other mines in which any official or member has a twenty percent or greater ownership interest;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_2"/><heading><desig>2.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The names and addresses of any agent of the applicant with responsibility for the business operation of the mine, and any person with an ownership or leasehold interest in the minerals to be mined;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_3"/><heading><desig>3.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Information about each independent contractor working at the mine: (i) the independent contractor's trade name, business address and business telephone number; (ii) a description of the nature of the work to be performed by the independent contractor and where at the mine the work is to be performed; (iii) the independent contractor's MSHA identification number, if any; (iv) the independent contractor's address of record for service of citations and other documents; (v) the names and addresses of persons with overall responsibility for operating decisions; and (vi) the names and addresses of persons with overall responsibility for the health and safety of employees;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_4"/><heading><desig>4.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The names and addresses of persons to be contacted in the event of an accident or other emergency at the mine;</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_5"/><heading><desig>5.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Such information required by the Department that is relevant to an assessment of the safety and health risks likely to be associated with the operation of the mine; and</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_a_6"/><heading><desig>6.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> For any license renewal, the annual report required pursuant to <citation type="statute" normalizedCite="VACODE 45.1-161.292:35"><content><span normalizedCite="Va. Code Ann. § 45.1-161.292:35">§ 45.1-161.292:35<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#7159#958#0000000045#0000000001#   161.292#0000000035#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></level></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_b"/><heading><desig>B.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> The application shall be certified as being complete and accurate by the applicant, if an individual; by the agent of a corporate applicant; or by a general partner of an applicant that is a partnership. The application shall be submitted on forms furnished or approved by the Department.</p></bodyText></level><level levelType="paragraph"><anchor id="_c"/><heading><desig>C.</desig></heading><bodyText><p> Within thirty days after the occurrence of any change in the information required by subsection A, the licensed operator shall notify the Department, in writing, of such change.</p></bodyText></level><history><historyGroup groupType="history-citation"><historyItem><bodyText><p><citation normalizedCite="1997 VA CH 390"><content><span normalizedCite="1997 Va. Ch. 390">1997, c. 390<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1997#000390#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>; <citation normalizedCite="1998 VA CH 695"><content><span normalizedCite="1998 Va. Ch. 695">1998, c. 695<locator><locatorKey><keyName name="citeReference"/><keyValue value="#1834#131#1998#000695#"/></locatorKey></locator></span></content></citation>.</p></bodyText></historyItem></historyGroup></history></level></statute></legislativeDocBody><metadata><dc:metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><dc:identifier identifierScheme="PGUID">urn:contentItem:5K0Y-PV20-004G-K276-00000-00</dc:identifier><dc:source sourceScheme="productContentSetIdentifier">10816</dc:source><dc:date dateType="last-updated">2016-06-15</dc:date></dc:metadata><publicationInfo><publicationName>CODE OF VIRGINIA </publicationName><copyright>Copyright © 2016  by Matthew Bender &amp; Company, Inc. a member of the LexisNexis Group. All rights reserved</copyright></publicationInfo><hierarchy><hierarchyLevel levelType="title"><heading><desig>TITLE 45.1.</desig><title>MINES AND MINING</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="chapter"><heading><desig>CHAPTER 14.4:1.</desig><title>MINERAL MINE SAFETY ACT</title></heading><hierarchyLevel levelType="article"><heading><desig>ARTICLE 4.</desig><title>LICENSING OF MINERAL MINES</title></heading></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchyLevel></hierarchy><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>Sole Proprietorships</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MEIwMzNBMUU0RDNDNEE0Q0IxQzAzRDAwNDdGNUYzQkM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjA4OEVGODBENzY4NDcxM0IyQzA1OTEwQzVDODRBOUE</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjA4OEVGODBENzY4NDcxM0IyQzA1OTEwQzVDODRBOUE7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDcwMkY0QzAwMDYyNDBFRjkyMDU5NDA3MEZGQTkwNjQ7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MTVCMEIxNDNCRDhENDA2OUEwRTczQTc4MjdGOUJBNEE</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RkE2ODg4Mjk1MTE2NDgzOTk1NTVERDRBRUJFRUUxMjk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NjMzQjkyNzZDOUQ4NEQ2NEIyOEYxNkJCNzBGNTk1OEY</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Sole Proprietorships</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MEIwMzNBMUU0RDNDNEE0Q0IxQzAzRDAwNDdGNUYzQkM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjA4OEVGODBENzY4NDcxM0IyQzA1OTEwQzVDODRBOUE</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Energy &amp; Utilities Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OUUzODAyRDk1QzVFNEZGMEJDM0RGMDYxOTlEMEEzRDA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6Mjk0QjdGQzUxRTVBNEU0Njk1NTIyOTQ3RTJBMjkwRDk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QUVBRUJBMUFDNjYwNDlBQjg2QzY2NjgwQjY0QzU5NUM</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RkM1QzU3MDk5NDNFNEM3OUIxMzAwQUIwMjY3OUE5Qjk7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RDM5MTFCRDA1Rjg2NEM4QzhDQzhBNkE4MjQzNUQxQzA</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Joint Ventures &amp; Partnerships</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RTgxRDg0NTc1QjI3NDg5OUI1MjdBMjdCRjRDRjZFRjg7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6M0VBNkQ0RUY5NENENDhEQUI4REU1MEFBQ0ExQjUyNTY</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Trademark Law</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QUY4QzQ2QTdDQjY1NEFGMjlGQjMwMTYzM0FDN0IxRTA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OTJGOTE4NkMyQ0M2NDcyQzlGMEQ3RTczNTg0MzBBM0E7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NkUwRDYyOTFBOTE1NDdCMjhGQjI0NjdDQ0M0NzEwMzY</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjkwOEJEMDlBMkRENDBDOThERjEwMjA2RThCNkZFQTM7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MDQ0QkU2NEZCRkIxNDE2MkJCMTE1M0ExMjVGRTY1NTc</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QTUzRTNENDYwNjJDNDVGNDk3QTY0QkZEMjc4MUEzNTc7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6RDVDM0Y3MDdEOTE5NEVCNDgxMDNDMjU0MjcxMzUyMTg</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>General Overview</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QjI0NDg2MzBERDBDNDYxQ0I4OTVENUI1MDJGN0FFRUU7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QkYzRTA5MzU2N0YwNDVGQTg2NUExNjFBMjkxQzcyNzE</classCode></classificationItem><classificationItem><className>Telephone Numbers</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6NzcxQjlDMjlGQzVDNEVCQzg5MjY5RDJFOTMzMjA5NTY7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6QzI5NEZCQjE4MUFCNEY3MkEyOENBMTc5MjBCNjIwMDk</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification><classificationGroup classificationScheme="indexing-terms"><classification classificationScheme="legal"><classificationItem><className>Business &amp; Corporate Compliance</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD0</classCode><classificationItem score="90"><className>Energy &amp; Utilities</className><classCode>Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6OUUzODAyRDk1QzVFNEZGMEJDM0RGMDYxOTlEMEEzRDA7cGFyZW50Z3VpZD11cm46dG9waWM6MUFEMUQ2QTA1OUZCNEE5RjkzNTA2RERFMUNEOTk1RTI</classCode></classificationItem></classificationItem></classification></classificationGroup></metadata></legislativeDoc>